<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 20:38:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Ask Jerry: Why doesn't Apple sell iOS to other companies? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Welcome to Ask Jerry, where we talk about any and all the questions you might have about the smart things in your life. I&apos;m Jerry, and I have spent the better part of my life working with tech. I have a background in engineering and R&D and have been covering Android and Google for the past 15 years.</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Ask Jerry</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="rbW6k4ZmBUAZL7mR2bMnV6" name="jerrydude-avatar.gif" caption="" alt="Android Avatar of Jerry" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rbW6k4ZmBUAZL7mR2bMnV6.gif" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Future)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">Ask Jerry is a column where we answer your burning Android/tech questions with the help of long-time Android Central editor Jerry Hildenbrand.</p></div></div>
<p>I&apos;m also really good at researching data about everything — that&apos;s a big part of our job here at Android Central — and I love to help people (another big part of our job!). If you have questions about your tech, I&apos;d love to talk about them. </p><p>Email me at <strong>askjerryac@gmail.com</strong>, and I&apos;ll try to get things sorted out. You can remain anonymous if you like, and we promise we&apos;re not sharing anything we don&apos;t cover here.</p><p>I look forward to hearing from you!</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="why-isn-apos-t-apple-selling-ios-2">Why isn&apos;t Apple selling iOS?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="bXrYPGW8SdFb53LKmEVk9f" name="oneplus-12-vs-iphone-15-pro-max-6.jpg" alt="OnePlus 12 vs. iPhone 15 Pro Max" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bXrYPGW8SdFb53LKmEVk9f.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Ed writes:</p><p><em><strong>Google&apos;s Android operating system operates on many different platforms and brands of phones, so why don’t any brands use iOS or request to use it?</strong></em></p>
<p>Ed asks a question here that I often think about — what if Apple licensed out its phone and tablet OS the way Google does, or Microsoft does for desktops and laptops? More importantly, has it ever been considered, and if not, why not?</p><p>I mean a lot of people would love it. Imagine the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best phones</a> out there, something like a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/i-spent-a-week-with-the-z-fold-5-coming-home">Galaxy Fold</a>, running iOS. You get the great and innovative physical hardware combined with the software many of us love to use. Or the fun form factor of a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/choosing-between-samsung-galaxy-z-flip-5-motorola-razr-plus">Galaxy Flip or Moto Razr</a>. I&apos;ll bet a lot of people would buy it and even more people would <em>want</em> to buy it.</p>
<p>I&apos;m quickly bounced back to reality when I remember one thing — Apple has no incentive to do this. Money may or may not be the root of all evil, but it is the root of every decision any tech company makes.</p>
<h2 id="cold-hard-cash-2">Cold hard cash</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="P4sX3BxVGEhcS6gHgvJ2nY" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Z-Fold-4-deals-money-03.jpg" alt="A Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 4 with US dollars" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/P4sX3BxVGEhcS6gHgvJ2nY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The iPhone is Apple&apos;s prime source of revenue. Without it, Apple couldn&apos;t afford to do the things it wants to do with other products like the iPad or MacBook. Without iPhone sales, Apple would look very different from what we see today.</p><p>Historically, Windows and Office are Microsoft&apos;s prime revenue streams. These two products have given Microsoft the cash to build a great cloud computing platform and build its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/why-im-switching-from-chromebook-to-surface-tablet">Surface laptops</a>. There is even enough money left over for"throw-away" products like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/do-you-have-any-interest-buying-microsoft-surface-duo">phones running Android</a> in case the idea takes off.</p><p>Android is not <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-leaked-2024-goals">Google&apos;s biggest source of revenue</a>. Android is a vehicle for monetization. Using software to ferry people into a system where each generates income isn&apos;t a new idea nor is Google the only company doing it, but Android is probably the most successful at it so far.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2046px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.30%;"><img id="AujxjzYqhcnBb7ZQ3RePwL" name="surface-duo-review-25.jpg" alt="Microsoft Surface Duo partially open" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AujxjzYqhcnBb7ZQ3RePwL.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2046" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Daniel Bader / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Each of these things is pretty different from the other but they help explain why Apple keeps iOS for itself. Apple depends on selling iPhones and there is too much competition for it to reinvent itself.</p><p>I&apos;ll Use Microsoft as an example again. The company came in at the right time with software that was so much better than anything else out there and everyone bought it. By today&apos;s standards, early versions of Windows and Office were terrible to use. But the computing age was new and Microsoft got in on the ground floor, amassing a fortune. It has leveraged this fortune to build other products that make money now that Windows and Office aren&apos;t the revenue stream of the future.</p>
<p>Google doesn&apos;t place as much importance on Android as a product because it just wants everyone to use the internet. Eyeballs on the web and web services are how Google makes money, regardless of the platform being used. </p><p>Android is a way to make computing more affordable because Google saw the importance of emerging markets like India and South America when they were "emerging". I remember speaking with some Google execs over 10 years ago and the most important thing was India&apos;s share of the world technology market. It was important that everyone in India who wanted a way to use the internet could afford to use the internet.</p><p>They were right, and as places like India turned into millions and millions of eyeballs on the web and Google&apos;s services, Google made a lot of money.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="qzygMhemnLWENqynvXb8EP" name="iphone13-pro-max-17.jpg" alt="iPhone 13 Pro Max" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qzygMhemnLWENqynvXb8EP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1536" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Apple, on the other hand, depends on people to purchase its hardware. To Apple, iOS is important because it is a way to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-shipped-more-phones-than-anyone-else-in-q1-2024">sell iPhones</a>, not the other way around. Apple has done a lot to maximize profits on the back of the iPhone and tailoring iOS for what it thinks is the best iPhone experience is one of the most important.</p><p>Apple could sell iOS to companies like Samsung or Xiaomi. I think both companies would be interested and buy it. But doing that would dilute and pollute the experience and prestige of owning the company&apos;s most important product: the iPhone.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/ask-jerry-why-doesnt-apple-sell-ios-to-other-companies</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Have a question about the tech in your life? If so, maybe we can get them answered! ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">PngZaSy2uBuCjftLtjtww9</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HrmCzNcQDgwjg2sArrBf7S.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 20:37:28 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HrmCzNcQDgwjg2sArrBf7S.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android statues]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android statues]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Android's Quick Share tipped to gain useful, faster sharing option ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The latest Google Play Service beta's code contained details about a new, speedier option for sending files in Quick Share.</li><li>It seems the feature is primed to pick up a QR code option, which will reportedly "speed up" the communication process between devices.</li><li>Google rebranded Nearby Share to Quick Share in January, and its CES 2024 appearance showed its new updates.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Quick Share lets users easily send files to one another and it looks like the feature is in line for a new feature to make things faster.</p><p>As spotted by AssembleDebug (<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/android-quick-share-qr-code-3444391/">Android Authority</a>), Android&apos;s Quick Share is preparing to roll out a QR code function. In version 24.20.13 of the Google Play Services beta, the QR option will reportedly give users an alternative way to establish a "connection" with another person. After Bluetooth and Location permissions are accepted, users can generate a code for your files.</p><p>The tipster states this can be done by selecting your files, tapping <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-use-nearby-share-your-android-phone">Quick Share</a> in the menu, and hitting "Share with QR code."</p><p>Supposedly, the early sighting shows that the QR code will remove the necessity behind altering your Quick Share privacy settings. Moreover, the QR code can "speed up" the process between two devices preparing to share and receive.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:265px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:226.42%;"><img id="i3PGaWn9rv9cpLBLzhYJzn" name="google-android-quick-share-qr-code-example.jpg" alt="An example of what Quick Share's new QR code option could look like." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/i3PGaWn9rv9cpLBLzhYJzn.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="265" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The tipster adds that the QR code creates a nearby deep link URL, which is the catalyst behind the established connection for sharing. For Android, this seems to work seamlessly without a hitch. However, it was discovered that attempting to do the same with an iPhone user will toss them to the Quick Share support page.</p><p>Google started its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-rolling-out-quick-share-to-pixel-devices">Nearby Share rebrand</a> to Quick Share in January. The company wanted to create interoperability for users for a better sharing experience. While the name is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-use-samsungs-quick-share-feature">similar to Samsung&apos;s</a>, Google&apos;s version is integrated with its Play Services. This allows the quick sharing method to be transferred to all Android phones, regardless of maker.</p><p>More importantly, Quick Share&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/embargo-19-1pm-et-quick-share-becomes-a-true-airdrop-alternative-with-support-for-all-android-and-chrome-os-devices">CES 2024 appearance</a> showed off its new peer-to-peer sharing protocol for Android and ChromeOS devices. The company also teased its plans to work with PC manufacturers for Quick Share support to computers through pre-installed apps.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-quick-share-speedier-sharing-option-tipped</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A tipster discovered a new sharing option in line for Android's Quick Share, which might speed up file transfers. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">srDSBruAqboB6KBRTTqJqd</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NeW7yGLqNLaYFmz8oh4bci.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 19:41:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NeW7yGLqNLaYFmz8oh4bci.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Hands-on with the Google Pixel 8 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Hands-on with the Google Pixel 8 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ MAJOR Discover Samsung sale just launched — here are the deals I’d buy before Memorial Day ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Memorial Day sales may be dominating the headlines, but Samsung just quietly <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/discover-samsung-event/"><strong>launched a major shopping event</strong></a> of its own, replete with some of the best tech deals this side of Black Friday. Whether you&apos;re in the market for a new smart TV, tablet, or a feature-packed smartphone, you&apos;ll find a selection of my favorite offers below.</p><p>Keep in mind that this Discover Samsung event only runs through May 26th, so you only have a few days to take advantage of the deals. Additionally, although we&apos;re using this guide to showcase the best <em>weeklong </em>offers, it&apos;s worth noting that Samsung is also dropping a lot of daily flash deals as part of the sale. These offers run for only 24 hours and may significantly improve upon the discounts detailed here. </p><p>Anyway, enough chitchat, if you&apos;re ready to save some cash on a great Samsung device (including several of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a>), keep reading to see my top picks.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-quick-links"><span>Quick links</span></h3>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/discover-samsung-event/"><strong>Deals of the Day — </strong><em><strong>see today's offer</strong></em></a></li><li><strong>Phones: </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/">up to $1,100 off Galaxy S24 series, foldable phones</a></li><li><strong>Tablets: </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/tablets-laptops-computers-deals/">enhanced trade-in credit, up to 50% off accessories</a></li><li><strong>Wearables: </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/watches-audio-accessories-deals/">up to $350 off Galaxy Watch w/ trade-in</a></li><li><strong>Smart TVs: </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/tv-and-home-theater-deals/">major discounts on OLED TVs, soundbars, and more</a></li><li><strong>Headphones/earbuds: </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/watches-audio-accessories-deals/">up to $50 instant trade-in credit, bundle offers</a></li><li><strong>Appliances: </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/home-appliance-and-smart-home-sales/">up to $1,400 off appliances, free installation</a></li></ul>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-samsung-deals"><span>Samsung deals</span></h3>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="57951ce2-cefd-472b-a11d-cf056fd253a1" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$859.99" data-dimension48="$859.99" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/smartphones/galaxy-s24/buy/galaxy-s24-256gb-unlocked-sm-s921ulbexaa/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1200px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="NqhoUu3WzqW2D7ngA6rmHK" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-render-square-crop-black.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NqhoUu3WzqW2D7ngA6rmHK.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1200" height="1200" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>1. Samsung Galaxy S24 256GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/smartphones/galaxy-s24/buy/galaxy-s24-256gb-unlocked-sm-s921ulbexaa/" data-dimension112="57951ce2-cefd-472b-a11d-cf056fd253a1" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$859.99" data-dimension48="$859.99"><del>$859.99</del><strong> $799.99, plus up to $535 off with trade-in and FREE screen protector</strong></a></p>
<p>Grab Samsung's base model flagship before the sale ends and you'll get a free storage boost to 256GB, plus a complimentary screen protector and up to $535 off your purchase when you trade in an old or broken phone. Buying direct from Samsung also means that you'll get access to some exclusive color options not available anywhere else.  <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/smartphones/galaxy-s24/buy/galaxy-s24-256gb-unlocked-sm-s921ulbexaa/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="57951ce2-cefd-472b-a11d-cf056fd253a1" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$859.99" data-dimension48="$859.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="8ba84ee1-ec7a-4854-acc9-0d6797859954" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="2. Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra 512GB: $1,419.99" data-dimension48="2. Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra 512GB: $1,419.99" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/smartphones/galaxy-s24-ultra/buy/galaxy-s24-ultra-512gb-unlocked-sm-s928uzvfxaa/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="VY4ygkqW3o67i8WnJ8pfQX" name="Samsung-Galaxy-s24-Ultra-render-bg.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VY4ygkqW3o67i8WnJ8pfQX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>2. Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra 512GB: </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/smartphones/galaxy-s24-ultra/buy/galaxy-s24-ultra-512gb-unlocked-sm-s928uzvfxaa/" data-dimension112="8ba84ee1-ec7a-4854-acc9-0d6797859954" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="2. Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra 512GB: $1,419.99" data-dimension48="2. Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra 512GB: $1,419.99"><del>$1,419.99</del> <strong>$1,299.99, plus up to $750 off with trade-in and FREE Galaxy Buds 2 Pro earbuds</strong></a></p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review#section-samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-price-and-availability">Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra</a> is supremely powerful, but it's also far from cheap. Fortunately, you can grab the phone unlocked during the Discover Samsung sale and get a free storage upgrade to 512GB AND a pair of Galaxy Buds 2 Pro (a $229 value). Trade in an old device and you could get up to $750 off, as well.</p>
<p>This offer is around all week long, but if you buy today (May 20th), your max trade-in credit will jump up to $1,100. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/smartphones/galaxy-s24-ultra/buy/galaxy-s24-ultra-512gb-unlocked-sm-s928uzvfxaa/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="8ba84ee1-ec7a-4854-acc9-0d6797859954" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="2. Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra 512GB: $1,419.99" data-dimension48="2. Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra 512GB: $1,419.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="ca327eb9-37d8-4e22-aa75-bdd67e8244cd" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="3. Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5 256GB: Up to $800 off with trade-in, plus free $100 Samsung credit with carrier activation" data-dimension48="3. Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5 256GB: Up to $800 off with trade-in, plus free $100 Samsung credit with carrier activation" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/smartphones/galaxy-z-fold5/buy/galaxy-z-fold5-256gb-unlocked-sm-f946uzuaxaa/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1464px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:99.04%;"><img id="6n5jxPjhMepcmiRXt2Qpbk" name="galaxy-z-fold-5-render-cream.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6n5jxPjhMepcmiRXt2Qpbk.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1464" height="1450" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>3. Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5 256GB: </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/smartphones/galaxy-z-fold5/buy/galaxy-z-fold5-256gb-unlocked-sm-f946uzuaxaa/" data-dimension112="ca327eb9-37d8-4e22-aa75-bdd67e8244cd" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="3. Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5 256GB: Up to $800 off with trade-in, plus free $100 Samsung credit with carrier activation" data-dimension48="3. Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5 256GB: Up to $800 off with trade-in, plus free $100 Samsung credit with carrier activation"><strong>Up to $800 off with trade-in, plus free $100 Samsung credit with carrier activation</strong></a></p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-5-review">Galaxy Z Fold 5</a> is Samsung's best foldable, complete with two glorious displays, excellent performance, and loads of software support. Purchase and activate the phone through your carrier during the sale event and you'll get $100 of instant Samsung credit straight away, plus up to $800 off when you trade in.  <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/smartphones/galaxy-z-fold5/buy/galaxy-z-fold5-256gb-unlocked-sm-f946uzuaxaa/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="ca327eb9-37d8-4e22-aa75-bdd67e8244cd" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="3. Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5 256GB: Up to $800 off with trade-in, plus free $100 Samsung credit with carrier activation" data-dimension48="3. Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5 256GB: Up to $800 off with trade-in, plus free $100 Samsung credit with carrier activation">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="119106da-c4e9-419e-94c9-4ec9165eaaf4" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$2,799.99" data-dimension48="$2,799.99" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/televisions-home-theater/tvs/qled-4k-tvs/85-class-qled-4k-qe1c-qn85qe1cafxza/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:696px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:82.76%;"><img id="Grxzp9QTnK2GZRxUrCK3nE" name="samsung-qled-tv-render.JPG" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Grxzp9QTnK2GZRxUrCK3nE.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="696" height="576" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>4. Samsung 85" Class QE1C QLED smart TV:</strong> <a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/televisions-home-theater/tvs/qled-4k-tvs/85-class-qled-4k-qe1c-qn85qe1cafxza/" data-dimension112="119106da-c4e9-419e-94c9-4ec9165eaaf4" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$2,799.99" data-dimension48="$2,799.99"><del>$2,799.99</del> <strong>$1,500 at Samsung</strong></a></p>
<p>Of course, smartphones aren't the only type of tech receiving discounts during Samsung's sale. Pick up the 85-inch Class QE1C QLED smart TV this week and you'll score a straight $1,299.99 discount, no strings attached. This beast of performance features AI-powered 4K upscaling so your content always looks as vivid and lifelike as possible, plus you get performance-boosting tools like the Motion Xcelerator and Object Tracking Sound support. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/televisions-home-theater/tvs/qled-4k-tvs/85-class-qled-4k-qe1c-qn85qe1cafxza/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="119106da-c4e9-419e-94c9-4ec9165eaaf4" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$2,799.99" data-dimension48="$2,799.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="c73f47c8-e74c-4f7e-b45c-528cb76faba4" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$2,599.99" data-dimension48="$2,599.99" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/televisions-home-theater/tvs/oled-tvs/65-class-s90c-oled-4k-smart-tv-2023-qn65s90cafxza/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1264px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:62.66%;"><img id="JQerdAQ8UM7xc4ZzR9h5rf" name="samsung-oled-tizen-tv-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JQerdAQ8UM7xc4ZzR9h5rf.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1264" height="792" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>5. Samsung 65" OLED S90C (2023) smart TV:</strong> <a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/televisions-home-theater/tvs/oled-tvs/65-class-s90c-oled-4k-smart-tv-2023-qn65s90cafxza/" data-dimension112="c73f47c8-e74c-4f7e-b45c-528cb76faba4" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$2,599.99" data-dimension48="$2,599.99"><del>$2,599.99</del><strong> $1,599.99 at Samsung</strong></a></p>
<p>Looking for a real deal OLED TV? Samsung's S90C series is one of the best-selling options on the market, with 4K upscaling, an ultra-slim construction, and truly glorious picture. Grab this 65-inch model during this week's Discover Samsung event and you'll get a mighty $1,000 carved off your purchase. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/televisions-home-theater/tvs/oled-tvs/65-class-s90c-oled-4k-smart-tv-2023-qn65s90cafxza/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="c73f47c8-e74c-4f7e-b45c-528cb76faba4" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$2,599.99" data-dimension48="$2,599.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="7de87046-062d-45db-ada2-3fb966c641f5" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$329.99" data-dimension48="$329.99" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/watches/galaxy-watch6/buy/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="bnafjK3yeBkd6g5XtEJ9qZ" name="galaxy-watch-6-square.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bnafjK3yeBkd6g5XtEJ9qZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="500" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>6. Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 44mm:</strong> <a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/watches/galaxy-watch6/buy/" data-dimension112="7de87046-062d-45db-ada2-3fb966c641f5" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$329.99" data-dimension48="$329.99"><del>$329.99</del><strong> $269.99, plus up to $200 off with trade-in at Samsung</strong></a></p>
<p>Over six months since its release date, and the Galaxy Watch 6 continues to reign as one of the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch">best Android smartwatches</a> on the market. Grab any configuration of the GW6 during the Discover Samsung sale and you'll get a straight $60 off plus up to $200 off when you trade in an older wearable. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/watches/galaxy-watch6/buy/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="7de87046-062d-45db-ada2-3fb966c641f5" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$329.99" data-dimension48="$329.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="f5ab8b31-380c-42c5-bc07-11a460c3f187" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="7. Samsung Galaxy S9 Ultra: $1,199.99" data-dimension48="7. Samsung Galaxy S9 Ultra: $1,199.99" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/tablets/galaxy-tab-s9/buy/galaxy-tab-s9-ultra-256gb-graphite-wi-fi-sm-x910nzaaxar/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="yLfHKyedVCjhtyaSNpCT67" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Tab-S9-Ultra-with-S-Pen-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yLfHKyedVCjhtyaSNpCT67.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1080" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>7. Samsung Galaxy S9 Ultra: </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/tablets/galaxy-tab-s9/buy/galaxy-tab-s9-ultra-256gb-graphite-wi-fi-sm-x910nzaaxar/" data-dimension112="f5ab8b31-380c-42c5-bc07-11a460c3f187" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="7. Samsung Galaxy S9 Ultra: $1,199.99" data-dimension48="7. Samsung Galaxy S9 Ultra: $1,199.99"><del>$1,199.99</del> <strong>$999.99, plus up to $800 off with trade-in at Samsung</strong></a></p>
<p>If you've been waiting for the right time to invest in the super powerful (and super expensive) Galaxy S9 Ultra, look no further than the Discover Samsung sale. You'll get a straight $200 off when you buy the tablet this week, plus up to $800 of trade-in credit is up for grabs if you have another device collecting dust. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/tablets/galaxy-tab-s9/buy/galaxy-tab-s9-ultra-256gb-graphite-wi-fi-sm-x910nzaaxar/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="f5ab8b31-380c-42c5-bc07-11a460c3f187" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="7. Samsung Galaxy S9 Ultra: $1,199.99" data-dimension48="7. Samsung Galaxy S9 Ultra: $1,199.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><em>Samsung isn&apos;t the only site dropping major discounts on tech this Summer. We&apos;ve also been gathering all of our favorite </em><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/amazon-kicks-off-memorial-day-sale-early-here-are-the-5-deals-id-recommend-now"><em>Amazon Memorial Day deals</em></a><em> and </em><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/best-buy-memorial-day-sale-2024-these-are-top-20-early-deals-id-buy-right-now"><em>Best Buy Memorial Day deals</em></a><em> for Android fans so you don&apos;t have to go looking on your own. </em></p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/major-discover-samsung-sale-just-launched-here-are-the-deals-id-buy-before-memorial-day</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ For one week only, Samsung is running a major sale on tech across the site, with a particular focus on daily flash deals. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">8E7anQhE8cLkGPP3JW9ds8</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WGZFcwvp3vUr2yezPByNfN.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 18:41:30 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WGZFcwvp3vUr2yezPByNfN.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The back of the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra in the Titanium Grey colorway]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The back of the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra in the Titanium Grey colorway]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Supposed Pixel 9 series color options leak alongside wallpaper teasers ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Rumors suggest the base Pixel 9, Pixel 9 Pro, and Pro XL will see four colorways during launch later this year.</li><li>The higher-end devices may offer Hazel, Obsidian, Porcelain, and Rose options.</li><li>Leaks about the Pixel 9's wallpapers surfaced, with those stating Google is opting for a "Swirling Petals" theme.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>The hype builds around Google&apos;s Pixel 9 series, and we see some rumors surrounding potential colorways.</p><p>Speculation stems from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/google-pixel-9-wallpapers-3444413/">Android Authority</a> who suggest the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9">Pixel 9 Pro and 9 Pro XL</a> will share four colorways. Both higher-end devices will feature a Hazel, Obsidian, Porcelain, and Rose option. The rumors continue to the base model, which suggests that its four options could be the following: Jade, Obsidian, Peony, and Porcelain.</p><p>The next iteration of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-fold-review">Pixel Fold</a>, rumored to go by the "Pixel 9 Pro Fold" moniker, might only have two colorways. The publication states the next foldable could see Obsidian and "gold" (Porcelain) options once it launches.</p><p>It&apos;s worth noting that these are reportedly the color "codenames," so there&apos;s a chance we might see something different later this year.</p><p>Leaks continue with the publication citing a Google insider for spilling the details about the Pixel 9&apos;s exclusive wallpapers. Supposedly, the series will sport a "Swirling Petal" theme. The backgrounds may represent "abstract florals" with a "swirling display."</p><p>If you want to download them, you can do so from Android Authority directly.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="yALGd4d6ppAH5GtnHrZ6Si" name="Google-Pixel-8-Pro-with-mint-case.jpg" alt="Hands-on with the Google Pixel 8 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yALGd4d6ppAH5GtnHrZ6Si.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The latest round of Pixel 9 rumors arrives one week after <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/entire-pixel-9-series-live-photos-specs-leak">the entire series</a> was leaked in live photos. Hours before <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-io-2024-biggest-announcements">I/O 2024</a>, we were given a good look at the series&apos; potential changes, like the camera lens, which doesn&apos;t stretch the span of the back panel. Leaked specs purported that the Pixel 9 could see a 6.2-inch display. The Pixel 9 Pro may see a 6.3-inch while the Pro XL could land at 6.7 inches.</p><p>It also seems Google will swap between matte and glossy finishes for the series. The different finishes may reportedly affect the rear camera visor and panel. We&apos;re expecting the 9 series to be powered by the new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-samsung-upgraded-tensor-g4-process">Tensor G4</a>, as well.</p><p>Elsewhere, in April, it was rumored that the "Fold 2" could become the "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-fold-successor-name-change-rumors">Pixel 9 Pro Fold</a>." The running theory is that the name change allows Google to bring the foldable into a more "flagship-level" space. Additionally, the device would (ideally) make its debut later this fall alongside the rest of the Pixel 9 series.</p><p>Internally, 16GB RAM and 256GB of storage are rumored for the foldable.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/pixel-9-leaked-colorways-wallpaper-theme</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A new leak speculated on the Google Pixel 9 series' potential colors alongside its new wallpaper theme. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">WKj4s9FCZWQKTAEetBwZD7</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dcNCbr6mRKoE8XqirVyVSS.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 18:27:03 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dcNCbr6mRKoE8XqirVyVSS.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[MySmartPrice]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A leaked rendering of the Pixel 9 Pro.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A leaked rendering of the Pixel 9 Pro.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Amazon's Memorial Day sale just dropped the OnePlus Open to its lowest price EVER ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Foldable phone deals are back, this time with the premium OnePlus Open. The unlocked <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CHN7M531"><strong>OnePlus Open is currently $300 off at Amazon</strong></a>, effectively bringing this pricy phone to its lowest price ever. Despite the steep price tag, you&apos;ll definitely be getting what you pay for with this device. The OnePlus Open boasts an impressive set of cameras, powerful performance, four Android OS updates, and over a day&apos;s worth of battery life per charge. It&apos;s also well-liked for its huge 6.31-inch cover screen, and its vibrant 7.82-inch inner screen.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="af5036af-8b77-4bdb-bf74-c7eac0a6a135" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,699" data-dimension48="$1,699" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CHN7M531" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="QSYk3NcBLurXEbth9DH4Bc" name="oneplus-open-bg.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QSYk3NcBLurXEbth9DH4Bc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>OnePlus Open 512GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CHN7M531" data-dimension112="af5036af-8b77-4bdb-bf74-c7eac0a6a135" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,699" data-dimension48="$1,699"><del>$1,699</del> <strong>$1,399 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>The 512GB OnePlus Open is a great premium-level foldable phone, and with a new $300 off at Amazon, it's now at its cheapest price ever. This is our <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">favorite premium foldable phone</a>, largely due to its vibrant inner and outer screens and fast performance. It also offers more than a day of battery life and powerful cameras that users appreciate.</p>
<p><strong>Price comparison:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oneplus-open-16gb-512gb-unlocked-voyager-black/6562713.p">Best Buy - $1,499</a> | <a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/OnePlus-Open-16GB-RAM-512GB-Dual-SIM-Voyager-Black-US-Factory-Unlocked-Android-Smartphone-4805-mAh-Battery-67W-Fast-Charging-Hasselblad-Camera-120Hz/5312154788">Walmart - $1,799</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CHN7M531" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="af5036af-8b77-4bdb-bf74-c7eac0a6a135" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,699" data-dimension48="$1,699">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>you can afford to get a phone at this price point and are looking for a good deal; having a powerful, sturdy phone with a bold, unique design is a priority to you; you frequently use multi-tasking features on your phone.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>you&apos;re looking for a phone that&apos;s capable of wireless charging; you can&apos;t imagine spending over $1,000 on a smartphone; you&apos;re looking for a phone you can game on at higher than 60fps.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-open-review">OnePlus Open</a> is definitely a premium phone, featuring a fold-out design that leaves hardly any visible crease between the inner screens. This phone offers 16GB of RAM and 512GB of storage, along with beautiful inner and outer screens, four Android OS updates, and excellent performance. People also appreciate the OnePlus Open&apos;s impressive set of cameras and its more than a day of battery life.</p><p>Some of the downsides to this phone include the fact that it doesn&apos;t include wireless charging, and it can&apos;t run games above 60fps. It&apos;s also a pretty expensive phone normally, though that makes this deal look pretty good if it checks all your other boxes.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/amazons-memorial-day-sale-just-dropped-the-oneplus-open-to-its-lowest-price-ever</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Amazon has cut the price of the OnePlus Open by $300, bringing the unlocked foldable phone to its lowest price yet. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Q3yedoha29ULNEFiig8pkA</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/htHM4nHEfUMhY7sUAwqhsD.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 16:27:26 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/htHM4nHEfUMhY7sUAwqhsD.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus Open review]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus Open review]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ FCC listings foreshadow Galaxy Watch 7 series and budget Galaxy Watch FE ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung is only months away from launching new smartwatches, and they’ve appeared in new FCC listings. </li><li>The model numbers appear to match the standard Galaxy Watch 7, but not the rumored Galaxy Watch 7 Pro variant.</li><li>Instead, the FCC listings could indicate the long-speculated Galaxy Watch FE is nearing a launch.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Leaks and rumors around the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-7">Samsung Galaxy Watch 7 series</a> are heating up, but we just got official confirmation that new smartwatches are coming in the way of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://apps.fcc.gov/oetcf/eas/reports/ViewExhibitReport.cfm?mode=Exhibits&RequestTimeout=500&calledFromFrame=Y&application_id=zbnNiYP2Den8e4GS3bLJ8w%3D%3D&fcc_id=A3LSMR861" target="_blank">Federal Communications Commission (FCC) listings</a>. Every new product that comes out with wireless connectivity, like Wi-Fi, Bluetooth, or cellular, must be registered and approved by the FCC. There were new listings tied to Samsung for a “smart wearable” device, and there is a strong likelihood that these are upcoming Galaxy Watches. </p><p>The listings, first spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.droid-life.com/2024/05/17/galaxy-watch-7-stops-through-fcc-galaxy-watch-fe-too/" target="_blank">Droid Life</a>, cover the following model numbers: SM-L300, SM-L305, SM-L310, SM-L315, and SM-R861. This aligns with prior leaks and what we’ve seen in previous filings. Last month, Samsung had to file paperwork with the Bluetooth Special Interest Group, since the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/galaxy-watch-7-bluetooth-certification#:~:text=The%20model%20number%2C%20SM%2DL305U,the%20current%20Galaxy%20Watch%206.">Galaxy Watch 7 will use the Bluetooth 5.3 spec</a>. The first four model numbers filed with the FCC match the ones that appeared in the Bluetooth SIG filings earlier. </p><p>Though the FCC filings only officially list these devices as ”smart wearables” from Samsung, that isn’t surprising. Companies try to keep the exact device they’re listing under wraps, but a specific FCC requirement usually reveals more about these devices. When registering a device, companies need to explain how users can find the regulatory information on that device. In this case, Samsung says that regulatory info is found on the About Watch page, confirming that these models are indeed Galaxy Watches. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="ng7EwTzTP7RFHNdYehnDVE" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Watch-6-watchface-detailed.jpg" alt="Samsung Galaxy Watch 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ng7EwTzTP7RFHNdYehnDVE.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>We’ve already seen the model numbers for the Galaxy Watch 7 before, which represent the first four model numbers in the above list. These account for both watch sizes (40mm or 44mm) and both connectivity options (Wi-Fi and Wi-Fi + LTE). As such, there doesn’t appear to be any confirmation of the rumored Galaxy Watch 7 Pro or even something like a Galaxy Watch 7 Classic based on these listings. </p><p>The last model number, SM-R861, is perhaps the most interesting. It doesn’t align with Samsung‘s typical model numbering scheme for flagship Galaxy Watch devices. This is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-likely-to-bring-galaxy-watch-fe-soon">likely the Galaxy Watch FE</a>, or whatever Samsung plans to call its budget Galaxy Watch wearable. It could be called the Galaxy Watch FE or the Galaxy Watch 4 (2024), according to leaks. The latter option may be correct, as the Galaxy Watch 4 model numbering starts with SM-R860, just like the unnamed wearable that appeared in FCC listings.</p><p>We’re going to find out more about the Samsung Galaxy Watch 7 lineup, and perhaps a budget Galaxy Watch model, at Samsung Unpacked this summer. We’ll also probably hear about <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/wear-os-5">Wear OS 5</a>, which was previewed at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-io-2024-biggest-announcements">Google I/O 2024</a>. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fcc-listings-foreshadow-galaxy-watch-7-series-and-budget-galaxy-watch-fe</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung’s upcoming Galaxy Watch 7 series is getting close to launching, and FCC listings confirm new Galaxy Watch 7 models and more.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">zXWzMgzkN38dthVZ99wqVX</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/epMw6fX5kQaJBUuk4svWca.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 15:53:11 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/epMw6fX5kQaJBUuk4svWca.jpeg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Galaxy Watch 6 Classic and Galaxy Watch 6 side-by-side]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Galaxy Watch 6 Classic and Galaxy Watch 6 side-by-side]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Android 15's satellite messaging is already showing up for some T-Mobile users ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>People who both upgraded to the Android 15 beta and have an eligible T-Mobile plan are now seeing a page in settings for satellite messaging. </li><li>This isn’t the first time we’ve seen this menu for satellite messaging, but it’s the first time it has actually appeared in working form for users. </li><li>Previous reports revealed that T-Mobile and Starlink were partnering to support satellite messaging on 15 Android devices. </li></ul>
<hr>
<p>So far, the biggest <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a> feature revealed to date is likely satellite messaging. There have been countless leaks and rumors regarding the feature, which still hasn’t been officially confirmed by Google, even after its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-io-2024-biggest-announcements">I/O 2024</a> developer conference. However, the closest thing we’ve gotten to an official confirmation just happened — people running the Android 15 beta on a device with T-Mobile cellular service are now being informed about satellite messaging, as <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/satellite-messaging-t-mobile-android-15-3444192/" target="_blank">Android Authority</a> reported.</p><p>A few T-Mobile users took to Reddit to share the new settings menu that appeared on their Android 15 device. It’s called <strong>Satellite Messaging</strong>, and it can be accessed by navigating through <strong>Settings > Network & Internet > SIMs > T-Mobile</strong> on devices running Android 15 Beta 2. Though some have managed to force show the Satellite Messaging menu in previous versions of Android 15, the settings page is only starting to appear by default in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-beta-2-just-landed-for-google-pixels-and-non-pixel-devices-too">Android 15 Beta 2</a>. </p><p>Here’s what the Satellite Messaging page will look like in Android 15, as shared by u/erichola on Reddit:</p>
<blockquote class="reddit-card"  ><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/tmobile/comments/1ct1no1/satellite_messaging_option_appeared_on_my_pixel_7">Satellite messaging option appeared on my Pixel 7. </a> from <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/tmobile">r/tmobile</a></blockquote><script async src="//embed.redditmedia.com/widgets/platform.js" charset="UTF-8"></script>
<p>Under the <strong>About satellite messaging</strong> section, there’s a sentence explaining how and if T-Mobile customers can take advantage of satellite messaging in Android 15. “You can send and receive text messages by satellite as part of an eligible T-Mobile account,“ it reads. While we don’t know what T-Mobile plans are supported right now, we do know that the user in question has T-Mobile’s Magenta plan. As such, we can assume that Magenta users will likely be able to use Android 15 satellite messaging without paying extra.</p><p>Notably, there don’t seem to be any restrictions on when and how satellite messaging can be used on Android 15. Many satellite-based features launched in the past are specifically designed to be used in an emergency. Satellite messaging on Android 15 is unique in that it appears to work anytime Wi-Fi and cellular are unavailable, and not limited to those dire situations.</p><p>T-Mobile already announced a partnership with Starlink, and plans to launch text messaging by satellite at some point this year. This is probably the reason why the carrier is the first to appear in the Android 15 settings app. Other carriers may appear in the future, and AT&T is already working on a satellite messaging strategy of its own. As Android Authority surmised, the Android 15 settings menu for satellite messaging doesn’t look like it is unique or exclusive to T-Mobile.</p><p>The presence of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-messages-beta-satellite-messaging-spotted">satellite messaging</a> in the settings menu all but confirms it is coming in Android 15. However, users likely won’t be able to actually use it until their carrier rolls out support for satellite messaging. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15s-satellite-messaging-is-already-showing-up-for-some-t-mobile-users</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google is working on satellite messaging for Android, and it appears Android 15 beta users with a T-Mobile data plan can already use it. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">PRfji2ueHdwfw86iHfCna8</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/a7NZY6fiEXh9Dfx4A7Xwkg.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 14:03:34 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/a7NZY6fiEXh9Dfx4A7Xwkg.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android 15 logo on Pixel 8]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android 15 logo on Pixel 8]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Chrome for iOS might soon gain Circle to Search feature ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google Chrome found testing a new flag for iOS devices that will enable Circle to Search.</li><li>It appears to be an updated version of Google Lens Search for iOS handsets.</li><li>Previously, similar functionality appeared through the Google Search app via a new shortcut.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google&apos;s Circle to Search appears to be expanding to more devices, according to new findings from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.macobserver.com/ios/google-chrome-for-ios-will-soon-get-circle-to-search-feature/">The Mac Observer</a>. This comes after the recent findings of Circle to Search being spotted on iOS devices through the Google Search app&apos;s shortcut workaround.</p><p>Per the publication&apos;s latest findings, Google is working on an updated version of Google Lens Search for iOS dubbed "LensOverlay," the supposed bundle will likely bring the popular Circle to Search feature. And, it will be incorporated into Google Chrome for iOS handsets through a flag dubbed "Lens Circle to Search."</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1361px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:42.47%;"><img id="sZnyjuXyKZtBCVmoPWEoCC" name="google-chrome-ios-circle-to-search-flag.jpg" alt="Circle to Search for iOS" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sZnyjuXyKZtBCVmoPWEoCC.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1361" height="578" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: The Mac Observer)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:40.00%;"><img id="tdyS6AWseDQstREeyXgkTC" name="google-chrome-ios-circle-to-search-flag-01.jpg" alt="Circle to Search for iOS" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tdyS6AWseDQstREeyXgkTC.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1000" height="400" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: The Mac Observer)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>When enabled, iPhone users can search for anything on their screens by circling or squiggling them, provided they are doing so in the Google Chrome app. The Mac Observer further notes that it can be accessible through the Google Lens app on the iOS handsets.</p><p>While it is unclear when the feature will roll out officially, it is believed to venture soon for iOS handsets. It still needs to be determined for iPad users whether this incorporation is part of a recent report, which suggested Apple was in talks with Google to bring its Gemini model to iPhones.</p>
<p>The new spotting is followed by the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-circle-to-search-workaround-for-iphones">recent workaround</a> through the Google Search app, which allowed iPhone users like the iPhone 15 Pro to assign their Action Button to launch Google Lens, which lets users scan their current screen. </p><p>While it&apos;s not the same methodology as Circle to Search, it still effectively completes the same job. It is not just for the latest iPhones; it also works for iPhones without an Action Button. Instead, they have to dig into their accessibility settings and look for double tap/triple tap at the back shortcut, enabling users to screenshot their current screen and open up the new Google Lens shortcut for analysis.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-chrome-for-ios-likely-to-get-circle-to-search</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google seems to be expanding its ways to incorporate the Circle to Search feature for iPhones. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">uMpQhXjL5M5pUny4jcEsWQ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/o9PEwKZCbvXt6TEUKSTMr.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 13:06:45 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/o9PEwKZCbvXt6TEUKSTMr.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Pixel 8a]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Pixel 8a]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Redmi Pad Pro review: Xiaomi's best budget tablet yet ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>After a brief hiatus, Xiaomi reentered the tablet segment with the launch of the Pad 6 last year. That particular model was aimed at the mid-range category, and continues to be a solid choice if you want a large tablet with powerful hardware and stellar battery life. The brand&apos;s more recent Pad 6s Pro 12.4 has even better hardware and a 3K panel with 144Hz.</p><p>But Xiaomi is always at its best when making budget products, and this is true when it comes to tablets as well; last year&apos;s Redmi Pad was one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-tablets">best budget tablets</a> around, and the latest Redmi Pad SE has a few tweaks to the design and upgraded hardware. Xiaomi is building on that foundation with the introduction of the Redmi Pad Pro, which has a larger 12.1-inch panel with an increased QHD resolution, 10000mAh battery, and a new design that uses aluminum liberally.</p><p>What&apos;s interesting is that Xiaomi has retained the 3.5mm jack and MicroSD slot, and the Redmi Pad Pro is still aimed at the budget segment, making it one of the best value-focused tablets you can buy today. My favorite feature is that it runs <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review">Android 14</a> out of the box; Xiaomi has been underhanded in this regard, launching several devices — including the Redmi Pad SE and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/redmi-note-13-pro-plus-review">Redmi Note 13 Pro+</a> — with Android 13 so it wouldn&apos;t have to roll out as many software updates, and that thankfully isn&apos;t an issue with the Redmi Pad Pro.</p><p>If you&apos;re looking to buy a budget tablet with a massive screen, here&apos;s why the Redmi Pad Pro may just be the best option currently available.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-redmi-pad-pro-pricing-and-availability"><span>Redmi Pad Pro: Pricing and availability</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="kwNnSEkmvdZNaCwLy82mLZ" name="redmi-pad-pro-review-20.jpg" alt="Redmi branding on the back of the Redmi Pad Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kwNnSEkmvdZNaCwLy82mLZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Xiaomi unveiled the Redmi Pad Pro in China on April 10, 2024, and the tablet made its global debut on May 20. It is available in three configurations: a base model with 6GB of RAM and 128GB of storage, an 8GB/128GB version, and a model with 8GB of RAM and 256GB of storage.</p><p>Xiaomi sells the Redmi Pad Pro with the keyboard case and stylus as a bundle in China, but that isn&apos;t the case in global markets. The tablet starts at £269 ($340) for the 6GB/128GB version in the U.K., going up to £299 ($380) for the 8GB/256GB model. Xiaomi is bundling a case as well as the Redmi Buds 5 with every order in the U.K. The stylus costs an additional £59 ($75), and the Redmi Smart Keyboard is debuting at £89 ($113).</p><p>In other countries in the region, the Redmi Pad Pro is set to start off at €299 ($325), with pre-orders kicking off May 21 and general availability from June 3. Xiaomi will launch the tablet in India, but as of now, there&apos;s no telling when that will be the case.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-redmi-pad-pro-design"><span>Redmi Pad Pro: Design</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="zSrfWgwC3xuYNEgfGyBNrT" name="redmi-pad-pro-review-1.jpg" alt="Redmi Pad Pro with keyboard case on a table" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zSrfWgwC3xuYNEgfGyBNrT.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Redmi Pad SE has a distinct resemblance to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/xiaomi-12-pro-review">Xiaomi 12 series</a>, and while the Redmi Pad Pro has a similar aesthetic, the new camera housing is visually distinctive. The oversized rings around the camera evoke memories of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/asus-zenfone-10-review">Zenfone 10</a>, and they dominate attention at the back.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="APt7puh4HP7cnpVDUTaScZ" name="redmi-pad-pro-review-21.jpg" alt="Detailed view of the rear cameras of the Redmi Pad Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/APt7puh4HP7cnpVDUTaScZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>There&apos;s a single 8MP camera at the back, so the LED flash gets the same adornment, and considering the camera lens and flash module are rather small, the outsizes housing looks almost comical. But what matters is that it doesn&apos;t protrude too much from the chassis, so there is no wobble when using the Redmi Pad Pro on a table.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="u2DcQAa7egQHncpGbP9JrX" name="redmi-pad-pro-review-14.jpg" alt="Redmi Pad Pro volume button on the right side" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/u2DcQAa7egQHncpGbP9JrX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Xiaomi sells the Redmi Pad Pro in three color variants — Grey, Mint Green, and Ocean Blue — and the green and blue models have very subtle pastel shades. That&apos;s understandable given that tablet designs tend to be more conservative, and to Xiaomi&apos;s credit, there are absolutely no issues with the build quality.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="x2XbgFFVYJG3MjyQh6KmLX" name="redmi-pad-pro-review-13.jpg" alt="Redmi Pad Pro's Dolby Vision branding" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/x2XbgFFVYJG3MjyQh6KmLX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Although the tablet is aimed at the budget segment, you get an aluminum chassis that feels great to hold and use. The rounded edges and beveled sides make a big difference in this area, and while it is heavy at 571g, the tablet balances the weight evenly, so it doesn&apos;t get uncomfortable with extended use.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="ZcpjmHf8puS4VbTyevA74Y" name="redmi-pad-pro-review-15.jpg" alt="Redmi Pad Pro bottom view with 2.5mm jack and USB-C port" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZcpjmHf8puS4VbTyevA74Y.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The power button is located at the top, with the volume buttons on the right. You don&apos;t get the ability to slot in a SIM card and connect to cellular networks, but there is a MicroSD slot that lets you extend the storage by an additional 1.5TB. What I like is that the Redmi Pad Pro has a 3.5mm jack, and there are no issues when using IEMs like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-fa19-review">Fiio FA19</a>.</p><p>On the audio side of things, Xiaomi offers four speakers on the Redmi Pad Pro — two on either side — and they sound great in their own right. Overall, the tablet gets a lot right on the design front, and it doesn&apos;t feel like a budget product.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-redmi-pad-pro-screen"><span>Redmi Pad Pro: Screen</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="rFMpaSQ5SKsmJeLpGQvPbW" name="redmi-pad-pro-review-9.jpg" alt="Redmi Pad Pro home page with icons" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rFMpaSQ5SKsmJeLpGQvPbW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Redmi Pad Pro comes with a 12.1-inch IPS LCD panel that is ideal for streaming content. The panel has a resolution of 2560 x 1600 with a standard 16:10 ratio, and it has Dolby Vision integration and a layer of Gorilla Glass 3. The maximum brightness isn&apos;t particularly high at 500 nits, but I didn&apos;t have any issues using the Redmi Pad Pro outdoors. The tablet goes up to 600 nits in HBM mode, but there&apos;s no noticeable difference when streaming videos.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="kgxJextjSzjBC4XwCTCw2V" name="redmi-pad-pro-review-4.jpg" alt="Redmi Pad Pro's keyboard case docked to the tablet" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kgxJextjSzjBC4XwCTCw2V.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>On that note, the Redmi Pad Pro has Widevine L1, and it is able to stream 1080p and HDR content from the likes of Netflix and YouTube without any hassle. While color fidelity isn&apos;t obviously as good as an OLED panel, the Redmi Pad Pro has plenty to offer in this area, and Xiaomi&apos;s factory calibration continues to be among the best around. The default Vivid mode has vibrant colors and good contrast, and you can tweak the color balance according to your tastes.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="pE8cFTczZfuGchfCxRxdNY" name="redmi-pad-pro-review-17.jpg" alt="Bezels on the Redmi Pad Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pE8cFTczZfuGchfCxRxdNY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Larger tablets are great for reading, and the Redmi Pad Pro includes Xiaomi&apos;s excellent Reading mode. The feature allows you to change the intensity of the colors, or switch to a monochrome palette, and this is ideal if you want to read an e-book. The tablet is decent enough when it comes to playing games as well — you can connect a Bluetooth controller with ease — but the hardware doesn&apos;t have as much grunt, limiting the potential to enjoy demanding titles.</p><p>The best part about the screen on the Redmi Pad Pro is that it has a 120Hz refresh rate; navigating the UI is smooth, and the difference is noticeable even when switching from the 90Hz Redmi Pad SE. That said, you&apos;ll need to go into the settings to enable 120Hz mode, as it is set to Auto out of the box.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="nPkF3zhVp8nuf8fkX4ZFaY" name="redmi-pad-pro-review-16.jpg" alt="Camera of the Redmi Pad Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nPkF3zhVp8nuf8fkX4ZFaY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I don&apos;t have any issues with the panel on the Redmi Pad Pro, and my only quibble has to do with the considerable bezels around the screen. I get that this is a budget tablet, but Xiaomi should have done more to trim the bezels. Talking about the bezels, the front camera is located on the leading edge, and while it isn&apos;t the best I&apos;ve used, it holds up well in video calls.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-redmi-pad-pro-hardware"><span>Redmi Pad Pro: Hardware</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="WexdwMVPzUAB6F2zedyYCa" name="redmi-pad-pro-review-23.jpg" alt="Redmi Pad Pro about device" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WexdwMVPzUAB6F2zedyYCa.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Xiaomi outfitted the Redmi Pad Pro with a Snapdragon 7s Gen 2, and although the chipset is good enough in daily use, it isn&apos;t exactly powerful. I noticed lag sporadically in mundane tasks like browsing in Chrome or switching between apps, and while it doesn&apos;t hinder usability too much, it is irksome.</p>
<p>The memory and storage modules are similarly dated, with Xiaomi using LPDDR4X modules with both the 6GB and 8GB models, and UFS 2.2 storage across the board. Thankfully, there&apos;s Wi-Fi 6 this time around, and you get Bluetooth 5.2. There&apos;s no NFC, you don&apos;t get any high-res codecs, and there&apos;s no ingress protection.</p>

<p>Annoyingly, you don&apos;t get fingerprint authentication on the Redmi Pad Pro either; you&apos;ll need to use face unlock or the usual passcode to log in to the device, and that&apos;s annoying. Xiaomi uses a side-mounted fingerprint reader that&apos;s baked into the power button on plenty of its budget and mid-range phones, and that would have been ideal on the tablet. That said, face unlock has been reliable, and while it isn&apos;t as secure,</p><p>The cameras are strictly average as well, and outside of video calls, the 8MP camera at the front doesn&apos;t have much utility. The 8MP camera at the back has a dedicated Night mode and takes usable shots in daylight, but you&apos;re better off using your phone cameras instead.</p><p>Switching over to the battery, the Redmi Pad Pro has a 10000mAh unit that is among the largest in this segment. I haven&apos;t used the tablet enough to judge battery life, but in less than a week of usage, it has lasted considerably longer than the Redmi Pad SE and any other budget tablet I used recently. I also like the fact that it has 33W charging, and while it takes nearly two hours to charge, it is noticeably faster than the 18W tech that Xiaomi offers on the rest of its budget tablets.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-redmi-pad-pro-accessories"><span>Redmi Pad Pro: Accessories</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="D7UB7PLAhR7mXK2j3SKDQV" name="redmi-pad-pro-review-5.jpg" alt="Redmi Pad Pro's keyboard case highlighted" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/D7UB7PLAhR7mXK2j3SKDQV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Xiaomi sells two accessories with the Redmi Pad Pro: a standard folio case that has decent protection, and a keyboard accessory dubbed the Redmi Smart Keyboard. I used the Xiaomi Pad 6 extensively with its keyboard case, and Xiaomi is doing things a bit differently with the Redmi Pad Pro; the case doesn&apos;t connect to the tablet using pogo pins at the back, instead relying on Bluetooth.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="SXRHg37BfyPVPTqQEYTYeV" name="redmi-pad-pro-review-6.jpg" alt="Side view of Redmi Pad Pro's keyboard case" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SXRHg37BfyPVPTqQEYTYeV.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="kgxJextjSzjBC4XwCTCw2V" name="redmi-pad-pro-review-4.jpg" alt="Redmi Pad Pro's keyboard case docked to the tablet" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kgxJextjSzjBC4XwCTCw2V.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="GTLKK7CbCBX36tfFtYndfU" name="redmi-pad-pro-review-3.jpg" alt="Redmi Pad Pro's keyboard case docked to the tablet" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GTLKK7CbCBX36tfFtYndfU.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Pairing the case to the Redmi Pad Pro is about as seamless as it gets; there&apos;s a toggle on the right that enables Bluetooth connectivity, and it automatically shows up in the device list. The case securely holds the Redmi Pad Pro, and the keys have good tactility. There&apos;s no backlighting, but outside of that, the Redmi Smart Keyboard nails the basics.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="wxyVCHdUcMxDwNh2QmfX8W" name="redmi-pad-pro-review-7.jpg" alt="Redmi Pad Pro stylus attachment" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wxyVCHdUcMxDwNh2QmfX8W.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The other accessory is a stylus called the Redmi Smart Pen, and it is similarly decent. It has 4096 levels of pressure sensitivity, and there&apos;s no noticeable latency when using the stylus to take notes or doodle. The bundled sketching utility is pretty basic, but you can use something like Infinite Painter and make detailed sketches.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="qsxpxkF6L8SZ9Ltxw799PW" name="redmi-pad-pro-review-8.jpg" alt="Redmi Pad Pro stylus charges via USB-C" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qsxpxkF6L8SZ9Ltxw799PW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While the stylus itself is quite good, it doesn&apos;t attach magnetically to the Redmi Pad Pro, and that limits its usability. I also noticed connectivity issues, and had to toggle the Bluetooth modem on the tablet to be able to use the stylus again. </p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-redmi-pad-pro-software"><span>Redmi Pad Pro: Software</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="arVTVf3G87TEfEsfSVxVqZ" name="redmi-pad-pro-review-22.jpg" alt="Redmi Pad Pro's multitasking highlighted" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/arVTVf3G87TEfEsfSVxVqZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>There isn&apos;t too much to talk about on the software side of things, with Xiaomi offering HyperOS 1.0.3.0 based on Android 14 out of the box. That in itself is a big deal, as Xiaomi has thus far been unwilling to pre-install Android 14 on its 2024 budget devices.</p><p>You get most of the same features as the phone build, and there is a decent amount of customizability. Xiaomi doesn&apos;t include many tablet-focused utilities; you still get a split notification pane with the toggles accessible via the right side, and there isn&apos;t a gesture to launch split-screen multitasking.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="z3mdbCL49vbMkNHAqGdBsW" name="redmi-pad-pro-review-10.jpg" alt="Redmi Pad Pro notification pane Control Center" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/z3mdbCL49vbMkNHAqGdBsW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>You will need to press down on an app card within the overview menu and select the mode manually, but once you pull up two windows side-by-side, you can easily resize and change the width of each window, and close both at the same time. The overview menu uses Xiaomi&apos;s standard vertical configuration, and there isn&apos;t a setting to switch it to horizontal scrolling.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="4G46ZcqCUQNRqFvT4mjP5X" name="redmi-pad-pro-review-11.jpg" alt="Redmi Pad Pro's notification pane" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4G46ZcqCUQNRqFvT4mjP5X.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The leftmost pane shows Google&apos;s Discover feed, and there&apos;s no way to disable it. The interface is in need of a visual overhaul, but it is better optimized than MIUI; Xiaomi now needs to turn its attention to polishing the visuals. On the whole, it is easy to navigate and use, and although there is a lot of overt styling, it isn&apos;t anywhere as cumbersome as previous versions of the skin. My biggest quibble is that the toggles in the Control Center don&apos;t have any labels.</p>
<p>When it comes to updates, the Redmi Pad Pro will get two platform updates along with three years of security updates. That is in line with other budget tablets, but considering Xiaomi&apos;s lackadaisical attitude when it comes to platform updates, the tablet is unlikely to make the switch to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a> sometime this year — or even in Q1 2025. That said, at least you&apos;ll get the update at some point, as well as Android 16 when that becomes available.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-redmi-pad-pro-the-competition"><span>Redmi Pad Pro: The competition</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="QsWHSKHcrAirELZcyzbRia" name="redmi-pad-pro-review-25.jpg" alt="Redmi Pad Pro next to Redmi Pad SE" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QsWHSKHcrAirELZcyzbRia.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>There&apos;s no shortage of budget tablets, and if you&apos;re looking to maximize value, Xiaomi&apos;s Redmi Pad SE ticks a lot of the right boxes. It also has a large screen, and while the hardware isn&apos;t as powerful as the Redmi Pad Pro and you miss out on the accessories, it is much more affordable. </p><p>If you need powerful hardware, the Xiaomi Pad 6 is still a great choice in 2024. It has a brighter panel, is terrific at gaming, and while the battery doesn&apos;t last as long, it has a leg up over the Redmi Pad Pro in all other areas.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-redmi-pad-pro-should-you-buy-it"><span>Redmi Pad Pro: Should you buy it?</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="uPpbjryeHPrgNP2inxhrRa" name="redmi-pad-pro-review-24.jpg" alt="Redmi Pad Pro home page" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uPpbjryeHPrgNP2inxhrRa.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>You should buy this if:</strong></p>
<ul><li>You need a large tablet</li><li>You want the best battery life in this segment</li><li>You want a good keyboard accessory</li></ul>
<p><strong>You shouldn&apos;t buy this if:</strong></p>
<ul><li>You need biometric authentication</li><li>You want long-term updates</li></ul>
<p>Xiaomi did all the right things with the Redmi Pad Pro. The switch to a larger screen, 120Hz panel, and increasing the battery size gives the tablet a distinct advantage over the Redmi Pad SE. While it won&apos;t dethrone the iPad, it is noticeably better to use than most budget tablets, and that in itself is a sizeable achievement.</p><p>The Redmi Pad Pro does a great job at the basics, and while you don&apos;t get the accessories bundled with the tablet, the keyboard is worth the investment if you need a budget tablet for productivity. In a similar vein, the stylus is a good choice if you want to sketch on the go.</p><p>I don&apos;t have many negatives to share; the hardware isn&apos;t ideal for gaming, and the lack of a secure authentication system is irksome. But outside of that, there really isn&apos;t much missing here, and if you need a reliable budget tablet with a 12.1-inch screen, the Redmi Pad Pro is a standout option.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/redmi-pad-pro-review</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Xiaomi's Redmi Pad Pro is now officially available outside China, and it has a lot of exciting features, including a massive 10000mAh battery. Combine that with a 12.1-inch panel and decent software features, and it's easy to see why this is Xiaomi's best budget tablet.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">9jhQgUELmqycGqQ6KBS88C</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oZ56kNrvMTYAYyUESS9Z6Z.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 08:34:27 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oZ56kNrvMTYAYyUESS9Z6Z.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Back view of the Redmi Pad Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Back view of the Redmi Pad Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Android 14 and Gemini AI are set to enhance the Google TV experience ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google TV will be gaining Android 14 TV OS with new features.</li><li>The new version promises improvements in performance, sustainability, accessibility, and multitasking.</li><li>Next to the new update, there are new Gen AI recommendations to look forward to.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google TV users are in for a treat as the search giant has announced that Android 14 is coming to their smart television sets alongside the smartness of Gen AI. </p><p>Through an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2024/05/android-14-and-compose-on-tv.html">accompanying blog post</a>, the new Android version for devices like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/chromecast-google-tv-review">Chromecast with Google TV</a> promises improvements in performance, sustainability, accessibility, and multitasking to help users have a more engaging TV experience. </p><p>The indicated performance improvements promise to bring "a snappier, more responsive TV experience." Google is also adding a handful of energy modes that will help users save power consumption when their TVs are in standby mode. These will primarily comprise of three modes: low energy, optimized energy, and increased energy mode, which are clearly illustrated in the image shared by Google in the announcement post (attached below).</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1358px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:44.18%;"><img id="CHpGLhuZGxWDDuEGciNwNH" name="google-tv-enegry-saving-modes-01.jpg" alt="Google TV new energy modes" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CHpGLhuZGxWDDuEGciNwNH.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1358" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The updates further add new accessibility features such as color correction, enhanced text options, and improved user navigation. These can be turned on or off per user preferences with the help of remote shortcuts. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/here-are-all-android-tv-devices-google-tv">Google TV</a> users with the new software can expect better multitasking as Picture-in-Picture support is coming to all Android 14-supported TVs. </p><p>Google has further shared little guides for developers on incorporating the new features on their apps that will help users take full advantage of the new operating system upgrade. As such, the search giant is also releasing Compose for TV in <strong>1.0.0-beta01</strong> for developers, which helps them build apps in new ways. </p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/s0jUt5LTtpI" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>In addition to these improvements, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gen-ai-search-upgrades-io-2024">Gen AI</a> will further bring nifty additions to Google TV users to help improve their watching experience. For instance, if a movie or TV show doesn&apos;t have a description on the Featured carousel on the home screen on Google TV, it will now showcase AI-generated descriptions (based on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini</a> model) for the movie or TV show and tell users what to watch. </p><p>These AI-generated content descriptions are also more personalized based on users&apos; preferred actor and genre. They can also be seen in users&apos; preferred native language. </p><p>The other highlights include quickly pairing the Google TV to wireless headphones or speakers with a single tap with the help of Fast Pair.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-tv-gains-gen-ai-and-android-14</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Next to Gen AI, Google TV is also gaining the Android 14 operating system with notable new features. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Ex6kJMvpHRaTuoDZENXFCb</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LaqeubkBCSZQiPL9LLbL7H.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 06:54:07 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LaqeubkBCSZQiPL9LLbL7H.jpeg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Joe Maring / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Chromecast With Google Tv 169 Crop]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Chromecast With Google Tv 169 Crop]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>