<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 05:16:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Our favorite phone of 2024 just quietly returned to its lowest price EVER, weeks before Black Friday ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Well, I <em>was </em>about to call it a day, but I just came across an early Black Friday deal at Best Buy that has stopped me dead in my tracks. The OnePlus 12, one of our favorite Android phones on the market today, is currently sitting on the retailer&apos;s site with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oneplus-12-256gb-unlocked-silky-black/6570636.p"><strong>a whopping $150 discount</strong></a>. That&apos;s the same price drop that we saw during Amazon&apos;s Prime Day sale in October, and we&apos;re still almost a month away from Black Friday! </p><p>True, the discount comes in the wake of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-13">OnePlus 13 reveal</a> in China a few days ago, but since there&apos;s no global release date for that phone yet, this is the best that OnePlus currently has to offer at well below the retail price. No trade-in required, no strings attached. </p>
<h2 id="the-apos-gorgeous-apos-oneplus-12-has-returned-to-its-prime-day-price-2">The &apos;gorgeous&apos; OnePlus 12 has returned to its Prime Day price</h2>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="7d393108-04a3-4e09-bd2f-f8b074e8f043" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799.99" data-dimension48="$799.99" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oneplus-12-256gb-unlocked-silky-black/6570636.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:546px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:117.22%;"><img id="WpApNUoUctCEufrWszeWw8" name="oneplus-12-render-black.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WpApNUoUctCEufrWszeWw8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="546" height="640" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>OnePlus 12 256GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oneplus-12-256gb-unlocked-silky-black/6570636.p" data-dimension112="7d393108-04a3-4e09-bd2f-f8b074e8f043" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799.99" data-dimension48="$799.99"><del>$799.99</del> <strong>$649.99 at Best Buy</strong></a></p>
<p>Here at Android Central, it's no secret that we're massive fans of the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12-review">OnePlus 12</a>. While the eye-catching flagship may lack some of the AI features found in its Samsung and Google counterparts, the OnePlus 12 is a champ where it counts. You get lightning-fast Snapdragon performance straight out of the box, plus a vibrant AMOLED 120Hz display, a two-day battery, and some of the best camera tech you'll ever use. </p>
<p><strong>Price comparison: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CQ5MYYZL">Amazon - $649.99</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oneplus-12-256gb-unlocked-silky-black/6570636.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="7d393108-04a3-4e09-bd2f-f8b074e8f043" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799.99" data-dimension48="$799.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/top-deals"><em><strong>See Best Buy's full list of early Black Friday deals</strong></em></a></li></ul>
<p>The OnePlus 12 earned the top spot in our list of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a> of 2024, not because it&apos;s the most powerful or innovative device that we&apos;ve ever used, but because it has the perfect balance of elegant, sophisticated design with butter-smooth performance and a price tag that won&apos;t demolish your bank account. After all, there&apos;s a good reason why so many folks compare the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12-vs-samsung-galaxy-s24">OnePlus 12 with the Samsung Galaxy S24</a> when shopping for a new smartphone. </p><p>While you&apos;ll miss out on some of those fancy AI features that other brands have been prioritizing lately, with the OnePlus 12 you&apos;re getting a phone that&apos;s simply great at being a phone. If all you need is a stylish device with great battery life, fast performance, and awesome camera software, then the OnePlus 12 is a great deal — <em>especially </em>when you compare it with an early Black Friday discount at Best Buy. </p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/our-favorite-phone-of-2024-just-quietly-returned-to-its-lowest-price-ever-weeks-before-black-friday</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Best Buy has randomly decided to slash $150 off the OnePlus 12, returning the beloved flagship to its lowest ever price.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">uFoM7E4Diuzm7zK7ahrbDB</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5YihoisE3ixZ3LsaxmhxfG.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 22:12:19 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5YihoisE3ixZ3LsaxmhxfG.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus 12 camera island with light reflection]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus 12 camera island with light reflection]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Gemini can adjust your smart home accessories with Google Home integration ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google is starting to roll out a slew of new Gemini extensions, including the Google Home app.</li><li>Users enrolled in the Public Preview for Google Home should start seeing the integration in the Gemini app for Android this week, with a gradual rollout over the next few weeks.</li><li>You'll be able to ask Gemini to make changes to your Home in natural language, and the Gemini extension will replace the Google Assistant.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Gemini is on a path to replace the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-assistant">Google Assistant</a>, and it's about to gain crucial functionality once reserved for Assistant. Soon, users will be able to control their smart home with a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-home">Google Home</a> extension in the Gemini app. It's rolling out now for users enrolled in the Public Preview for Google Home on Android, and the gradual rollout will continue over the coming weeks.</p><p>After you gain access to the new Google Home extension, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-gemini-app-android">Gemini</a> will be able to use this newfound integration to control your smart home without needing to invoke the Google Assistant. The extension can activate scenes, change the status of connected accessories, and more. What's different about using Gemini for these purposes instead of Assistant? You can use natural language to get things done instead of using specific word choice.</p><p>Specifically, Google explains that telling <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini</a> the phrase "the sun is too bright in the living room" will result in the AI assistant closing the smart window blinds in your home. The company also gives an example of using "help me clean up the kitchen" to start a robot vacuum.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="4sUeciYBZHaLoMa5KiYw7h" name="google-pixel-9-pro-fold-review-20.jpg" alt="Gemini response on Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4sUeciYBZHaLoMa5KiYw7h.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2500" height="1406" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>To try out these new features, open the <strong>Google Home app</strong> on your Android device. Tap the <strong>Settings</strong> button, then select <strong>Public Preview</strong>. From there, press <strong>Join Public Preview</strong> to enroll your account. You should soon gain access to the Google Home extension for Gemini.</p><p>There are a few limitations to note, though. It's only available on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phones</a> and is restricted to English prompts. Additionally, Gemini can't control smart security devices, such as gates, cameras, locks, doors, and garage doors. On devices that don't have Gemini, like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/nest-audio-review">Nest smart speakers</a> and displays, you'll still be using Google Assistant.</p><p>You can try the Google Home extension in the Gemini app today if you're enrolled in the early preview, and a wider release is likely to follow in the future.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="ee2fde27-a921-40c8-ae21-b1672448b297">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/B22jKfVHKzg8nbRGgwTHSP.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro official render - Rose Quartz - Front and Back"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 Pro</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Pixel power</strong></em></p><p>The Google Pixel 9 Pro is equipped with a powerful Tensor chip, allowing it to handle fun and useful AI features on-device. Gemini is also included, allowing you to control your smart devices or have full-on conversations for a bit of inspiration.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/gemini-google-home-integration-public-preview-rollout</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ You can now try out the Google Home extension in the Gemini app as the functionality enters Public Preview. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">zZpCLWEnK2tWThRJzgzWjL</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MEypxaySVNEaqavKxefoBf.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 21:33:48 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MEypxaySVNEaqavKxefoBf.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Home integration in the Gemini app for Android. ]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Home integration in the Gemini app for Android. ]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ When it comes to Canada's Online News Act, Google wins even when it's losing ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The Canadian Radio-television and Telecommunications Commission (CRTC) has <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://nmc-mic.ca/2024/10/29/google-receives-five-year-exemption-from-crtc/">granted Google a five-year exemption</a> through the country's Online News Act. Google has agreed to pay CAD 100 million yearly to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://cjc-ccj.ca/en/">Canadian Journalism Collective</a> (CJC), a federally incorporated nonprofit organization created to distribute funds allocated under the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-response-canada-bill-c-18">Online News Act</a>. The CRTC also stipulated that additional news outlets be allowed to join CJC to qualify for funds.</p><p>If you're not a Canadian let me help this make some more sense. Canada passed the Online News Act to force companies like Google or Meta—which use small portions of news articles in search results—to negotiate a fair price for the use of these snippets. The CRTC <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://crtc.gc.ca/eng/archive/2024/2024-262.htm">has decided</a> that Google will pay CAD 100 million per year to the CJC which will then disperse funds to news organizations affected by Google's use.</p><p>It seems that being plagued by bureaucracy is not exclusive to the U.S.</p>
<p>I'm not a fan of laws like Canada's Online News Act. I can tell you from experience that becoming featured by a company like Google is 100% a net positive, even if the company used a small portion of your text in a snippet or AI summary. In my opinion, as long as Google links back to the source (it does) anyone interested in reading more than a headline will follow through to the original source.</p><p>Regardless of how I feel about these types of laws, it is the law in Canada, and companies like Google, Apple, and Meta who aggregate and disseminate news summaries are bound by it. Other countries have similar laws.</p><p>I'll also assume that these laws are in place because government bodies like the CRTC believe they serve the interests of the citizens they are charged with serving. Forget about partisanship or left versus right for a moment; federal agencies are supposed to look out for our best interests regardless of where we live.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2047px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="Rk48GXqLxWCgSRaHtwd2o5" name="West_Block_Temp_House_of_Commons,_2022.jpg" alt="Canada's House of Commons" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Rk48GXqLxWCgSRaHtwd2o5.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2047" height="1151" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Hutima - Own work, CC BY-SA 4.0)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Then there is the reality. Laws like Canada's Online News Act are designed to prop up an industry that's currently struggling by having companies that are struggling less provide funding. If part of the reason for the decline is that Google and Meta are "stealing" the synopsis of an article for their aggregation feed, that's fine. Google and Meta should compensate news organizations that provide the content from which they make a huge profit. My opinion that one could leverage being featured by Google or Meta in a lucrative way doesn't matter because I am not a government official.</p><p>It's the CRTC's job to assist news organizations, too. A news outlet is not a citizen, but there should be a government agency that ensures things are done fairly by both sides. The Canadian government has a responsibility not to let Canadian news organizations die. And no, that's not socialism; a government serving the interests of business is the opposite, so save your comment.</p><p>I ask you then, was CAD 100 million enough? Is that number going to keep Canada's news industry alive in times when Google and other tech companies "steal" their content for financial gain? To Google, 100 million Canadian dollars is a laughable amount. Google <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/alphabet-q3-2024-earnings">"earns" that much without even trying</a>.</p><p>This is why I dislike these types of laws. Google should be forced to allow companies to opt out of its search and news services until it has reached an agreement with each individual organization. A smaller company may only be "worth" paying $200,000 a year to use its content, while a large company like the NYT or Washington Post can negotiate for more. Having a lump sum paid out through yet another government body is another way Google wins even when it has lost.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-canada-online-news-act-exemption</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google is getting off easy this time. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Z4XuMAWHHGRboRLVgnj533</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZtjXaaHyTYrAT4dTbChrFe.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 21:15:43 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZtjXaaHyTYrAT4dTbChrFe.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A Google sign at the Mountain View Google campus.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A Google sign at the Mountain View Google campus.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Messages might give its read receipts a new home and design ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Users on Reddit reported new read receipt indicators for RCS chats in Google Messages and an APK teardown provided more insight.</li><li>Per the teardown, Google is testing a change in Messages that moves those sent/delivered indicators inside the bubble with your text.</li><li>A Reddit user discovered that you'd have to press and hold a message and drag it to view the time it was sent.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google is reportedly developing a redesign for its RCS text indicators in Messages.</p><p>The company is developing a (type of) "in-line" read receipt notification for its RCS-enabled chats. Users on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GoogleMessages/comments/1ggwf3f/google_messages_read_receipt_ui_changed_for_me/">Reddit have reported</a> these new indicators on their devices while in the Google Messages beta (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/google-messages-read-receipt-rollout-3496172/">Android Authority</a>). More importantly, the publication conducted an APK dive of the recent beta version (messages.android_20241029_00_RC00)</p><p>From screenshots shared on Reddit to the publication's teardown, these new indicators will occupy the right-most corner of your text bubble.</p><p>Further digging shows that the animations have changed, too. According to the post, sending a message is accompanied by an ellipsis (three dots) before turning into a single check mark. A second check mark — or part of it — appears against the first, showing that the message has been sent and delivered successfully.</p><p>These new receipt indicators are (potentially) always present in the text thread no matter the number of messages. This contrasts how Messages is currently where the most recently sent text displays its RCS sent/delivered indicators. Additionally, a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GoogleMessages/comments/1ggwf3f/comment/lut1874/?utm_source=share&utm_medium=web3x&utm_name=web3xcss&utm_term=1&utm_content=share_button">user on Reddit</a> in the beta states Google changed how you can see the time of a text.</p><p>The user states users must "hold and pull the screen to see the time the message came/sent." After, the app will automatically drop the text to cover those extra details.</p>
<blockquote class="reddit-card"  ><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GoogleMessages/comments/1ggwf3f/google_messages_read_receipt_ui_changed_for_me">Google messages Read receipt u.i changed for me.</a> from <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GoogleMessages">r/GoogleMessages</a></blockquote><script async src="//embed.redditmedia.com/widgets/platform.js" charset="UTF-8"></script>
<p>As the test expands to more users, it's unclear when Google will roll this out. Reports of these revamped indicators were posted recently, so the company will likely wait a while for feedback/testing before pushing it to everyone.</p><p>It's worth remembering that Google Messages used to (digitally) say "Sending..." and "Sent" when texting others. That changed last year when the company introduced <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-messages-new-read-receipts">the new checkmarks</a> we've become accustomed to seeing in the app. With this change looming, Google moves them from beneath your message, beside the time, to inside the bubble with your text.</p><p>Aside from your texts, it was reported recently that Google Messages could receive extra privacy options through <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-messages-adding-profile-discovery-privacy-feature">Profile Discovery</a>. Such options include showing your name and profile icon to "people you message," "only contacts," or "no one." These additions were discovered on the setup screen for the Messages app.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-messages-read-receipts-placement-redesign-spotted</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google was spotted testing a new style of read receipt for its chats in Messages. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">FxAaToBtyjHwtGeG3USdsF</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qmjZ9Buznno9fFnNqySv5V.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 19:38:59 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qmjZ9Buznno9fFnNqySv5V.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nick Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Messages on Pixel 6 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Messages on Pixel 6 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Get ready — Google's Android 15 QPR2 Beta 1 is on its way ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google prepares Pixel testers for its upcoming Android 15 QPR2 Beta 1.</li><li>The company states this build is intended to run through Q1 2025 as it will be its March 2025 feature drop.</li><li>Android 15 QPR1 Beta 3 dropped last week with system crash fixes, but Google recently confirmed Android 16 will debut in Q2 2025.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google is alerting all interested Pixel testers about its next QPR test for Android 15.</p><p>The company <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/android_beta/comments/1ggq2he/android_15_qpr2_beta_around_the_corner/">took to Reddit</a> to announce the upcoming start of the Android 15 QPR2 Beta 1. Google states this next beta will "build on top of" the Android 15 QPR1 release, which is expected to hit devices in December. If you are an enrolled Pixel tester through Google's program, the company detailed steps for those willing to stay or those looking to exit.</p><p>Google states any enrolled tester who'd rather receive the stable QPR1 feature drop must "opt out of the program." To avoid a complete data wipe on your Pixel, the post recommends that users follow the remaining steps:</p>
<ul><li>Ignore/don’t apply the downgrade OTA update.The OTA message will have ‘Downgrade’ in the description. Opting out will not cause a data wipe as long as you <strong>don’t</strong> apply the downgrade OTA update. </li><li>If your device is offered the Android 15 QPR2 Beta 1 update, <strong>don’t</strong> install the update. Instead, first <a href="https://www.google.com/android/beta#devices" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>opt out of the program</u></a>, ignore/don’t apply the downgrade OTA update.</li><li>Wait for the final public stable release of Android 15 QPR1 (AP4A), which is coming in December.</li></ul>
<blockquote class="reddit-card"  ><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/android_beta/comments/1ggq2he/android_15_qpr2_beta_around_the_corner">Android 15 QPR2 Beta around the corner!</a> from <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/android_beta">r/android_beta</a></blockquote><script async src="//embed.redditmedia.com/widgets/platform.js" charset="UTF-8"></script>
<p>For those looking to stay, Google states the Android 15 QPR2 Beta 1 will be automatically downloaded (likely as an OTA update) once it arrives. The post adds that this next QPR build is intended to be the March 2025 feature drop. Additionally, Google estimates that Android 15 QPR2 will conclude sometime during Q1 2025.</p><p>Aside from "kicking off soon," Google did not give a specific date for the start of QPR2 Beta 1. However, with QPR1 confirmed to roll out in December, perhaps we're looking at a launch in January for the next one, but we'll have to wait and see for an official post.</p><p>The company rolled out <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-qpr1-beta-3-bluetooth-foldable-update">Android 15 QPR1 Beta 3</a> last week, and that patch was full of fixes for system crashes. It arrived a little later than what testers (us included) expected. Regardless, the update also provided a blank screen fix for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-fold-review">Google's foldable phones</a> that occurred when users unfolded the device.</p><p>More importantly, Google's confirmed timeline for QPR2 Beta 1 might signal the end of Android 15's beta cycle. The company dropped a major <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-play-store-gemini-android-studio-sdk-updates">Android SDK</a> update yesterday (Oct 31) and with it came confirmation of Android 16 in Q2 2025. Considering Q1 runs from January to March, Android 15's testing might not go further than that. A Q2 launch for Android 16 gives us April through June to play with as we might see a beta or two before its launch.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-teases-upcoming-android-15-qpr-2-beta-1</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google informed users of its upcoming Android 15 QPR2 Beta 1. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">nJrWdMPjf68Kjb3jRYHgJo</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WymQhvqn9KZWMgDvhbDvdg.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 18:49:27 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WymQhvqn9KZWMgDvhbDvdg.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android 15 logo on Pixel 8]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android 15 logo on Pixel 8]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ It's time for Samsung to step up its support game ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Samsung recently announced <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-is-expanding-its-brick-and-mortar-repair-network-across-the-us">a new partnership with Assurant</a> that will bring 300 new places to have your Galaxy product repaired. That's good news, and any move toward more and better customer service after the sale is great to see. But Samsung can do so much better.</p><p>Nine months of every year, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/samsungs-market-share-europe-jumped-over-40-q2-2019">Samsung is the largest electronics retailer in the world</a>; second-place Apple can only best its numbers the month after a new iPhone is announced. Samsung is the world's biggest consumer electronics manufacturer. There is no reason it shouldn't offer the best customer service, too.</p>

<p>There is an easy-to-follow formula here; if you guessed the Apple Store, you're right. You might not want to read this, but Samsung could build just a few models of Galaxy phones and sell support contracts that include friendly, helpful people employed by the company in a Galaxy store who are trained to fix any issue. If you have trouble with your Galaxy phone, watch, tablet, laptop, or earbuds, bring them to the nearest one and get them fixed or replaced while waiting. This works in the West, and we know it works because we can see it.</p><p>Samsung could continue to offer its full portfolio of products without the Galaxy branding for people who aren't looking to spend $1,000 or more instead of considering a new "luxury" brand name like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-reportedly-considers-new-phone-brand-separate-from-galaxy" target="_blank">it is rumored to be doing</a>. This would let the Galaxy name mean more, not less.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4160px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="rdaihAGj8bCoYZiWRNS8RQ" name="apple-store-new-york.jpg" alt="Apple Store in NYC" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rdaihAGj8bCoYZiWRNS8RQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4160" height="2340" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Many people think Samsung builds some of the finest consumer electronics available. I'm one of them. The materials, build quality, fit and finish, and overall package of a Samsung phone or tablet are second to none. The company is taking the time and resources to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-one-ui-6">improve its software offerings</a> and has turned itself around from being a laughing stock just a few years ago to building something people love. The next logical move is to treat its customers to the same A+ level of support, and one way to do that is by opening more physical stores customers could just walk into when they need help.</p><p>Samsung has some flagship stores in a few cities in the United States, but my guess is that many of you probably haven't seen a Samsung store or would know where to find one.</p><p>I think it would be a good move and a lucrative one at that. I'll be blunt — "poor" people don't buy <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review">Galaxy S Ultras</a> or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Galaxy Z Folds</a>. Poor people aren't buying <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/apple-iphone-16-pro-max-review">iPhone 16 Pro Max</a> phones, either. You don't have to be rich to afford Samsung's latest and greatest, but you are going to have a certain level of disposable income. If you're reading this, you probably fall into this category.</p><p>With so much invested into a product, paying $10 a month or $100 a year for top-tier support isn't a bad idea. People are <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-is-samsung-care">paying it now</a>, only to be left to deal with over-the-phone support or third-party stores where walking out with a solution an hour later isn't a guarantee. If this idea didn't make money, Apple wouldn't be doing it. Apple doesn't operate any area of its business at a loss.</p>
<p>You may not be willing to pay for this "privilege," but I'll bet plenty of people would. A Galaxy Store in all the places where you would find an Apple store would make perfect sense, and not just big flagship stores in a few big cities across the country. Even smaller stores in malls where there's a good amount of traffic would make sense, and Samsung could even put them right across from Apple stores just to piss them off.</p><p>I'm not trying to claim Samsung could ever have the ... rabid ... fandom that Apple has, where people would line up around the block to buy the new Galaxy phone. I'm saying that isn't what keeps an Apple Store profitable; product sales and paid customer service throughout the year are where the money is. Samsung can try to get its share of that money while offering us the level of customer support we deserve when we pay for it.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/we-need-more-samsung-stores</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung needs to offer the same type of support its biggest competitor does. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">EnEHWWAsbew49vsawntGrD</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/m9nBdBGHXUwKxDeYWdkv6K.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 18:12:39 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/m9nBdBGHXUwKxDeYWdkv6K.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung logo]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung logo]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung's One UI 7 (Android 15) beta might finally be upon us ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Rumors from a tipster on X claim Samsung could start its One UI 7 (Android 15) beta in "another half month," potentially placing us in mid-November.</li><li>Elsewhere, Samsung has reportedly created the Public Beta forum pages for the Galaxy S24 and S23 series devices.</li><li>The major OS upgrade will debut with the Galaxy S25 series and a recent major leak showcased new parental and AI features.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Rumors are floating around that we're (finally) approaching the start of Samsung's Android 15 beta.</p><p>Well-known X tipster <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/UniverseIce/status/1852158438484382194">Ice Universe</a> claims that Samsung is preparing to launch its One UI 7 (Android 15) beta later in November (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/11/01/samsung-galaxy-android-15-beta-november/">9to5Google</a>). The tipster's post reads, "it will take another half month before Beta starts." As others on X have started to guess, that <em>could </em>put us around mid-November (fingers crossed).</p><p>While this might seem too good to be true, another tipster spotted more evidence.</p><p>Another tipster, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/tarunvats33/status/1852000525635539307">Tarun Vats</a>, discovered Samsung's official One UI 7 beta forum pages have started appearing. Samsung has placed forum pages for the Galaxy S24 and S23 series under its "One UI Beta Program" tag. Users chimed in, asking questions about specifics such as the timing for each Galaxy model. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/tarunvats33/status/1852002041792430157">Vats states</a> they "don't think" the One UI 7 beta will begin simultaneously for the S24 and the S23.</p><p>It's unclear how much of an increased delay the past-gen series could see if this proves true. Additionally, Vats states these forum pages have appeared on Samsung's U.S. community forums, furthering suspicions behind an upcoming Public Beta start for One UI 7.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Breaking News 💥One UI 7 beta for the Galaxy S24/S23 series is confirmed, as the Beta forum page has been created for it.Repost 🔁#OneUI7 #GalaxyS24 #GalaxyS23 #Samsung pic.twitter.com/0RFTHRS9Yn<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1852000525635539307">October 31, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>With Samsung's forum pages reportedly created for the S24 and S23 series, the company might hit that "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-plans-one-ui-7-public-beta">later this year</a>" estimation for the beta. Samsung's Sally Hyesoon Jeong appeared at SDC 2024 where they stated users could "preview" the software in an upcoming beta. While a test period for developers was confirmed, regular users will have a chance once a "schedule is confirmed" by Samsung.</p><p>Seeing how the rumors have progressed, perhaps there's hope that a confirmed schedule will be shared soon.</p><p>Samsung's One UI 7 experienced a more substantial delay than we expected. While the update isn't expected until next year <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-confirms-one-ui-7-wont-hit-beta-until-end-of-this-year">with the Galaxy S25 series</a>, the company demoed the software <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-one-ui-7-changes-teased-sdc-2024">during SDC 2024</a>. The major OS upgrade was shown off on a Galaxy S24 Ultra, shedding light on a change: the separation of its notification and Quick Settings panels. It seems users may have to swipe on the left or right side of their device to access either panel.</p><p>That demo also clued us into the Apple-like vibes Samsung is pushing for with One UI 7 and its UI changes. However, 9to5 highlights Samsung's next <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.sdc-korea.com/">SDC event in Korea</a> on November 21. There's a chance that we'll either hear more about One UI 7 there or, perhaps, that'll kick off its beta.</p><p>More recently, a massive One UI 7 leak surfaced, showing Samsung's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/huge-one-ui-7-samsung-parent-ai-features-leak">parental and AI-focused features</a>. It seems parents will have more built-in ways of protecting their children from harmful online content on their Galaxy devices. Samsung isn't letting go of AI advancements as the leak showed One UI 7 may incorporate Circle to Search and tools to enhance photography.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-one-ui-7-android-15-beta-impending-arrival</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ After official forum pages were discovered, Samsung was rumored to be coming up on its One UI 7 beta start. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">oadLwTQ7Me8Xi9waCxDb8e</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yFmLhsbp8G89X6TVQ6Twh5.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 17:35:42 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yFmLhsbp8G89X6TVQ6Twh5.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Galaxy S24 family including the smaller Galaxy S24, larger Galaxy S24 Plus, and premium Galaxy S24 Ultra]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Galaxy S24 family including the smaller Galaxy S24, larger Galaxy S24 Plus, and premium Galaxy S24 Ultra]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung confirms Galaxy S25, suggests a cheaper foldable and XR device could be on the horizon ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung released its quarterly earnings reports this week, and its device experience division reported $2.45 billion in profits.</li><li>The company is projecting “limited growth” for the final quarter of 2024, and is otherwise looking ahead to 2025.</li><li>In releases and earnings calls, Samsung teased multiple future projects, including the Galaxy S25 series, an XR device, and a cheaper folding phone.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>It’s earnings week, and we’ve already learned a lot about <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/alphabet-q3-2024-earnings">Google</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-q3-2024-earnings">Meta</a> from their financial results. Now, it’s Samsung’s turn, and the South Korean tech giant is spilling the beans on its future plans. Aside from telling us how it performed last quarter, it’s also providing a few semi-cryptic details about its 2025 plans.</p><p>Samsung is a very large company, and some of its greatest successes last quarter actually came from the emergence of HBM DDR5 SSDs and system-on-a-chip (SoC) sales. Narrowing things down a bit, the company’s “Device eXperience” division, which includes phones and mobile devices, recorded an operating profit of roughly $2.45 billion (3.37 trillion South Korean won). It’s projecting “limited growth” for the final quarter of 2024 but has a few ideas about what revenue drivers 2025 might hold.</p><p>Namely, Samsung’s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://news.samsung.com/kr/%EC%82%BC%EC%84%B1%EC%A0%84%EC%9E%90-2024%EB%85%84-3%EB%B6%84%EA%B8%B0-%EC%8B%A4%EC%A0%81-%EB%B0%9C%ED%91%9C" target="_blank">earnings report</a> included the first official confirmation of the Galaxy S25 series, which will launch next year.</p><p>“Based on the advancement of Galaxy AI, MX plans to promote flagship-oriented sales growth and profitability improvement such as <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25">Galaxy S25 series</a> and foldable, while also expanding sales of ecosystem products such as Galaxy Tab, Book and Wearable,” the report stated, translated to English.</p><p>“The Galaxy S25 series, which will be released in the first half of next year, plans to lead daily innovation by increasing the experience perfection of Galaxy AI and expand sales by strengthening marketing and experience programs.”</p><p>More importantly, Samsung acknowledged its long-planned extended reality headset, which was initially slated for a 2024 release. Now, it’s looking like Samsung’s offering won’t debut until next year.</p><p>”Through the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-ring-review">Galaxy Ring</a> released this year, we plan to contribute to the expansion of the Samsung Health ecosystem and strengthen the connection experience between our products such as XR (eXtended Reality) devices scheduled to be released in the future,” the release explains.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="fSQpbH5NEEocfFYy9uGJqe" name="psvr-2-meta-quest-3-in-the-sunlight.jpg" alt="A PlayStation VR2 next to a Meta Quest 3 VR headset" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fSQpbH5NEEocfFYy9uGJqe.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Samsung continues to view foldables as a growth vector for innovation, and it may be changing its tune on whether a cheaper foldable can (or should) exist. As spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/Jukanlosreve/status/1851808909050482694" target="_blank">Jukanlosreve on X (formerly Twitter)</a>, Samsung’s comments on an earnings call seem to suggest it is warming to the idea of a budget option.</p><p>”We are considering ways to lower entry barriers so that more customers can actually experience foldable products, given the high satisfaction among existing foldable users,” the company said.</p><p>This comes less than a week after <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-says-it-has-no-plans-to-make-a-cheaper-foldable-but-why">Samsung said it had “no plans” for a cheaper foldable</a>. We’ll have to wait and see what comes of this, but it’s clear that Samsung sees the Galaxy S25 series, an XR device, and foldables as three key parts of its 2025 growth strategy.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="ba5d6d54-1d2e-4090-84cc-24a8e1330a9e">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JrEgbbZSCjj6z4VY5Zx5XP.jpg' alt="Render of the blue Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 6"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title"></div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Flip it</strong></em></p><p>The Galaxy Z Flip 6 is one of the best foldable phones you can buy, sporting a powerful Snapdragon chip, great cameras, and a large cover screen for notifications, selfies, apps, and more.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-confirms-galaxy-s25-teases-cheaper-foldable-xr-device-2025</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Shortly after dispelling the idea of a cheaper foldable, Samsung appears to be changing its tune. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">FvfkFAP9w3DH4L27LKphTG</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2LxkjTPus64c9bXU2eztuB.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 17:26:53 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2LxkjTPus64c9bXU2eztuB.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 on cobblestone road]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 on cobblestone road]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Chromebook vs. iPad: Here's what I think is the better choice ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Beyond the Alphabet</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="74uXEL5FbSyzjPgHM9K6b7" name="lloyd-beyond-the-alphabet2.png" caption="" alt="Android Central's LLoyd with a projection with a Google logo" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/74uXEL5FbSyzjPgHM9K6b7.png" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text"><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/beyond-the-alphabet">Beyond the Alphabet</a> is a weekly column that focuses on the tech world both inside and out of the confines of Mountain View.</p></div></div>
<p>After Apple recently announced its latest M4-powered series of MacBook Pro's, the company made another change that was unexpected. Every current MacBook in Apple's lineup now ships with 16GB of RAM as a base, an upgrade from the previous minimum of 8GB.</p><p>Originally, I was going to compare the MacBook Air to the current crop of Chromebooks until I realized that you can't get a new MacBook for less than $1,100. Meanwhile, the most expensive Chromebook is the new Samsung Galaxy Chromebook Plus, which is $400 cheaper. Yes, I know there are still a few HP Dragonfly Pro Chromebooks floating around, but those aren't as widely available and are clearly being phased out.</p><p>After some prodding in a meeting, I turned my attention to a comparison that <em>does</em> make sense: Chromebook vs. iPad.</p>

<h2 id="chromebook-vs-ipad-price-2">Chromebook vs. iPad: Price</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2070px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.28%;"><img id="9a5y8YszsGek8fus8e5PyQ" name="ipad-10th-gen-imore.jpg" alt="Back of the iPad (10th Generation) next to keyboard and Apple Pencil" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9a5y8YszsGek8fus8e5PyQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2070" height="1165" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: iMore)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Currently, there are six different iPad models to choose from, starting with the iPad (10th generation) for $349 and going all the way up to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/apple-ipad-pro-oled-m4-2024">M4 12.9-inch iPad Pro</a> for $1,299. Meanwhile, the cheapest Chromebook that's been released in 2024 is the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/hp-fortis-chromebooks-2024-announcement">HP Chromebook 14-inch</a>, which retails for $249.</p><p>From there, we have a variety of options at different price points, and while the majority of them are laptops, there are a couple of tablets thrown into the mix. These include the likes of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/new-chromebooks-arrive-in-all-shapes-and-sizes-starting-today">ASUS Chromebook CM30</a>, and more recently, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-tablets/lenovo-chromebook-duet-11-review">Lenovo Chromebook Duet 11</a>.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="M3dUF5rkP2jHjSAKQa3jRj" name="lenovo-chromebook-duet-11-review-1.jpg" alt="Lenovo Chromebook Duet 11 propped vertically" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/M3dUF5rkP2jHjSAKQa3jRj.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While both of these are tablets, ASUS and Lenovo include a keyboard case in the box. In doing so, it removes any potential stress and additional cost for those who want a true 2-in-1 device. On the other hand, no matter what iPad you're considering, the only other thing that comes in the box is a charging cable.</p><p>Making matters worse for the iPad is that if you want to go with first-party accessories, Apple's Magic Keyboard Folio is priced at $249. Plus, if you want a stylus, tack on another $79, bringing the grand total to about $680.</p><p>That immediately puts the "cheapest" iPad in the same price bracket as the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/samsung-galaxy-chromebook-plus-review">Galaxy Chromebook Plus</a> and Chromebook Plus Spin 714. It is also almost $300 more expensive than the Lenovo Chromebook Duet 11.</p><p>And we haven't even talked about the hardware or specs.</p>
<h2 id="chromebook-vs-ipad-hardware-specs-2">Chromebook vs. iPad: Hardware & Specs</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="qi9dBKgZ36vQhoTe2Lmiei" name="ipad-pro-2022-129-16.jpg" alt="iPad Pro 12.9" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qi9dBKgZ36vQhoTe2Lmiei.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>So, what are you getting with the base model iPad for $349? It's powered by the A14 Bionic SoC, which debuted with the iPhone 12 and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apple-ipad-air-2020-review">iPad Air in 2020</a>. This is paired with 4GB of RAM and either 128GB or 256GB of storage, and if you want to use it anywhere, there are Cellular options available.</p><p>I'm not going to sugarcoat anything here, but there's a good reason why Apple is able to "get away" with using a four-year-old processor without facing much backlash. Since Apple controls the entire "stack," it's able to better optimize the software and hardware, when it relies on older processors. This is also why Apple was able to maintain its position as a leader in the industry when it comes to providing software updates for longer than the competition.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="JhSg5h3YR8hLjLQkWruzgb" name="MediaTek-Kampino-520-528-hero.jpg" alt="The new MediaTek Kompanio chips for Chromebooks" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JhSg5h3YR8hLjLQkWruzgb.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: MediaTek)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>As for Chromebooks, the aforementioned ASUS Chromebook CM30 is powered by the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/mediatek-kompanio-520-528-launch">MediaTek Kompanio 520</a>. It also sports 4GB of RAM and 64GB of non-upgradeable storage. But as I mentioned before, ASUS includes the detachable keyboard folio case in the box, which is already a huge benefit, even if you don't plan to use it all that much.</p><p>Performance is where things take a sharp turn. On Geekbench, the Kompanio 520 offers a single-core score of 510 and a multi-core score of 1532. Despite being four years old, the A12 Bionic achieved scores of 1590 and 4247, respectively. Let me put it this way: the cheapest iPad is closer to the Intel-powered Galaxy Chromebook Plus in terms of performance.</p><p>It's not even close; the iPad wins by a landslide here.</p>
<h2 id="chromebook-vs-ipad-software-2">Chromebook vs. iPad: Software</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="AxXbRAekQDdfvQnXsV5Trj" name="lenovo-chromebook-duet-11-review-16x9-1.jpg" alt="Lenovo Chromebook Duet 11 review hero 16x9" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AxXbRAekQDdfvQnXsV5Trj.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Software is the key to everything, and this is where a sub-$300 Chromebook outshines even a $1300 iPad. With a Chromebook, you not only have access to the ever-growing world of web apps and extensions, but the Play Store is also just a click away. Not to mention that there's an even bigger repository of apps at your disposal if you feel comfortable enough to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/how-to-install-and-run-linux-apps-on-a-chromebook">enable Linux support</a>.</p><p>On an iPad, everything is powered by either the App Store or Safari, and there is just a little bit of wiggle room for anything else. While you can use Chrome or Firefox on an iPad, you won't find any extension support, and for whatever reason, web apps don't always feel as fluid as they do on a Chromebook.</p><p>While important, I'd argue that usability is even more important, especially when it comes to things like using more than one app at a time. The iPad is superb if you're trying to stay focused on one app, but it immediately begins to fall short when you want to toss another app into the mix.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="WEEobcWZ3WxmYUfg8ruqjn" name="ipad-pro-2021-stage-manager-ipados-16-1.jpg" alt="Stage Manager on iPad Pro - 2" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WEEobcWZ3WxmYUfg8ruqjn.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2500" height="1406" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>"But what about <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/apple-should-think-different-with-ipad-pro">Stage Manager</a>?" You might be asking, and I'm glad you did. When enabled, it lets you use up to four different apps at the same time. Allowing you to resize and move them around with relative ease. There's even a slide-out "dock" of sorts, letting you basically work within different spaces that are comprised of different apps.</p><p>Technically another app can be used, provided that you can remember that the Slide Over is at your disposal or even how to use it. But it's cumbersome at best, and downright useless more often than not.</p><p>None of that is a problem with a Chromebook, as it works just like any other desktop operating system. The only difference comes when using either a ChromeOS tablet or a Chromebook with a convertible form factor. When doing so, it's more similar to using any <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-tablets">Android tablet</a> or iPad, with your app windows locked to a few different layouts.</p><p>However, I'd still argue that Google's implementation is still a bit better. Instead of trying to guess where to put app windows, you can just swipe down from the top of the screen and pick from a few different layouts. These include being able to put an app off to the side and slide it back into view.</p>
<h2 id="chromebooks-are-better-and-more-versatile-than-ever-2">Chromebooks are better and more versatile than ever</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="ivkSpvcBEnF7tVrN3Mcv9a" name="acer-chromebook-spin-714-hero-alt-16x9.jpg" alt="Acer Chromebook Spin 714 review hero 16x9" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ivkSpvcBEnF7tVrN3Mcv9a.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2500" height="1406" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>This might just sound like a puff piece for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-chromebook">Chromebooks</a>, and to a certain extent, it kind of is. But it's just because I feel as though we're finally moving away from the days of seeing a million different cheap Chromebooks that are underpowered or just bad. In years past, I would have likely recommended an iPad to just about anyone who asked, regardless of how they planned to use it.</p><p>However, the landscape has shifted quite dramatically for Chromebooks. For one, with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/ask-jerry-choosing-the-right-chromebook">Chromebook Plus</a>, you know exactly what the minimum specs are, so there's no need to worry about compromising. Regardless of whether you want a tablet or a laptop, you have options to choose from, both of which are going to be either in-line or less expensive than what you would spend on an iPad.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="942a7ee4-29ca-40d3-90db-3de474082970">
            <a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/computing/chromebooks/galaxy-chromebook-plus/buy/galaxy-chromebook-plus-15-6-intel-core-3-256gb-neptune-blue-xe550xga-kc1us/" data-model-name="Galaxy Chromebook Plus, 15.6""><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VCR79RjWNeApWsJnDjX3tY.jpg' alt="Samsung Galaxy Chromebook Plus product render"></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Galaxy Chromebook Plus, 15.6"</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best Chromebook in the Galaxy</strong></em></p><p>The Galaxy Chromebook Plus is a powerful ChromeOS machine, thanks to the Intel chip and 8GB of RAM. The 1080p OLED display is vibrant and you have enough ports and battery life to get you through the work day.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/chromebook-vs-ipad</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Chromebooks have come a long way, but how do they compare to Apple's iPads? ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">k23wm5hACP96cwUenzSepJ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/95c9nStgqwKfiDgrYRVQw3.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Chromebooks &amp; Laptops]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ andrew.myrick@futurenet.com (Andrew Myrick) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/95c9nStgqwKfiDgrYRVQw3.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Empty desktop on the Samsung Galaxy Chromebook Plus]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Empty desktop on the Samsung Galaxy Chromebook Plus]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ How to create Private Space for your apps on Pixel ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>As the most widely used operating system in the world, Android has matured to a point where annual releases don&apos;t really matter as much as they used to in the past few years. The same is true for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-review" target="_blank">Android 15</a> as well, which is overall a rather modest update over its predecessor. However, the latest version of Google&apos;s popular mobile OS does pack in several new features that are designed to improve your everyday user experience, with &apos;Private Space&apos; being one such addition.</p><p>Essentially a digital vault, Private Space lets you conveniently lock sensitive apps (and by extension, the data accessible through them) in a separate sandbox. You can also set up a second instance of any app in Private Space, which can be then secured with a locking mechanism (e.g., fingerprint, PIN) that&apos;s different from your Pixel&apos;s phone&apos;s main screen lock. Sounds like something you can benefit from? Here&apos;s how to create Private Space for your apps on Pixel, and give the confidential information on your phone an additional layer of protection.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-create-private-space-for-apps-on-your-pixel-2">How to create Private Space for apps on your Pixel</h2>
<p>In addition to the obvious requirement of Android 15, Private Space needs a device having more than 6GB of RAM. Thankfully, the majority of Google&apos;s recent smartphones — including all members of the newest <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9" target="_blank">Pixel 9</a> series — fulfill these conditions. Also, this feature doesn&apos;t work on managed devices that are usually issued by organizations to their employees. With that said, here&apos;s how to get started with Private Space.</p>
<p>1. Go to your smartphone&apos;s <strong>Settings</strong> app, scroll down and and tap the <strong>Security & privacy</strong> option.</p><p>2. Now, tap the <strong>Private space</strong> option under the <strong>Privacy</strong> subsection.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:74.07%;"><img id="nMvvgoWyDTeFftNaM9ectg" name="how to create private space for apps on your pixel - navigating to private space option.jpg" alt="how to create private space for apps on your pixel - navigating to private space option" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nMvvgoWyDTeFftNaM9ectg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="3240" height="2400" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud-Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>3. Once you&apos;ve authenticated yourself with your device&apos;s screen lock, you&apos;ll see the Private Space main screen. It highlights how the feature works, as well as a couple of important things about it. Scroll down to read everything, and tap the <strong>Set up</strong> button.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:74.07%;"><img id="vSXEyLp8FQuY6XP9APVhpW" name="how to create private space for apps on your pixel - private space main screen and explanation.jpg" alt="how to create private space for apps on your pixel - private space main screen and explanation" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vSXEyLp8FQuY6XP9APVhpW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="3240" height="2400" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud-Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>4. Your Private Space will now be created. When it&apos;s done, you can choose to sign in with an existing or new Google account to the Private Space. However, this step is optional, and can be bypassed by tapping the <strong>Skip</strong> option.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:74.07%;"><img id="yZkeqR7sW258zsmW8jQKP6" name="how to create private space for apps on your pixel - private space creation and google account options.jpg" alt="how to create private space for apps on your pixel - private space creation and google account options" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yZkeqR7sW258zsmW8jQKP6.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="3240" height="2400" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud-Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>5. Now you can configure a lock for the newly created Private Space by tapping the <strong>Choose new lock</strong> button. Finally, tap <strong>Done</strong> on the last screen, and you&apos;re all set.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:74.07%;"><img id="Y9heoz5c4bXTGiYzpPL52G" name="how to create private space for apps on your pixel - lock configuration and finalization of private space.jpg" alt="how to create private space for apps on your pixel - lock configuration and finalization of private space" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Y9heoz5c4bXTGiYzpPL52G.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="3240" height="2400" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud-Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<h2 id="accessing-your-private-space-and-installing-apps-to-it-2">Accessing your Private Space and installing apps to it</h2>
<p>1. The Private Space appears at the bottom of the app drawer with a <strong>"Private"</strong> label and a <strong>lock</strong> <strong>icon</strong>. Once you tap it, you can see the currently installed apps.</p><p>2. To add a new app, simply tap the <strong>Install</strong> button. This will take you to a locked version of the Play Store, from where you can download and install any app to the Private Space.</p><p><em><strong>Note:</strong></em><em> The apps (and) data in Private Space are isolated from the regular apps, so you&apos;ll have to set them up as new before using them.</em></p><p>3. Tapping the <strong>gear</strong> <strong>icon</strong> takes you to the settings for your Private Space. Here, you can configure options such as automatic locking, visibility, and more.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:74.07%;"><img id="U4tzDGfZPVyKQQUVnhgRrg" name="how to create private space for apps on your pixel - accessing private space and its settings, and installing apps.jpg" alt="how to create private space for apps on your pixel - accessing private space and its settings, and installing apps" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/U4tzDGfZPVyKQQUVnhgRrg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="3240" height="2400" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<h2 id="turn-your-pixel-smartphone-into-a-digital-safe-deposit-box-2">Turn your Pixel smartphone into a digital safe deposit box</h2>
<p>Google Pixels are among the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones" target="_blank">best Android phones</a> available in the market, and one of the major reasons for that is the top-tier software experience that they come with. When you buy a Pixel smartphone, you&apos;re the first in line to get the newest software release(s), which often include many Pixel-exclusive goodies.</p><p>One such feature is Private Space, which ensures that you—and only you—can see and interact with the confidential apps on your smartphone. Apart from the regular screen lock, Private Space provides your data with an additional layer of protection. It&apos;s extremely easy to set up, lets you run a second instance of any app, and can even be hidden away from view. It&apos;s just one of the many gems you can find in Android 15, which is best experienced on a top-of-the-line device like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-review" target="_blank">Pixel 9</a>, which offers a gorgeous design, class-leading cameras, superb everyday performance, and more.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="ae37a824-29b5-4f79-8367-120d98c7cef8">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tnQGJNQVqF2XVQV4KfMbN8.jpg' alt="google pixel 9 square render"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="80" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Stylish and powerful</strong></em></p>
<p>Despite being the base model in the company's newest line-up, the Google Pixel 9 offers just about everything you could want in a flagship Android phone. It has a premium design, awesome performance, incredible cameras, and is backed by seven years of OS and security updates.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-create-private-space-for-your-apps-on-pixel</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Here's how to create private space for your apps on Pixel phones. This handy Android 15 feature lets you effortlessly secure all your apps and data. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">ttM2WqJaoA4guVhcRFPp7K</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yNQj5Y8xEryNbhrR9FbGe7.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 11:43:02 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ sharmarajat@zoho.com (Rajat Sharma) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yNQj5Y8xEryNbhrR9FbGe7.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Private Space in Pixel 9 Pro XL on Android 15]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Private Space in Pixel 9 Pro XL on Android 15]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>