<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 17:02:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Chrome picks up Lens on desktop and 'Tab Compare' in latest AI update ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google is detailing a few AI features Chrome users on desktop can expect over the next few weeks.</li><li>Such features include the debut of Google Lens in Chrome on computers, adding visual search abilities, follow-up questions, and multisearch.</li><li>Chrome on desktop also picks up "Tab Compare" when searching for multiple products and conversational AI for rediscovering your browsing history.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google has developed a few new AI tools for Chrome, arriving for users today (August 1) in a big way.</p><p>In a press release, the company states that Chrome on desktop is picking up three new AI features, beginning with Google Lens on desktop. Those same capabilities we&apos;re used to on our <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phones</a> will hit computers via a Lens icon in the address bar. </p><p>Google states users can click the icon, which will attach a mini Lens icon to their mouse. You then "click and drag" over an area on your display to have Lens run a visual search. The search begins immediately after finishing your area highlight. Chrome will display relevant search results in a new side panel to the right.</p><p>Those on Android will <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-lens-new-search-feature-lets-you-find-objects-using-a-mix-of-text-and-images">be familiar with multisearch</a>, another feature desktop users won&apos;t miss out on. Google adds that after the initial query is run, users can click the text bar at the top of the results panel to add more. Users can refine the search by color, brand, or other details. Moreover, you can toss in a follow-up question to keep Chrome&apos;s AI going.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/43YUCNEHBHU" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>Lens in Chrome on desktop also lets you highlight text in a video to "quickly get a description in the side panel." Discovering new merchandise like backpacks or dresses is also possible by simply highlighting the object and letting the AI do its thing.</p><p>This feature will begin rolling out "over the next few days."</p><p>"Tab Compare" is another new AI-backed feature for Chrome that lets users see a quick AI-generated product comparison using <em>your </em>tabs. Google states that when users are browsing different devices (say, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">foldables</a> or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-bluetooth-speakers">Bluetooth speakers</a>) switching tabs is often the norm. However, Tab Compare will collect the information you have spread across those tabs and Chrome is said to "suggest" that users open this AI-generated comparison to save time.</p><p>The comparison page will display the name of each product you&apos;ve got open in your tabs alongside pricing, reviews, and other technical specs.</p><p>The "next few weeks" will bring this feature to all desktop Chrome users.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:667px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:89.96%;"><img id="AUQBzjUyy6gXztra8DsA6S" name="google-chrome-tab-compare-ai-feature.jpg" alt="Google Chrome on desktop is preparing to pick up "Tab Compare," an AI generated page of product details for comparison." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AUQBzjUyy6gXztra8DsA6S.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="667" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1685px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:35.61%;"><img id="6wcWVAYz5V8KgwdfjRjvGV" name="google-chrome-search-history-conversational-ai.jpg" alt="Chrome on desktop will bring conversational AI software for past website rediscovery." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6wcWVAYz5V8KgwdfjRjvGV.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1685" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Chrome&apos;s final AI feature feels <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">reminiscent of Gemini</a> as the company plugs in more conversational software to rediscover your history. Soon, users can ask Chrome a question about a previous site they&apos;ve visited. Chrome will then display in its address bar "Search History" with a magnifying glass and a classic Google AI star, indicating the conversational AI&apos;s presence.</p><p>From there, Chrome&apos;s drop-down menu will pull information from your browsing history to show website links that might solve your query. Google states that this feature is optional and users can enable or disable it via the settings. More importantly, those rolling in incognito mode will never have sites visited appear when using this AI search.</p><p>Chrome&apos;s AI history search will begin rolling out to U.S. users "in the coming weeks."</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-chrome-ai-feature-lens-tab-compare-update</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google detailed several new AI features in line for desktop Chrome users, including the debut of Lens. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">qJxJgg43Lg2RwomVp5RNBg</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6wDQWkwELky67VYDh4TL6W.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 16:32:56 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6wDQWkwELky67VYDh4TL6W.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google / YouTube]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Chrome on desktops gains Lens for visual searches like Android.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Chrome on desktops gains Lens for visual searches like Android.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Upcoming OnePlus Buds Pro 3 likely to support AI call summary feature ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>OnePlus app's teardown reveals a new AI feature likely in the works.</li><li>The popular AI Summary feature on OnePlus phones might extend to OnePlus Buds.</li><li>If the feature goes live, future OnePlus Buds will be able to create call transcripts via AI.</li><li>The leaked OnePlus Buds 3 Pro could be the first to feature this tool.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>OnePlus is reportedly integrating a handy new AI feature into its wireless earbuds to generate call AI summaries, according to new findings from an APK teardown.</p><p>The APK teardown, done by folks at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/oneplus-buds-ai-call-summaries-apk-teardown-3466073/">Android Authority</a>, reveals a new AI call summaries feature, which can be carried out through OnePlus wireless earbuds. The findings were seen via the OnePlus Buds app bearing the <strong>14.8.2 version</strong>. The publication&apos;s screenshot of the app reveals the new AI Call Assistant toggle. Once enabled, users would need to press their compatible OnePlus Buds&apos; stem three times, which can trigger the AI summary for calls.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure pull-right inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2700px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:222.22%;"><img id="R4T4fsZDyusL7QWzSaCvvE" name="OnePlus-Buds-app-AI-call-summari.jpg" alt="OnePlus Buds app AI Summary" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/R4T4fsZDyusL7QWzSaCvvE.jpg" mos="" align="right" fullscreen="" width="2700" height="6000" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pull-right"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class="pull-right inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>First discovered back in February, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/oneplus-12-receives-new-ai-features">OnePlus&apos; AI Call Summarizer</a> automatically extracts key information like instructions, addresses, names, or phone numbers from a phone call. Currently available on OnePlus phones, this will now work as a hands-free option when you take Bluetooth calls through your OnePlus Buds. </p><p>Needless to say, the said AI summarize feature will only work with compatible earbuds alongside a supported OnePlus phone that also sports an AI summary function, like the recent <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-nord-4-with-snapdragon-7-plus-gen-3-goes-official">OnePlus Nord 4</a>, for example.</p>
<p>Users further have to bear in mind that if the supported OnePlus phone, for some reason, is in power-saving mode, meditation mode, or children&apos;s space mode, the AI summary mode might not work effectively. Other than that, next to the calls, AI summaries also work for online meetings made through supported third-party applications.</p><p>Lastly, as Android Authority notes, the compatible OnePlus Buds in question are likely the upcoming OnePlus Buds Pro 3. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.smartprix.com/bytes/exclusive-oneplus-buds-pro-3-design-specs-revealed-ahead-of-launch/" target="_blank">SmartPrix</a> leaked the Buds Pro 3 design and specs on Wednesday, suggesting they&apos;ll arrive soon as a successor to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/oneplus-buds-2-pro-review">OnePlus Buds Pro 2</a>.</p><p>While these AI features could come to the Buds Pro 3 first, we expect these AI features to trickle down to older earbuds from the company, like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/oneplus-buds-3-review">OnePlus Buds 3</a>.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Earbuds deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/promo/headphone-and-speaker-deals"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/browse/electronics/shop-headphones-by-type/3944_133251_1095191_1230614?sort=best_match&cat_id=3944_133251_1095191_1230614_1230476&stores=3081&ps=40"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=earbuds&crid=2RWE1G9N1EIF&sprefix=earbuds%2Caps%2C161&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/mobile/audio/all-audio/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.dell.com/en-us/search/earbuds"><u><strong>Dell</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/oneplus-may-introduce-ai-call-summary-to-its-earbuds</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ OnePlus might add a new AI call summary feature for the upcoming earbuds and hopefully for the older generation earbuds too. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">AkLkKu9NWdEyekVkHrGeDf</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/v4VZzw3bJiUtTLcSAJGCxH.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 16:23:22 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/v4VZzw3bJiUtTLcSAJGCxH.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[OnePlus]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Blue OnePlus Buds 3 and case]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Blue OnePlus Buds 3 and case]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Qi2 is a great short-term fix that will stifle innovation ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>HMD has sent me their new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/hmd-skyline-qi2-launch">Skyline</a> to take a look at, review, and tear apart. Billed a great phone for creators, it also hosts new ideas about repairability and is dead simple for anyone — not just a skilled technician — to open and perform basic repairs and replacements.</p><p>It&apos;s also the first Android phone to be widely released that supports the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qi2-wireless-charging-standard">Qi2 standard</a> out of the box. You don&apos;t need a case or a fancy black plate to use the new generation of wireless charging on this one.</p>
<p>I&apos;m a nerd. I have this cool new pink phone (it&apos;s so very pink) with fancy camera features, and what I really care about is how easy it is to tear it apart so I can look at things like the Qi2 charging coil (spoiler: it&apos;s disappointing and a Qi2 coil looks very much like a Qi coil.) That&apos;s mostly because I don&apos;t think Qi2 is a good idea.</p><p>It may sound like blasphemy, and people who want wireless charging with all the convenience of magnets may disagree, but in the long term, I believe Qi2 is going to stifle innovation in this area.</p>
<h2 id="what-is-qi2-and-why-is-it-great-2">What is Qi2 and why is it great?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="nUxw9PjtmJ2EGrFZhV92Pi" name="iOttie-Velox-Mini-Qi2-Air-Vent-Mount-ring-01.jpg" alt="iOttie Velox Mini Qi2 Air Vent Mount" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nUxw9PjtmJ2EGrFZhV92Pi.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Qi2 is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-magsafe-accessories-for-android-phones">MagSafe</a>. It&apos;s not "like MagSafe," it <em>is</em> MagSafe because <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/1/3/23538131/qi2-wireless-charging-apple-samsung">Apple provided what was needed for free</a> to the standards committee. It&apos;s now an open standard from the WPC (<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.chargewithqi.com/qi2/">Wireless Power Consortium</a>) that defines how wireless charging coils can be combined with a "magnetic power profile" to ensure the coil in the charger and the coil in the phone are perfectly aligned. In layman&apos;s terms, it is the original Qi wireless standard with Apple&apos;s MagSafe idea attached to it.</p><p>This is not a bad thing. It&apos;s great that Apple was willing to contribute and give up its usual MFi certification or requirement of genuine Apple hardware and provide a working profile standard. By making sure the coils are properly aligned, devices will charge faster and waste less power. It&apos;s also not as easy as you might think it is because magnets can easily interfere with inductive (wireless) charging — especially when nearby like they are in Qi2-certified devices.</p>
<p>It&apos;s also a really good idea for most phone makers and consumers. At least in the short term. Standards mean you can use the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-charging-pads">same wireless charger</a> for both an iPhone and an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phone</a> as long as both support them. Since the standard is open and free for anyone to use the list of supported devices will be a lot higher.</p><p>For phone makers like HMD, it means they do not have to engineer their own solutions. The company knows that if it follows the standard, you can buy a compatible charger and it just works. </p><p>In almost every case a standard is a good thing, and we should get behind them even if it means a little more regulation when enforcing them. Almost every case.</p>
<h2 id="what-apos-s-wrong-with-qi2-2">What&apos;s wrong with Qi2?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:650px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.31%;"><img id="XWXF2Wm2NkY6eKfREU4Qz3" name="qi-charger.jpg" alt="Qi charging coil" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XWXF2Wm2NkY6eKfREU4Qz3.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="650" height="366" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Jerry Hildenbrand)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Nothing is wrong with Qi2 today</strong>. It&apos;s a way to deliver wireless charging to any device in a safe way, using cheap commercially available chargers without the markup of a name brand attached. It&apos;s important to remember that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wireless-charging-plain-english">copper wire, magnets, and plastic</a> are the same regardless of which company uses them. With certification, you can be assured that a cheap charger from Amazon is as safe and effective as an expensive one with a big tech company&apos;s name on it.</p><p>This is a good thing, but it&apos;s also a problem. A company like HMD may not be ready to dedicate the time and money to a five-person team to develop a better way to align a wireless charger, but Apple, Samsung, or OnePlus will.</p>
<p>If OnePlus — a company known for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/oneplus-8-pro-has-30w-wireless-charging-heres-how-it-works">pushing the limits when it comes to charging tech</a> — does develop a new and better way, it would need to build a device that works poorly (if at all) with existing equipment you probably already have. If you buy a phone that claims to charge wirelessly in 30 minutes, having it take three hours to charge with your existing equipment is a bad look.</p><p>That&apos;s what would happen because of the way "compatibility" is managed with the Qi2 standard. If it works and is safe, but it doesn&apos;t have approved and certified Qi2 components, it cuts charging rates to the bare minimum. This wastes power and lengthens your charging time, defeating the very idea of Qi2.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="NVZcecvwYGwFcujFKEroRj" name="OnePlus-Warp-Charge-wireless-one-plus-9.jpg" alt="A OnePlus 9 Pro on the OnePlus Warp Charge wireless charger" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NVZcecvwYGwFcujFKEroRj.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Hayato Huseman / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>"Magnetic charging" isn&apos;t new. Sony and Samsung offered <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/samsung-nexus-10-review">magnetic charging systems</a> more than 10 years ago, and everyone remembers Apple&apos;s magnetic MacBook chargers. The difference now is that the charging methods and standards are tied to the magnetic latching system.</p><p>If this all sounds like techno-nerd babble, I get it. What I&apos;m saying is that OnePlus, for example, has no incentive to build a better system because nothing it makes will work well with everything that&apos;s out there right now. Wireless charging is just like that because of how it works; it sort of has to be. For now, anyway. What if OnePlus could change that?</p>
<p>It&apos;s a big ask, but I would love to see the magnetic power profile part of Qi2 separated from the wireless power transfer part. Ideally, Qi2 would be the latest wireless transfer standard and something like QiM could handle things like clearance and placements of magnetic points of attachment. I hate that they are bundled together, even if it&apos;s an <em>optional</em> standard.</p><p>This way, OnePlus could build it better but maintain compatibility in a way that makes its new powerful wireless charger not suck. Until then, you won&apos;t want to use anything new or different.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/qi2-will-stifle-innovation</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Qi2 brings an open standard so any phone can have MagSafe charging. Compatibility issues and market conditions mean it could stop the next great thing from happening. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">26n5UQTofjDNmBYa8PSRAi</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/n3CVznVANEF2nV3JT7FPC9.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 16:01:44 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/n3CVznVANEF2nV3JT7FPC9.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jerry Hildenbrand]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Qi2 charger coil]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Qi2 charger coil]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The rumored ‘Google TV Streamer’ might fall short at competing with the Apple TV ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google may be gearing up to release a streaming box called the Google TV Streamer, according to 9to5Google. </li><li>The upcoming device’s specs may have been revealed in a regulatory filing with the U.S. Federal Communications Commission.</li><li>While the form factor matches that of the Apple TV, the specs might signal that the Google TV Streamer isn’t a high-end device.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>There have been plenty of rumblings about the future of Google TV over the last few months. First, we learned that a Chromecast with Google TV 4K successor was imminent. Then, Walmart’s sub-brand Onn launched a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/walmart-onn-google-tv-4k-pro-review">new Google TV 4K Pro</a> device, and it quickly became the best Google TV box you can buy. Now, we know that the Chromecast with Google TV 4K replacement isn’t another streaming stick — it’s a streaming box, more akin to the Apple TV.  </p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/07/22/google-tv-streamer/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a> first uncovered the existence of a new set-top box, dubbed the “Google TV Streamer.” Unlike most streaming boxes, which have a small surface area and a taller design, the Google TV Streamer is like a flat wedge. It looks like it’ll fit into the Google Home and Google Nest ecosystems well since it looks like part of a Nest Hub or Nest Hub Max. If you imagine hard enough, you can even spot the resemblance to the Pixel Tablet speaker dock, as 9to5Google pointed out.</p><p>The Google TV Streamer would mark a shift in Google&apos;s strategy and streaming efforts. The entire point of its streaming sticks was to conveniently plug into the back of a TV and stay out of the way. Products like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/chromecast-with-google-tv-hd-review">Chromecast with Google TV HD</a> and Chromecast with Google TV 4K were made to be relatively cheap, low-powered, and virtually invisible once installed.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="4v6F8gUY7aFFgctHBCfQRR" name="onn-walmart-4k-tv-pro-remote-chromecast-google-tv-remote-amazon-fire-tv-remote.jpg" alt="Onn Google TV 4K Pro remote with the Chromecast remote and Fire TV remote" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4v6F8gUY7aFFgctHBCfQRR.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2500" height="1406" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>By comparison, the Google TV Streamer isn’t trying to be hidden. It looks like one of the larger streaming boxes we’ve seen lately, at least in terms of service area. It also could be trying to provide more power and a premium feature set. Early reports about the Chromecast with Google TV 4K revealed that the product’s successor would almost certainly include a chip upgrade, perhaps with more RAM and storage. Now, the new form factor for the Google TV Streamer likely means it would offer more ports. </p><p>That much may have been confirmed in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://fcc.report/FCC-ID/HFS-GRS6B" target="_blank">regulatory filing</a> with the U.S. Federal Communications Commission (FCC) first spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/07/28/google-tv-streamer-fcc/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a>. The FCC ID, HFS-GRS6B, is associated with Quanta Computer, Inc. — not Google. However, as 9to5Google notes, Quanta Computer has produced Google products in the past, including the Pixelbook, Pixel Slate, and Pixelbook Go. </p><p>The filing notes that there is at least an HDMI port, an Ethernet port, and a USB-C port. The wireless device referenced in the listing runs Android since the Android Debug Bridge was used for testing. Additionally, it features a Thread radio that can be used to interact with other smart devices.</p><p>That makes the Google TV Streamer sound like a higher-end version of the Chromecast with Google TV 4K, but there are other attributes that point to the contrary. For example, the Wi-Fi 2.4GHz 802.11b/g/n and Wi-Fi 5GHz 802.11a/n/ac support referenced in the regulatory filing is far from the latest and greatest. There also isn’t ultra-wideband (UWB) support mentioned, which would prevent the Google TV Streamer from working with software features like Tap to Cast. </p>
<h2 id="the-google-tv-streamer-will-have-to-prove-it-can-compete-with-apple-tv-2">The Google TV Streamer will have to prove it can compete with Apple TV</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.20%;"><img id="DPSJ4KoUwoxMuhxzeMwm6W" name="apple-tv-4k-on-table.jpg" alt="Apple TV 4K with Siri Remote sitting on table" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DPSJ4KoUwoxMuhxzeMwm6W.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1151" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: iMore)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Now that the Google TV Streamer appears to be taking the set-top box form factor, the Apple TV is a natural competitor. Apple’s streaming box uses Apple silicon chips that are old, but still dwarfs the low-end processors found in current Chromecast streaming sticks. That helps the Apple TV 4K play games, deliver solid software experiences, and support plenty of video and audio formats. Apple’s form factor also supports Ethernet for faster streaming speeds.</p><p>It’s nice to see that Google may be following suit by offering more ports on the rumored Google TV Streamer. Ethernet is a huge plus, and facilitates a better experience overall. You won’t have to worry about buffering while trying to watch video content, or whether your Google TV box is too far away from your router. A wired internet connection still trumps wireless, and that’s why Ethernet would be a great addition to Google’s next streaming device.</p><p>However, there are reasons to be concerned about Google’s ability to compete with the Apple TV. For starters, we don’t know what processor will be inside the Google TV Streamer, and that will have a big impact on real-world performance. Plus, the omission of modern Wi-Fi specifications and UWB support makes me wonder what kind of price point the Google TV Streamer will target. Is it a higher-end Google TV device, or is it just a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/chromecast-with-google-tv-4k-successor-may-come-soon-new-remote">Chromecast with Google TV</a> replacement in a different form?</p><p>The answer to that question might determine whether the Google TV Streamer will give the Apple TV a run for its money. Google has an event coming up shortly, so here’s to hoping we see more about the company’s smart home plans there. We’re looking forward to potentially seeing a Google TV Streamer debut, but a revamp of the Google Home and Nest product lines would be nice, too.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/rumored-google-tv-streamer-to-compete-with-apple-tv</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google might be ditching the streaming stick form factor, but the leaked ‘Google TV Streamer’ might not be a full-on Apple TV competitor. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">G5DrLGCNSpuSBBfhQZp2Te</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/73CdRRjb9Dk6iCTmpno25E.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 15:28:39 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Streaming &amp; TV]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/73CdRRjb9Dk6iCTmpno25E.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[9to5Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A leaked image of the Google TV streaming box.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A leaked image of the Google TV streaming box.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Factory Reset Protection: What you need to know ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-factory-reset-android-phone">Factory Reset Protection</a> (FRP) is a security method that was designed to make sure someone can&apos;t just wipe and factory reset your phone (or tablet or wearable) if you&apos;ve lost it or it was stolen.</p><p>Starting way back with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/lollipop">Android 5</a>, FRP is "standard" in vanilla Android, and the companies making our phones have implemented it in their own models. It&apos;s a good thing — it makes a stolen device almost impossible to use, which makes it less appealing to thieves, and anything that can protect our data on the devices we&apos;ve lost is welcome.</p><p>It can become a problem if you <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-places-buy-refurbished-phone">sell, trade, or even give away a phone</a> without factory resetting it, though. How it works explains why.</p>
<h2 id="how-it-works-2">How it works</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:640px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:67.34%;"><img id="qqZVBGLRi7AzNfGGxyAFiQ" name="op6tfingerprint.gif" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qqZVBGLRi7AzNfGGxyAFiQ.gif" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="640" height="431" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div></figure>
<p>Simply put, FRP uses the credentials of the last account on the device to permit wiping or resetting the phone.</p><p>You have to be signed in with the "owner" account (the one you used to set it up) to factory reset it. That means if you give me your phone, I can&apos;t reset it without you being signed in. There are random workarounds on the Internet, but they tend to get patched almost as soon as they are discovered and you probably don&apos;t want to try random software you found on YouTube.</p><p>You&apos;ll pretty much need to know the login details for the last account to use the device before you can reset it and create a new owner account. Note that this means you may need to have the password or PIN, not just have access to a fingerprint.</p>
<p>We&apos;ve been bitten by this ourselves. We ship phones all over North America and the U.K., and sometimes it&apos;s easy to forget you&apos;re still signed in when you stick a phone in a box. And yes, we have needed to share a password to get past the initial setup because of other policies Google has in place to protect your account.</p>
<p>This is a bit of an inconvenience, but it&apos;s understandable because FRP is in place to make sure your data is safe if you lose your device or it gets stolen.</p><p>You do have to remember the one critical rule: <strong>If you change or reset your Google account password, you shouldn&apos;t use it to wipe a phone that&apos;s using it for 72 hours</strong>. If you do this, Google can (and has) lock down your entire account. If this happens you&apos;ll need to try and contact Google support to get it fixed. Nobody wants that so change it and wait a few days.</p>
<h2 id="disable-it-the-right-way-2">Disable it the right way</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="xDYn85tVjymLmMThTWmNKN" name="how-to-factory-reset-fitbit-smartwatch-1.jpg" alt="How To Factory Reset Fitbit Smartwatch 1" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xDYn85tVjymLmMThTWmNKN.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Source: Jeramy Johnson / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Disabling FRP (Factory Reset Protection) is simple. On most phones, it will be automatically done whenever you choose to reset the data through the phone&apos;s settings. If your phone has an extra layer of reset protection from the company who built it or has a "find my phone" app from the company who built it, you&apos;ll want to disable that manually first.</p>
<p>There may be a few devices still in use that require a bit more hands-on work. If your phone is really old, you <strong>might</strong> need to remove the accounts that are signed in manually:</p>
<ul><li>Open your device settings and remove any security you have for the lock screen. This isn't a required step for all phones, but some want you to do this, so we're including it here.</li><li>Once that's done, you need to remove any and all Google Accounts from the phone or tablet. That's also done in the settings — look for a section labeled Accounts. With an account selected, look for a delete or remove option, usually hidden behind the three little dots in the top corner of the screen.</li><li>When you've made sure all of the Google accounts have been erased, you can then factory reset your phone or tablet through the device settings.</li></ul>
<p>On modern Android phones, there shouldn&apos;t be any problems as long as you choose to factory reset your phone through its settings. This will automatically remove all the associated accounts in a way that "frees" the phone from FRP. If you try to reset a phone through the bootloader, FRP will kick in, and it can&apos;t be set back up without the previous account&apos;s password.</p>
<p>You can make sure any reset protection has been removed from a phone you want to find a new owner for. Just try to sign back into it after you&apos;ve reset it.</p><p><strong>If it asks for the previous username and password, FRP is still enabled.</strong> If it doesn&apos;t, you&apos;re good to go: power it off and box it up!</p>
<h2 id="oops-too-late-i-already-sent-it-2">Oops! Too late, I already sent it.</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:66.63%;"><img id="jA4kiePQfUR22kSAurbezF" name="google-passwords-pixel-5-2021.jpg" alt="Google Passwords Pixel 5" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jA4kiePQfUR22kSAurbezF.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="533" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Source: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>If you&apos;ve forgotten to turn off FRP and send a phone to someone else, you&apos;ll likely need to help them get it set up. <strong>This means giving them access to your Google account password</strong>. The only other reasonable option is to have it returned so you can do it yourself.</p>
<p>If you choose to let someone know your Google credentials, do it while you are on the phone with them. Give them the password to your account and have them verify that it worked, and they can continue the setup process. <strong>Then immediately </strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/plus/answer/41078?hl=en"><strong>change your Google account password</strong></a><strong>, as well as any other accounts that might have been using the same password.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Remember to not erase or delete the Google account from another phone for 72 hours after you&apos;ve done this!</strong> If you try, you may be locked out of your account and need to speak with someone at Google to resolve everything.</p>
<p>While we haven&apos;t seen headlines telling us mobile phone theft is down by any measurable percentage since FRP was enabled, it&apos;s still a good way to keep your data safe. And it&apos;s pretty easy to disable when you want someone else to be able to use your old phone.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/factory-reset-protection-what-you-need-know</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Factory Reset Protection helps keep your data safe if your device is lost or stolen, but you need to remember to disable it before a new user can set it up and sign in. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">gSt6YxiNAVzWQy6yjXWCZM</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pegdUwvL2eBZqCQe3wmCGb.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 14:59:47 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pegdUwvL2eBZqCQe3wmCGb.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Device reset protection]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Device reset protection]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Best Motorola Razr 2024 screen protectors 2024 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>You&apos;d be surprised to learn that many of the best Motorola Razr 2024 screen protectors overlap with the best Razr+ 2024 screen protectors. This is because they share the same internal screen size of 6.9 inches. The story on the outside is different, however, as the Razr 2024 (also known as the Motorola Razr 50) has a smaller 3.6-inch cover display.</p><p>The internal flexible display of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2024-hands-on">Motorola Razr 2024</a> needs a flexible film to protect it. With the cover display, you don&apos;t need to worry as much as both TPU films and tempered glass protectors are applicable.</p>
<h2 id="keep-your-razr-2024-in-mint-condition-with-these-screen-protectors-2">Keep your Razr 2024 in mint condition with these screen protectors</h2>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="2ff7ccff-e1e8-42dc-a234-ce1e9da0a50d">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kXhu9NvtxUUy5Qk7dshjjP.jpg' alt="Supershieldz 2 Pack Motorola Razr 2024 Screen Protector"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Supershieldz 2 Pack Motorola Razr 2024 Screen Protector</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best overall</strong></em></p>
<p>Supershieldz makes fantastic screen protectors of all sorts. The 2 Pack Motorola Razr 2024 Screen Protector is a bundle of soft TPU films, two for each display of the foldable. These films offer high clarity, good touch response, and self-healing properties.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="beefd2e7-3f95-4f12-baaa-1db82811cf5b">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/g5XvWiT7cyHC5eiyYbAB3o.jpg' alt="Suttkue Motorola Razr 2024 Screen Protector"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Suttkue Motorola Razr 2024 Screen Protector</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best value</strong></em></p>
<p>Suttkue gives you an all-in-one solution with the Suttkue Motorola Razr 2024 Screen Protector. This comprehensive set includes a tempered glass unit for the front screen, two glass camera lens protectors, and two flexible TPU films for the Razr's inner display.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="0e9e9039-f854-411c-a0f2-0d01c1ede550">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/G7csf7rBYtBVnvjvMwtJ2i.jpg' alt="ArmorSuit 2+2 Pack Screen Protector for Motorola Razr (2024)"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">ArmorSuit 2+2 Pack Screen Protector for Motorola Razr (2024)</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best full coverage</strong></em></p>
<p>ArmorSuit gives you the most coverage with its flexible TPU screen guards for the Motorola Razr 2024. There are two films for each of the phone's screens in the box and all of them are oleophobic, repelling water, dust, dirt, oil, fingerprints, and other debris.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="72cf78eb-0814-4d1e-be65-a650d94de314">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dWtp6GYpkGoEoWHbJLTRyV.jpg' alt="Anoowkoa Moto Razr 2024 Soft Flexible TPU Film"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Anoowkoa Moto Razr 2024 Soft Flexible TPU Film</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best cheap</strong></em></p>
<p>This isn't a known name brand but the reviews speak well of the product. The cheerfully cheap Anoowkoa Moto Razr 2024 Soft Flexible TPU Film gives you two thin films for the phone with detailed instructions and tools for at-home installation.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="df44edfd-d69a-4511-baa1-efdfcf8146ef">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2gVurKad7eP4Ej53NoEi5K.jpg' alt="Supershieldz 2 Pack Motorola Razr 2024 Tempered Glass Screen Protector"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Supershieldz 2 Pack Motorola Razr 2024 Tempered Glass Screen Protector</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best glass</strong></em></p>
<p>While plastic screen guards are great, glass is more durable and wards off cracks better. That's why the Supershieldz 2 Pack Motorola Razr 2024 Tempered Glass Screen Protector is a good pick for your Razr's outer display. You'll need to get a flexible film for the internal screen separately.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="a05e0d9f-3f74-4d3e-b789-8be568e0abcf">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/V5EWQmGabyE9QfASGMEfdc.jpg' alt="Orzero 3 Pack Screen Protector for Motorola Razr Plus 2024"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Orzero 3 Pack Screen Protector for Motorola Razr 2024</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best water repellent</strong></em></p>
<p>Orzero's TPU screen protector for the Motorola Razr 2024 also fits the Plus model. This trio of flexible films features oleophobic and hydrophobic layers, repelling solid and liquid particles alike. For the fragile inner screen of the Razr 2024, this is a very good feature to have.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<ul><li><a href="#main"><strong>Back to the top ^</strong></a></li></ul>
<h2 id="these-motorola-razr-2024-screen-protectors-take-the-job-seriously-2">These Motorola Razr 2024 screen protectors take the job seriously</h2>
<p>The best overall Motorola Razr 2024 screen protector is none other than the one from the famously reliable brand called Supershieldz. The affordable Supershieldz 2 Pack Motorola Razr 2024 Screen Protector gives you high-quality TPU films for both the internal as well as the external displays of the Razr 2024. You get two pieces per screen, adding value and stretching your dollar to the max.</p><p>If you want an even more comprehensive set than the one from Supershieldz, get the Suttkue Motorola Razr 2024 Screen Protector. This multipack includes two self-healing TPU screen guards for the inner screen, two tempered glass camera lens protectors, and a tempered glass screen protector for the front display that has black borders.</p><p>Once you&apos;re done picking screen protectors for your foldable Motorola, be sure to check out all the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-motorola-razr-2024-cases">best Motorola Razr 2024 cases</a> for full 360-degree protection. Cases with raised edges prevent direct contact, which is even better than what a screen protector does. Use both forms of defense to maximize your Razr&apos;s protection.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-motorola-razr-2024-screen-protectors</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The best Motorola Razr 2024 screen protectors are inexpensive but provide reliable protection for your foldable. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">wc75ewBjpYtk5hsGihinY8</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rGwGHzDny625oebApQjdCk.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 12:25:12 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rGwGHzDny625oebApQjdCk.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 and Razr 2024 next to each other]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 and Razr 2024 next to each other]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The POCO Pad is a rebadged Redmi Pad Pro with a key difference ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>When I <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/redmi-pad-pro-review">reviewed the Redmi Pad Pro</a>, I called it Xiaomi&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-android-tablet">best budget tablet</a> to date. The combination of decent hardware, 12.1-inch LCD panel, and 10000mAh battery make it a great choice if you just need a reliable option to stream multimedia or read on the go.</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Hardwired</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="5u6gVPowTCuSQ8NJeoktj7" name="lloyd-hardwired.png" caption="" alt="Android Central's LLoyd with a bionic eye" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5u6gVPowTCuSQ8NJeoktj7.png" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">In <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/hardwired">Hardwired</a>, AC Senior Editor Harish Jonnalagadda delves into all things hardware, including phones, audio products, storage servers, and routers.</p></div></div>
<p>So when POCO announced that it was coming out with a tablet of its own, I was intrigued. Xiaomi&apos;s budget-focused brand is doing all the right things in 2024, and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/poco-f6-review">POCO F6</a> is among the best phones you can get in the sub-$400 segment. Now, POCO is known for reusing existing Xiaomi designs; the strategy makes sense as it tends to rebadge Redmi products usually exclusive to China.</p><p>This time though, it did that with Xiaomi&apos;s latest tablet. The POCO Pad is based on the Redmi Pad Pro, and barring the logo at the back, there is virtually no difference. This isn&apos;t a bad thing necessarily as the POCO Pad is debuting in countries where Xiaomi doesn&apos;t sell the Redmi Pad Pro, so there isn&apos;t much in the way of overlap.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="3bCGcpdLUUUFFxHHDS9TQf" name="poco-pad-3.jpg" alt="POCO Pad" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3bCGcpdLUUUFFxHHDS9TQf.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>That said, the POCO Pad has two key tweaks that make it a better choice in my book: it comes with 256GB as standard, and you get a 33W charger in the box. Xiaomi is usually good when it comes to bundling accessories, but it omitted the charger on the Redmi Pad Pro, but the POCO Pad addresses the issue.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="CgfiFJAT7GVDDb8tdtFfvf" name="poco-pad-5.jpg" alt="POCO Pad" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CgfiFJAT7GVDDb8tdtFfvf.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>And with 256GB of UFS 2.2 storage out of the box, you get double the amount of base storage as the Redmi Pad Pro — at the same cost. While the hardware changes are welcome, POCO doesn&apos;t sell a cellular model of the Pad; you&apos;ll need to get the Redmi Pad Pro if you want to slot in a SIM card.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="nnDNAq3AD5ciAMjAMvkpAg" name="poco-pad-6.jpg" alt="POCO Pad" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nnDNAq3AD5ciAMjAMvkpAg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Otherwise, using both tablets is identical. I switched from the Redmi Pad Pro to the POCO Pad, and noticed no difference between the two. That&apos;s a given as they share the same hardware, and there isn&apos;t anything different on the software side either; the POCO Pad is also based on Android 14.</p>
<p>Just like the Redmi Pad Pro, the POCO Pad is great in daily use; the Snapdragon 7s Gen 2 isn&apos;t the most powerful chipset by any measure, but it doesn&apos;t lag in mundane tasks like streaming video or browsing. I like that there&apos;s a 3.5mm jack, and the MicroSD slot is intact, so you can easily extend storage if that&apos;s something you need.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="h424cs9HsDY2sDbWtLaZVg" name="poco-pad-7.jpg" alt="POCO Pad" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/h424cs9HsDY2sDbWtLaZVg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The 12.1-inch LCD panel goes up to 120Hz, and while it isn&apos;t anywhere as vibrant as the AMOLED panels Xiaomi uses on its phones, it is serviceable in this context. It has good colors and contrast, and I didn&apos;t see any issues using the panel outdoors. On a similar note, the onboard sound is pretty great, and it is more than adequate if you&apos;re looking to just stream the occasional video.</p>
<p>Battery life is an area where the POCO Pad has a distinct advantage; it is able to easily outmatch its rivals, and I easily got a screen-on time exceeding nine hours between charges. Even though it has 33W charging, it takes over two hours to charge the 10000mAh battery, but that isn&apos;t a big inconvenience.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="pxgMQDZCwPsJQaLyvh7vAf" name="poco-pad-2.jpg" alt="POCO Pad" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pxgMQDZCwPsJQaLyvh7vAf.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In fact, my main point of contention with the POCO Pad is that it doesn&apos;t have a fingerprint sensor; you&apos;re limited to a traditional password and face unlock. Other than that, I don&apos;t have any issues with the POCO Pad. Rounding out the hardware, POCO is offering the same stylus and keyboard case that&apos;s bundled with the Redmi Pad Pro, and that&apos;s good to see.</p><p>Overall, POCO hasn&apos;t changed things too much from the Redmi Pad Pro, but by increasing the storage and bundling all the requisite accessories, it created a budget tablet that&apos;s nearly perfect.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/the-poco-pad-is-a-rebadged-redmi-pad-pro-with-a-key-difference</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The POCO Pad is identical to the Redmi Pad Pro, but it includes a few additions that allows it to stand out.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">9X4eTDB3hRLL2hwmyDJyDS</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qyVFZYWo4zM2JZaNJn58ve.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 10:58:02 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qyVFZYWo4zM2JZaNJn58ve.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[POCO Pad]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[POCO Pad]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ OnePlus Open 2: Leaks, rumors, specs, and release date ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-open-review">OnePlus Open</a> debuted to much fanfare at the end of last year, and it is one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">best foldables</a> available today. A lot of that is down to the hardware; the Open has a gorgeous design, smooth hinge with no visible crease, excellent internal hardware, a larger battery than the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Galaxy Z Fold 6</a>, 67W charging, and terrific cameras.</p><p>While there were software issues out of the box, these have been addressed with subsequent updates. With the Open gaining decent momentum, it&apos;s now time to take a look at what the Open 2 could bring to the table. What&apos;s immediately clear is that OnePlus isn&apos;t launching the Open 2 this year — the foldable is estimated to debut in Q1 2025. That said, let&apos;s take a look at the possible hardware and design changes coming to the device. </p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-oneplus-open-2-design"><span>OnePlus Open 2: Design</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="5YPXRoyAY3swpXj75cfitK" name="oneplus-open-35.jpg" alt="OnePlus Open review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5YPXRoyAY3swpXj75cfitK.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>OnePlus designed the Open in collaboration with OPPO, and that&apos;s evident when viewing the device next to the Find N2. In fact, the Find N3 is identical to the Open, with the only difference being that it is limited to China, whereas the Open is sold in global markets. </p><p>As such, it is unlikely we&apos;ll see any major design change with the Open 2. While OPPO likes to switch up the design of its Find X devices — the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oppo-find-x7-ultra-review">Find X7 Ultra</a> has a distinct design that stands out — it has maintained the same styling to all of its foldables, and that isn&apos;t likely to change. </p><p>What could be different is a new hinge that is even lighter than the previous generation. Honor has the distinction of the thinnest foldable in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-v2-review">Magic V2</a>, and as this is a key area of contention between all the Chinese manufacturers, it is entirely likely the Open 2 will feature a redesigned hinge. In fact, recent leaks point to the fact that the Open 2&apos;s hinge will be lighter and sturdier, and it will be interesting to see if it ends up being thinner than the just-released Magic V3. </p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-oneplus-open-2-specs"><span>OnePlus Open 2: Specs</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="otdGLT6rYiTxVh5oAktd2H" name="oneplus-open-25.jpg" alt="OnePlus Open review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/otdGLT6rYiTxVh5oAktd2H.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The OnePlus Open has an outstanding hardware package, and that is set to continue with the Open 2. The upcoming foldable will be powered by the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3, and it should retain the same 67W charging tech. </p><p>OnePlus isn&apos;t messing with battery tech on most of its devices, and while it has 150W charging available, it isn&apos;t usable in North America, so for devices that are launching globally, it is limiting the charging potential to 100W or 67W. Considering the limited room on a foldable, I don&apos;t see any changes in this area. </p><p>Having said that, the Open 2 is likely to include a larger battery that lasts noticeably longer. There hasn&apos;t been any confirmation about the battery size, but OnePlus is said to offer up to a 6000mAh battery on the foldable. What I like is that the battery uses silicon-carbide tech, just like the Magic V2. </p><p>The rest of the hardware is likely to be unchanged, but I&apos;ll update this post once we have credible details. </p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-oneplus-open-2-cameras"><span>OnePlus Open 2: Cameras</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="MFbv8pqxhAinWWcVKYewKD" name="oneplus-open-9.jpg" alt="OnePlus Open review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MFbv8pqxhAinWWcVKYewKD.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>OnePlus did all the right things when it comes to the Open cameras, with the foldable offering a fabulous set of lenses at the back. With 2024 phones pushing the boundaries of camera tech — the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12-review">OnePlus 12</a>, Find X7 Ultra, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/xiaomi-14-ultra-review">Xiaomi 14 Ultra</a>, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-6-pro-review">Honor magic 6 Pro</a> all have sizeable gains — the upcoming foldable should have some of these gains baked in. </p><p>Then again, considering the launch window of the Open 2, it could be a while before we know what camera hardware the device is packing to any reasonable degree. What you need to know at this point is that the cameras should be on the same level as the OnePlus 12, and that&apos;s a terrific starting point. </p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-oneplus-open-2-release-date"><span>OnePlus Open 2: Release date</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="GkuiDi9EL2qQjKaytP7bEC" name="oneplus-open-2.jpg" alt="OnePlus Open review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GkuiDi9EL2qQjKaytP7bEC.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>OnePlus usually likes to have a major release in Q4, but it may be doing things a bit differently with the Open 2. While an earlier launch positions the Open 2 against the likes of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6">Galaxy Z Fold 6</a>, it looks like OnePlus is mulling launching the foldable in 2025 instead. </p><p>That&apos;s an interesting move, and it means the Open 2 will debut alongside the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-13">OnePlus 13</a> instead. Of course, this is just conjecture at this point, and we don&apos;t know if OnePlus is actually delaying the launch until next year. But as always, I&apos;ll update this post once more information becomes available. </p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-oneplus-open-2-what-i-want-to-see"><span>OnePlus Open 2: What I want to see</span></h2>
<h2 id="oneplus-needs-to-add-wireless-charging-2">OnePlus needs to add wireless charging</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="Fy7EdSSW3TzME3zjwU23HM" name="oneplus-open-39.jpg" alt="OnePlus Open review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Fy7EdSSW3TzME3zjwU23HM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I don&apos;t know who signed off on not including wireless charging on the OnePlus Open, but it is the biggest limitation on the device. Sure, the phone was designed in conjunction with OPPO, and the Chinese manufacturer doesn&apos;t offer wireless charging on its own devices — so you don&apos;t get one here.</p><p>However, the Open is sold in a lot of global markets, and with OnePlus positioning it as the ideal alternative to Samsung in North America, it needed to nail the table stakes features. While the battery life itself is much better than Samsung&apos;s foldables, the fact that it is limited to wired charging — no matter how fast — makes it a little less enticing.</p><p>With the Open 2, OnePlus has to rectify this particular issue and offer wireless charging out of the box. While it&apos;s okay for a device like the OnePlus 11 to miss out on it, the Open costs nearly thrice as much at $1,699, and not having the ability to charge wirelessly is a shortsighted move.</p>
<h2 id="polished-software-out-of-the-box-2">Polished software out of the box</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="XfwHZfFvCTHoKYvZ8dSYcF" name="oneplus-open-23.jpg" alt="OnePlus Open review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XfwHZfFvCTHoKYvZ8dSYcF.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>This is a regular complaint with all OnePlus phones, but I want to see better software out of the box with the Open 2, not a few months down the line. Yes, the ColorOS integration made things that much more difficult, but it&apos;s been two years now, and that cannot be the excuse to deliver shoddy software on every new phone.</p><p>OnePlus has shown that it can deliver; the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12-review">OnePlus 12</a> was devoid of any major bugs, and it was optimized for the hardware. I know achieving the same on a foldable is twice as hard as there are two screens to deal with and numerous scaling issues, but the Open 2 has to do better. And while we&apos;re at it, can I get a 5x5 grid? I still don&apos;t understand why that isn&apos;t available on the Open.</p>
<h2 id="ip68-water-resistance-2">IP68 water resistance</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="U8WKGQq2BDu7mHJeTEyR4C" name="oneplus-open-1.jpg" alt="OnePlus Open review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/U8WKGQq2BDu7mHJeTEyR4C.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The OnePlus Open has IPX4 water resistance, and that means that it can withstand an occasional splash of water. OnePlus says that the hinge automatically ejects any dust that manages to get in, and even though it isn&apos;t tested, it should do a decent job with any dust ingress as well.</p><p>That said, I&apos;d like to see IP68 water resistance on the Open 2. That would make the foldable that much more resilient to the elements, and bring it to parity with Samsung&apos;s latest foldables.</p>
<h2 id="stylus-integration-would-be-nice-to-have-2">Stylus integration would be nice to have</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="otdGLT6rYiTxVh5oAktd2H" name="oneplus-open-25.jpg" alt="OnePlus Open review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/otdGLT6rYiTxVh5oAktd2H.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>This is another one of those features that feels motivated by OPPO. As the brand doesn&apos;t pay particular attention to global markets, adding stylus integration wasn&apos;t a priority, and the Open misses out on it. I&apos;m not saying the foldable should have come with a stylus in the box — even Samsung isn&apos;t that generous — but the ability to use a stylus with the inner screen makes the foldable that much more useful.</p><p>Even if OnePlus decides it doesn&apos;t want to bother making its own stylus, there are plenty of aftermarket styli that do a great job with note-taking and doodling. I have a half-dozen styli in the house, and while I don&apos;t really use them as much as I should, having the option to do so on the Open 2 would go a long way.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="58b33d6a-a65d-4fff-9af3-4709d7fd834e">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/i72maMJpZUbzyf2vtKk88i.jpg' alt="An official render of the OnePlus Open in both colorways"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">OnePlus Open</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>The OnePlus Open is one of the best foldables you can buy today. It has terrific hardware combined with stellar cameras, the best hinge in this category, and standout battery life. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-open-2</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The OnePlus Open is here, and it is amazing. Here's what you need to know about the Open 2, and when it might become available.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">ERv6bKuiWZZtQNJ9oAh3z4</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VWt54kP4N2G3vsMUqzSpCH.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 03:54:50 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VWt54kP4N2G3vsMUqzSpCH.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus Open review]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus Open review]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ This $149 Qualcomm-powered Raspberry Pi rival has 5G and an AI accelerator ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/raspberry-pi">Raspberry Pi</a> is one of the most useful single-board computers you can buy today; the extensibility of the platform combined with the great hardware allows you to do just about anything. I have two <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/raspberry-pi-4-review">Pi 4</a> units in the house, and I use them to run a home-wide ad blocker, VPN, music server, and Home Assistant.</p><p>You don&apos;t usually get many launches in this segment, but that&apos;s changing with the debut of Tachyon, Particle&apos;s latest single-board computer. Particle is an IoT microcontroller manufacturer, and with the Tachyon, it is rolling out a solution that has incredible hardware — and all the extras you need to get started.</p><p>The Tachyon is powered by Qualcomm&apos;s QCM6490, and the chipset has an eight-core configuration of Arm v8 cores, including a Cortex A78 core running at 2.7GHz, three A78 cores at 2.4GHz, and four A55 cores at 1.9GHz. You also get an Adreno 643 GPU, and what&apos;s particularly interesting is that there&apos;s an NPU that goes up to 12 TOPS, unlocking a suite of AI use cases.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:6038px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="fgijRYubsYiwrbcccwaMaV" name="particle-tachyon-3.jpg" alt="Particle Tachyon board in-hand" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fgijRYubsYiwrbcccwaMaV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="6038" height="3396" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Particle)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>There&apos;s a lot to like on the connectivity side of things as well, with the Tachyon offering Wi-Fi 6 and Bluetooth 5.2 along with global 5G connectivity. The board is sold in two variants — North America and Rest of World — and it has distinct 5G bands based on the region. The NA unit comes with bands 2/5/7/12/13/14/25/26/29/30/38/41/48/66/70/71/77/78, and the global variant has 1/3/5/4/8/20/28/38/40/41/77/78/79.</p><p>The board comes with 4GB of RAM as standard, and there&apos;s 64GB of UFS storage pre-installed. The rest of the hardware includes a standard 40-pin GPIO header, two USB-C 3.1 ports, GPS, and SD card reader. The only limitation that I can see is the lack of an Ethernet port, and if you wanted to set it up as a headless server, it becomes a bit of a hassle.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:6460px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="riQZ28Dc4bvSkNupi682iY" name="particle-tachyon-1.jpg" alt="Particle Tachyon board with cable connected to it" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/riQZ28Dc4bvSkNupi682iY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="6460" height="3634" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Particle)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>As for the software, the Tachyon runs Ubuntu, and you can install Android just as easily. The QCM6490 can work with Windows 11 as well, but Particle says it hasn&apos;t seen demand for it, so it isn&apos;t providing a way to install that on the Tachyon yet.</p><p>Coming in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/particle-iot/tachyon-powerful-5g-single-board-computer-w-ai-accelerator">at $149 on Kickstarter</a>, the Tachyon clearly has a lot going for it, and it is one of the fastest products in this segment. If you&apos;ve dabbled with a Pi in the past and want something with a little more power or a built-in AI accelerator, the Tachyon is turning out to be a decent choice. The product is still in the crowdfunding phase, with deliveries only going out in January 2025. I&apos;ll get my hands on one closer to launch, but if you&apos;re eyeing an upgrade to your Pi 5, this may just be it.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/particle-tachyon-debuts-take-on-raspberry-pi-5</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Particle just unveiled the Tachyon, a single-board computer that takes on the Raspberry Pi. With powerful Qualcomm hardware, global 5G, and the ability to run AI natively, it may just be what you need.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">rNfGjhFaZNvtmDWGiSemw7</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/exqhQEg59ePuZyY6qjeN5X.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 03:41:34 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Smart Home]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/exqhQEg59ePuZyY6qjeN5X.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Particle]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Particle Tachyon board next to Pi 5]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Particle Tachyon board next to Pi 5]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Ayaneo recreates two of the best gaming handhelds, powered by Android ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>After being announced earlier this year, the Ayaneo Pocket DMG and Pocket Micro are now available for pre-order. </li><li>Both of these gaming handhelds are running Android, with the DMG powered by the Snapdragon G3x Gen 2 and the Micro uses the Helio G99.</li><li>Early Bird pricing for the Pocket Micro starts at $189, while the DMG starts at $339.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>The world of gaming handhelds goes far beyond the likes of the Steam Deck and recently released ROG Ally X. Over the past year alone, we&apos;ve seen a rise in handhelds powered by Android, such as the AYN Odin 2 and Ayaneo Pocket S. However, Ayaneo is coming strong with two handhelds that are sure to invoke some nostalgia.</p><p>As you might have surmised, the Ayaneo Pocket DMG is a vertical <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/best-android-gaming-handheld-consoles">gaming handheld</a>, offering a reminiscent design of the original Game Boy. It features a 3.92-inch OLED display, with a 1240 x 1080 resolution and is capable of reaching up to 500 nits of brightness. </p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="9DnfVA67zAZjdnCdxEtV46" name="ayaneo-pocket-dmg-109.jpeg" alt="Ayaneo Pocket DMG" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9DnfVA67zAZjdnCdxEtV46.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ayaneo)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="LVtYdtwnWapo8E4LaPM4q4" name="ayaneo-pocket-dmg-046.jpeg" alt="Ayaneo Pocket DMG" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LVtYdtwnWapo8E4LaPM4q4.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ayaneo)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="KutEog8k46tjpLWNJFheR6" name="ayaneo-pocket-dmg-005.jpeg" alt="Ayaneo Pocket DMG" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KutEog8k46tjpLWNJFheR6.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ayaneo)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Perhaps the most surprising aspect of the DMG is that it&apos;s powered by the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/snapdragon-g-series-chips">Snapdragon G3x Gen 2</a>. This is the same chip that&apos;s found in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/ayaneo-pocket-s-pre-orders">Ayaneo Pocket S</a>, marking just the second device to make use of this SoC. There are also four different configurations to choose from, starting with 8GB of RAM and 128GB of storage and maxing out with 16GB of RAM and 1TB of storage. Oh, and there&apos;s a microSD card slot if you need even more space for games.</p><p>Although the design harkens back to the Game Boy, this isn&apos;t the same handheld you grew up with. In addition to the D-Pad and ABXY buttons, the Pocket DMG is also equipped with a Hall Sensing joystick, resting within a "Dual-Mode Touchpad" area. This should make it easy to navigate throughout the interface, but it can also be mapped to act as an additional thumbstick. </p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="Cytr6G6D5wJGUvWuxHWkX4" name="ayaneo-pocket-dmg-057.jpeg" alt="Ayaneo Pocket DMG" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Cytr6G6D5wJGUvWuxHWkX4.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ayaneo)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="AGD3uMdvkL69dk2mvvebM5" name="ayaneo-pocket-dmg-015.jpeg" alt="Ayaneo Pocket DMG" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AGD3uMdvkL69dk2mvvebM5.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ayaneo)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="iRHV7Vow2C3w8wDGgzpkjn" name="ayaneo-pocket-dmg-144.jpeg" alt="Ayaneo Pocket DMG" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/iRHV7Vow2C3w8wDGgzpkjn.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ayaneo)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>You can check out the full spec sheet below, but the Pocket DMG is packed to the gills with features and options that you wouldn&apos;t expect. This includes things like Active Air Cooling, "Coastline" shoulder buttons, and a 6,000mAh battery.</p>

<p>If the idea of a vertical handheld isn&apos;t your cup of tea, then you might want to check out the Ayaneo Pocket Micro. This one was designed with the Game Boy Micro in mind, which was first released back in 2005. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="qkjb9bVgydeEkAZq8pD9L9" name="ayaneo-pocket-micro-174.jpeg" alt="Ayaneo Pocket Micro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qkjb9bVgydeEkAZq8pD9L9.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ayaneo)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>With the Pocket Micro, we have a 3.5-inch IPS display, complete with a 960 x 640 resolution. That might not seem like a big deal, but between the resolution and 3:2 aspect ratio, this pocketable handheld offers 4x scaling for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-game-boy-game-boy-advance-emulators-android">Game Boy Advance emulation</a>. </p><p>Under the hood, Ayaneo opted to go with MediaTek&apos;s Helio G99 chip, the same SoC found in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/samsung-galaxy-tab-a9-series-launch">Samsung&apos;s Galaxy Tab A9</a> and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/tecno-camon-20-pro-and-camon-20-premier-review#section-tecno-camon-20-pro-and-camon-20-premier-performance-and-battery">Tecno Camon 20 Pro</a>. This is paired with either 6GB or 8GB of RAM and 128GB or 256GB of expandable storage. As for battery life, Ayaneo squeezed a 2,600mAh cell into the Pocket Micro, claiming it offers more than six hours of gameplay on a single charge.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="tGksvqBSiYkxQCjPEBQD8B" name="ayaneo-pocket-micro-206.jpeg" alt="Ayaneo Pocket Micro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tGksvqBSiYkxQCjPEBQD8B.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ayaneo)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="F4SibbTVa6LHSsCE29o398" name="ayaneo-pocket-micro-207.jpeg" alt="Ayaneo Pocket Micro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/F4SibbTVa6LHSsCE29o398.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ayaneo)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="St3bGN2axknssJP8M3iSr9" name="ayaneo-pocket-micro-183.jpeg" alt="Ayaneo Pocket Micro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/St3bGN2axknssJP8M3iSr9.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ayaneo)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>One thing you don&apos;t have to worry about with the Pocket Micro are bezels. It follows in the footsteps of the Pocket S, offering an immersive experience without worrying about distracting bezels getting in the way. </p><p>In terms of controls, the D-Pad and ABXY buttons are slightly inset, providing another call back to the original Micro. However, Ayaneo&apos;s handheld brings thumbsticks on either side, in addition to the four bumpers found on the top. </p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="MifAwun5c6xKKhTKXZ7ie8" name="ayaneo-pocket-micro-200.jpeg" alt="Ayaneo Pocket Micro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MifAwun5c6xKKhTKXZ7ie8.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ayaneo)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="CkTK325Gmua7TLGHhzFxPA" name="ayaneo-pocket-micro-201.jpeg" alt="Ayaneo Pocket Micro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CkTK325Gmua7TLGHhzFxPA.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ayaneo)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="2sZqMKiL5Rpx6WN9spLk37" name="ayaneo-pocket-micro-163.jpeg" alt="Ayaneo Pocket Micro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2sZqMKiL5Rpx6WN9spLk37.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ayaneo)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Lastly, if you&apos;re worried about durability with the Pocket Micro, you can rest easy. Ayaneo relies on the "same CNC aluminum alloy frame" that the company began using with the Pocket S. Plus, there&apos;s an anodized finish providing a "matte texture for a luxurious tactile experience."</p><p>Now for the big questions — how much will these cost and when will they be available? Starting with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.indiegogo.com/projects/pocket-dmg-snapdragon-g3x-gen-2-vertical-handheld#/">Pocket DMG</a>, we hope you&apos;re ready to empty your wallets. The splits in pricing below are for the Early Bird price and what the device will retail for. </p>
<ul><li>8GB+128GB: $339 / $449</li><li>12GB+256GB: $419 / $529</li><li>16GB+512GB: $499 / $609</li><li>16GB+1TB: $589 / $699</li></ul>
<p>The only catch here is that the 16GB/1TB model is only available with the "Retro Color limited edition" Pocket DMG. Any of the other configurations are only available in either Moon White or Arctic Black.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="LMcYQfhPDG2oygMubScHyN" name="ayaneo-pocket-dmg-pricing.jpeg" alt="Ayaneo Pocket DMG pricing" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LMcYQfhPDG2oygMubScHyN.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ayaneo)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="4xn5CrCyYuPCRAqfMehXbN" name="ayaneo-pocket-micro-pricing.jpeg" alt="Ayaneo Pocket Micro pricing" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4xn5CrCyYuPCRAqfMehXbN.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ayaneo)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="yjqpAnhS4hQsxzDnEJXYTP" name="ayaneo-pocket-dmg-micro-shipping-timeframe.jpeg" alt="Ayaneo Pocket DMG and Micro shipping expectations" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yjqpAnhS4hQsxzDnEJXYTP.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ayaneo)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Things are a bit more simple with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.indiegogo.com/projects/pocket-micro-tribute-to-classic-pocket-handhelds#/">Ayaneo Pocket Micro</a>, as there are only two configurations. The 6GB/128GB model will set you back $189 if you pre-order through Indiegogo and will retail for $219. Meanwhile, the 8GB/256GB version can be had for $219 during the Early Bird period or $249. However, there is a Retro Gray limited edition with an 8GB/256GB configuration, coming in with an Early Bird price of $249 while retailing normally for $279.</p><p>Unfortunately, although it&apos;s great that you can get your order in now, be prepared to wait a bit. Ayaneo estimates the Pocket Micro will ship in the "middle of September," while the Pocket DMG won&apos;t arrive until the "end of October."</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/ayaneo-pocket-dmg-pocket-micro-launch</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Have you ever wanted an original Game Boy running Android? What about the Game Boy Micro? Ayaneo has you covered thanks to the Pocket DMG and Pocket Micro.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">RK9gnkvHdKCQu98k2dCDyS</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5kWg72zWn5imz69eks2KJn.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 23:39:21 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ andrew.myrick@futurenet.com (Andrew Myrick) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5kWg72zWn5imz69eks2KJn.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Ayaneo]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Ayaneo Pocket DMG]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Ayaneo Pocket DMG]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>