<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 17:01:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Android 15 vs. 14: A boring update, but part of Google's bigger picture ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>After a month of delays, Android 15 is officially available. It's the seemingly smallest update we've seen from the Android team yet, sporting a handful of new features with only a few that could be categorized as "headliners."</p><p>Many of the biggest <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a> features are found in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-pixel-october-2024-feature-drop">October Feature Drop</a> for Pixel phones. While some of that has to do with Pixels catching up to other phones for feature parity, some of this signals a shift in Google's strategy.</p><p>Funny enough, our favorite new security features, like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/the-new-remote-lock-tool-does-more-for-security-than-any-other-feature-from-google">new remote lock tool</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-adds-anti-theft-security-features-like-theft-detection-lock">theft prevention features</a> aren't even part of Android 15  —  those just so happen to coincide with the Android 15 release and are already available on all Android phones via Google Play Services. That's fine by me because it ensures more people get it <em>right now</em>, but it certainly doesn't help "sell" the Android 15 update.</p><p>So, what's different between Android 14 and Android 15? Not much, but that's probably OK.</p>
<h2 id="os-updates-are-becoming-less-important-2">OS updates are becoming less important</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="NMKzfoCA9KYCgfxHqqEUJn" name="android-14-pixel-9-pro-xl-android-15-pixel-9-pro-fold-2.jpg" alt="Android 14 on Google Pixel 9 Pro XL and Android 15 on Pixel 9 Pro Fold" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NMKzfoCA9KYCgfxHqqEUJn.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>If there's any over-arching theme with Android 15, it's that base operating system updates are becoming less and less important. After years of being made fun of on stage during Apple's annual WWDC conference, Google modularized Android to put the onus for feature delivery on individual phone manufacturers instead of Google itself.</p><p>In other words, many of Android 15's new features might make you think, "Hey, that isn't new," if you aren't a Pixel user. It's a lot like how we poke fun at Apple for "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/everything-the-iphone-16-and-apple-watch-series-10-stole-from-android">stealing features</a>" from Android phones each year.</p><p>Case in point, new Android 15 features like Private Space, the upgraded Bluetooth quick tile, a high-quality webcam for computers, multitasking enhancements for foldables, and true full-screen mode are all things found on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a> from Samsung, OnePlus, Motorola, and others.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>Most new Android 15 features are probably already on your phone if you don't use a Pixel.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>OnePlus is unveiling its Android 15-based update, Oxygen OS 15, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-based-oxygenos-15-is-launching-sooner-than-you-think">on October 24</a>, while Motorola is already testing the update out for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/motorola-edge-50-fusion-gets-android-15-beta">a few lucky owners</a>. Samsung owners, meanwhile, will have to wait <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-confirms-one-ui-7-wont-hit-beta-until-end-of-this-year">until the Galaxy S25 launches</a> to get the Android 15 update.</p><p>While news of having to wait months used to be a huge problem, users of all of these phones can feel content in the knowledge that most of the best Android 15 features are already on their phones thanks to feature-rich skins like Samsung's One UI, OnePlus's Oxygen OS, and Motorola's Hello UI.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="rXSUQdURZW9sgRmzMZ2jjT" name="oxygenos-15.jpg" alt="OxygenOS 15 launch invite" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rXSUQdURZW9sgRmzMZ2jjT.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OnePlus)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>If I'm excited about any one category of new Android 15 features, it's the ones for foldables, but those, too, are already present on a number of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">foldable devices</a>. A new continuity feature lets you use an app on the big screen, then close the phone and immediately continue using that app on the cover screen.</p><p>Another new feature allows you to save split-screen app combos and pin them to the taskbar so you can quickly launch them when you need them. There's also a new persistent taskbar option that makes foldables and tablets <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/android-15s-new-tablet-features-get-me-one-step-closer-to-ditching-my-laptop-forever">a lot more like a laptop</a>.</p><p>Again, all of these features were already on many tablets and foldables, but their introduction into base Android 15 means that <em>all</em> foldables and tablets going forward should have these features.</p>
<h2 id="the-pixel-is-the-real-winner-2">The Pixel is the real winner</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="sCjLTjsmraBP7RKK4F4x7N" name="continue-using-apps-settings-pixel-9-pro-fold-1.jpg" alt="Continue apps on cover screen settings panel on Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sCjLTjsmraBP7RKK4F4x7N.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Being a Pixel owner has always meant that you get the latest version of Android first, and this time it means you get the <em>most</em> features from the Android 15 update. That's because Google launched Android 15 alongside the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-pixel-october-2024-feature-drop">October Feature Drop</a>.</p><p>Aside from the aforementioned Android 15 features, Pixel owners will get a new vibration intensity slider and adaptive haptics options to adjust vibration dynamically, haptic feedback on the brightness slider, a Gemini extension for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-use-the-pixel-screenshots-app-on-the-google-pixel-9">Pixel Screenshots app</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-audio-magic-eraser">Audio Magic Eraser</a> on more Pixel devices, a new underwater photography mode in the camera, a new temperature sensor mode in the camera, upgrades to casting and media control sharing across Pixel devices, a new volume adjustment UI, and Instagram Night Sight mode for more Pixel devices.</p>
<p>Even the new partial screen recorder app might be Pixel exclusive for a while if your specific manufacturer of choice opts to use their own screen recording tool. We'll just have to wait and see what gets added to those individual phone updates.</p><p>In particular, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-fold-review">Pixel 9 Pro Fold</a> is the biggest recipient of new features since it gets all the Android 15 features, everything from the October Pixel Feature Drop, and all the new foldable features. The lone exception is the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/google-pixel-tablet-review">Pixel Tablet</a> which got some new screensaver options in the form of Photo Frame, Clock Screensaver, and Smart Home Panel Screensaver.</p><p>Android 15 is easily the most boring update for the OS yet, but it also shows the heightened importance of individual manufacturer updates. What Google debuted on its Pixel phones will look significantly different from anything on a Motorola, Samsung, OnePlus, Vivo, or Oppo phone, but that's largely OK since Google is delivering the most important security features via Google Play Services to all existing Android phones, anyway.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="6e221697-fa2e-4ccb-8b41-bd59a912536a">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:121.08%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Y8nScb7AAtxK4j2d2EnxjV.jpg' alt="Pixel 9 render in Obsidian"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>Get the latest updates right away with the Google Pixel 9 and keep getting them for the next seven years thanks to Google's incredible update promise. Plus, quarterly Pixel Feature Drops mean you'll always get something exciting and new four times per year.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/android-15-vs-android-14</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Android 15 introduces a lot of great new security features and a couple quality of life adjustments, but the changes from Android 14 aren't as big as you might hope. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">ErsyS9LL3B5kwde6cCUUp5</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/R3Mk6dJu8qh9PLboKDFfiF.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/R3Mk6dJu8qh9PLboKDFfiF.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Looking through a Pixel 9 Pro XL Thinborne case at an Android 15 logo on a Pixel 8 Pro&#039;s display]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Looking through a Pixel 9 Pro XL Thinborne case at an Android 15 logo on a Pixel 8 Pro&#039;s display]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ How to adjust Meta Quest 3S lenses to get the clearest view ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>You've come to the right place if you need to know how to set the IPD on Meta Quest 3S. Setting the correct inter-pupillary distance, or IPD, is one of the key pillars of having a good VR experience. When your IPD is set incorrectly, it can cause nausea, headaches, and dizziness. It can also make it difficult to slice blocks accurately in Beat Saber because your brain can't deduce the proper distance between objects.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-3s">Meta Quest 3S</a>'s IPD adjustment method is quite different from other VR headsets on the market, so we've put together this guide to help you find your ideal IPD preset as well as some hidden tricks to enable additional IPD settings.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-measure-your-ipd-2">How to measure your IPD</h2>
<p>In order to measure your IPD, you'll need two things: a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Westcott-Non-Shatter-Ruler-Inches-13862/dp/B00309RVJ6/">ruler with millimeter markings</a>, and a mirror. Any ruler will work so long as it has millimeter markings, but you will want a hard ruler instead of a flimsy tape measure to ensure accuracy.</p>
<ol start="1"><li>While looking in the mirror, <strong>close your left eye</strong>.</li><li>Look straight into the mirror at your right eye <strong>with your right eye</strong>.</li><li>Hold the ruler just below your eye and center the <strong>zero marker</strong> on your right pupil.</li><li><strong>Close your right eye</strong> and <strong>open your left eye</strong>, making sure to not move the ruler.</li><li>Look into the mirror at your left eye <strong>with your left eye</strong>.</li><li>Look straight and <strong>note the millimeter distance</strong> that matches up to the center of your left pupil.</li></ol>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="ycnsgzER8Le3Q8T4xprv2H" name="measure-ipd.jpg" alt="How to measure your IPD by using a ruler" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ycnsgzER8Le3Q8T4xprv2H.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>For example, my IPD is 66mm. The average IPD sits around 63mm, but can range between 55mm and 72mm (or higher) depending on the person.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-adjust-the-ipd-on-meta-quest-3s-2">How to adjust the IPD on Meta Quest 3S</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.30%;"><img id="M9yDchVsbRfkFHcNUpXpMB" name="Meta-Quest-3S-lenses-close" alt="Looking at the lenses inside a Meta Quest 3S headset" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/M9yDchVsbRfkFHcNUpXpMB.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1153" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Now that you have your IPD measured, you can accurately set the IPD on your Oculus Quest 2. You'll do this by physically sliding the lenses closer or further apart from one another. The Oculus Quest 2 features three presets for IPD adjustment: preset 1 is 58mm, preset 2 is 63mm, and preset 3 is 68mm. By default, the Oculus Quest 2 ships at IPD preset 2, which covers the average IPD.</p>
<ol start="1"><li>Determine which preset works best for you using the measurements you wrote down earlier.</li><li>The closest preset is <strong>58mm.</strong> The middle preset is <strong>63mm.</strong> The furthest apart preset is <strong>68mm</strong>.</li><li>While holding the Meta Quest 3S, <strong>grab ahold of the gray cover </strong>on the outside of one lens.</li><li>Gently push the lens in toward the other to <strong>lower IPD</strong>, or push them apart to <strong>raise IPD</strong>.</li></ol>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Wp1Yc5g7ZKk" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<h2 id="what-if-my-ipd-doesn-t-match-the-presets-on-meta-quest-3s-2">What if my IPD doesn't match the presets on Meta Quest 3S?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="B5TbKFZYw8FCZsRWoQQGNB" name="Meta-Quest-3S-lenses-angle" alt="Looking at the lenses inside a Meta Quest 3S headset" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/B5TbKFZYw8FCZsRWoQQGNB.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>If your IPD isn't exactly 58mm, 63mm, or 68mm, don't worry. Meta has designed the lenses on the Meta Quest 3S to help fit a range of IPD, but while one of those presets will fit nicely for most people, some folks will find they need a setting in between.</p><p>The trick is to gently move the lenses between presets and stop somewhere between the preset point.</p>
<ol start="1"><li>While holding the Oculus Quest 2, <strong>grab ahold of the gray plastic</strong> on the outside of one lens.</li><li>Gently push the lens in toward the other to <strong>lower IPD</strong> or push them apart to <strong>raise IPD</strong>.</li><li>Try to <strong>push just past</strong> preset 1 or preset 2 to get a more accurate IPD.</li><li>If you're having trouble pushing past, try pushing the lenses inward <strong>from a higher IPD preset</strong> instead.</li></ol>
<p>The Meta Quest 3S still only supports a maximum IPD range of 58-68mm, but using the spaces between presets can help folks who have IPD between the numbers. For instance, someone with an IPD of 60 or 61 might try the space between preset 1 and preset 2. Someone like me who has an IPD of 66 can try the space between preset 2 and preset 3 for a more comfortable experience.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="ff4eccdf-2d60-45b0-b077-b6a984cd337e">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fCUPHg8DY6xth6JoYMuDGK.jpg' alt="An official product render of the Meta Quest 3S with its controllers"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Meta Quest 3S</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>Get the best of virtual reality and mixed reality with the Meta Quest 3S, a more affordable headset from Meta. Sporting next-generation controllers, hand tracking, a cutting-edge chip, and support for Quest 3-exclusive games.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/how-adjust-eye-distance-ipd-oculus-quest-2</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ It's important to get the right lens spacing when you're playing in VR on a Meta Quest 3S. Here's how to adjust the Meta Quest 3S IPD. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">qNvnu8LbJGtdKLhkahyQXF</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2e9CgQ3QdVfmVpJ5YMYCHB.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 16:23:46 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2e9CgQ3QdVfmVpJ5YMYCHB.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Looking at the cameras on the front of a Meta Quest 3S headset]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Looking at the cameras on the front of a Meta Quest 3S headset]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Best cases for the Samsung Galaxy S24 FE 2024 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Samsung didn&apos;t make as much of a splash about the Galaxy S24 FE, but it&apos;s an excellent phone regardless. Just like the flagship S24 series, the S24 FE is guaranteed to get updates for seven years. If your phone is going to live that long, you need one of the best cases for the Samsung Galaxy S24 FE to keep it fresh physically speaking too.</p><p>Happily, all the best case makers are offering fantastic cases for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-fe-launch">Galaxy S24 FE</a>, and that too at affordable price points. The best S24 FE cases come in lovely colors, slim or rugged options, and add useful features such as MagSafe or a kickstand to your "fan edition" <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-samsung-phones">Samsung phone</a>.</p>
<h2 id="cover-up-your-galaxy-s24-fe-with-these-stylish-cases-2">Cover up your Galaxy S24 FE with these stylish cases</h2>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="e1e6ae43-7c02-47c9-9bdb-016873897c0a">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fwgm8KKLcEFoQnuLmWGi96.jpg' alt="Caseology Parallax for Samsung Galaxy S24 FE"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Caseology Parallax for Samsung Galaxy S24 FE</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best overall</strong></em></p>
<p>Time after time, the Caseology Parallax wins me over. This superb Samsung Galaxy S24 FE case is thin, elegant, anti-slip, and protective. It comes in some cool colorways and has raised bezels to add military-grade drop protection.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="57d21b43-1b88-4991-af7c-eb790e9f4782">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yYy6UFvdpuB44J9oDzgh8e.jpg' alt="Samsung Galaxy S24 FE Flipsuit Case"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S24 FE Flipsuit Case</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best first-party</strong></em></p>
<p>Samsung's own Galaxy S24 FE Flipsuit Case costs a pretty penny, crossing the $30 price point. Available in a few styles, the basic TPU case changes your phone's theme automatically to match the design of the case. You can buy additional interactive cards to switch up its look.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="f7d11026-8cba-4559-b3ef-78677f40605c">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/EfiCXu3F9WSTSZL2a2rsF5.jpg' alt="Crave Dual Guard Samsung Galaxy S24 FE Case"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Crave Dual Guard Samsung Galaxy S24 FE Case</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best grip</strong></em></p>
<p>I have tested the Crave Dual Guard and was pleasantly surprised by the quality, considering the price. The Crave Dual Guard Samsung Galaxy S24 FE Case has a grippy textured back comprising of tiny dots for added friction. It doesn't bulk up your phone and comes in eight excellent colors.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="d0362b59-7624-49a4-824e-a97eff01935d">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zYkdcXG9BdbBx38KYW2nNZ.jpg' alt="TOCOL Magnetic Samsung Galaxy S24 FE Case"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">TOCOL Magnetic Samsung Galaxy S24 FE Case</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best</strong></em><em><strong> MagSafe</strong></em></p>
<p>You can add MagSafe without thickening up your device with the ultra-affordable TOCOL Magnetic Samsung Galaxy S24 FE Case. This case costs only $10 but you get bang-for-buck value, with a handful of colorways, a MagSafe ring built-in, and 15ft military-grade impact protection.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="bba73798-b710-4cf5-ba0c-78c85e41f4a3">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ANbogHD7jFEFVTBo2FR5AK.jpg' alt="Spigen Tough Armor MagFit for Galaxy S24 FE"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Spigen Tough Armor MagFit for Galaxy S24 FE</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best multifunctional</strong></em></p>
<p>Spigen's Tough Armor MagFit adds heavy-duty protection, a kickstand, and MagSafe functionality to the Galaxy S24 FE. I wish this came in more shades, but Spigen only offers black. The design is much tamer than other tough cases and it costs less too.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="e386ef79-9531-4d75-9c47-0285be2cd7ff">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/i6cv2ab5P4gs4QpBEJbcWj.jpg' alt="FNTCASE Samsung Galaxy S24 FE Case with Kickstand & Holster"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">FNTCASE Samsung Galaxy S24 FE Case with Kickstand & Holster</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best rugged</strong></em></p>
<p>FNTCASE is a lesser-known brand but I have tried and tested its rugged cases and found them satisfactory. The brand's Samsung Galaxy S24 FE Case with Kickstand & Holster comes in some really cool hues. I especially love the purple variant. You get a built-in screen guard, tough layers for hardcore impact absorption, grippy scored sides, a kickstand, and even a holster!</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<ul><li><a href="#main"><strong>Back to the top ^</strong></a></li></ul>
<h2 id="you-don-apos-t-need-a-bulky-case-to-protect-your-galaxy-s24-fe-2">You don&apos;t need a bulky case to protect your Galaxy S24 FE</h2>
<p>I&apos;m really glad that the best cases for the Samsung Galaxy S24 FE are from reliable brands. Every option in this roundup comes from tried and tested case makers, so you can choose anything from this list and feel confident in your choice.</p><p>Picking the right case depends on a lot of factors. Most people want good drop protection without bulking up their phones. Of course, price plays a vital role as well. All things considered, the Caseology Parallax is the best case for the Samsung Galaxy S24 FE. It&apos;s one heck of a good-looking case and comes in attractive colors. More importantly, it is budget-friendly, drop-proof, and thin enough to be used with a wireless charger. The textured sides add grip, preventing accidental slips and drops.</p><p>Functionality is something else that you might prioritize. If you want your Galaxy S24 FE case to add more functionality to your device, you should consider something that adds MagSafe support. MagSafe is a gateway. Even if the case doesn&apos;t have a stand, you can slap on a stand, grip, or any other <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-magsafe-accessories-for-android-phones">MagSafe accessory</a> whenever you like.</p><p>Depending on how you use your phone, both the Spigen Tough Armor MagFit and TOCOL Magnetic Samsung Galaxy S24 FE Case are solid choices that add MagSafe support to your phone. TOCOL&apos;s offering is rather slim and comes in a couple of translucent hues, so you might like it more if you prefer a lightweight or stylish case. On the other hand, Spigen&apos;s build quality is top-notch and adds heavy-duty drop protection. If you&apos;re a clumsy individual, the Spigen Tough Armor MagFit is better suited for your S24 FE. I just wish it came in more colors.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-cases-for-the-samsung-galaxy-s24-fe</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Researching the best cases for the Samsung Galaxy S24 FE? Look no more as we have done the homework for you. Here are all the top contenders! ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">8T4mGVxFyfQc4aBfmTupdL</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gzk24KyGs79J3sBZmoXp8m.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 16:02:22 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gzk24KyGs79J3sBZmoXp8m.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Caseology]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Caseology Parallax for Samsung Galaxy S24 FE]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Caseology Parallax for Samsung Galaxy S24 FE]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google is just teasing us now ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Beyond the Alphabet</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="74uXEL5FbSyzjPgHM9K6b7" name="lloyd-beyond-the-alphabet2.png" caption="" alt="Android Central's LLoyd with a projection with a Google logo" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/74uXEL5FbSyzjPgHM9K6b7.png" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text"><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/beyond-the-alphabet">Beyond the Alphabet</a> is a weekly column that focuses on the tech world both inside and out of the confines of Mountain View.</p></div></div>
<p>It arrived a bit later than expected, but Android 15 is finally rolling out, bringing with it a slew of new features. Many of these are primarily directed at our smartphones, but the Pixel Tablet just got a major upgrade and one that makes me chuckle.</p><p>Shortly after the Pixel Tablet debuted, I couldn't help but write about how it is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/google-pixel-tablet-not-nest-hub-replacement">basically a replacement</a> for the Nest Hub. Google continues to suggest otherwise, but now, I can't help but feel like Google is playing a bit of "peek-a-boo."</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="dCvKo4Vcg9qQXVET9tzGQT" name="home-control-screen-saver-pixel-9-pro-fold-google-pixel-tablet.jpg.jpg" alt="Home Control screen saver on Pixel 9 Pro Fold and widgets on Pixel Tablet" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dCvKo4Vcg9qQXVET9tzGQT.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>When docked, the Pixel Tablet already looks like an improved version of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/google-pixel-tablet-nest-hub-max-kitchen-test">Nest Hub Max</a>, and Hub Mode adds familiar functionality, such as turning it into a digital photo frame. Google has already implemented the ability to show device controls when in Hub Mode, but with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15" target="_blank">Android 15</a>, there's a new "Home Controls" screensaver that you can enjoy.</p><p>As you might suspect, this puts all of your favorite shortcuts from the Home app right on the lock screen. And the best part, at least for me, is that you don't need to fiddle with anything to get these controls to show. Now, I'm able to unlock my front door, turn lights on and off, or adjust the thermostat even faster.</p><p>Not only that, but if you've taken the time to set up Home Assistant, you can rely on that, as opposed to the Google Home app. There's a bit of configuration that needs to be done, but once you're done, the Home Assistant Dashboard appears when the Pixel Tablet's screen saver is activated.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="3HPQpanRc6kHcuRNCZodKP" name="google-pixel-tablet-home-assistant-dashboard.jpg" alt="Home Assistant Dashboard on Pixel Tablet" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3HPQpanRc6kHcuRNCZodKP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Oh, and there's something else — the Home Control screen saver isn't limited to the Pixel Tablet — it's available on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-fold-review">Pixel 9 Pro Fold</a> too. I noticed this after tossing the 9 Pro Fold onto my MagSafe stand before getting into bed. It came as a bit of a surprise because I initially thought Google would have made this a tablet-exclusive. Thankfully, that's not the case.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:5472px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="bi7MhZGQa4eW7r5ZWBEvcF" name="google-pixel-tablet-nest-hub-max.jpg" alt="Nest Hub Max next to Pixel Tablet on countertop" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bi7MhZGQa4eW7r5ZWBEvcF.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="5472" height="3078" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I feel like Google is just messing with us now. It didn't announce a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/google-pixel-tablet-2">Pixel Tablet 2</a>, nor have we seen anything in the way of a revamped Nest lineup besides the Thermostat and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/why-the-google-tv-streamer-is-more-important-than-you-think">TV Streamer</a>.</p><p>Given the enormous push to throw Gemini into anything and everything it can, I have to imagine that the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-smart-display">Nest smart displays</a> and speakers are next. Besides not being updated or refreshed in years, you can't even pair Google's new TV Streamer with Nest Audio, which is surely a missed opportunity.</p><p>Unless it isn't.</p><p>Sure, we can argue about backward compatibility and all that jazz, but Google is obviously taking very precise and calculated steps. We just have no idea what the end goal is with all of the various changes and additions being made to the overarching lineup.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/we-need-new-nest-hardware-not-pixel-tablet-2">As I explained</a> to Android Central's editor-in-chief, Shruti Shekar, it was really weird to see Google announce so many products only to leave the Nest Hub and Audio untouched. Arguably, these devices are just as important as the TV Streamer and Nest Thermostat when it comes to building a smart home.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>Maybe Google is just trying to let Gemini bake a bit longer before introducing new smart speakers and displays.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>One theory that I have is that Google wanted to wait until after the Pixel 9 series was released. This gets <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini</a> into the hands of many more people, operating as a kind of public beta without calling it as such. In doing so, it provides Google with the necessary data and feedback that can be used to improve Gemini so that it works as well as, but hopefully better than, Google Assistant.</p><p>The year is rapidly coming to a close, and it's been an incredibly wild ride, as we saw Bard (thankfully) rebranded to Gemini, while on-device AI capabilities have vastly improved. With the Android 15 finally out of the way, perhaps <em>now</em> is the time for Google to pull back the veil on what lies in wake with either the Pixel Tablet 2 or the next lineup of Nest displays and speakers.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="9b3ca2f0-941e-49ae-a96c-e7eb4124aa23">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Fa597SdtCGpg5MdQ2EdNpY.jpg' alt="Pixel Tablet product render"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel Tablet</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Not just a tablet</strong></em></p><p>The Pixel Tablet offers much more functionality than just being a way to enjoy movies, videos, or games. With Android 15, it gets even more useful and helpful features. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<hr>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/google-is-just-teasing-us-now-android-15-pixel-tablet</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Android 15 has arrived, and with it comes a new feature that turns the Pixel Tablet into more of a dedicated smart home hub than it already was.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">zQCarSKKWx9ftKxDuEVBPF</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jtgyFzP65Qgs6yJTZMKhPU.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ andrew.myrick@futurenet.com (Andrew Myrick) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jtgyFzP65Qgs6yJTZMKhPU.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Home Control screen saver on the Pixel Tablet]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Home Control screen saver on the Pixel Tablet]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Android 15 review: Smooth operator ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Last year&apos;s Android update was tame by any standard; outside of a few customization options, tweaks to the Material You aesthetic, and the usual security updates, we didn&apos;t get many new features in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review">Android 14</a>. That&apos;s why I was excited when I installed the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a> beta earlier in the year; Google introduced over a dozen new features, including notification cooldown, battery charging limit, and so much more.  </p><p>There&apos;s just one problem: most of these features are missing in the stable release. Some features — like the ability to limit battery charging to 80% — have been pushed to the QPR1 released that&apos;s slated to arrive in December, and others are likely coming in next year&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16">Android 16</a> release.</p><p>That said, there are numerous smaller changes that end up making a difference in day-to-day use, and if you&apos;re on a Pixel, you&apos;ll immediately notice the smoother animations. While most recent Pixels have 120Hz panels, the interface is nowhere as smooth as the likes of MIUI or ColorOS, and that&apos;s thankfully changing; I noticed a big uptick in fluidity on my <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/i-was-wrong-about-the-pixel-9-pro-xl">Pixel 9 Pro XL</a> after switching to the Android 15 stable build.</p><p>This isn&apos;t just the case on the Pixel 9 Pro XL; I found the same to be true on my <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/i-switched-from-iphone-to-pixel-after-12-years">Pixel 9</a>, and last year&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-review">Pixel 8</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/i-switched-back-to-the-pixel-8-pro-and-i-couldnt-be-happier">8 Pro</a> as well. This change alone makes Android 15 much better, and you get a slate of security updates and theft protection features that ensure it is nearly impossible for thieves to access your stolen device&apos;s data.</p><p>While there isn&apos;t much in the way of UI changes, the redesigned volume panel on the Pixels is great to use, Private Space is a fantastic addition, and there are smaller tweaks throughout the interface. I used the preview builds of Android 15 and tested all beta releases, and switched over to the stable build on my Pixel 9 Pro XL as soon as it became available. So here&apos;s everything you need to know about what Android 15 has to offer, and when (or if) all of these features will make their way to your device.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-android-15-brings-much-needed-fluidity-to-pixels"><span>Android 15 brings much-needed fluidity to Pixels</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="eVc6dkCxz3spdacUidzBUo" name="android-15-12.jpg" alt="Android 15 home page on Pixel 9, Pixel 9 Pro XL, and Pixel 9 Pro Fold" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/eVc6dkCxz3spdacUidzBUo.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While I like Pixel Launcher in general, the interface has its share of issues; there is noticeable jitter, the animations are janky, and it just isn&apos;t a great experience. The Pixel 9 Pro XL is a little better in this area, but the device still doesn&apos;t measure up to other Android skins when it come to fluidity.</p><p>That&apos;s changing with Android 15. Google overhauled the animations, and they&apos;re much smoother; whether it&apos;s going back to the home screen, using the overview menu, switching between apps, or just navigating the app drawer, there&apos;s a fluidity that was clearly missing in Android 14. This is the most noticeable difference in Android 15, and it makes Pixels that much better to use. The change isn&apos;t just limited to the Pixel 9 series, but goes back to the Pixel 8 and 8 Pro, and the Pixel 7 series as well.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="L7iRZha7H6gb6t96FdJcnn" name="android-15-5.jpg" alt="Android 15 home page on Pixel 9, Pixel 9 Pro XL, and Pixel 9 Pro Fold unfolded to a review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/L7iRZha7H6gb6t96FdJcnn.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Other skins like OxygenOS still have an edge when it comes to overall fluidity, but Google made up a lot of ground on the Pixels, and it finally feels like these devices can take full advantage of 120Hz panels.</p><p>Another problem that routinely plagues Pixels is scrolling; when reading a long-form article or continually scrolling, there has always been a noticeable stutter, and thankfully, Android 15 addresses this issue. Scrolling is just as smooth as general navigation, and again, this is a vital change that makes a real difference in usability.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-private-space-locks-down-your-data"><span>Private Space locks down your data</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="e2KXrjW4SKh46eKbakzGa9" name="android-15-private-space.jpg" alt="Private Space in Pixel 9 Pro XL on Android 15" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/e2KXrjW4SKh46eKbakzGa9.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Most Android skins come with the ability to lock apps and sensitive data behind a password, and with Android 15, Google is introducing its take on the feature. Dubbed Private Space, it allows you to lock apps in a distinct space that&apos;s outside the main app drawer.</p><p>It basically creates a sandbox, so you will need to use a different Google account with the mode. Any apps within Private Space don&apos;t show up in the app list, privacy dashboard, or permissions manager, and it isn&apos;t possible to move them to a new device. You can also set up a new screen lock to access Private Space, and the mode is accessible by navigating to the bottom of the app drawer and choosing the Private section.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="yNQj5Y8xEryNbhrR9FbGe7" name="android-15-private-space-2.jpg" alt="Private Space in Pixel 9 Pro XL on Android 15" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yNQj5Y8xEryNbhrR9FbGe7.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>What&apos;s interesting about Private Space is that you can run a second instance of an app without too much of a hassle. MIUI and ColorOS have a nifty app clone feature, but Private Space allows you to do something similar on Pixels; if anything, it is a better implementation as you can use any app or messaging service you want in this mode.</p><p>You also get full access to the camera, and any photos or videos taken when using this mode will be saved in the Private Space gallery and won&apos;t show up in the regular gallery. Overall, Google did a great job with Private Space, and if you want to hide sensitive data, this is an incredibly useful feature.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-android-15-has-much-better-widget-previews"><span>Android 15 has much better widget previews</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="WzRU5LH8xKKJcuoKMBeDEA" name="android-15-widgets.jpg" alt="Widget previews on Android 15 with Pixel 9, 9 Pro XL, and 9 Pro Fold" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WzRU5LH8xKKJcuoKMBeDEA.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Android 15 doesn&apos;t introduce any major changes to the interface, and that&apos;s not a bad thing. The Material You aesthetic clearly has a lot going for it, and three years after its debut, it continues to stand out for its usage of bold colors and distinctive styling. I get that not everyone is a fan of the design, but it is one of the reasons I like using Pixel devices, and it&apos;s good to see Google not changing things wholesale.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="6jFJuFYJMztUA7RHWLFDTB" name="android-15-widgets-2.jpg" alt="Widget previews on Android 15 with Pixel 9 Pro XL" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6jFJuFYJMztUA7RHWLFDTB.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>That said, there are a few smaller additions, starting with widget previews. When you go into the widget section, you get a live preview of the widget, and that gives you a much better idea of how it will look like on your home screen. This is a minor tweak as things go, but it makes selecting the right widget just that little easier.</p>
<p>On the subject of things that haven&apos;t been addressed, themed icons are still annoying to use, and after three years, the feature is still in beta. Google just isn&apos;t able to deliver in this regard, and it should look to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/everything-ios-18-stole-from-android">iOS 18</a> to see how to get this right in one go — my <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/apple-iphone-16-pro-max-review">iPhone 16 Pro Max</a> has better icon styling than my Pixel 9 Pro XL. </p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-android-15-has-a-brand-new-volume-panel"><span>Android 15 has a brand-new volume panel </span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="2aaWbVWSSAFVAmLknuX2y8" name="android-15-volume-panel.jpg" alt="Android 15 volume panel on Pixel 9 Pro XL, Pixel 9 Pro Fold, and Pixel 9" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2aaWbVWSSAFVAmLknuX2y8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google likes fiddling with the volume control on Pixels, and this time, I actually like the changes. The volume panel (accessible by selecting the three dots underneath the volume slider) is noticeably bigger and has chunky controls, and it looks cleaner. You also get to see what device is being used to play audio, and like everything else, the colors change based on the accent colors you&apos;ve selected.</p><p>Of course, there&apos;s a good chance that this volume panel is limited to Pixels; other skins use their own system, and it&apos;s unlikely they&apos;ll use Google&apos;s panel.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-android-15-delivers-much-better-haptics"><span>Android 15 delivers much better haptics</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="Bd6Phb2k7MGga6tiHdnEtA" name="android-15-vibration.jpg" alt="Vibration settings in Android 15 on Pixel 9, 9 Pro XL, and 9 Pro Fold" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Bd6Phb2k7MGga6tiHdnEtA.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Android 15 unlocks the use of haptics in new locations, and this is a great move. The haptic motor is now triggered when you change the brightness using the brightness slider, or adjusting the volume. You still get haptic feedback when you use the back gesture, in the overview menu, and when you&apos;re using the keyboard (if you have it enabled).</p><p>You can now select the intensity of haptic feedback; I like this feature in ColorOS, and it&apos;s good to see Google bringing it to a wider variety of devices. Another new addition is adaptive vibration, which dynamically adjusts the intensity of the haptic motor based on the environment; you get a stronger feedback if your phone is in your pocket or if your surroundings are noisy, with gentler vibration when it&apos;s next to you on a table.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-android-15-safeguards-your-data-like-never-before"><span>Android 15 safeguards your data like never before</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="PZmTBF383aXxx5rRyRhLmC" name="android-15-security.jpg" alt="Anti-theft features in Android 15 on Pixel 9, 9 Pro XL, and 9 Pro Fold" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PZmTBF383aXxx5rRyRhLmC.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google does a good job adding security and privacy features to every new Android release, and that&apos;s true with Android 15 as well. This time, a key focus is theft prevention, with Google leveraging its on-device AI smarts to offer a suite of features aimed at ensuring your data isn&apos;t accessible if your device is stolen.</p>
<p>Remote Lock is the best feature in this regard; if your lose your device, you can easily lock its screen with a phone number by going to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://android.com/lock">android.com/lock</a> — it&apos;s as easy as that. All you need to do is enable the feature in your phone — it&apos;s located in the Theft protection menu in the Device unlock settings — and verify your phone number associated with your Google account.</p>
<p>Obviously, the device needs to be online for this feature to work. If it&apos;s offline, the device will lock the next time it goes online. There&apos;s another feature dubbed Offline device lock that locks the screen shortly after your device goes offline, and this is done automatically to safeguard your data.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="bZX9HeyfogAq73Lp9QPG86" name="android-15-remote-lock.jpg" alt="Remote Lock highlighted in Pixel 9 Pro XL" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bZX9HeyfogAq73Lp9QPG86.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Theft Detection Lock uses onboard sensors to determine if your phone is stolen. If you&apos;re using your phone and someone snatches your phone and tries to run or drive away, the device automatically locks. Google is rolling out this feature widely, stating that all devices running Android 10 and above should be getting an update to include this feature shortly.</p><p>There are lots of smaller changes designed to protect your data:</p>
<ul><li>Google is rolling out "enhanced factory reset protection," which makes it harder to reset your device if it is stolen. You'll need to verify your Google account credentials before a reset, and that should deter thieves from being able to reset a device.</li><li>Entering multiple wrong passwords will lock the device for a duration, which is what most other Android skins already do.</li><li>Any changes made to Find My Device settings will now need a PIN, password, or biometrics.</li><li>Google will roll out an Identity Check feature later this year that will require biometric authentication when accessing key Google account or device details, like changing the PIN, accessing Passkeys from an unknown location, or disabling theft prevention. The feature will be opt-in.</li></ul>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-android-15-brings-selective-screen-recording"><span>Android 15 brings selective screen recording</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="bN8r5aXfUJ8hYRVJm5mS6C" name="android-15-recording.jpg" alt="Android 15 recording feature on Pixel 9, 9 Pro XL, and 9 Pro Fold" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bN8r5aXfUJ8hYRVJm5mS6C.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Android 15 brings changes to the built-in screen recording service; you can now use partial screen recording to record just an app window instead of the entire screen. This is useful if you&apos;re documenting something within an app and don&apos;t want other details — network connectivity, unread notifications, or the status bar — to show up in the recording.</p><p>As always, you can record audio along with the screen, and there&apos;s the ability to choose the source: device audio, mic, or a combination of the two.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-app-archiving-in-android-15-is-actually-great"><span>App archiving in Android 15 is actually great</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="SnN6yo3KE5x6EbGzLcJjz4" name="android-15-archiving.jpg" alt="Archiving on Android 15" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SnN6yo3KE5x6EbGzLcJjz4.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>App Archiving is now available in Android 15, and it allows you to delete an app while still having its data preserved. Basically, the data associated with that app is stored in your Google account, and once you need to use it again, you can just install it. The app icon stays in your app drawer, but it is greyed out and has a download icon. Selecting it will download the app onto your device again, and all the settings and data is intact.</p><p>This is a fantastic feature to use on Pixels; Google still has just 128GB of storage on base models of its latest flagships, and if you don&apos;t pay an additional $100 to get extra storage, there&apos;s a good chance you&apos;ll fill up the storage on your phone in a matter of months. To give you some context, in less than two months of using my Pixel 9 Pro XL, I used up 138GB of data; I&apos;m using the 256GB model, but if I had the 128GB version, I would&apos;ve had to archive just about every installed game.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-predictive-back-gesture-might-just-be-usable-now"><span>Predictive back gesture might just be usable now</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="S3keEyv4T4yADcvhRccYZ5" name="android-15-back.jpg" alt="Back gesture in use within settings on Pixel 9 Pro XL in Android 15" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/S3keEyv4T4yADcvhRccYZ5.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It feels like the predictive back gesture has been around for a while now, and while Google initially showcased it two years ago, it&apos;s finally usable now. The back gesture allows you to essentially preview the page you&apos;ll be returning to when you start using the back gesture, and it is a nifty navigational aid.</p><p>The predictive back gesture is enabled by default on Pixels, but Google doesn&apos;t enforce its use, so it its usage isn&apos;t consistent — even Chrome doesn&apos;t have it yet. And it remains to be seen if other brands utilize the feature at all in their own skins.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-foldables-get-much-needed-love-in-android-15"><span>Foldables get much-needed love in Android 15</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="jmsaWUXY8HDHuPZEPq8HZ" name="android-15-6.jpg" alt="Pixel 9 Pro Fold taskbar on Android 15 with Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro XL next to it" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jmsaWUXY8HDHuPZEPq8HZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Foldables are mainstream enough these days, but the usability varies significantly based on manufacturer. Google is addressing this in Android 15 by making a few features standard on foldables, including the ability to pin the taskbar at the bottom of the screen.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="KJhKRYgT3CzLd3GERKbnA3" name="android-15-20.jpg" alt="Create multitasking pair on Pixel 9 Pro Fold" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KJhKRYgT3CzLd3GERKbnA3.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Other brands do a good job with multitasking features, but it has been a bit of an afterthought on Pixels. That&apos;s thankfully changing with App Pairs; the feature allows you to launch two apps in split-screen mode at once. It&apos;s easy to set up and use, and if you launch the same two apps in split-screen mode, you can basically set up an icon that will launch that app pair automatically — the window configuration will be preserved as well.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-android-15-coming-to-a-phone-near-you"><span>Android 15: Coming to a phone near you</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="wQ5kQ7Tz2Q38S3qddmfDT4" name="android-15-23.jpg" alt="Android 15 Easter egg on Pixel 9 Pro XL, Pixel 9, and Pixel 9 Pro Fold" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wQ5kQ7Tz2Q38S3qddmfDT4.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Android 15 doesn&apos;t have many exciting features, and that&apos;s by design. Google changed how it handles updates in the last two years; instead of bundling all its features into a single version update at the end of the year, it continually rolls out new features as they become available. By ensuring that system and security patches aren&apos;t linked to the version release, Google effectively ensures that a wider swathe of devices can get essential updates.</p><p>That said, you still get noteworthy additions. Private Space does a great job locking down sensitive data, the UI tweaks and improvements to haptics make using Pixels that much more enjoyable, and Google introduced much-needed theft protection measures.</p><p>What I like the most about Android 15 is the increased fluidity; it just makes such a big difference on Pixels, and the system-level optimization should allow other brands to take advantage of this. As for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/when-will-my-phone-get-android-15">when your phone will get the Android 15 update</a>, now that the stable build is available, other manufacturers will start rolling out their own beta programs, and we should get the stable release on most flagships before the end of the year.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-review</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Android 15 doesn't have huge UI changes or groundbreaking features, but it brings a host of smaller tweaks that make a genuine difference in daily use.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">LouGhFbxi3BqgfEtYTfmX9</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/C7zTvtoXoCMSCMi5d4u3n3.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 14:33:52 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/C7zTvtoXoCMSCMi5d4u3n3.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android 15 Easter egg on Pixel 9 Pro XL, Pixel 9, and Pixel 9 Pro Fold]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android 15 Easter egg on Pixel 9 Pro XL, Pixel 9, and Pixel 9 Pro Fold]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung's rumored Galaxy Z Fold 6 Slim likely releasing next week ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung has a new teaser for an upcoming launch event in Korea on October 21.</li><li>The teaser hints at a new Galaxy foldable, likely a slimmer Galaxy Z Fold 6.</li><li>It is unclear whether the new foldable device's launch is also aimed at a global release.</li></ul>
<p>Putting an end to all rumors, Samsung has finally revealed the launch date of the rumored foldable phone. The company&apos;s Korean newsroom has shared a new teaser of a launch event scheduled for coming Monday (Oct. 21).</p><p>However, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://news.samsung.com/kr/%EC%B4%88%EB%8C%80%EC%9E%A5-10%EC%9B%94-21%EC%9D%BC-%EC%83%88%EB%A1%9C%EC%9A%B4-%EA%B0%A4%EB%9F%AD%EC%8B%9C%EA%B0%80-%EA%B3%B5%EA%B0%9C%EB%90%A9%EB%8B%88%EB%8B%A4">teaser shared</a> (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/mobile/october-21-will-be-a-big-day-for-samsung-foldables-galaxy-z-fold-special-edition/?utm_source=twitter&utm_medium=socialorg&utm_campaign=rss-feed">Digital Trends</a>) on YouTube doesn&apos;t specify whether it is a Galaxy Z Fold 6 Special Edition or the long-rumored Galaxy Z Fold 6 Slim. Per the teaser, it surely appears to be the latter model, as the device is teased in an envelope passing under a door rail.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PnA5VH5iDFk" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>The device in the teaser is surely a book-style Galaxy foldable phone, with its screen turning on to showcase the launch date. Needless to say, an envelope is typically thinner, and such a thin phone packed in it reminds us of Steve Jobs&apos;s popular unveiling of the MacBook Air in 2008.</p><p>The latest teaser doesn&apos;t give away much, aside from the launch date and the slimmer foldable phone tentatively named Galaxy Z Fold 6 Slim. It is also unclear whether the event is exclusive to the Korean market or the device will be available in other regions, too.</p>
<p>Having said that, one interesting aspect of the teaser video description happens to be the "yet another innovation" tagline (Korean-translated). It is highly unlikely that Samsung would say the rumored Galaxy Z Fold 6 Special Edition is an innovation as it is something that&apos;s already available (<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Galaxy Z Fold 6</a>) to the masses.</p><p>These pieces of evidence point to a slimmer Galaxy foldable phone coming next week. Previous leaks have given us a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/alleged-galaxy-z-fold-6-special-edition-photo-rumors">sneak peek</a> at how the device would probably look. It is believed to be slimmer than the current Z Fold 6, with a thickness of 10.6mm (when folded), while the former measures 12.1mm. The leak also indicated that it would have a boxy design with a brushed metal finish and should make the device hold comfortably in one hand.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:490px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:122.45%;"><img id="rdGGwNfr2sydiEdNP3FYh3" name="samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-special-edition-alleged-photo.jpg" alt="An alleged photo of the Galaxy Z Fold 6 "Special Edition" with a potential brushed metal finish and camera array changes." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rdGGwNfr2sydiEdNP3FYh3.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="490" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While triple cameras on the current Galaxy Z Fold 6 don&apos;t protrude that much, the upcoming foldable&apos;s previous leak hints at the device featuring triple cameras placed in a separate camera module that protrudes quite significantly due to the slimness the device incorporates.</p><p>Overall, Samsung seems to be aiming at current slimmer foldables, launched recently, such as <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-v3-hands-on">Honor Magic V3</a>. It is one of the slimmest <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">foldable phones</a> available there, measuring only 9.3mm when folded.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-slim-gets-a-launch-date</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A new slimmer Galaxy Z Fold 6 has been making rounds for quite a while now. Finally, Samsung teases it in a video. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">2pzeDaDGd58YoqJdt9DaJc</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uAQUEJY5SAcxwFeSKFJx2S.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 12:53:22 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uAQUEJY5SAcxwFeSKFJx2S.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Samsung]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Galaxy Z Fold 6 Slim teaser]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Galaxy Z Fold 6 Slim teaser]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Meet app's original version is officially gone for good ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The original Google Meet app is officially done on Android devices.</li><li>A pop-up now encourages users to download the latest version with new features like reactions and direct calling.</li><li>The original app has been removed from the Play Store, so no one can download it or find info about it anymore.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>The original Google Meet app has reportedly stopped working on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android smartphones</a> once and for all.</p><p>The original Google Meet app, which was once Hangouts Meet, debuted in April 2020. In 2022, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-duo-update-meet-icon">Google switched the Duo app over to the Meet</a> name as well. To keep things clear, the company labeled the first version as "original" and shifted focus to the newer Meet, which attracted a larger user crowd.</p><p>However, with two <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-meet">Google Meet</a> apps in play, things got a bit messy. So, Google sent out alerts to users of the original app, encouraging them to uninstall it and switch over to the Meet that used to be Duo.</p><p>Having provided users with ample time to get used to the change, Google has chosen to sunset the original Meet app. Former users will be directed to download the rebranded Meet that evolved from Duo.</p><p>According to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/10/16/google-meet-original-deprecated/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a>, the original Meet app is now officially out of service. Users are greeted with a prompt to download the latest version. A pop-up in the old app points them to the new Meet, showcasing fun features like reactions and the ability to call other Meet users.</p><p>Android Central can also confirm that Google has taken the initiative to yank the original Meet app from the Play Store, so users can no longer download it or find any info about it.</p><p>Considering the new app has hit over 5 billion downloads, it makes total sense to retire the older one that only reached 500 million.</p><p>On top of that, ditching the original Meet app is a no-brainer for Google since it&apos;s all in on making the newer, more popular version even better.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-meet-apps-original-version-is-officially-gone-for-good</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google is shutting down the original version of Meet to simplify its video conferencing lineup. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">hbLa3zytqU4jX7b6BLcBg6</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tRiekvZ2DfyzAsjMQHb6EJ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:31:49 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tRiekvZ2DfyzAsjMQHb6EJ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Meet logo on a phone screen]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Meet logo on a phone screen]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Who needs Black Friday? This HUGE 100-inch Hisense 4K TV is $1,700 off at Best Buy right now ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Big TV deals are in season even this far in advance of Black Friday, and this next entry&apos;s a good one.<strong> </strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/hisense-100-class-u8-series-mini-led-4k-uhd-qled-google-tv-2023/6561416.p" target="_blank"><strong>Best Buy has cut $1,700 off the 100-inch 4K Hisense Class U8 Series TV</strong></a>,<strong> </strong>representing a 34% discount on a certifiably massive display. This TV features Hisense&apos;s ULED Mini-LED, offering 4K and four times as many pixels as a regular Full HD TV. With a refresh rate of 144Hz, this screen is a great option for fast-paced gaming, as supported by visual features like Motion Rate 480 enhancements, HDR 10 Plus, and adaptive synchronization.</p><p>It also comes with the user-friendly Google smart TV platform, sporting popular apps like Netflix, Hulu, Prime Video, Apple TV Plus, Peacock, and more.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="9025cd3e-46ca-4ab7-bd77-682df5905128" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$4,999.99" data-dimension48="$4,999.99" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/hisense-100-class-u8-series-mini-led-4k-uhd-qled-google-tv-2023/6561416.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="VwWvjiJeQd8DiBCGw6jkCJ" name="hisense u8 miniled tv reco 600x600.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VwWvjiJeQd8DiBCGw6jkCJ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Hisense 100-inch Class U8 Series 4K TV:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/hisense-100-class-u8-series-mini-led-4k-uhd-qled-google-tv-2023/6561416.p" target="_blank" data-dimension112="9025cd3e-46ca-4ab7-bd77-682df5905128" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$4,999.99" data-dimension48="$4,999.99"><del>$4,999.99</del> <strong>$3,299.99 at Best Buy</strong></a></p>
<p>The Hisense U8 Series has a lot to offer, and those looking for a 100-inch TV will especially like the price point on this one. For a limited time, Best Buy has knocked a whopping $1,700 off the price of this Hisense 100-inch Google TV, though it's tough to say how long it will last.</p>
<p>This TV has just about all the features someone could need in a high-end television, from HDR and synchronization settings for gaming to a 144Hz refresh rate and motion enhancement technology.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/hisense-100-class-u8-series-mini-led-4k-uhd-qled-google-tv-2023/6561416.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="9025cd3e-46ca-4ab7-bd77-682df5905128" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$4,999.99" data-dimension48="$4,999.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>you were already considering a large TV in this price range; you need something with a high refresh rate for gaming; you want a TV with easy access to Google Assistant or Amazon Alexa; </p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>you&apos;re looking for a smaller TV than this; you&apos;d rather go with a budget option, or at least one under $3,000.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/hisense-h65g-series-tv-review">Hisense TVs</a> have developed name-brand recognition by this point, and while the U8 Class Series is our top mid-range pick for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-4k-tvs-chromecast#section-best-midrange-pick">best 4K TVs to use with Chromecast</a>, the 100-inch version doesn&apos;t exactly fall into the mid-range price category so much as its smaller sizes. However, this discount chops an impressive $1,700 off the TV&apos;s price, so if you&apos;re in the market, now might be a great time to buy.</p><p>The 100-inch Hisense U8 Class Series sports a 144Hz regular refresh rate with motion frame rate enhancements backed by Motion Rate 480. As such, this is a solid option for high-speed movie or show watching, gaming, or really anything where you want to catch each and every frame.</p><p>As for connectivity, it includes four HDMI ports, a composite video input, two USB-A ports, connections for analog and optical digital audio, and a LAN input. Did we mention that it&apos;s $1,700 off?!</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/who-needs-black-friday-this-huge-100-inch-hisense-4k-tv-is-usd1-700-off-at-best-buy-right-now</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ So it looks like Best Buy went crazy and launched a $1,700 discount on this 100-inch 4K Hisense TV, but this is a deal that probably won't stick around long. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">usxM9S3oo7AZwyyy2es4QD</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/G9SqfjmsFw78KnzoGWzBdK.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 21:19:37 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Streaming &amp; TV]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ zacharydvisconti@gmail.com (Zachary Visconti) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/G9SqfjmsFw78KnzoGWzBdK.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Hisense]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Hisense U8 series 4K Google TV]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Hisense U8 series 4K Google TV]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ NotebookLM update lets you 'guide' its AI and listen while you work ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google detailed two new features arriving for NotebookLM, beginning with a "customize" button to guide the AI hosts in Audio Overviews.</li><li>The other feature lets users listen to their generated audio files in the background while working elsewhere in the app.</li><li>Google is also starting its pilot program for a "NotebookLM for Business."</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>We've had a little over a month to experience NotebookLM's "Audio Overviews" and Google is taking the next step as it sheds the experimental tag.</p><p>With two new features on the way, the company looks to deliver more ways for users to get more out of their Audio Overviews in NotebookLM. In a Keyword <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.google/technology/ai/notebooklm-update-october-2024/">blog post</a>, Google states its digital note-taker is receiving a tool that lets users "guide the conversation." Before starting a "deep dive," the post states users can write specific instructions for the AI to adhere to.</p><p>Users will find a new "Customize" button beside the standard "Generate" one. Clicking it will open a floating text box that asks what the AI should focus on. This is likely where users can fine-tune the AI to their needs; however, Google gives a few suggestions.</p><p>Users can tell the AI to focus on a specific source, topic, or audience.</p><p>The other feature joining the fray today (Oct 17) adds background listening. Google says users can start an Audio Overview and then hop out and retain the ability to do other things within their digital notebook.</p><p>Lastly, the post highlights the introduction of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://notebooklm.google/business">NotebookLM for Business</a>. Those interested <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://notebooklm.google/business">must apply</a> as Google says its pilot program has begun. If you're selected, you will gain early access to "new product features, training, and email support." Since this is for business folk, Google states this version of NotebookLM lets users focus on sales via product roadmaps and feature specs.</p><p>Additionally, there are Training & Onboarding tools and more for marketing and product development.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:848px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:70.75%;"><img id="NQYFWdKEGUiZ9SuqavKCsk" name="google-notebooklm-customize-audio-overview-box.jpg" alt="NotebookLM picks up a "Customize" button for Audio Overviews." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NQYFWdKEGUiZ9SuqavKCsk.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="848" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google debuted <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/notebooklm-audio-overviews-radio-like-ai">Audio Overviews</a> in NotebookLM in mid-September. The application turns your scribbled notes/research into an audio file read aloud by AI. The feature delivers two AI "hosts," which makes it feel like you're listening to a radio talk show fueled by your research. Google states the AI hosts can summarize the provided material and "make connections" between subjects.</p><p>Users can add follow-up questions to these Audio Overviews and more. However, Google warns that the AI is prone to making mistakes (hallucinating), so it's best to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-notebooklm-limited-launch">backtrack its statements</a>.</p><p>What's more, Google reiterates the app's usage of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini-1-5-next-gen-ai-model">Gemini 1.5</a> model. Its performance is roughly 87% better than the original 1.0 model and its ability to deliver "relevant and useful" information has been enhanced.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/notebooklm-guide-ai-hosts-business-pilot-program</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google highlighted two new features for NotebookLM and introduced a Business variant of the app. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">pkC5vxPvdGEmTNgXRi9JEQ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zzPTyYHBTjqpoen3vuSttM.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 20:20:33 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zzPTyYHBTjqpoen3vuSttM.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google launches a customizable button for the AI hosts in NotebookLM.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google launches a customizable button for the AI hosts in NotebookLM.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Not everything has to be so scandalous. Or does it? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>If there is one thing Android users do better than anyone else, it's making a fuss over things that aren't really mysterious or misleading. Thanks to internet brand rivalry and one-sided loyalty to a company that doesn't even know you exist, every little thing can quickly become a scandal.</p><p>The latest example of this is that the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9">Pixel 9</a> (and every Pixel phone before it) doesn't support <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/text-message-exploits-are-scarier-than-ever-but-you-can-protect-yourself-with-these-tips">Android 15's stingray protections</a>. No, not the swimming, fishy kind of stingray; the small device designed to capture your SMS messages and phone calls.</p>
<p>The heart of the issue is that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/android-15-mobile-network-security-pixel-3490909/">these settings did appear in beta builds of Android 15</a> on the Pixel, even though they did nothing because the phone's hardware or configuration doesn't support it. When <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a> proper came around, they were gone. As they should have been because they are not supported.</p><p>That's it. Nothing more. Many phones don't support these features, but because the Pixel comes from Google, who worked on ways to fight this, some folks think there is some sort of conspiracy afoot or something. I don't work for Google, but I can assure you there isn't. When and if the feature can be supported, the settings will appear.</p>

<p>This is worth noting because if you are interested in the protections offered here, you should know which phones actually support them. If you're like everyone else who wasn't going to use them anyway, feel free to say "huh" and move on to the next thing without any guilt over not participating in the outrage. This is why beta builds exist — to catch mistakes like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://issuetracker.google.com/issues/335438231?pli=1">exposing an invalid setting before a product comes to market</a>. If not having this feature influences your buying decisions, don't buy a Pixel phone, and you're good.</p><p>There is something to think about here, though: what does phone security mean, and can complaining really make a difference?</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="N7Nvx7CVWYiToqZw8BHgM9" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-Plus-translate-messages-official-01.jpg" alt="An official Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus promo image showcasing the message translate feature" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/N7Nvx7CVWYiToqZw8BHgM9.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Samsung)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>For some people, being an active target of phone hacking is a valid concern. The rich, the famous, the leaders of the world, these folks have to worry about someone getting into their phones and digging for information they do not want to share. Smart people with these needs have a professional manage their communication devices and use hardened and/or strictly <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-phone-business/1000">locked down devices</a> that are a lot safer than the phone you bought off Amazon. Others need to depend that their phone has the latest patches against remote exploits and features like stingray protection.</p><p>Most likely, you don't fall into any of these groups and are like me: just an average person who still doesn't want anyone to see anything I don't want to share. Security is still important, but not in the same way and not for the same reasons. We need protection from ourselves.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="vBh9sfJXpxS7PQfMzmHdx5" name="google-pixel-9-vs-oneplus-12-15.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 9 vs. OnePlus 12 back view" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vBh9sfJXpxS7PQfMzmHdx5.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>For us, the most important part of a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-important-are-android-security-patches">security-focused patch or update</a> is the things that keep some random bit of code from doing things it shouldn't be allowed to do because we clicked OK on the wrong thing. Maybe we followed a link we shouldn't have, and something got downloaded. Maybe we installed an app that tries to do things it shouldn't. Maybe someone installed something when we weren't looking. This happens far more often than when foreign spies actively target our devices or SMS messages, but it can have the same result.</p><p>When the company that made your phone holds these security updates from you, and you get upset, that's a lot more productive than crying foul when a phone doesn't support a thing it was never advertised as supporting. Neither may make a difference because the companies involved rarely care about anything but profits, but our continued complaining might; even <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.motorola.com/we/smartphones-moto-g-75-5g/p?skuId=631">Motorola now sells phones</a> that get software support for six years or more.</p>
<p>Maybe being outraged is the right call. That's for you to decide, and I'll decide where to focus my displeasure. Complaining about a thing long enough can make a difference.</p><p>Just complain about the right thing — Pixel phones (and all phones) should support some security issue Google found important enough to make part of Android itself. A setting that was in beta software but missing from the release build is a different story.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-android-15-stingray-protection-support</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ It's easy to get caught up in the internet's collective outrage. But it's often not very productive. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">emSR6BnNFgrE8S6PdJuvRH</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dbHJ5cMcCGriMRdKQmMRsA.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 20:13:04 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dbHJ5cMcCGriMRdKQmMRsA.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9 Pro XL with Pixel 8 Pro and 7 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9 Pro XL with Pixel 8 Pro and 7 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>