<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 17:20:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ OnePlus 12R gains Magic Eraser look-alike with new OxygenOS 14 update ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>OnePlus is bringing OxygenOS 14.0.0.505 update for Indian OnePlus 12R users.</li><li>It brings an object/person removal tool similar to the OnePlus 11 and OnePlus 12.</li><li>The update is incremental, with a broader rollout expected in the next few days.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>OnePlus is rolling out a new April 2024 update for the OnePlus 12R for the Indian region. The changelog of the latest firmware indicates that it is bringing the unwanted object removal or people tool for the photos captured on the device.</p><p>In the accompanying <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://community.oneplus.com/thread/1568977884347891713">community post</a>, OnePlus shared the firmware details for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12r-review">OnePlus 12R</a>, dubbed <strong>OxygenOS 14.0.0.505</strong> version. It is currently rolling out to the Indian OnePlus 12R users in batches. The prominent aspect of the latest update is the AIGC Remover, which was earlier available for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12-review">OnePlus 12</a> and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-11-review">OnePlus 11</a> users.</p>
<p>The latest feature on the OnePlus 12R will allow users to "remove unwanted objects or people and make your photos look cleaner." It sounds and works very similar to Google&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-use-magic-eraser-non-pixel-phones">Magic Eraser</a> feature, which has been available for Pixel phones for a while now.</p><p>Meanwhile, OnePlus recently <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/oneplus-ai-eraser-launch">announced</a> a new Pixel-inspired AI feature dubbed AI Eraser, which lets users substitute unwanted objects in a photo. The AI Eraser is available for the company&apos;s prominent handsets, such as the OnePlus 11, OnePlus 12, OnePlus 12R, OnePlus Open, and the Nord CE 4.</p><p>The other highlights from the changelog comprise the ability to create photo collages without frames in photos. A new nifty shortcut has been added to turn on the flashlight by pressing the Volume Down rocker on the OnePlus 12R for a long time. Users can also adjust volumes for apps individually with a new "app-specific" feature added with the update.</p><p>There are several other improvements included with the latest update, which are per the changelog:</p>
<ul><li>Improves the volume bar's design for ease of use and visual consistency.</li><li>Improves the touch control experience in certain scenarios.</li><li>Improves the compatibility of USB connections between phones and cars, and phones and PCs.</li><li>Improves system stability.</li></ul>
<p>As mentioned, the rollout is incremental and for the Indian region. The broader rollout is expected in the next few days, notes OnePlus.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="d4e0e897-c2e3-42ab-b3ed-8b28bbb3e9f1">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ExtMRD6dRszoNepqSqcTfa.jpg' alt='OnePlus 12R with extra space '></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">OnePlus 12R</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Flagship killer</strong></em></p>
<p>OnePlus 12R comes as the toned-down version of the flagship OnePlus 12 and yet manages to retain some of its best features. Unfortunately, it doesn't support UFS 4.0, but users should still see impressive storage speeds with UFS 3.1.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/oneplus-12r-gets-magic-eraser-tool-dubbed-aigc-remover</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The new OxygenOS update also brings several other improvements next to system-wide stability. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">SpzFfmCEJfL2MjUimvmD3T</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HDg3LYUxQPgBDabAab4t2T.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 16:45:04 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HDg3LYUxQPgBDabAab4t2T.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus 12R review]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus 12R review]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung launches Galaxy Tab S6 Lite, mid-range tablet for the US ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The Galaxy Tab S6 Lite (2024) Wi-Fi model debuts into the U.S. market.</li><li>The tablet was previously launched globally and is now available in the U.S. starting at $329.</li><li>Exynos 1280 SoC powers the new Galaxy Tab S6 Lite model.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Samsung is bringing the Galaxy Tab S6 Lite (2024) model to the U.S. for $329, according to a spotted new Amazon US listing.</p><p>The new tablet from Samsung, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Android-Included-Speakers-Exclusive/dp/B0CWS8MNW1?th=1&linkCode=sl1&tag=schoon0f-20&linkId=f4c5510b58649cffbf16c6798ae4d4a7&language=en_US&ref_=as_li_ss_tl">already listed</a> on Amazon US (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/04/08/samsung-galaxy-tab-s6-lite-2024-us-amazon-price/#more-613640">9to5Google</a>) and has two storage options: a 64GB one and a 128GB variant. Both models, however, have only 4GB of RAM. The device seems to be an Amazon Exclusive for the American market, as the listing’s description implies.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 1</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="SZinsW6C9yRE9PcE3qiMx7" name="samsung-galaxy-tab-s6-lite-review-12.jpeg" alt="Samsung Galaxy Tab S6 Lite Review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SZinsW6C9yRE9PcE3qiMx7.jpeg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1536" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="caption-text">Samsung Galaxy Tab S6 Lite Review </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Joe Maring / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>While the base variant of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-android-tablet">cheaper Android tablet</a> is priced at $329, the larger 128GB variant retails at $399. The available colorways are Oxford Gray, Chiffon Pink, and Mint. The device appears to be shipping right away if interested buyers are subscribed to Amazon Prime.</p><p>The Galaxy Tab S6 Lite (2024) launched in some global markets late last month as a minor refresh to the 2020 model, which came under the same moniker. Both models appear identical in design, and most of the specs are the same except for the chipset.</p><p>The new model ships with Samsung’s in-house developed Exynos 1280 processor with 2.4GHz clock speeds — the same one that powered the mid-range <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/samsung-galaxy-a53-5g-review">Galaxy A53 5G</a> handset. </p>
<p>The tablet&apos;s highlights include a 10.4-inch screen—a WUXGA Plus display with a 2000 x 1200 resolution. It supports microSD expansion up to 1TB, a massive 7040mAh battery capacity with a promise of 14-hour non-stop video playback, and Dolby Atmos-certified speakers. For optics, the tablet relies on a single 8MP rear camera shooter and a 5MP for selfies.</p><p>The device is also accompanied by an S-Pen for productivity, which includes the ability to take notes while the tablet screen is locked and support for Samsung DeX. The device also comprises two models: a Wi-Fi-only model and an LTE variant, but the Amazon above listing doesn’t mention the LTE variant.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Tablet deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/ipad-tablets-ereaders/tablets/pcmcat209000050008.c?id=pcmcat209000050008"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/search?q=tablet"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/tablets-laptops-computers-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=tablet&crid=2HCFROTF588S1&sprefix=tablet%2Caps%2C159&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.dell.com/en-us/search/tablet"><u><strong>Dell</strong></u></a><strong> |</strong></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/samsung-brings-galaxy-tab-s6-lite-2024-to-the-us</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung has refreshed its cheaper Android tablet this year, after launching it back in 2022. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Pky6nP3jMgNnQsxJ4hgd9h</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Wsz292gmpAdy25ceMPiqgU.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 16:07:02 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Wsz292gmpAdy25ceMPiqgU.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[91mobiles]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Galaxy Tab S6 Lite (2024) in Mint]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Galaxy Tab S6 Lite (2024) in Mint]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google unveils a new custom chip to supercharge tasks like search and AI ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google introduces Axion, a powerful chip designed for data centers, capable of handling various tasks including Google searches and AI operations.</li><li>Axion is Google's first custom Arm-based CPU for data centers, promising to provide significant performance improvements over current cloud tools.</li><li>Google plans to offer virtual machines powered by Axion processors to customers in the coming months.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google has <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/compute/introducing-googles-new-arm-based-cpu" target="_blank">introduced</a> a brand new chip called Axion for data centers, and it&apos;s touted to be capable of handling everything from Google searches to AI tasks.</p><p>Axion is Google&apos;s first custom Arm-based CPU for data centers, built using Arm&apos;s Neoverse V2 CPU platform. Axion will be the muscle behind all sorts of things you use every day, like Google searches and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-is-reportedly-weighing-making-search-generative-experience-a-paid-feature">AI-powered tasks</a>.</p><p>Google says Axion knocks it out of the park, crushing current Arm-based cloud tools by 30% and leaving even the latest x86-based virtual machines (VMs) in the dust, with a 50% performance boost. Plus, it sips power more efficiently, saving 60% compared to those old x86 VMs.</p><p>The Mountain View-based tech giant is using the same circuitry built by Arm as Amazon and Microsoft to design the Axion chip. That makes Google the third big tech company to jump on board with this framework, as reported by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.wsj.com/tech/google-expands-in-house-chip-efforts-in-costly-ai-battle-3121c852" target="_blank">The Wall Street Journal</a>.</p><p>Google says it has already put Axion to work internally, running first-party services such as BigTable, Spanner, BigQuery, Blobstore, Pub/Sub, Google Earth Engine, and the YouTube Ads platform on Google Cloud. And it plans to keep ramping up its use in the future.</p><p>Google plans to give us a sneak peek at virtual machines powered by Axion processors in the next few months. Later this year, Axion will be up for grabs for all Google Cloud customers.</p><p>To set the record straight, the company is not going to sell Axion chips directly to customers. Instead, it&apos;ll let you rent access to this custom hardware.</p><p>Google has been designing its own chips for a while now, mostly for the Pixel phones (like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-pixel-6">Pixel 6</a>) to make them faster and better. The company also makes special chips called "Tensor Processing Unit" (TPU) to help run its data centers, since way back in 2015.</p><p>There are a couple reasons why Google built Axion. First, it wants to be less reliant on other companies for parts, as per WSJ. Second, it lets the company compete better with cloud giants like Amazon and Microsoft, which are also building their own superchips. Basically, it&apos;s an arms race for faster and more efficient cloud services.</p><p>Google is betting big on its new Axion chip to handle the ever-growing need for computing power, especially for AI services.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google/google-unveils-update-to-ai-chip</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google unveiled Axion, its new chip for data centers and the first one built based on Arm technology. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">YzkmF83GoaoVPKZVpkmFqV</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rndDsNbSySJFMhwDXetJ9.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 15:23:24 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rndDsNbSySJFMhwDXetJ9.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Made by Google logo]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Made by Google logo]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ How to use Dual Audio on a Samsung phone ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Dual audio on your Samsung devices lets you share the wealth, music-wise, by allowing you to simultaneously share audio to two earphones or speakers. You can also control the volume from an easy-to-access area so that both devices have the volume of audio you want.</p><p>Whether the earbuds you share your music with are among the best<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-spatial-audio-earbuds"> that support spatial audio</a> or not, you&apos;ll find the helpful feature. Those days of giving your friend one of the earbuds are long gone.</p>
<h2 id="what-is-samsung-dual-audio-2">What is Samsung Dual Audio?</h2>
<p>Samsung Dual Audio lets you connect your Galaxy phone to two Bluetooth headphones simultaneously. This feature is useful when hiking with friends and both want to hear the same music. You and your friend can listen to the same Spotify music list, and you can even control <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-control-spotify-music-from-strava-app">it from the Strava app</a> if you like.</p>
<h2 id="how-do-i-use-dual-audio-on-my-samsung-2">How do I use Dual Audio on my Samsung?</h2>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> The Dual Audio feature won&apos;t work on all <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-samsung-phones">Samsung Galaxy phones</a>. During my testing using a Galaxy A series phone, it was not available. It was not until I switched to an S series Galaxy phone that it became available. If you follow the steps but can&apos;t access Dual Audio, your Galaxy phone will not support it.</p><p>To start using Dual Audio, you must pair your first earbuds.</p><p>1. Go to <strong>Settings</strong>.</p><p>2. Select <strong>Connections</strong>.</p><p>3. Choose <strong>Bluetooth</strong> and toggle it on. Make sure that the earbuds you want to pair are also on. You can also swipe down from the top of your display, long-press on the Bluetooth icon, and look for the earbuds in the Searching for Devices section. You can also choose from the devices that have been paired already.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1578px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:101.39%;"><img id="rNFtYS6STZ7wbGQyufBsqb" name="Galaxy-Dual-Audio.jpg" alt="Pairing Bluetooth devices in Galaxy settings" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rNFtYS6STZ7wbGQyufBsqb.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1578" height="1600" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Judy Sanhz / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>4. You must <strong>pair two sets of earbuds</strong>. Don&apos;t worry about losing the connection for the first set of earbuds when pairing the second. The first connection will remain when you pair the second set of earbuds.</p><p>5. Once paired, <strong>swipe down</strong> from the <strong>top of your display</strong> and tap on <strong>Media Output</strong>. You can also try swiping down twice to check if the option appears.</p><p>6. When you see the <strong>two earbuds</strong> you paired, <strong>select them</strong>.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1578px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:101.39%;"><img id="2KNNTYYGgoL7Vbmhtco84G" name="Galaxy-Dual-Audio-Options.jpg" alt="Pairing earbuds in Galaxy phone with Dual Audio" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2KNNTYYGgoL7Vbmhtco84G.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1578" height="1600" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Judy Sanhz / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>You can use any brand of Bluetooth speakers or earbuds to use the feature. As you can see in the image above, you can control the volume for both devices from the same area. You also have the option of the volume buttons as usual. If you ever want to go back to only listening to music from one device, all you need to do is deselect one of the devices.</p><p>There could be a slight lag when using Dual Audio, but hopefully, it won&apos;t be much of a problem.</p>
<h2 id="which-samsung-phones-have-dual-audio-2">Which Samsung phones have Dual Audio?</h2>
<p>Bluetooth 5.0 or higher is a requirement, but even then you won&apos;t find Dual Audio on every Samsung Galaxy. It is available on the latest S series, such as the Samsung Galaxy S24, S24 Plus, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review">S24 Ultra</a>. The latest Galaxy Tabs S6, S7, S8 and the Galaxy Z Flip 5 and below will come with the helpful feature.</p><p>You may not always want to have your music come from two devices. For those times when you only want to change your device&apos;s audio output to a single device, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-change-the-audio-output-on-android">these are the steps you need to follow</a>.</p>
<h2 id="two-is-better-than-one-2">Two is better than one</h2>
<p>The Dual Audio feature is a huge help. You could watch a movie, and a friend wants to listen to it. Now, you can pair their earbuds with your phone so they can listen in, and you can continue to enjoy the stereo sound of your earbuds, whether they are one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-samsung-earbuds">best Samsung earbuds</a> or not.</p><p>To ensure you always enjoy the latest features Samsung or any manufacturer has to offer, always have your apps and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-better-at-updates-than-google">Samsung device updated</a>. The Dual Audio feature is a must-have, and we only hope it gets better and more accessible with time. The more devices you can share your audio with, the better, right?</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="389bd487-bb4a-42b8-bb93-25abe406ab4b">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/us5uBzbMSjqWPB8urvEEEf.jpg' alt='Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="90" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Dual Audio and more</strong></em></p>
<p>The Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra not only offers Dual Audio, but other fantastic features such as the massive 5,000mAh battery and an amazing 6.8-inch AMOLED display. You'll become a multitasking champ with this model thanks to the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 processor.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-use-dual-audio-on-a-samsung-phone</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ With Dual Audio on your Galaxy phone, you can share your music with others by following a few simple steps. But does the feature work with all Samsung devices? ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">KJ5aBNYpnye3mZM77YMD4R</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bGxWkGFnuWxJKEb7dKTsFi.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 14:56:27 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ judysanhz30@gmail.com (Judy Sanhz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bGxWkGFnuWxJKEb7dKTsFi.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Judy Sanhz / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Dual Audio feature on a Galaxy phone with two Bluetooth devices selected]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Dual Audio feature on a Galaxy phone with two Bluetooth devices selected]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Best wireless headphones under $100 in 2024 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Quick menu</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="TpSJCMnpMUMsYEUPJbwDWk" name="Soundcore-by-Anker-Life-Q30-lifestyle.jpg" caption="" alt="Lifestyle shot of Anker Soundcore Life Q30." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TpSJCMnpMUMsYEUPJbwDWk.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Anker)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text"><strong>1.</strong> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones-under-100#section-at-a-glance">At a glance</a><br>
<strong>2.</strong> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones-under-100#section-best-overall">Best overall</a><br>
<strong>3.</strong> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones-under-100#section-best-true-wireless">Best true wireless</a><br>
<strong>4.</strong> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones-under-100#section-best-value">Best value</a><br>
<strong>5.</strong> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones-under-100#section-best-workout-buds">Best workout buds</a><br>
<strong>6.</strong> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones-under-100#section-best-on-ear">Best on-ear</a><br>
<strong>7.</strong> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones-under-100#section-best-neckbuds">Best neckbuds</a><br>
<strong>8.</strong> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones-under-100#section-best-battery-life">Best battery life</a></p></div></div>
<p>If there&apos;s one thing the best wireless headphones under $100 prove, it&apos;s that you don&apos;t have to shell out hundreds of dollars on premium audio gear to enjoy listening to your music. Sure, you might miss out on a few nice-to-have features but for the most part, these affordable options come with all the essentials such as Active Noise Cancelation (ANC), app-based customization, and much more.</p><p>What&apos;s even better is that if you don&apos;t like traditional headphones, there are a lot of true wireless earbuds and even neckbuds to choose from. Our top vote goes to the Anker Soundcore Life Q30, a pair of headphones that offer amazing sound quality, long battery life, and ANC at an excellent price. If you&apos;d rather prefer true wireless earbuds, we suggest the Anker Soundcore Life P3. These come with a balanced soundstage, offer a comfortable fit, and have a case with wireless charging support.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-at-a-glance"><span>At a glance</span></h3>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="787004cb-cb82-4f31-993b-52e16fe109db">
            <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones-under-100#section-best-overall" data-model-name="Anker Soundcore Life Q30"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PCGW7wibHhZphyAKXiwjgK.jpg' alt='anker soundcore life q30 render 400x500'><span class='featured__label hero__label'>Best overall</span></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">1. Anker Soundcore Life Q30</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="80" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>Featuring an improved design and great build quality, the Anker Soundcore Life Q30 headphones are comfortable enough to be used for long periods of time. This is important too, considering they can go for up to an amazing 40 hours on a full charge.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones-under-100#section-best-overall"><em><strong>Read more below.</strong></em></a></p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="dc7c0cec-5a55-4275-8107-9913162d913f">
            <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones-under-100#section-best-true-wireless" data-model-name="Anker Soundcore Life P3"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3zEtaLeHSyeT34K8wTwdpQ.jpg' alt='anker soundcore life p3 render 400x500'><span class='featured__label hero__label'>Best true wireless</span></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">2. Anker Soundcore Life P3</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="80" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>With a balanced overall sound signature, the Anker Soundcore Life P3 offer everything from good battery life to a comfortable fit. These true wireless earbuds can last up to six hours on a full charge with ANC enabled and can be charged both wired and wirelessly when in the case.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones-under-100#section-best-true-wireless"><em><strong>Read more below.</strong></em></a></p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="b5e11730-2c07-4d4e-ae56-76af7cc9f539">
            <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones-under-100#section-best-value" data-model-name="Creative Zen Hybrid"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZMqrqUqwCaxuGuaxoSHwaa.jpg' alt='creative zen hybrid render 400x500'><span class='featured__label hero__label'>Best value</span></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">3. Creative Zen Hybrid</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="70" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>Offering solid ANC performance, the Creative Zen Hybrid come with custom-tuned 40mm neodymium drivers to give you high-quality sound. The headphones can be folded in multiple ways and can have a battery life of up to 27 hours with ANC enabled.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones-under-100#section-best-value"><em><strong>Read more below.</strong></em></a></p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="fc59c8d6-fe46-4613-b8ed-b173aeca5b7d">
            <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones-under-100#section-best-workout-buds" data-model-name="JLab Audio Epic Air Sport ANC"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XAyQskXsvEbcHZqncP5MCh.jpg' alt='jlab audio epic air sport anc render 400x500'><span class='featured__label hero__label'>Best workout buds</span></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">4. JLab Audio Epic Air Sport ANC</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="80" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>The JLab Audio Epic Air Sport ANC are the ideal companion for your active lifestyle. True to their name, these wireless earbuds have an epic battery life of up to ten hours with ANC on. You get a fairly balanced overall soundstage and the IP66 rating allows them to be used when you're sweating in the gym.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones-under-100#section-best-workout-buds"><em><strong>Read more below.</strong></em></a></p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="c5d4a1d4-ec1e-446d-875b-385e9b171baa">
            <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones-under-100#section-best-on-ear" data-model-name="Jabra Elite 45h"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ymfYUnTUyGQRzacCDLogxm.jpg' alt='jabra elite 45h render 400x500'><span class='featured__label hero__label'>Best on-ear</span></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">5. Jabra Elite 45h</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="80" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>With ear cushions made from memory foam, the Jabra Elite 45h can be worn all day without any issues. These headphones are lightweight and can be folded for easier storage and portability. You also get two-mic technology for better calls, voice assistant support, and a battery life of up to 50 hours.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones-under-100#section-best-on-ear"><em><strong>Read more below.</strong></em></a></p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="bbca768e-dbe5-4c45-b5b2-b5aebebd29db">
            <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones-under-100#section-best-neckbuds" data-model-name="Beats Flex Wireless"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ujyTk7pyLx4Tzf3Y2H7kqB.jpg' alt='beats flex wireless render 400x500'><span class='featured__label hero__label'>Best neckbuds</span></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">6. Beats Flex Wireless</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="70" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>The Beats Flex Wireless have a vibrant soundstage, even if they focus a little more on bass. These lightweight neckbuds feature in-line controls for all major functions and have a battery life of up to 12 hours on a single charge. You also have four colorways to choose from.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones-under-100#section-best-neckbuds"><em><strong>Read more below.</strong></em></a></p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<div class="collapsible-block-start"></div><div class="collapsible-block-title"load-the-next-1-product"><p>Load the next 1 product ↴</p></div>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="ddb1db67-4ace-4b29-b461-1d5106825293">
            <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones-under-100#section-best-battery-life" data-model-name="1MORE SonoFlow"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/aQvhYo3ZaXcc7y6MvrEoNG.jpg' alt='1more sonoflow render 400x500'><span class='featured__label hero__label'>Best battery life</span></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">7. 1More SonoFlow</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="80" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>The 1More SonoFlow are certified for Hi-Res Audio and Hi-Res Audio Wireless, and support LDAC for a top-tier music listening experience. The headphones can be simultaneously connected to two devices and have a battery life of up to 50 hours on a full charge with ANC enabled.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones-under-100#section-best-battery-life"><em><strong>Read more below.</strong></em></a></p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<div class="collapsible-block-end"></div>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-best-overall"><span>Best overall</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="WfBwsPT7D537tiamkJpDZ8" name="Anker-Soundcore-Q30-wearing-2.jpg" alt="Wearing the Anker Soundcore Life Q30." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WfBwsPT7D537tiamkJpDZ8.jpg" mos="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bC4FwxxctEXJVt6WgPptSo.jpg" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1500" height="844" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ted Kritsonis / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<div class="buying-guide-block"><h3 id="1-anker-soundcore-life-q30-2"><span class="title__text"><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/anker-soundcore-q30-review">1. Anker Soundcore Life Q30</a></span><span class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span></span></h3><div class="_hawk subtitle"><p>Best overall</p></div><p class="specs__container"></p><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Superb audio quality</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Outstanding battery life</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Better build this time</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Great companion app</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">ANC support</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">Limited touch controls</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">Bulky design</div></div>
<p>Need long battery life? We got plenty when we reviewed the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/anker-soundcore-q30-review" target="_blank">Anker Soundcore Life Q30</a>, so you can expect up to 40 hours of playback while ANC is enabled, with that number going up to a ridiculous 60 hours when ANC is off. That&apos;s impressive for a pair of budget headphones and adding USB-C now makes fast charging possible. Plug in for five minutes and get four hours of playtime.</p><p>That kind of long battery life makes comfort a more significant factor, and thankfully, Anker delivers there. It has improved the design and materials from the previous iteration, with a nice headband with deep and wide ear cups to accommodate even the biggest ears. That combination makes longer listening periods a lot easier on your head and ears. It also means they deliver better passive noise isolation and effective ANC.</p><p>The ANC is still best at dealing with higher-frequency sounds, with minimal improvement in handling lower-frequency ones. Usually, it&apos;s the opposite, especially at this price range, which makes these unique. If you live with screaming kids, you might appreciate the help. You also get three distinct settings on the app as well.</p><p>Still, sound quality is excellent for the price, thanks to a lively soundstage out of the box that doesn&apos;t skew too far one way or the other. If you want bass, you can get even more of it through the great Soundcore app that includes a customizable equalizer and over 20 presets. It changes the overall sound to find a combination that better suits your ears.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-best-true-wireless"><span>Best true wireless</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="kQXGht6KpfXDMRUbf2r4EF" name="Anker-Soundcore-Life-P3-wearing.jpg" alt="Wearing the Anker Soundcore Life P3." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kQXGht6KpfXDMRUbf2r4EF.jpg" mos="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SyMi8aZTmnqiakgGKdwPsn.jpg" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ted Kritsonis / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<div class="buying-guide-block"><h3 id="2-anker-soundcore-life-p3-2"><span class="title__text"><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/anker-soundcore-life-p3-review">2. Anker Soundcore Life P3</a></span><span class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span></span></h3><div class="_hawk subtitle"><p>Best true wireless</p></div><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Good sound quality</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Surprising ANC performance</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Pretty comfortable fit</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Solid app support</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Wireless charging support</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">Weaker mid-range sound</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">Not especially durable</div></div>
<p>Although <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-earbuds" target="_blank">wireless earbuds</a> often get the most attention at the higher end of the pricing bracket, good ones are now easier than ever to find on a budget as well. The Anker Soundcore Life P3 stand firmly in that category with a nicely balanced sound signature. You will hear bass punch through with a slight boost to the highs, and fairly consistent mids for exceptional performance.</p><p>The comfortable design is helpful, but you need to get a good seal to get everything the sound can offer you. That way, you can hear more of what the larger drivers inside are capable of delivering, which is impressive at this price. It doesn&apos;t hurt that there&apos;s ANC onboard, with a pretty effective ambient mode to work with when you need to hear the background around you.</p><p>Make good use of the Soundcore app and the deep equalizer to change how these earbuds sound. Bluetooth connections are pretty sturdy for phone calls on top of that. The IPX5 rating isn&apos;t especially rugged, so these are maybe not the ideal pair to work out with, but they&apos;re not super fragile, either.</p><p>Battery life is OK at up to six hours with ANC on (seven when off) and another three full charges in the case to keep the music playing for a reasonable amount of time. An extra perk is wireless charging support.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-best-value"><span>Best value</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.30%;"><img id="is4okhdypYD4QZ2BbZtoE9" name="Creative-Zen-Hybrid-lifestyle.jpg" alt="Creative Zen Hybrid headphones lifestyle on train." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/is4okhdypYD4QZ2BbZtoE9.jpg" mos="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pP7bYY9hcV8eKtsYa785vE.jpg" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1080" height="608" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Creative)</span></figcaption></figure>
<div class="buying-guide-block"><h3 id="3-creative-zen-hybrid-2"><span class="title__text">3. Creative Zen Hybrid</span><span class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span></span></h3><div class="_hawk subtitle"><p>Best value</p></div><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Great audio quality</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Good ANC performance for the price</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Long battery life</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Great comfort</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Wired playback if you like</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">Limited Bluetooth codec support</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">SXFI limited to downloaded files</div></div>
<p>Creative has a real knack for delivering great value for the dollar, and the Zen Hybrid over-ears follow the trend. For well under $100, you get solid audio quality with a nice mix of highs, mids, and bass. Sadly, you can&apos;t tailor the audio in the Creative app, and Bluetooth codecs are also limited to SBC and AAC, so you won&apos;t be able to enjoy hi-res audio. The SXFI spatial audio technology only works on audio files you have downloaded on your phone or tablet, so you won&apos;t get all the audio goodies without some caveats, but there are other features to enjoy.</p><p>ANC performance should meet your measured expectations for more affordable headphones, which is to say that it will muffle background sounds without heavily dampening lower or higher frequencies. The headphones feel comfortable to wear for longer periods of time and since they also fold up, you can take them with you on a commute or trip without issues.</p><p>Battery life holds up well at up to 27 hours per charge with ANC turned on, and up to 37 hours with it turned off. If you feel like going old school with a wired connection, plug in the included 3.5mm line-in cable to listen that way — assuming you have an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-usb-c-headphone-adapter" target="_blank">adapter for the USB-C port</a> on your phone. </p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-best-workout-buds"><span>Best workout buds</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.20%;"><img id="DSECdE9StJGQAHbzW6AEQ4" name="JLab-Epic-Air-Sport-ANC-wear-ear.jpg" alt="Close up view of JLab Epic Air Sport ANC." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DSECdE9StJGQAHbzW6AEQ4.jpg" mos="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uQL8z8zCVyMCvbShUEvpX5.jpg" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1151" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ted Kritsonis / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<div class="buying-guide-block"><h3 id="4-jlab-audio-epic-air-sport-anc-2"><span class="title__text"><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/jlab-epic-air-sport-anc-review">4. JLab Audio Epic Air Sport ANC</a></span><span class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span></span></h3><div class="_hawk subtitle"><p>Best workout buds</p></div><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Solid audio quality</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">IP66 sweat resistance</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Excellent app support</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Long battery life for workouts</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">ANC and ambient modes</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">Don&apos;t swim with them</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">Bulkier design may not be for everyone</div></div>
<p>JLab Audio has been making workout earbuds for some time now, and the Epic Air Sport ANC earbuds are among its latest pair made to use routinely while breaking a sweat — <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/jlab-epic-air-sport-anc-review" target="_blank">something we noticed when we reviewed them</a>, too. The IP66 rating gives them enough ruggedness to work out or go on a run in such scenarios. However, they&apos;re not made to be waterproof, so you need to be careful around water.</p><p>The combination of ear hooks and six pairs of ear tips make these comfortable and stable enough to stay in your ears, provided you don&apos;t mind a little extra bulk in size. What&apos;s cool is that JLab also changes things up with the tips, so you get different sizes, lengths and materials, including foam. A good passive seal always helps, though you do have ANC support to block out background noise when you need to. If you need to hear your surroundings, you can also use the Be Aware mode.</p><p>The default soundstage is mostly balanced, with bass getting an extra boost, which is par for the course for a pair of JLab earbuds. If you&apos;re not feeling that, you can easily change it via JLab&apos;s smartphone app, which offers a nice mix of ANC controls and an equalizer to customize the sound.</p><p>JLab claims up to 15 hours of battery life per charge, which is really high, though that number is relative because it applies when ANC is off. Keep it on, and that number goes down to about 10 hours. Raise the volume, and it drops down further, but it&apos;s still a very respectable figure. Interestingly, the USB-A charging cable is built into the case, though you can also use wireless charging.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-best-on-ear"><span>Best on-ear</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:961px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.19%;"><img id="pP4kpF9bBuAWYnMEAFDsXN" name="jabra elite 45h lifestyle image official.jpg" alt="jabra elite 45h lifestyle image official" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pP4kpF9bBuAWYnMEAFDsXN.jpg" mos="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PecfjzYJKmutiQsmef52JC.jpg" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="961" height="540" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Jabra)</span></figcaption></figure>
<div class="buying-guide-block"><h3 id="5-jabra-elite-45h-2"><span class="title__text">5. Jabra Elite 45h</span><span class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span></span></h3><div class="_hawk subtitle"><p>Best on-ear</p></div><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Great sound quality</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Lightweight design</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Premium build materials</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Outstanding battery life</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Solid app support</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">Call quality isn't good enough</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">Ho-hum aesthetics</div></div>
<p>On-ear headphones aren&apos;t as common or popular as over-the-ear cans, but they are lighter and easier to wear in most cases. On the other hand, they won&apos;t give you too much in the way of passive noise isolation, allowing you to hear what&apos;s happening around you. Jabra didn&apos;t make the Elite 45h fancy on the outside, but it&apos;s what&apos;s on the inside that counts.</p><p>The Jabra Elite 45h headphones play it safe by default with a balanced and neutral soundstage, but the sound quality is still superb. You can tweak it more to your liking through Jabra&apos;s Sound+ app and its equalizer, which gives you existing presets or the ability to create your own. Unfortunately, phone call quality doesn&apos;t follow suit, and that might be because the two-mic array needed a third one to amplify your voice. It&apos;s one of the trade-offs of a product in this price range.</p><p>Battery life hits crazy levels if you listen to the default volume throughout the day. It&apos;s the only way you&apos;ll get to 50 hours but even if you were to raise it, you&apos;d still be getting north of 30 hours without blinking an eye. On top of that, Jabra has included a modern USB-C port with them for convenient charging.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-best-neckbuds"><span>Best neckbuds</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1707px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="tPRmUbjdAcqUFom6zJLHUo" name="Beats-Flex-Wireless-neckband-headphones-lifestyle.jpg" alt="Beats Flex Wireless headphones lifestyle." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tPRmUbjdAcqUFom6zJLHUo.jpg" mos="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gyHbhb2ka9kec57pzk6znX.jpg" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1707" height="960" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Beats)</span></figcaption></figure>
<div class="buying-guide-block"><h3 id="6-beats-flex-wireless-2"><span class="title__text">6. Beats Flex Wireless</span><span class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span></span></h3><div class="_hawk subtitle"><p>Best neckbuds</p></div><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Good sound quality</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Comfortable fit</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Decent battery life</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Multipoint support</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Four funky color options</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">No ANC support</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">No IP protection</div></div>
<p>Even though <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-neckband-headphones-under-100" target="_blank">neckband earbuds</a> aren&apos;t that common these days, you can still find good options like the Beats Flex Wireless. It might be easy to pass on them if you&apos;re an Android user, especially since you can&apos;t derive any benefits from Apple&apos;s W1 chip that they come with but look a little closer, and they may be worth a look. The key is the Beats app, which enables faster pairing, access to settings, and even firmware updates.</p><p>Per their reputation, the Beats Flex Wireless offer plenty of bass if you&apos;re looking for it, with a vibrant soundstage that at least gives some life to the highs and the mids. Lightweight and easy to manage, you can wear them for leisure, but be careful when it comes to workouts because there is no IP protection here. There&apos;s also no ANC on board. The good news, however, is that the two ends connect with magnets, which is super convenient for those times when you&apos;re taking a break from listening to tunes.</p><p>The neckbuds support multi-point pairing with up to two devices at the same time, like your phone and computer, for example. Listen to audio coming from your PC while picking up a phone call whenever it comes in — a switch that happens on its own. if you need Google Assistant, press the button on the neckband to wake it up and get the voice assistant talking. Also, you get up to 12 hours of battery life, based on volume levels.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-best-battery-life"><span>Best battery life</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1200px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="GQtspRQxb2QquFPUQ8LqEK" name="1More-SonoFlow-headphones-close.jpg" alt="Closer view of man wearing 1More SonoFlow headphones." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GQtspRQxb2QquFPUQ8LqEK.jpg" mos="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8gpii8h9ZebZK5r9AJQ5sf.jpg" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1200" height="675" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: 1More)</span></figcaption></figure>
<div class="buying-guide-block"><h3 id="7-1more-sonoflow-2"><span class="title__text">7. 1More SonoFlow</span><span class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span></span></h3><div class="_hawk subtitle"><p>Best battery life</p></div><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Great sound quality</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Excellent ANC performance</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Comfortable fit</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Solid app support</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Really long battery life</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">No aptX, if you&apos;re looking for that</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">Wired mode cuts out all features</div></div>
<p>1More usually comes up with pleasant surprises at budget-friendly prices, and the SonoFlow headphones are no different. These headphones can play up to a whopping 70 hours at their default volume with ANC off; with it on, you can still get an amazing 50 hours of use on a full charge. That&apos;s enough to listen to your music for weeks before having to charge these up again. And when you have to, plug in for five minutes, and you&apos;ll get up to five hours of playback, depending on volume levels.</p><p>The good news here is that they also sound good for all that time you&apos;re listening to them. That&apos;s in part because the 1More SonoFlow generously support Sony&apos;s LDAC codec for hi-res audio, in case you want that kind of flexibility. Once you get into the 1More Music app, you can tweak the sound even further using the equalizer.</p><p>ANC is fantastic for the price, drowning out noise in ways that remind you of what a bargain these cans are. That&apos;s great, considering how comfortable they are to wear for longer periods of time. Plus, they fold up and come with a protective case.</p>
<ul><li><a href="#main"><strong>Back to the top ^</strong></a></li></ul>
<h2 id="good-sound-doesn-apos-t-have-to-cost-you-a-fortune-2">Good sound doesn&apos;t have to cost you a fortune</h2>
<p>There are <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones" target="_blank">plenty of worthy headphones</a> out there that won&apos;t break the bank and as you can see from the list above, the best wireless headphones under $100 come in a variety of shapes and sizes. Our top pick — the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/anker-soundcore-q30-review" target="_blank">Anker Soundcore Life Q30</a> — have the right balance of sound quality and battery life. You can also take a look at the Anker Soundcore Life P3 if you want great sound in a more compact package.</p><p>The timing couldn&apos;t be better, either. Headphones aren&apos;t just on the premium side, especially when there&apos;s plenty to like in the affordable category. They also come in different types, be they over-ear, on-ear, or wireless earbuds. With this list, there are many choices for you to consider.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones-under-100</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ With one of the best wireless headphones under $100, you can elevate your music listening experience without having to fork out hundreds of dollars. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">yWfKo67CRn4ixWmCv96Hj</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TpSJCMnpMUMsYEUPJbwDWk.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 14:46:05 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Headphones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ ted@byteddyk.com (Ted Kritsonis) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TpSJCMnpMUMsYEUPJbwDWk.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Daniel Bader / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus Bullets WIreless 2]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus Bullets WIreless 2]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google app is already revealing the Pixel 9's setup animation and files ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A beta version of the Google app includes code and files related to the unreleased Google Pixel 9 series.</li><li>One file represents the Pixel 9's setup animation, which is new but does not reveal much about the new phones. </li><li>Another is related to a digital assistant, though it notably does not reference the rumored "Pixie" assistant that may debut alongside the Pixel 9 series.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>There are a handful of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9">Google Pixel 9</a> leaks making rounds, and even more concerning the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/alleged-google-pixel-8a-cases-hands-on">Pixel 8a</a> that could launch as early as next month. However, it&apos;s rare that we get something straight from the source. While it&apos;s not much, a new beta version of the Google app reveals that the company is actively making preparations for the Pixel 9 series. There are still a lot of unknowns surrounding the smartphone lineup, but this latest leak confirms the Pixel 9 naming scheme, at the very least.</p><p>Android code sleuth <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://twitter.com/AssembleDebug/status/1777414041079796063" target="_blank">AssembleDebug on X</a> noticed a few files in beta version <strong>15.14.34.29.arm64</strong> of the Google app that are directly related to the Pixel 9. These files are connected to the Google Assistant setup process, which comes from the Google app. This explains why the beta version of the Google app is the software that contains references to the Pixel 9, rather than just an unreleased Android version. There is some added significance to the Assistant setup process on the Pixel 9 since it was previously reported that the smartphone might <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-pixie-pixel-9-report">feature a new "Pixie" digital assistant</a>.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Google App is preparing support for the upcoming Google Pixel 9 Read - https://t.co/tbzO3dmvsc#Google #Android #Pixels #Pixel9 pic.twitter.com/5oda2XcQkg<a href="https://twitter.com/AssembleDebug/status/1777414041079796063">April 8, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>There are two files included in the Google app beta, per AssembleDebug, that are related to the Google Pixel 9:</p>
<ul><li>assistant_robin_suw_pixel9_fragment.xml</li><li>assistant_robin_suw_pixel9.json</li></ul>
<p>The tipster explains that the first file is likely the Google Assistant setup wizard for the Pixel 9 or the Assistant setup page directly. The second file is the setup animation, which features generic Google icons and design language. Aside from the file names, there isn&apos;t much to indicate that these assets are related to the Pixel 9. Still, it&apos;s the first indirect reference to the Pixel 9&apos;s existence from Google, and it comes months ahead of the lineup&apos;s expected launch.</p><p>So far, there are also no references to the rumored Pixie assistant. Pixie, which could be an internal codename, is said to be a more powerful version of the Google Assistant leveraging on-device data and AI. Google appears to be moving away from the Google Assistant entirely, removing features in recent months and requiring Gemini users to replace Assistant on their phones. One theory is that Gemini isn&apos;t the thing that will replace Assistant once and for all — but another software feature will. </p><p>The Google Pixel 9 series is probably months away from an official launch, as Google usually unveils these phones in the fall. However, these references to the Pixel 9 in beta versions of the Google app are just the start. Rumors and leaks surrounding Google&apos;s next generation of flagship phones will only intensify as a launch gets closer.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-app-is-already-revealing-the-pixel-9s-setup-animation-and-files</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ There are plenty of Google Pixel 9 rumors and leaks swirling around, but we now have a sneak peek at the phone's setup experience straight from the source. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">nYGRYniANrWAnL5zgwSGsj</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/q3Tw3ZYvQEcbBC7akRG9UE.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 14:04:02 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/q3Tw3ZYvQEcbBC7akRG9UE.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9 mockup with name]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9 mockup with name]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Gemini will soon be added to the Google app on Android ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>After debuting the standalone Gemini app for Android, Google chose to incorporate the AI chatbot into the regular Google app on iOS instead.</li><li>Now, Google is testing making the Google app for Android work like the iOS version. </li><li>The change brings a toggle for users to switch between Google Search and Gemini easily, streamlining the experience. </li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google rolled out its artificial intelligence chatbot in a few different ways, starting with Bard and eventually rebranding to Gemini. However, even after switching to Gemini, the chatbot still appeared on iOS and Android in different ways. Android users got a Gemini app that could replace the Google Assistant on their <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">flagship phones</a>, and iPhone users gained access to Gemini through the existing Google app. Now, a leaked version of the Google app aims to bring similar functionality to Android. </p><p>Android tipster <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://twitter.com/AssembleDebug" target="_blank">AssembleDebug on X</a> discovered an unreleased toggle in the Google app for Android that allows users to switch between Google Search and Gemini. This functionality isn&apos;t available publicly yet, but AssembleDebug presumably got it working after flipping a few developer flags. In a video shared with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://piunikaweb.com/2024/04/07/google-app-android-gemini-toggle/" target="_blank">PiunikaWeb</a>, we can see how the Google app for Android might look in a future update after gaining native support for Gemini.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Google app for Android to soon get toggle to switch between Gemini and Search [just like on iOS]📝 Read - https://t.co/eMgD2NxZKX#Google #Android pic.twitter.com/i19Msjb8wm<a href="https://twitter.com/AssembleDebug/status/1776897022966309238">April 7, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>After opening the Google app, users will still be greeted with the main Google Search tab by default. This is also known as the "Discover" feed, which suggests articles and content from the web. At the top center of the screen, there will be a new toggle that can switch between Google Search and Gemini. This broadly changes whether user queries are answered with search results or by Gemini&apos;s AI models. Aside from the functionality shift, the entire Google app user interface changes when you toggle between Search and Gemini.</p><p>When you tap the Gemini icon at the top of the screen, the Google app transforms to mimic the standalone Gemini app. The text box for Gemini will be available, accepting voice-to-text input and photo uploads as well, just like other instances of Gemini. The app will also give examples of questions that Gemini can answer and provide you with your recent chat history.</p><p>Google is trying out Gemini in a few places so far, most recently <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/gemini-makes-an-appearance-in-the-google-messages-beta">adding the chatbot to the beta version of Google Messages</a>. The regular Google app looks to be next to receive Gemini functionality, giving Android users more ways to access the chatbot. At first glance, it might seem redundant on Android, considering there is a standalone Gemini app. However, using the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-assistant-becomes-gemini-but-only-in-certain-countries">Gemini app automatically replaces the Google Assistant</a>, and the Google app could serve as an alternative.</p><p>Unfortunately, that isn&apos;t guaranteed. AssembleDebug told <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/google-android-app-gemini-toggle-3432129/" target="_blank">Android Authority</a> that using Gemini in the Google app will still prompt Android users to replace Google Assistant with the AI chatbot. </p><p>We&apos;re unsure when Gemini will be publicly released in the Google app, but it&apos;s clearly under active development. Similar features have been available to a limited number of iOS users since the Gemini rebrand. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/gemini-will-soon-be-added-to-the-google-app-on-android</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ When Google first launched Gemini, it was only available in the Google app on iOS. Now, Gemini is also headed to the Android version of the app.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">DQ5k7b87BnPYt8M5k6QXSJ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QUuejB6p5fokJUFyse3swb.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 13:19:43 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QUuejB6p5fokJUFyse3swb.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Google Gemini app]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Google Gemini app]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Pixel 8a live photos show off big bezels and a rounded design ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Real-world photos of the Pixel 8a have leaked, revealing a matte finish on the back, a departure from previous models.</li><li>The leaked photos show the Pixel 8a's rounded corners, following the design language of the Pixel 8.</li><li>The leaked images show the Pixel 8a with thick bezels, consistent with past A-series Pixel models.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google Pixel 8a leaks <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-coming-with-android-battery-stats">seem to be out of control</a>, with the supposed specs and renders plastered all over the web. Now there&apos;s a new leak claiming to show off live photos of Google&apos;s next mid-range model.</p><p>TechDroider posted a couple of real-world photos of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a">Google Pixel 8a</a> on X (formerly Twitter). One shows the front, and the other gives a peek at the back. The back sports a matte finish, a change from the shiny back panel we saw on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-7a-review">Pixel 7a</a>.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Google Pixel 8A pic.twitter.com/2Jopl3R2Mi<a href="https://twitter.com/techdroider/status/1777368163845632382">April 8, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>Along with the matte back, the leaked photos show the Pixel 8a has rounded corners, sticking to the rounded look Google introduced with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-review">Pixel 8</a>.</p><p>It remains unknown where the images came from, but they reveal a device with noticeable bezels. Actually, the bezels around the phone&apos;s edges are pretty thick, but this lines up with what we&apos;ve seen on past A-series Pixel models.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:497px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:150.91%;"><img id="PVqaBr2m9MAtqAprxkyQnF" name="Google-Pixel-8a-back.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 8a matte back" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PVqaBr2m9MAtqAprxkyQnF.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="497" height="750" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: TechDroider / X)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:490px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:153.06%;"><img id="GzMjrWj5fxCidZYPyKF6fF" name="Google-Pixel-8a-front.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 8a screen closeup" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GzMjrWj5fxCidZYPyKF6fF.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="490" height="750" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: TechDroider / X)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Big bezels aren&apos;t necessarily a bad thing, but these leaks do make the Pixel 8a look a bit budget-friendly. Maybe it&apos;s just the angle of the photos, though. Hopefully the real phone has slimmer bezels.</p><p>These images also offer a sneak peek at the rumored 6.1-inch screen. Previous rumors suggest that the Pixel 8a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-leaked-display-upgrade">might be the first in its series to sport a 120Hz refresh rate screen</a>.</p><p>Earlier leaks have suggested that the Pixel 8a might pack some nice upgrades under the hood. It&apos;s rumored to come with Google&apos;s latest Tensor G3 chip, which should deliver a performance boost compared to the Pixel 7a.</p><p>The camera setup might stay the same with a 64MP main sensor and a 13MP ultrawide sensor, but that&apos;s still a pretty good combo.</p><p>Pixel 8a leaks are painting a picture of a handset ready to reclaim its spot as a top contender in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-android-phones">mid-range device</a> category. However, rumors suggest that the phone <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-rumored-to-have-higher-price">might come with a significant price increase</a>, which could be a downside for some potential buyers.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-live-photos-leaked</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ These supposed pictures of the Google Pixel 8a give us a better view of both the front and back of the upcoming mid-range model. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">TMXmKZLe2LzCvb5DnZsECJ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/imgvxRR8FUb2cmw5XGDHNL.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 08:57:27 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/imgvxRR8FUb2cmw5XGDHNL.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[null]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The back of the Charcoal Google Pixel 7a]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The back of the Charcoal Google Pixel 7a]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Fiio KA13 review: This tiny dongle DAC has huge potential ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>A dongle DAC is the easiest way to connect IEMs and enthusiast headsets to your phone. These days, there are dozens of great choices that don&apos;t cost too much money, and Fiio by itself has a ton of enticing products in this segment. While the Chinese audio manufacturer sells a lot of high-end products and has ventured into a lot of new categories over the last 12 months, it is still at its best when making budget DACs, and the KA13 is one of its best yet.</p><p>The KA13 has a lot of similarities to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-ka5-review">KA5 dongle DAC I reviewed</a> last year, and while there isn&apos;t a TFT panel this time around, you get 3.5mm and 4.4mm ports, a great DAC, and plenty of power — this tiny dongle delivers up to 550mW, and is able to drive any IEM or headset.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="XpFVsBv9gNrwAJy47e5v5A" name="fiio-ka13-4.jpg" alt="Fiio KA13 dongle DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XpFVsBv9gNrwAJy47e5v5A.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The KA13 is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/FiiO-JadeAudio-Portable-Adapter-Compatible/dp/B0CJ6SXFWB">available for just $79 on Amazon</a>, making it a standout value — just like the rest of Fiio&apos;s dongle DAC offerings. Like its siblings, the DAC is branded under the Jade Audio label; this means the product is aimed at a younger audience and budget-focused, but other than that distinction, there isn&apos;t any difference in terms of build quality or features.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="x8fP6pfwdyEi6CHgYnfdpA" name="fiio-ka13-8.jpg" alt="Fiio KA13 dongle DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/x8fP6pfwdyEi6CHgYnfdpA.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Fiio doesn&apos;t usually change the design of its products, and the KA13 is about the same size as its siblings, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-ka3-portable-dac-review">KA3</a> and KA5. It uses the same metal enclosure, but the design is a little cleaner, and there&apos;s a tiny window next to the USB-C port that lights up when the DAC is in use.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="ePLU4SCTEjQKZJayrfTbeA" name="fiio-ka13-7.jpg" alt="Fiio KA13 dongle DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ePLU4SCTEjQKZJayrfTbeA.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>At just 18.5g, the KA13 is about as portable as a dongle DAC can get while still offering high-quality DAC hardware. If you want a design that stands out a bit, the white version definitely looks striking. The underside has a glass back and Jade Audio branding along with an intricate pattern that looks stylish, and on the whole, the KA13 looks like a product that should cost a lot more than $79.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="X8bCo2JULoZkcEhitoGMPB" name="fiio-ka13-11.jpg" alt="Fiio KA13 dongle DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/X8bCo2JULoZkcEhitoGMPB.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>A new addition on the KA13 is a toggle that enables desktop mode. You also get a volume rocker that lets you adjust the volume with ease, and the connectors are located at either ends — one side has USB-C, and the other has a single-ended 3.5mm jack and a balanced 4.4mm out.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="a2k7L5toivx9Xqbq4Lzk8B" name="fiio-ka13-10.jpg" alt="Fiio KA13 dongle DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/a2k7L5toivx9Xqbq4Lzk8B.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Fiio bundles a short USB-C to USB-C cable in the box, and you get a dongle to use with USB-A ports, and a USB-C to Lightning cable if you don&apos;t have the iPhone 15 and are using an older model. I used the USB-C connector with my <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/apple-iphone-15-pro-max-long-term-review">iPhone 15 Pro Max</a>, and there were no issues whatsoever. But a bulk of the testing was done with the DAC paired to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-6-pro-review">Magic 6 Pro</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-pro-review">Pixel 8 Pro</a>, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/xiaomi-14-review">Xiaomi 14</a>.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="jF82V7a24MDBv7yojeJJKA" name="fiio-ka13-5.jpg" alt="Fiio KA13 dongle DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jF82V7a24MDBv7yojeJJKA.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Easily the best part about using the KA13 is its versatility; you can connect the DAC to your phone, tablet, Windows machine, and any other device that has a USB-C port and get great audio out, no drivers needed. I used the DAC with Fiio&apos;s entry-level <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-fh11-review">FH11 IEMs</a>, and it did a (predictably) great job. Given the power on offer, I also used it with the demanding <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-fx15-review">FX15</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-ft5-review">FT5 headset</a>, and a slew of products over the course of three months.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="jezskjTBUU2EU4qRerw8u9" name="fiio-ka13-3.jpg" alt="Fiio KA13 dongle DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jezskjTBUU2EU4qRerw8u9.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>My main takeaway is that the KA13 is one of the most powerful dongle DACs you can buy today. It has more than enough power to drive any IEM, and it also handles demanding headsets with ease. The DAC is able to deliver 290mW at 16Ω and 170mW at 32Ω over the 3.5mm port, going up to 500mW at 16Ω and 550mW at 32Ω via the balanced 4.4mm port. These numbers are when the desktop mode is enabled, and honestly, if you&apos;re using anything other than sensitive IEMs, it makes sense to toggle the mode.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="495UBURGbR8GBkkp4kgGR9" name="fiio-ka13-1.jpg" alt="Fiio KA13 dongle DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/495UBURGbR8GBkkp4kgGR9.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The KA13 uses dual Cirrus Logic CS43131 DAC chips combined with an SG Micro SGM8262 amp, and if that sounds familiar, it&apos;s because Fiio used the same configuration inside the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-kb3-hifi-audio-mechanical-keyboard-review">KB3 keyboard</a> that also houses a DAC. The KA13 is able to hit 384kHz/32-bit via PCM and DSD128, and while the KA5 is able to go up to 768kHz, it doesn&apos;t quite manage to deliver the same level of power.</p>
<p>Coming to the sound, the KA13 has a slightly narrower soundstage than the KA5, but where it excels is the tonality. It is able to deliver a clean low-end with good articulation, natural mids with great vocal clarity, and good treble extension. Using it with the FX15 was an absolute joy, and the DAC clearly has a lot of potential.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="yUVkNMguEdipL9KW7F2WZB" name="fiio-ka13-12.jpg" alt="Fiio KA13 dongle DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yUVkNMguEdipL9KW7F2WZB.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>But it&apos;s the power that it is able to deliver that makes it unique; if you want a dongle DAC that can drive demanding headsets, this is the one to get. Obviously, the KA13 has a higher power draw than other DACs in this segment, but the fact that you&apos;re able to get this level of power out of such a small chassis is an achievement in and of itself.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="1e7e589d-53db-4b2e-9ee1-379ec4704ffc">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4Xs2xzcWSSoUjXedHGKPJ6.jpg' alt='Fiio KA13'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Fiio KA13</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>The KA13 has a sturdy build quality, and delivers incredible power. If you need a DAC to use with your phone, this is a standout choice. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-ka13-review</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Fiio KA13 is a dongle DAC that costs just $79. While that's enticing in its own right, it's the power on offer that makes it truly stand out.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">2s3efDPAGtV8UY2byfdQLA</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xRJb7NRQiMpfXnpTsAp9b9.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 05:25:26 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xRJb7NRQiMpfXnpTsAp9b9.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Fiio KA13 dongle DAC review]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Fiio KA13 dongle DAC review]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Fiio FH11 review: Stylish entry-level IEMs with a fun sound ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Fiio&apos;s entry-level products are among the best you&apos;ll find in the segment, and the reason for that is the brand&apos;s focus on value. Having tested nearly two dozen Fiio products over the course of the last 18 months, I can say with some guarantee that the brand usually offers the best value in whatever segment it is targeting.</p><p>And while hero products like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-k9-review">K9 Pro DAC</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-r7-review">R7 all-in-one network streamer</a> do a great job bringing attention to the brand, it&apos;s budget IEMs like the FH11 that lead sales charts. The FH11 is a hybrid IEM that uses a 10mm dynamic driver in conjunction with a balanced armature driver, and what makes it stand out is the design and affordability — coming in at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/FiiO-FH11-Earphone-Detachable-Audiophile/dp/B0CCSHYTS3">just $54 on Amazon</a>, the FH11 is one of Fiio&apos;s most affordable IEMs yet.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="fxQnEetT8qprd7ukGhr6rc" name="fiio-fh11-2.jpg" alt="Fiio FH11 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fxQnEetT8qprd7ukGhr6rc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The FH11 has an interesting design that doesn&apos;t have many similarities to the rest of the brand&apos;s IEM portfolio. Fiio dubs this design Bionic Conch, noting that it creates a "sense of flow" and elevated sound quality. What I like is that the zinc alloy chassis looks great, and the design looks much more upmarket than the entry-level price tag.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="DtxtTmFATkHkAY3hfSEoZd" name="fiio-fh11-6.jpg" alt="Fiio FH11 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DtxtTmFATkHkAY3hfSEoZd.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The faceplate has a star pattern that looks elegant, and the only issue I have with the design is that the faceplate tends to pick up smudges easily. Fiio is known to bundle plenty of accessories with its IEMs, and you get six sets of ear tips with the FH11 — three balanced and three bass-focused. You should be able to find something that fits with relative ease.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="UHTmF3mwK3cDn9SL4n2Zhd" name="fiio-fh11-7.jpg" alt="Fiio FH11 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/UHTmF3mwK3cDn9SL4n2Zhd.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The metal shells are clearly built to last and have better build quality than most IEMs in this segment, but they are on the heavier side, coming in at 10g each. That affects the comfort, and while I didn&apos;t have any issues getting these to fit, they exert pressure on the inner ear, and it is noticeable with extended use. The design allows for standout noise isolation, particularly if you&apos;re using the bass tips.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="LcBzHAaB2fve36e9FEyoFd" name="fiio-fh11-4.jpg" alt="Fiio FH11 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LcBzHAaB2fve36e9FEyoFd.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Fiio hasn&apos;t made many changes on the cable side of things, and you get a decent 4-strand braided cable that ends in a 3.5mm jack. The cable connects to the shell via standard 2-pin connectors, with blue and red indicators (left and right).</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="FZuFksR8tnkAsWApkPqYyc" name="fiio-fh11-3.jpg" alt="Fiio FH11 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FZuFksR8tnkAsWApkPqYyc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>With a sensitivity of 111dB and 24Ω, the FH11 is easy to drive with any source. That said, you will need to use a good dongle DAC to get the most out of the se IEMs, and in my testing, I paired it with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-ka5-review">Fiio&apos;s KA5</a> and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-m15s-review">M15S audio player</a>. Using a powerful source unlocks the potential of the sound, leading to a much more vibrant profile.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="zUvcDfvo7fLqHcdvf9sFgc" name="fiio-fh11-1.jpg" alt="Fiio FH11 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zUvcDfvo7fLqHcdvf9sFgc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>On that note, the FH11 is designed to deliver an energetic bass; if you want better resolution and imaging, you should consider the FD11 instead. Both IEMs share the same design and aesthetics, but they differ in the drivers and tuning. The FH11 uses a custom 10mm carbon dynamic driver — similar to that of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/FiiO-FH15-Knowles-Technology-Earphone/dp/B0BPCFPMDV">$200 FH15</a> — and this driver is lighter while having a high tensile strength, allowing it to deliver faster transients and less distortion.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="yGgrQBN8ZWzwrxxZE37jUe" name="fiio-fh11-11.jpg" alt="Fiio FH11 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yGgrQBN8ZWzwrxxZE37jUe.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>That is clearly evident in the sound; the FH11 has an elevated bass shelf that gives it a distinct sound characteristic, and the low-end has a lot of exuberance that sometimes bleeds into the mid-range. The mids are a bit recessed, but you still get clarity at the higher end of the frequency range, and vocals shine through. The treble is overly bright at times, and you do get some sibilance.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="hZCCDezSS4VvCpKrX4d5te" name="fiio-fh11-12.jpg" alt="Fiio FH11 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hZCCDezSS4VvCpKrX4d5te.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>On the whole though, the FH11 manages to produce a fun sound that pairs well with a lot of genres, and what is misses out in technicality, it more than makes up with vibrancy. You don&apos;t buy this IEM if you want a neutral sound with good resolution — you get this if you want the best bass in the budget segment.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="8fe1aade-cfb5-4859-9290-736e54caf48e">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:101.83%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/n8GivZy3oukZ6gzz5Cqn6V.jpg' alt='Fiio FH11'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Fiio FH11</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>The FH11 has a sturdy design with excellent build quality, and you get an engaging sound that's predominantly bass-focused. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-fh11-review</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The FH11 is Fiio's latest entry-level IEM, and it manages to deliver an engaging sound combined with an elegant design.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">GTqQAX7szeyEmVdsSwDGha</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8L3ycCn992S6KP7Ew2HMSd.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 03:57:53 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8L3ycCn992S6KP7Ew2HMSd.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Fiio FH11 review]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Fiio FH11 review]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>