<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 18:14:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Stop what you're doing! The best fitness watch just crashed to an all-time low for Black Friday ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The Garmin Venu 3 straddles the fine line between a fitness watch and a smartwatch, and ends up offering the best of both — well, almost. It has always been a bit pricey, but this <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CDC6LH5W"><strong>early Black Friday deal knocks 25% off</strong></a> the retail price bringing it down to just $349.99. This offer applies to the 41mm and 45mm dial options. This is an amazing deal for what we consider, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-smartwatches-fitness">best fitness watch</a> for most people.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-venu-3-review">Garmin Venu 3</a> features a large and vibrant AMOLED display, a stellar 14-day battery life, and highly accurate GPS, heart rate monitoring and sleep data. It even has a built-in microphone and speaker for answering calls, and it comes in two sizes to fit all wrist types.</p>
<h2 id="our-favorite-garmin-watch-just-scored-a-record-smashing-discount-2">Our favorite Garmin watch just scored a record-smashing discount</h2>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="14faa506-12d6-4703-a21b-394a55180620" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Garmin Venu 3: $449.99" data-dimension48="Garmin Venu 3: $449.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CDC6LH5W" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="CGWtuCbbuVhUT5b6RqoyYc" name="garmin venu 3.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CGWtuCbbuVhUT5b6RqoyYc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Garmin Venu 3: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CDC6LH5W" data-dimension112="14faa506-12d6-4703-a21b-394a55180620" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Garmin Venu 3: $449.99" data-dimension48="Garmin Venu 3: $449.99" data-dimension25=""><del>$449.99</del> <strong>$349.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p><p>The Venu 3 fitness watch appeals to a wide audience thanks to its stylish design and accurate fitness tracking. Grab this superb deal that knocks 25% off the price, bringing it down to its lowest ever at $349.99.<a href="http://samsung.com"></a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CDC6LH5W" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="14faa506-12d6-4703-a21b-394a55180620" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Garmin Venu 3: $449.99" data-dimension48="Garmin Venu 3: $449.99" data-dimension25="">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Black Friday</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/best-buy-black-friday-sale-top-android-deals-2024">Black Friday Best Buy deals</a><br><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/best-buy-black-friday-sale-top-android-deals-2024"></a><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/walmart-just-dropped-its-first-batch-of-black-friday-deals-and-android-users-should-take-note">-Black Friday Walmart deals<br>-</a><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Black Friday Google Pixel deals<br></a>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Black Friday Motorola deals<br></a>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024">Black Friday Samsung deals<br></a>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Black Friday OnePlus deals</a><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/walmart-just-dropped-its-first-batch-of-black-friday-deals-and-android-users-should-take-note"></a></p></div></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if:</strong> You want Garmin-grade tracking accuracy, minus the bulky design; you need a mic/ speaker in your fitness watch; you only track basic workout metrics.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>You need full smartwatch functionality with all apps; you need LTE connectivity; you need to track more robust fitness metrics.</p><p>The Garmin Venu 3 dips its toes in, both, fitness and smartwatch pools as it tries to appeal to everyone. On one hand, it's easily one of the best looking fitness watches out there. It comes in black or white trims, and two sizes of 41mm and 45mm. This classic smartwatch design is complemented by the crisp and bright 1.4-inch AMOLED display. The inclusion of a mic and speaker means you can use it to answer calls directly from your wrist. It's no smartwatch replacment as app support is limited and the processor isn't very powerful.</p><p>The Venu 3 also offers dependable health tracking tech that we've come to expect from a Garmin product. The fitness metrics are not as detailed as the Forerunner series, but it's accurate enough for you to rely on the data. In our review, we found all the important metrics like heart rate, sleep, and ECG readings were fairly accurate, making it a reliable watch for fitness tracking.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/stop-what-youre-doing-the-best-fitness-watch-just-crashed-to-an-all-time-low-for-black-friday</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Garmin's stylish Venu 3 fitness watch finally gets a deep discount of 25%, bringing the price down to $349.99. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">nEK3ER6vpjPCCFVhRjVWhD</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VaRzhLNHQgjVNWKPwJve8A.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ roydon.cerejo@gmail.com (Roydon Cerejo) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VaRzhLNHQgjVNWKPwJve8A.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jerry Hildenbrand]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Garmin Venu 3 Sleep tracking]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Garmin Venu 3 Sleep tracking]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ When will your Pixel phone stop receiving updates? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Google is finally seeing decent sales momentum with its Pixel devices, and it isn&apos;t hard to see why — the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-review">Pixel 8a</a> continues to be the best mid-range phone you can buy today, and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/pixel-9-pro-xl-two-months-later">Pixel 9</a> series has the best AI utilities currently available. Google&apos;s software efforts continue to stand out; Pixels have a clean interface with bold Material You styling, and they receive updates ahead of any other Android device.</p><p>What I like about the software on Pixel phones is that it is uncluttered, and you don&apos;t get any bloatware whatsoever. That in itself is a big deal, and it&apos;s one of the main reasons why I usually switch back to a Pixel after I&apos;m done reviewing the latest phones. Another thing Google changed recently is long-term update guarantee; starting with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-review">Pixel 8</a> series, all Pixel phones will get seven years of Android OS updates, and that includes the Pixel 8a as well.</p><p>In addition to the yearly Android OS update, Google rolls out monthly security updates to all eligible Pixels, and you get regular Feature Drops that introduce exciting new features. Eligible Pixels picked up the stable <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a> update as soon as it became available in mid-October 2024, and with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16">Android 16</a> coming earlier than ever before in 2025, devices that are slated to get the update will pick it up as soon as it goes live in Q2 2025.</p><p>So here&apos;s a rundown of how many Android OS and security updates your Pixel phone will receive, and when you might want to consider upgrading.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-pixel-9-pixel-9-pro-9-pro-xl-and-pixel-9-pro-fold"><span>Pixel 9, Pixel 9 Pro, 9 Pro XL, and Pixel 9 Pro Fold</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="GDPQjBRpXvvndJVVE2459P" name="pixel-9-9-pro-xl-1.jpg" alt="Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro XL next to one another" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GDPQjBRpXvvndJVVE2459P.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The latest Pixels made their debut in August 2024, and they came with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review">Android 14</a> out of the box. The Android 15 update is now available to these phones, and all four devices will get seven years of guaranteed Android OS updates and security patches. What that means is that the Pixel 9, Pixel 9 Pro, Pixel 9 Pro XL, and Pixel 9 Pro Fold will get Android OS updates and security patches at least until August 2031.</p><p>Although Google doesn&apos;t detail how long Feature Drops will be available, it&apos;s a good bet that those updates will also likely continue until 2031. It&apos;s another matter as to whether these phones are actually usable by then — the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-tensor-g4">Tensor G4</a> isn&apos;t particularly fast today — but what you need to know is that all four phones will get guaranteed updates until August 2031, and that&apos;s a big deal.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-pixel-8-and-pixel-8-pro"><span>Pixel 8 and Pixel 8 Pro</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="RqZdaSY2y6q65n3Auhn4EH" name="pixel-8-5.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 8 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RqZdaSY2y6q65n3Auhn4EH.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Pixel 8 and Pixel 8 Pro became available in October 2023, and both phones ran Android 14 out of the box and have picked up the Android 15 update. This launch was momentous from a software point of view as these devices became the first from Google to be eligible to get long-term software updates. As such, both the Pixel 8 and Pixel 8 Pro will get seven years of Android OS updates and security patches.</p><p>Both phones will get guaranteed platform and security updates at least until October 2030, so you don&apos;t have anything to worry about in this regard. The way I see it, the Tensor G3 platform powering both phones is the bottleneck; while these devices will get software updates until the end of the decade, Google has a sizeable task optimizing the hardware so that future Android versions run smoothly.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-pixel-8a"><span>Pixel 8a</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="6tcayRk63cRY9xtVSBnnQQ" name="google-pixel-8a-blue-with-flowers-01.jpg" alt="The blue Google Pixel 8a on a tea tray with blue hydrangeas above it" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6tcayRk63cRY9xtVSBnnQQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Pixel 8a is about as straightforward a recommendation as any on this list. The device has the same Tensor G3 chip as the regular Pixel 8, and it has a 120Hz panel and decent battery life. The best part is that it will also get the same seven-year update guarantee as the rest of the Pixel 8 series, and that&apos;s unheard of in the mid-range segment.</p><p>As the Pixel 8a was unveiled in May 2031, it will get guaranteed Android OS and security updates at least until May 2031. The phone came with Android 14 out of the box, and the Android 15 update is available to the device.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-pixel-7-and-pixel-7-pro"><span>Pixel 7 and Pixel 7 Pro</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="y93H3D4cqy23Y9spCfaLyJ" name="google-pixel-7-pro-review-7.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 7 Pro back view straight on angle against green background" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/y93H3D4cqy23Y9spCfaLyJ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div></figure>
<p>The Pixel 7 and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-7-pro-review">Pixel 7 Pro</a> debuted in October 2022 with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-13-review">Android 13</a> out of the box, and they&apos;ve picked up the Android 15 update. The phones hold up incredibly well two years after launch, but they won&apos;t get the same number of updates as newer Pixels; Google only guarantees Android OS updates until October 2025, and security patches for an additional two years beyond that, until October 2027.</p><p>That means next year&apos;s Android 16 update will be the last platform update going out to the Pixel 7 and 7 Pro. Obviously, both phones will still get security updates beyond that, and Google is likely to continue delivering Pixel drops with additional features. But the fact that they won&apos;t get platform updates after Android 16 is a letdown, and it remains to be seen if Google changes tack.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-pixel-7a"><span>Pixel 7a</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="49AVQgVxLWzNimwEovQZeL" name="Google-Pixel-7a-back-02.jpg" alt="The back of the Charcoal Google Pixel 7a" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/49AVQgVxLWzNimwEovQZeL.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Like the Pixel 8a, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-7a-review">Pixel 7a</a> is a great mid-ranger, and while I didn&apos;t like the fact that the phone came with a 90Hz OLED panel, that&apos;s about the only shortcoming. The phone launched in May 2023 with Android 13 out of the box, and it picked up the stable Android 15 update. Similar to the regular Pixel 7, the Pixel 7a will get three platform updates and five years of security patches.</p><p>So it will get guaranteed Android OS updates until May 2026, and security updates until May 2028. Interestingly, the accelerated timeline of Android releases means it is likely that the Pixel 7a may get the Android 17 update should that become available by May 2026.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-pixel-6-and-pixel-6-pro"><span>Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="a5DWzv3aX96VzFXqn8Hejb" name="pixel-6-pro-fall-autumn-04.jpg" alt="Google's Pixel 6 Pro on a fence with Autumn trees in the background" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/a5DWzv3aX96VzFXqn8Hejb.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google unveiled the Pixel 6 and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-pixel-6-pro-review">Pixel 6 Pro</a> back in October 2021, with both phones coming with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/android-12">Android 12</a> out of the box. Similar to the Pixel 7, both the Pixel 6 and 6 Pro are guaranteed three Android OS updates along with five years of security updates.</p><p>Incidentally, the Android 15 update that rolled out to these devices in October 2024 is the last platform update, and they&apos;ll only get security patches going forward until October 2026. Google may roll out the occasional Pixel drop with new features, but that isn&apos;t a given. If you&apos;re rocking either device, I&apos;d suggest taking a look at trade-in values to the Pixel 9 or 9 Pro XL — now is the best time to make the switch to Google&apos;s latest phones.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-pixel-6a"><span>Pixel 6a</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="cyZGwhbyGXwbMikWfukXXT" name="Google-Pixel-6a-back-water-02.jpg" alt="Water on the back of the Google Pixel 6a" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/cyZGwhbyGXwbMikWfukXXT.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-6a-review">Pixel 6a</a> gained a lot of attention when it debuted in July 2022, and that&apos;s because it had the same Tensor platform as the regular Pixel 6 series. While I enjoyed using the device, I didn&apos;t like the fact that it came with a 60Hz panel — that made it feel slow.</p><p>The Pixel 6a came with Android 12 out of the box, and it made the switch to Android 15. With Google offering the same update guarantee, the phone will get Android OS updates until July 2025 and security updates until July 2027. This is where things get interesting; Google said the phone would get three Android OS updates, and it has picked those up already.</p><p>But Google guarantees updates up to three years from the month the phone went on sale, and with the Android 16 stable update coming out well before July 2025, there&apos;s a good chance that the Pixel 6a will get the update. I asked Google to clarify its stance on this, and will update once I hear back.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-pixel-5-and-pixel-5a"><span>Pixel 5 and Pixel 5a</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="KtaabneeRpenrZ6fwb5bRK" name="pixel-5-16-9.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 5" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KtaabneeRpenrZ6fwb5bRK.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-pixel-5-review">Pixel 5</a> debuted in October 2020 with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/android-11-review">Android 11</a> out of the box, and with Google guaranteeing three Android OS updates, the Android 14 update that rolled out last year was the last platform version available to the device. It won&apos;t make the switch to Android 15, nor will it get any new security updates — Google only guaranteed three years of security updates until the Pixel 5 series.</p><p>That said, the Pixel 5 was the last Google device that came with unlimited Google Photos storage — provided you used the storage saver tier. This was a big deal at the time, and it&apos;s annoying that Google doesn&apos;t offer the feature any longer on its devices.</p><p>The Pixel 5a came much later — it went on sale in August 2021 — and it ran Android 11 out of the box. Similar to the regular model, the Android 14 update was the platform update, and it isn&apos;t picking up any new Android updates or security patches.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-pixel-4a-and-pixel-4a-5g"><span>Pixel 4a and Pixel 4a 5G</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="xxYYhsxGLmdsKUfp3wjjEL" name="google-pixel-4a-black-back-in-full.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 4a" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xxYYhsxGLmdsKUfp3wjjEL.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Martonik / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-pixel-4a-review">Pixel 4a</a> was announced in August 2020 with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/android-10">Android 10</a> out of the box, and it picked up the Android 13 update two years ago. Like other Pixel devices at the time, it was eligible to get three Android OS as well as security updates, and those have been delivered.</p><p>The Pixel 4a 5G debuted alongside the Pixel 5, and went on sale in November 2020. As a result of later availability, it came with Android 11 out of the box, and made the switch to Android 14 last year.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-pixel-4-and-pixel-4-xl"><span>Pixel 4 and Pixel 4 XL </span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.29%;"><img id="tcFXchcnGaE6EDp3tm6scC" name="google-pixel-4-back-orange-board.jpg" alt="Oh So Orange Pixel 4" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tcFXchcnGaE6EDp3tm6scC.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1400" height="788" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nick Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Although the hardware wasn&apos;t quite the best, I have good memories of using the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-pixel-4-xl-review-one-month-later">Pixel 4 XL</a>. The phone&apos;s unique radar-based face recognition tech — powered by a set of sensors dubbed Soli — relied on the 60Hz frequency, making it ineligible to be <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/why-google-not-launching-pixel-4-4-xl-india">released in countries like India</a>, where the band is used by the government.</p><p>Both the Pixel 4 and 4 XL launched in October 2019 with Android 10, and came with three years of guaranteed OS and security updates — the Android 13 update that rolled out two years ago is the last platform build they received.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-pixel-3a-and-pixel-3a-xl"><span>Pixel 3a and Pixel 3a XL </span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="MxvcEjuZPSUdN6AEAinS5T" name="google-pixel-3a-xl-preview-1.jpg" alt="Pixel 3a XL" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MxvcEjuZPSUdN6AEAinS5T.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1536" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Daniel Bader / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While Google had been making phones for over three years by this point, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-pixel-3a-review">Pixel 3a</a> and 3a XL allowed the brand to break into the mainstream market. Their value-focused pricing made the devices stand out, and although the hardware was underwhelming, you still got great cameras and clean software.</p><p>The Pixel 3a and 3a XL debuted in May 2019 with Android 9.0 Pie, and they picked up their requisite three Android OS updates, bringing them both to Android 12.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-pixel-3-and-pixel-3-xl"><span>Pixel 3 and Pixel 3 XL</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="SCrP2oYDajJUutg8jTqY4k" name="google-pixel-3-xl-white-front-home-screen.jpg" alt="Pixel 3 XL home screen" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SCrP2oYDajJUutg8jTqY4k.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-pixel-3-review">Pixel 3 XL</a> has the distinction of being the ugliest Pixel thanks to its dual front cameras, and while I got great photos out of the device, it was also fragile — a single tumble broke the back cover. The devices were unveiled in October 2018 with Android 9.0 Pie out of the box, and picked up Android 12 three years ago.</p><p>While they&apos;re not receiving updates, they&apos;re still quite usable, and the Snapdragon 845 holds up well in day-to-day tasks.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-pixel-2-and-pixel-2-xl"><span>Pixel 2 and Pixel 2 XL</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="RdVAc6bTUD8Vt2LM9f9Ybc" name="Google-Pixel-2-XL-black-in-hand-wide.jpg" alt="Black Google Pixel 2 XL in hand" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RdVAc6bTUD8Vt2LM9f9Ybc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I used all the Pixels released by Google, and the Panda <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-pixel-2-review">Pixel 2 XL</a> will go down as one of the most memorable. The distinctive two-tone design and fantastic cameras gave the phone a clear edge against its rivals, and while Google bungled the OLED panel — it had significant issues with color balance — it didn&apos;t matter.</p><p>The Pixel 2 and 2 XL debuted in October 2017 with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/oreo">Android 8.0 Oreo</a>, and like other devices at the time, they got three guaranteed Android OS updates and security patches, with Android 11 being the last one in 2020.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-pixel-and-pixel-xl"><span>Pixel and Pixel XL</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="brhGbj3FPAb5xN6ivvWEfH" name="pixel-xl-back.jpg" alt="Google Pixel XL back against blue background" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/brhGbj3FPAb5xN6ivvWEfH.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Google phones that started it all still have a unique attribute: they include unlimited Google Photos storage in original quality. Google didn&apos;t set a time limit on this feature, so if you have a Pixel lying around, you can still back up photos to Google Photos and not have it count toward your storage quota.</p><p>Both phones debuted in October 2016 with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/nougat">Android 7.1 Nougat</a> out of the box, and picked up their last platform update in October 2019 (Android 10).</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="23689a06-af68-439d-87c5-79302441adde">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/R6LSZJjgkpJt5yhjZxf4P9.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro render"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 Pro</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>If you need to upgrade and want a new phone, my suggestion is the Pixel 9 Pro. It is easier to hold and use than the 9 Pro XL, and you get the same set of cameras at the back. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="0c08ef2a-c622-497f-8e2e-ecfef2035b0e">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vmLdNVEV4CGYnz9stgpRA.jpg' alt="google pixel 8a render 400x500"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 8a</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>If you're after the best value, the Pixel 8a is still the device to beat right now. It delivers the best cameras in this category, and with seven guaranteed Android OS updates, it will pick up more software updates than any other mid-range phone. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/when-will-your-pixel-phone-stop-receiving-updates</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Pixel phones now get seven years of Android OS updates as standard, but that wasn't always the case. So let's take a look at how long your Pixel device will continue to get software updates.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">QH9AL7WuRKHfm4aXe4ha4F</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kpwXQ7avAaS9vB9H8gVcVP.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 16:33:24 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kpwXQ7avAaS9vB9H8gVcVP.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro XL beside Pixel 8 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro XL beside Pixel 8 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ For real? Ray-Ban Meta Smart Glasses just got their first HUGE discount ever! ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Ray-Ban Meta Smart Glasses are finally on sale for Black Friday, giving you the first big discount ever for the best smart glasses ever made. Amazon and Best Buy are giving you a cool <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/ray-ban-meta-wayfarer-smart-glasses-with-meta-ai-audio-photo-video-compatibility-green-lenses-shiny-black/6560291.p?skuId=6560291"><strong>$60 discount</strong></a>, making them $38 less than the previous best price we've seen. Some pairs and styles are up to $75 off, so be sure to check through them all for your favorite.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/ray-ban-meta-smart-glasses-review">Ray-Ban Meta Smart Glasses</a> are a brilliant way to stay connected without having to pull your phone out of your pocket constantly. They've got great built-in Bluetooth speakers in each temple, hours of battery life, and a handy camera that can capture the moment far quicker than a smartphone.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="8378b9e4-d698-43f1-915a-6f04ef0011a7" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Price comparison: Amazon - $239" data-dimension48="Price comparison: Amazon - $239" data-dimension25="$239" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/ray-ban-meta-wayfarer-smart-glasses-with-meta-ai-audio-photo-video-compatibility-green-lenses-shiny-black/6560291.p?skuId=6560291" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3840px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="BidBGb9aexCScWJDMeqyVV" name="Meta-Ray-Ban-glasses-headliner-low-bridge-fit-shiny-black.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BidBGb9aexCScWJDMeqyVV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3840" height="2160" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>Get the best smart glasses for the best price ever! This <strong>20% discount</strong> will save you enough to tack on prescription or other special lenses and still save a bunch of money thanks to this early Black Friday deal from Best Buy and Amazon.</p><p><strong>Price comparison: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CGXX2HG5/" data-dimension112="8378b9e4-d698-43f1-915a-6f04ef0011a7" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Price comparison: Amazon - $239" data-dimension48="Price comparison: Amazon - $239" data-dimension25="$239">Amazon - $239</a> | <a href="https://www.targetoptical.com/to-us/ray-ban-meta">Target - $299</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/ray-ban-meta-wayfarer-smart-glasses-with-meta-ai-audio-photo-video-compatibility-green-lenses-shiny-black/6560291.p?skuId=6560291" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="8378b9e4-d698-43f1-915a-6f04ef0011a7" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Price comparison: Amazon - $239" data-dimension48="Price comparison: Amazon - $239" data-dimension25="$239">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Black Friday</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Black Friday Google Pixel deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Black Friday Motorola deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024-early-deals-and-how-to-prepare-for-the-big-sales">Black Friday Samsung deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Black Friday OnePlus deals</a></p></div></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>Wearing earbuds bothers you or you just want a quicker, better way to capture photos and videos than your phone.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>You're an audiophile and have to have the best sound quality. These are great for a lot of things but earbuds still sound better.</p><p>I've run tests before with my own pair and found that I could record or take a picture in 2 seconds flat while it could <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/do-photography-focused-phones-make-any-sense">take 6 seconds</a> (or longer) to pull your phone out of your pocket and open the camera. Four seconds doesn't sound like much but, as a parent, I know 4 seconds can mean the difference between catching the moment and missing it entirely.</p><p>You can livestream to Instagram straight from your glasses and even switch perspectives between your glasses and your phone on a whim during the stream. They're incredibly versatile and it's truly amazing what you can record while your hands are free.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="Mxa23399ApcQFXJPCLHNjB" name="Meta-RayBan-Smart-Glasses-New-Options.jpg" alt="New colorways for Meta Ray-Ban." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Mxa23399ApcQFXJPCLHNjB.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Meta)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Ray-Ban Meta Smart Glasses look just like your favorite pair of Ray-Bans and even come in several different styles, dozens of colors, and include support for prescription or transitions lenses.</p><p>You can choose from Wayfarer, Skyler, or Headliner styles, all of which look just like those authentic Ray-Bans you've been wearing for years. Special lenses will cost a little bit more but those are all on sale too! Polarized versions <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/ray-ban-meta-wayfarer-smart-glasses-with-meta-ai-audio-photo-video-compatibility-polarized-blue-lenses-matte-jeans/6560301.p?skuId=6560301">are going for $263</a> — that's <strong>$65.80 off</strong> — while Transitions lenses <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/ray-ban-meta-wayfarer-large-smart-glasses-with-meta-ai-audio-photo-video-compatibility-clear-to-green-transitions-lenses-matte-black/6596886.p?skuId=6596886">will run you $303</a>, which is $75.80 off!</p><p>Ray-Ban Meta Smart Glasses are also <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/ray-ban-meta-smart-glasses-just-got-a-bunch-of-ai-upgrades-and-live-translation">powered by Meta AI</a>, so that camera is more useful than just taking pictures or video. You can ask it to scan QR codes, remember things so you don't have to open the notes app on your phone, read out cooking instructions on a recipe, and so much more.</p><p>They'll also read out text messages as they come in or just stream music from your favorite service. Plus, the case that ships with the glasses charge them just like a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-earbuds">great pair of wireless earbuds</a>, so you never have to worry about running out of battery.</p><p>Personally, I love these for taking meetings on the go, making phone calls, or even listening to music since they leave my ears open to hear the world around me. If nothing, that's the best use-case for them in my opinion and why I wear these far more often than any pair of earbuds or headphones.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/ray-ban-meta-smart-glasses-black-friday-2024-deal</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Ray-Ban Meta Smart Glasses are the best smart glasses ever and now this Black Friday sale gets them down to their best price ever! ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">kt3NiHvMiUKMJuGdsPviEC</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/v2py6YMqJLAjZDsYEjAKEX.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 14:47:44 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/v2py6YMqJLAjZDsYEjAKEX.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Taking the transparent Ray-Ban Meta Smart Glasses out of its charging case]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Taking the transparent Ray-Ban Meta Smart Glasses out of its charging case]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Finally! This 2024 Motorola phone is now worth buying, thanks to Amazon's Black Friday sale ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The Motorola Edge 2024's launch price was a huge disappointment since the performance didn't quite match up to the cost. But at $349.99, the Edge 2024 gets a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Motorola-Unlocked-256GB-Camera-Midnight/dp/B0D2JB6HP5"><strong>whopping 36% discount</strong></a> from its typical price of $549.99, making it worth a second look. The design, display, and some of the Moto software features truly makes this stand out from other mid-range phones in the segment.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="a3f85b5a-b7d6-4bd9-810a-27b6ab550069" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$549.99" data-dimension48="$549.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/Motorola-Unlocked-256GB-Camera-Midnight/dp/B0D2JB6HP5" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="P2JdKiPbNyQnTHaU449fSP" name="motorola edge 2024 square render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/P2JdKiPbNyQnTHaU449fSP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="800" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Motorola Edge 2024:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Motorola-Unlocked-256GB-Camera-Midnight/dp/B0D2JB6HP5" data-dimension112="a3f85b5a-b7d6-4bd9-810a-27b6ab550069" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$549.99" data-dimension48="$549.99" data-dimension25=""><del>$549.99</del> <strong>$349.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p><p>The Motorola Edge 2024 is a stylish mid-ranger with a classy vegan-leather back, an eye-friendly pOLED display, and excellent Hello UI features. It's also worth buying now at this heavily discounted price of $349.99, which is a 44% cut from its typical price.</p><p><strong>Price comparison: </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Motorola-Edge-2024-Unlocked-Made-for-US-8-256GB-50MP-Camera-Midnight-Blue/8396259650">Walmart - $479.99</a><a href="http://samsung.com"></a><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Motorola-Unlocked-256GB-Camera-Midnight/dp/B0D2JB6HP5"><strong></strong></a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/Motorola-Unlocked-256GB-Camera-Midnight/dp/B0D2JB6HP5" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="a3f85b5a-b7d6-4bd9-810a-27b6ab550069" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$549.99" data-dimension48="$549.99" data-dimension25="">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Black Friday</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Black Friday Google Pixel deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Black Friday Motorola deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024-early-deals-and-how-to-prepare-for-the-big-sales">Black Friday Samsung deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Black Friday OnePlus deals</a><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more"><strong></strong></a><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more"><strong></strong></a></p></div></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>You want a phone display without PWM dimming; you need good battery life and fast charging; you want a slim and classy-looking phone.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>You need strong gaming performance; more than two years of OS upgrades; very good cameras.</p><p>If you look at the headline of our <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-edge-2024-review">Motorola Edge 2024 review</a>, you're probably wondering why on earth are we recommending this phone. But give it a thorough read and you'll see there are many things to like about it. The launch price was something that really put us off, among other things. But at $350, it's priced what it should have been in the first place.</p><p>This is not the phone to get if you need great cameras, as the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-review">Pixel 8a</a> is the better choice. It's not great for gaming either, which is where the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12r-review">OnePlus 12R</a> comes in. But if all you need is a slim phone that looks more premium that it is and a display that won't cause headaches if you're PWM-sensitive, then the Edge 2024 at this Black Friday deal price is worth buying.</p><p>This is not the first time the Edge 2024's price has dipped this low, but it certianly seems like it's the lowest it will go before its successor comes along. The Hello UX interface based on Android 14 is clean and you get plenty of useful gestures. Battery life is great and the 68W charging speed can top up the 5,000mAh battery really quickly. You'll have to buy the charger separately though.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/finally-this-2024-motorola-phone-is-now-worth-buying-thanks-to-amazons-black-friday-sale</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Edge 2024's gorgeous, eye-friendly display and a beautiful design is finally a second look with this 44% discount for Black Friday. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">sLUEnBoi4h8RZCEgHq6zXC</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/i4pZZvLZrTTi5FZhp67c5U.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ roydon.cerejo@gmail.com (Roydon Cerejo) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/i4pZZvLZrTTi5FZhp67c5U.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Motorola Edge (2024)&#039;s pOLED display showing the boot logo]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Motorola Edge (2024)&#039;s pOLED display showing the boot logo]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google reveals the top-watched shows and movies on Google TV in 2024 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>As 2024 comes to an end, Google released the top-watched movies, shows, and Freeplay channels on Google TV.</li><li>Users can watch from the "Best of 2024" collection on their Google TV device or via the Google TV mobile app.</li><li>It'll show up in the <strong>For You</strong> tab on the Google TV Streamer, Google TV-enabled devices, and the iOS and Android mobile apps.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>It's that time of year again. The holiday season is approaching and 2024 is coming to an end, and that means streaming services are ready to reveal their top-streamed content. YouTube Music already gave some users <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-music-recap-2024-arrives-early">an early peek at their 2024 Recap</a>, and now, Google is sharing its "Best of 2024" list for Google TV. In a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.google/products/google-tv/google-tvbest-of-2024/" target="_blank">blog post</a>, the company pulled back the curtain on the most-watched movies, shows, and Freeplay channels over the past year.</p><p>Google's data is based on watch clicks on the Google TV interface by U.S. users. According to that data, the most-watched movie of 2024 was Road House, the remake of the 1989 thriller starring Jake Gyllenhaal. Honorable mentions go to Challengers and Dune: Part Two, which are listed as staff picks and must-watch films of the year.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="j5uYb7UiCBYrPdBVSZxyD5" name="kw_blog_movie.width-1000.format-webp" alt="Google TV best of 2024 graphics" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/j5uYb7UiCBYrPdBVSZxyD5.webp" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1000" height="750" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Up next, the most-watched TV show was Shōgun, which takes viewers back to an ancient Japanese empire. It also features phenomenal storytelling, Google writes. As an honorable mention, the staff pick for a must-watch TV show is the third season of Hacks, a comedy that follows the life of a Las Vegas comedian.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="pTg72wiDb4i8V3VVodaaE5" name="kw_blog_show.width-1000.format-webp" alt="Google TV best of 2024 graphics" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pTg72wiDb4i8V3VVodaaE5.webp" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1000" height="750" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Finally, Google TV offers 150 live TV channels for free, and the most popular one was ION Television this year. The network features reruns of popular dramas, like Law and Order: Special Victims Unit and FBI, helping it earn the top spot. On top of that, the channel includes professional sporting events, like WNBA games.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="2GuGRdUmNUg2Gd3S7ceXD5" name="blog_ion_112124.width-1000.format-webp" alt="Google TV best of 2024 graphics" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2GuGRdUmNUg2Gd3S7ceXD5.webp" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1000" height="750" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>All these picks will be available on your <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/google-tv-streamer-review">Google TV Streamer</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/google-tv-streamer-vs-chromecast-with-google-tv-4k">Chromecast with Google TV</a>, or your TV or set-top box with Google TV built-in. You'll find them in the <strong>For You</strong> tab listed under the <strong>Best of 2024 </strong>collection. If you don't own a Google TV device, you can check out the top movies, TV shows, and channels on the iOS and Android mobile apps. So, what do you think of the most-watched content on Google TV this year?</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/google-reveals-the-top-watched-shows-and-movies-on-google-tv-in-2024</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Curious to know which was the top Freeplay channel? Google's ready to share that, too. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">EoQJ2VJteRPoDCfuAd8rDE</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SKQa8xXBu72u9nDg5Ks89S.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 06:55:23 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Streaming &amp; TV]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SKQa8xXBu72u9nDg5Ks89S.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A graphic for Google&#039;s best of 2024 list for Google TV.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A graphic for Google&#039;s best of 2024 list for Google TV.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Fitbit may eventually become a pre-installed app on Android phones ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The brand-new Oppo Find X8 series includes the Fitbit app in the pre-installed Google folder by default.</li><li>While most Android phones ship with a slew of pre-installed Android apps, this is the first time the Fitbit app has been included.</li><li>The presence of the Fitbit app on the Oppo Find X8 series could be a precursor to it being included on more Android phones in the future.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>The Oppo Find X8 and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oppo-find-x8-pro-review">Oppo Find X8 Pro</a> are now available globally, and we've reviewed the Find X8 Pro as one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a> you can buy — if you're outside of North America. Aside from packing a great camera and impressive specs, the Oppo Find X8 series includes a new, pre-installed Google app for the first time: <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fitbit">Fitbit</a>.</p><p>The move, initially spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/11/21/fitbit-might-come-preloaded-on-your-next-android-phone/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a>, represents a first for an Android phone. On Find X8 phones, the Fitbit app is pre-installed and appears in the Google folder. Interestingly, the Fitbit app seemingly replaces the Google Fit app in this folder, since the latter isn't installed by default. While the company's own Google Pixel brand has included the Fitbit app on its phones, the Oppo Find X8 lineup represents the first time a partner OEM made the switch.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="bYxGZwm4q8HvUXDa4epyRX" name="oppo-find-x8-pro-12.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bYxGZwm4q8HvUXDa4epyRX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>This comes as Google tries to streamline its fitness offerings. The company <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-redirects-fitbit-store-purchases">shut down the Fitbit web dashboard earlier this year</a>, but is simultaneously going all-in on the Fitbit app for mobile. In fact, Google Fit APIs are being discontinued, and Google is giving developers until June 30, 2025 to switch, according to a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://developer.android.com/health-and-fitness/guides/health-connect/migrate/migration-guide" target="_blank">support document</a>.</p><p>While most Android users in the U.S. probably aren't importing an Oppo Find X8 device, the inclusion of the Fitbit app could be a sign of what's to come stateside. Future phones from the likes of Samsung, Nothing, and OnePlus could similarly feature the pre-installed Fitbit app, taking the place of Google Fit. Although many users like Fitbit and the features it offers, some users are unsatisfied by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-design-fitbit-app-redesign">how it feels out of place</a> beside other stock Google apps, using its own color theme and ignoring system defaults.</p><p>"The Fitbit app has been available since earlier this year to Android OEMs as we continue to support the health and wellness of more consumers," a Google spokesperson said in a statement to Android Central. "Several device manufacturers have chosen to preload the app on their mobile devices."</p><p>This statement reveals that while Oppo is the first partner OEM to include Fitbit in its default apps package, other companies have had the opportunity to as well dating back to early 2024. Presumably, more brands will follow as Google Fit continues to give way for Fitbit as Android's top fitness service.</p><p><strong>Update (Nov. 21, 2:45 p.m. ET)</strong>: Added comment from Google spokesperson.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/fitbit-may-eventually-become-a-pre-installed-app-on-android-phones</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The launch of the Oppo Find X8 series hints that the Fitbit app might become a core part of the Android experience. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">aoezWcf35BWHCoyTeqXVUM</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LtZcjgFBNMX3NLL2Dho7gB.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 22:43:43 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LtZcjgFBNMX3NLL2Dho7gB.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Pixel Watch 3 run coaching suggestion in the Fitbit app on a Pixel 9]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Pixel Watch 3 run coaching suggestion in the Fitbit app on a Pixel 9]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ It's already Black Friday for my favorite Meta Quest 3 and 3S accessories ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Get the most epic Quest this holiday season with early Black Friday deals from Kiwi Design, my favorite Meta Quest accessory company. I've recently received all the latest from the company and <em>everything</em> is on sale well ahead of Black Friday <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/KIWI-design-Boost-Battery-Compatible/dp/B0D6W88TCN/"><strong>including 25% off my new favorite head strap</strong></a>. It works with BOTH the Meta Quest 3 and Meta Quest 3S, so there's no need to figure out an exact model.</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Black Friday deals</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Black Friday Google Pixel deals<br></a>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Black Friday Motorola deals<br></a>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024">Black Friday Samsung deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Black Friday OnePlus deals</a></p></div></div>
<p>The Kiwi Design H4 is the company's brand new halo-style strap that is designed to take weight off your face with an easily adjustable strap that has ample padding for your forehead and the back of your head.</p><p>Better yet, it features quality batteries from Amprius Technologies in Fremont, California, including dual USB-PD charging tech that ensures your Meta Quest gets the correct voltage at all times and doesn't get overcharged. That battery not only adds hours of additional playtime but also helps better balance out the head strap for added comfort.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="e9fb01ac-7378-4ec3-ab73-b40afbe44582" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Add battery life and comfort to your Meta Quest 3 or Meta Quest 3S with the best halo-style head strap you can buy. Thanks to an early Black Friday 2024 sale, this one is a cool 25% off." data-dimension48="Add battery life and comfort to your Meta Quest 3 or Meta Quest 3S with the best halo-style head strap you can buy. Thanks to an early Black Friday 2024 sale, this one is a cool 25% off." data-dimension25="$59.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/KIWI-design-Boost-Battery-Compatible/dp/B0D6W88TCN/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:61.20%;"><img id="fFccQDsc7XdRdUbxgkcTxH" name="meta-quest-3s-kiwi-design-h4-head-strap-render" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fFccQDsc7XdRdUbxgkcTxH.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1500" height="918" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>Add battery life and comfort to your Meta Quest 3 or Meta Quest 3S with the best halo-style head strap you can buy. Thanks to an early Black Friday 2024 sale, this one is a cool <strong>25% off</strong>.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/KIWI-design-Boost-Battery-Compatible/dp/B0D6W88TCN/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="e9fb01ac-7378-4ec3-ab73-b40afbe44582" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Add battery life and comfort to your Meta Quest 3 or Meta Quest 3S with the best halo-style head strap you can buy. Thanks to an early Black Friday 2024 sale, this one is a cool 25% off." data-dimension48="Add battery life and comfort to your Meta Quest 3 or Meta Quest 3S with the best halo-style head strap you can buy. Thanks to an early Black Friday 2024 sale, this one is a cool 25% off." data-dimension25="$59.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>You like to play long VR sessions and need more comfort or longer battery life.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>You only play for 30 minutes or so at a time or are already comfortable with the head strap you've got.</p>
<p>My previous favorite head strap was the BoboVR M3 Pro but Kiwi Design's strap adds tweaks the strap design in a way that's far more comfortable. Not only is it higher up and larger, but that forehead padding is adjustable via a handy dial in the front.</p><p>Kiwi also thought of plenty of other niceties like a rigid front connector — instead of the annoying cloth Velcro one most head straps use — as well as a battery that intelligently adjusts voltage to ensure your headset gets the right amount of power without that annoying hissing sound some batteries make.</p><p>While you're adding extra comfort to your Quest 3 or 3S, you should also grab a pair of Kiwi Design G4 Pro controller straps. They're <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/KIWI-design-Controller-Compatible-Accessories/dp/B0DFXW7JTN"><strong>20% off</strong></a> right now and are the most comfortable controller grips I've ever used.</p><p>They not only add important grip and padding to the Quest 3 or Quest 3S controllers — which are a little too compact for my liking — but the hand strap is a luxuriously soft cloth that feels similar to one of those extra-soft blankets you might have on your couch.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="87f07a8a-1058-43a7-9e7c-12ef2e5f1bd7" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Get a grip and get the best controller grips I've ever used for 20% off! These work with the Meta Quest 3 and Quest 3S controllers, adding grip, a supple and soft hand strap, and convenient battery doors so you don't have to remove them to swap out the battery." data-dimension48="Get a grip and get the best controller grips I've ever used for 20% off! These work with the Meta Quest 3 and Quest 3S controllers, adding grip, a supple and soft hand strap, and convenient battery doors so you don't have to remove them to swap out the battery." data-dimension25="$23.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/KIWI-design-Controller-Compatible-Accessories/dp/B0DFXW7JTN" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:94.07%;"><img id="vnVrqpbLQVa8ZYYaoCQ3BS" name="meta-quest-3s-kiwi-design-g4-pro-controller-grips-render" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vnVrqpbLQVa8ZYYaoCQ3BS.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1500" height="1411" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>Get a grip and get the best controller grips I've ever used for <strong>20% off</strong>! These work with the Meta Quest 3 and Quest 3S controllers, adding grip, a supple and soft hand strap, and convenient battery doors so you don't have to remove them to swap out the battery.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/KIWI-design-Controller-Compatible-Accessories/dp/B0DFXW7JTN" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="87f07a8a-1058-43a7-9e7c-12ef2e5f1bd7" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Get a grip and get the best controller grips I've ever used for 20% off! These work with the Meta Quest 3 and Quest 3S controllers, adding grip, a supple and soft hand strap, and convenient battery doors so you don't have to remove them to swap out the battery." data-dimension48="Get a grip and get the best controller grips I've ever used for 20% off! These work with the Meta Quest 3 and Quest 3S controllers, adding grip, a supple and soft hand strap, and convenient battery doors so you don't have to remove them to swap out the battery." data-dimension25="$23.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>You tend to drop the Quest 3 or Quest 3S's controllers, or just find them uncomfortable/too small.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>You use a dock to charge your controllers. Most grips aren't compatible with a dock.</p>
<p>These grips also have a convenient battery door on the side so you don't have to remove them just to swap out the controller battery every so often. If you haven't used controller grips yet, you're seriously not ready for how much better these make things. It's unreal!</p><p>Kiwi Design also has its V3 facial interface replacement on sale which is <em>a lot</em> more comfortable than the default facial interface shape and padding. This isn't just a silicone pad you put over top of the original facial interface, it's a full replacement that also adds ventilation to keep the Quest 3's lenses from fogging up during play.</p><p>Plus, it's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/KIWI-design-Interface-Compatible-Accessories/dp/B0D48YLZJD"><strong>20% off</strong></a> right now during Kiwi Design's early Black Friday sale. The V3 <strong>ONLY</strong> works for the Meta Quest 3, though, so if you have a Quest 3S you'll want to grab the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/KIWI-design-Facial-Interface-Compatible/dp/B0DFXXW829/">Kiwi Design V4 facial interface</a>, instead.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="22839d5a-f2a1-4b54-b48c-7054369b678d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Get a better, more comfortable fit that's easier to clean and keeps lens fogging away, all at 20% off for during Kiwi Design's early Black Friday sale." data-dimension48="Get a better, more comfortable fit that's easier to clean and keeps lens fogging away, all at 20% off for during Kiwi Design's early Black Friday sale." data-dimension25="$19.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/KIWI-design-Interface-Compatible-Accessories/dp/B0D48YLZJD" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:66.20%;"><img id="XJxkhkobN3BiMqR5hszpdH" name="meta-quest-3-kiwi-design-v3-facial-interface-render" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XJxkhkobN3BiMqR5hszpdH.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1500" height="993" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>Get a better, more comfortable fit that's easier to clean and keeps lens fogging away, all at <strong>20% off</strong> for during Kiwi Design's early Black Friday sale.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/KIWI-design-Interface-Compatible-Accessories/dp/B0D48YLZJD" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="22839d5a-f2a1-4b54-b48c-7054369b678d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Get a better, more comfortable fit that's easier to clean and keeps lens fogging away, all at 20% off for during Kiwi Design's early Black Friday sale." data-dimension48="Get a better, more comfortable fit that's easier to clean and keeps lens fogging away, all at 20% off for during Kiwi Design's early Black Friday sale." data-dimension25="$19.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>The default face pad isn't comfortable for any reason or your lenses get fogged up while playing.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>You find PU leather uncomfortable.</p>
<p>The supple padding both wicks away sweat and is super easy to clean thanks to the PU leather material it's made of. The padding is easily removed and reinstalled via a Velcro backing, and most other face pads fit without issue. If you've already got some face pads lying around from other Quest headsets, they should work on this one.</p><p>Two pads come in the pack so it's easy to swap pads when you swap the headset, ensuring you're only sharing fun, not sweat.</p><p>Black Friday doesn't officially start until November 29, 2024, but there's no reason to wait until then to outfit your Quest 3 or Quest 3S with the best accessories. We don't ever see deals better than these, so you might as well jump on them now if you've been considering upgrading your headset this year.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-3-and-3s-accessory-sale-black-friday-2024</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Kiwi Design has long been one of our favorite Meta Quest accessory companies, and their best Quest 3 and Quest 3S accessories are already on sale ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">y8tjUgHCe588Wgw3CYUB38</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/882jrU6Swy5Em5ovYoyrnF.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 21:10:47 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/882jrU6Swy5Em5ovYoyrnF.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A Meta Quest 3 with a Kiwi Design H4 head strap alongside a Kiwi Design V4 facial interface and G4 Pro controller grips]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A Meta Quest 3 with a Kiwi Design H4 head strap alongside a Kiwi Design V4 facial interface and G4 Pro controller grips]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Android 16 could go 'even dimmer' in a more convenient way for users ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google reportedly showcased its new "Even Dimmer" mode for Android 16 in its first Developer Preview.</li><li>The feature will let users drop their display's brightness far lower than usual but through its brightness bar and an expected Quick Settings tile.</li><li>Google was spotted working on "Extra Dim," which "Even Dimmer" now replaced in Android 15 DP1.</li><li>Android 16 is set to arrive in Q2 2025.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>With Android 16's first preview in the wild, a recent discovery suggests a slight revamp for its eye-health-focused feature.</p><p>According to Mishaal Rahman (<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/android-16-dp1-even-dimmer-3501674/">Android Authority</a>), Google has slightly reworked its lower brightness feature in the first Android 16 Developer Preview. Rahman states that "Extra Dim" has seemingly been reworked to "Even Dimmer" with the latest OS build. These features are reportedly the same; however, the latter has only surfaced on the Pixel 9.</p><p>Rahman states users must "manually" activate this "Even Dimmer" mode via the Accessibility page within Settings.</p><p>More importantly, the major change is that "Even Dimmer" will reportedly appear in Android's brightness bar. This likely means users can lower their brightness even further through the Quick Settings menu.</p><p>The post reiterates that this feature is essentially an "additional dimming layer." Discoveries show that Google intends users to utilize "Even Dimmer" in darker scenarios where you wouldn't want a blindingly bright display. It's worth mentioning that these lower brightness levels can only activate once the brightness bar is "at its lowest."</p><p>Elsewhere, Rahman discovered that Android 16 Developer Preview 1 teases an upcoming Quick Settings tile for "Even Dimmer." Rahman speculates that the setting in the Accessibility page will arrive <em>before </em>the tile.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:277px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:216.61%;"><img id="ghbmTb3pD8FH7oGtWWhD9D" name="android-16-even-dimmer-extra-dim-replacement" alt="Android 16 seemingly reworked its "Extra Dim" mode to "Even Dimmer."" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ghbmTb3pD8FH7oGtWWhD9D.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="277" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google's original plan, "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-beta-even-dimmer-setting-spotted">Extra Dim</a>," was discovered earlier this year during the Android 15 beta. Most of its functionality seems similar to what was seen during Beta 1. Moreover, the report stated that testers could find it within the Adaptive brightness toggle via the Display settings page. This made it so users were required to go in and set this mode every time they wanted a (much) lower brightness.</p><p>Now, with Google seemingly reworking it and placing it outside the settings, users can quickly toggle, slide the bar, and go. However, one concern is how such a vastly lower brightness setting could affect those with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-is-pwm-display-flicker-tips-and-tricks">PWM sensitivity</a>.</p><p>Google just dropped its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16-developer-preview-1-is-here-with-new-features-and-a-snappier-release-timeline">Android 16 Developer Preview 1</a>, which is packed with several new features. This extremely early release signifies Google's earlier planned schedule for the release of Android 16. According to its timeline, the next major OS is planned for a Q2 2025 release. Elsewhere, it seems the software could include a new trick to calm down <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16-has-a-new-trick-to-put-a-damper-on-annoying-app-pings">those annoying notifications</a>.</p><p>Android 16 could feature a "Notification Cooldown" feature that "softens" the volume/alert of notifications that constantly notify you.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://shop-links.co/link?id=pcmcat1563302848653&publisher_slug=future&exclusive=1&u1=ac-us-7747702061179056976&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Ftop-deals%2Fcell-phone-deals%2Fpcmcat1563302848653.c%3Fid%3Dpcmcat1563302848653&article_name=Google%20Messages%20is%20preparing%20to%20handle%20dual%20SIM%20for%20RCS%20%7C%20Android%20Central&article_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.androidcentral.com%2Fapps-software%2Fgoogle-messages-support-for-dual-sim-rcs" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1943169/565706/9383?subId1=ac-us-7160325522328441519&sharedId=ac-us&u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fcp%2Fcell-phones%2F1105910%3Fpovid%3Dweb_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://shop-links.co/link?publisher_slug=future&exclusive=1&u1=ac-us-4001522076082960358&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.samsung.com%2Fus%2Fshop%2Fall-deals%2Fcell-phone-deals%2F&article_name=Google%20Messages%20is%20preparing%20to%20handle%20dual%20SIM%20for%20RCS%20%7C%20Android%20Central&article_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.androidcentral.com%2Fapps-software%2Fgoogle-messages-support-for-dual-sim-rcs" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://target.georiot.com/Proxy.ashx?tsid=169923&GR_URL=https%3A%2F%2Famazon.com%2Fs%3Fk%3Dcell%2Bphone%26crid%3D19CKV7OMEPEMF%26sprefix%3Dcell%2Bphone%252Caps%252C222%26ref%3Dnb_sb_noss_1%26tag%3Dhawk-future-20%26ascsubtag%3Dac-us-2642651856565627239-20" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-100048248-15733793?sid=ac-us-1238438477430007860&url=https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-100048248-15735111?sid=ac-us-3441836421221625028&url=https://www.att.com/" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="2633f04e-d85d-4ca1-aace-b7dc3f87882e">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sr66Lm9uCSgvS29MgezixS.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL render"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 Pro XL</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>Google's Pixel 9 Pro XL is the largest of its available next-gen slab phones. The device delivers a thin build with strong cameras backed by several AI-based editing tools. Moreover, Google's AI model Gemini is woven throughout the Pixel 9 Pro XL. Users will find an assortment of on-device AI tools for various daily tasks.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16-even-dimmer-brightness-tile-spotted</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google was spotted reworking its "Extra Dim" feature in Android 16 Developer Preview 1. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">FHpmNFrQWwutxURypQtQBc</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MLCKfeSHeDZWCUwT9QjhHA.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 20:28:30 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MLCKfeSHeDZWCUwT9QjhHA.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Brady Snyder / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The logo for Android 16 on a Pixel 9 Pro Fold. ]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The logo for Android 16 on a Pixel 9 Pro Fold. ]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra vs. Google Pixel 9 Pro XL: To wait or not to wait ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[         <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="102f451c-678f-404b-9824-e5e4482f9863">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PBHvpjpX26yLAmUkjL5o3W.jpg' alt="Galaxy S24 Ultra in Titanium Yellow"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The future king</strong></em></p><p>The Galaxy S25 Ultra is still a few months away, but some of the leaks have given us a rough idea on what to expect. Plus, going by Samsung's typical upgrades, we can make an educated guess about what the S25 would be like. It's going to be a powerful phone with a brilliant display and cameras for sure. We can't wait to see what One UI 7 is like, too. The only thing we're afraid of is the price, which is certianly going to be higher.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Custom 'Snapdragon 8 Elite for Galaxy' SoC (most likely)</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>New design with flat sides (rumored)</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Will have the S Pen built-in</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>OneUI 7 interface with new AI features</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Best telephoto cameras (likely)</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Likely launching in Q1 2025</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Will probably be quite expensive</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Battery and charging speeds might stay the same</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="0864dd84-c426-4330-ae4b-4fa92d227e9a">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VGAZM4QYiiwFRMyZ5tthCk.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL official render - Hazel - back"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 Pro XL</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="90" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The best of Google</strong></em></p><p>The Pixel 9 Pro XL is a beast of a smartphone if your primary goal is to use a ton of AI features for work or play. It simply has the best selection of AI tools and features that you'll want to use over and over. It will be cheaper than the S25, the design is great, you get improved battery and charging speeds, and a bright display. It can't compete in some areas though like the low-frequency PWM display dimming, non-gaming grade SoC, and the low base storage.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Should be cheaper than the S25 Ultra</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Superb AI features and software experience</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Excellent cameras</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Day-one software updates</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Eye-catching design</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>128GB base storage is shameful</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Display can wreck havoc for PWM-sensitive folk</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Processor is not built for heavy gaming</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<p>We're about to get a new wave of flagship Android phones in 2025, and the Samsung Galaxy S25 series will most likely be the first major global launch. We should expect a trio of new models like the last few years, which means many would be contemplating an upgrade. Samsung will be pushing its hero model front and center — the Galaxy S25 Ultra — which is slated to come with a host of upgrades.</p><p>All those who skipped the S24 Ultra would be looking at the new model as a potential candidate. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-review">Pixel 9 Pro XL</a> is another strong smartphone worth looking at. It too, costs above $1,000 and could actually be lower by the time January comes along.</p><p>Deciding between the Galaxy S25 Ultra vs. Pixel 9 Pro XL comes down to this; are you willing to wait a few months and pay full-price for cutting-edge tech or should you opt for a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">deal on the Pixel</a> and live with a few compromises? It's not an easy decision, but one we must make.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-vs-google-pixel-9-pro-xl-design-2">Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra vs. Google Pixel 9 Pro XL: Design</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1066px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.29%;"><img id="n6PXaFPNmcpnShZH3pGRHJ" name="Galaxy-S25-Ultra-renders-leak-03.jpg" alt="Galaxy S25 Ultra renders leak" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/n6PXaFPNmcpnShZH3pGRHJ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1066" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OnLeaks/ Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25">Galaxy S25 Ultra</a> is rumored to have a slight design change, and this render (above) gives us a good idea of what it could look like. That, and our first <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-should-you-wait" target="_blank">S25 Ultra case</a> that we've received from Fibreborne, points to the phone having flat sides and rounded corners. This puts it more in line with the rest of the series, but the edges of the Ultra would have a lesser curve than the S25 and S25 Plus. Some of the leaked dimensions point to the phone <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-thinnest-lightest-model-rumor">being lighter</a> and slimmer than its predecessor, which means it could be lighter than even the Pixel 9 Pro XL.</p><p>The main silhouette of the Galaxy S25 Ultra should be similar to the S24 Ultra, with a similar layout for the ports and buttons. Even the camera layout seems to be nearly identical, based on the leaked renders and the cases we received. While the flat sides and lighter design should make it easier to hold, it's still going to be a massive phone. Other design staples should also be in place, such as the IP68 waterproofing, the S Pen stylus, and the USB-C 3.2 port.</p><p>We should also expect <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-series-color-options-tipped">similar colors for the S25 Ultra</a> as we have for the current-gen phone. Samsung.com should have some exclusive shades, which would vary depending on the region.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="A5JUsMmXbpHi5T5WexKYy9" name="google-pixel-9-pro-xl-in-hand-rear.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL in hand" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/A5JUsMmXbpHi5T5WexKYy9.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Pixel 9 Pro XL adopted a new design language with glossy, flat sides and a more pronounced camera bar on the back. This very iPhone Pro-like aesthetic actually looks very flattering, and the new colours it comes in really helps it stand out. The 9 Pro XL is relatively slim at 8.5mm in thickness, but it is on the heavier side at 221g. Thankfully, the edges don't really dig into your palm to make it uncomfortable.</p><p>The Pixel 9 Pro XL is the larger variant of the 9 Pro, and is the direct replacement for the Pixel 8 Pro even though the nomenclature is a bit different this time around. You get IP68 dust and waterproofing, Gorilla Glass Victus 2 scratch protection over the display, and eSIM support.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-vs-google-pixel-9-pro-xl-display-2">Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra vs. Google Pixel 9 Pro XL: Display</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="GGAfLvqLid7eLG5D28wsYk" name="galaxy-s24-ultra-dead-to-me.png" alt="Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra with Battery Dying wallpaper" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GGAfLvqLid7eLG5D28wsYk.png" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nick Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>We don't have a lot of information about the S25 Ultra's display yet, other than the fact that the corners will be more curved than the current model. Everything points to it being the same 6.8-inch size with a QHD+ resolution, LTPO 120Hz refresh rate, and support for HDR playback. We could see an improved Corning Gorilla Armor scratch protection, higher peak brightness, and a better anti-reflective coating. One trick that it will continue to have is support for the S Pen stylus with over 4,000 levels of pressure sensitivity.</p><p>Meanwhile, the Pixel 9 Pro XL features Google's Super Actua display panel of the same 6.8-inch size and a resolution of 2,992x1,344 pixels. This LTPO panel also has a higher peak brightness than the current S24 Ultra of 3,000 nits, along with a 120Hz variable refresh rate. The biggest issue still plaguing Pixel phones is the abysmal 240Hz PWM dimming rate which it uses across the brightness spectrum. This can cause severe headaches for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-is-pwm-display-flicker-tips-and-tricks">people that are sensitive</a> to this, and can end up being a deal-breaker.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-vs-google-pixel-9-pro-xl-hardware-specs-2">Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra vs. Google Pixel 9 Pro XL: Hardware & specs</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="JSWpEtXtpmh2kSKikBmvB" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-Ultra-purple-03.jpg" alt="Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra cameras" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JSWpEtXtpmh2kSKikBmvB.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div></figure>
<p>We might not have the official price for the Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra yet, but based on Samsung's track record for this year alone, it'll most likely be $100 more than the S24 Ultra's pricing. The latter officially starts at $1,299.99 (less during <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024">Black Friday deals</a>), which means the S25 Ultra will be either the same or more. You should expect the same storage variants starting with 256GB. RAM should also be 12GB, but this could be spec'ed higher up to 16GB in order to run newer Galaxy AI features. The phone will also most likely sport the latest <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/snapdragon-8-elite">Qualcomm Snapdragon 8 Elite</a> SoC, which is said to bring laptop-class CPU performance to smartphones.</p><p>The Google Pixel 9 Pro XL cannot hope to compete with the raw processing power of the S25 Ultra, as its Tensor G4 SoC simply isn't built for it. Google has made big improvements to thermal efficiency and AI performance with this generation, compared to the previous one. In our review, we noticed that while the SoC still throttles when playing demanding games, it doesn't get as hot, so it takes longer for the phone to reach its thermal threshold.</p><p>Pricing is slightly better for the Pixel. While most should skip past the entry 128GB model, the 256GB variant costs $1,199, 512GB is $1,319, and the 1TB variant is $1,549. This is, of course, before you apply any coupons or discounts from retailers, which there most certainly will be. Unless you pre-order the S25 Ultra, this phone is unlikely to see any sort of discount for at least a few months after launch.</p><p>You can take a look at all the differences in specs in the table below.</p>

<p>A <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-and-s25-plus-rumored-to-use-sony-sensors">rumor</a> from December 2023 suggested that Samsung will switch to all Sony sensors for the S25 and S25 Plus models, but the Ultra might continue using Samsung's ISOCELL sensors. Samsung already rejigged the telephoto cameras on the S24 Ultra this year, dropping the magnification of the 10x module to 5x but, in turn, using a higher resolution sensor. It's high time we got better ultrawide and selfie cameras for the Ultra, and our hope is that they change with the S25 Ultra. In terms of capabilities, the S24 Ultra can already record 8K videos and capture HDR videos, so our guess is that we could see some new AI-based capture modes like the Pixel.</p><p>The Pixel 9 Pro XL passed our camera tests with flying colors, delivering excellent details, colors, and white balance. It's also very effective for capturing subjects in motion, like pets or toddlers. Whether it's low-light or day-light, the 9 Pro XL's cameras are up to the job and almost never disappoint. Exclusive AI features like Add Me take the photography experience a step further.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1066px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.29%;"><img id="98HWPjmm9qdD2aBRcKnpVJ" name="Galaxy-S25-Ultra-renders-leak-02.jpg" alt="Galaxy S25 Ultra renders leak" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/98HWPjmm9qdD2aBRcKnpVJ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1066" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OnLeaks/ Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Galaxy S25 Ultra is rumored to have the same battery capacity as the S24 Ultra, which is not a bad thing. The 5,000mAh capacity delivered multiple-day battery life on the S24 Ultra, so I would imagine with the newer chip and other software optimizations, the S25 Ultra should do just as well, if not better. Samsung hasn't budged from the 45W wired charging for many years, and it doesn't seem like it will anytime soon.</p><p>The Pixel 9 Pro XL has impressive battery life, often stretching well beyond a full day, even with heavy use. According to our parent company's lab test results, the 9 Pro XL took an average of 13 hours to drain its battery completely, compared to the nine hours it took for the 8 Pro. Considering it has nearly the same capacity as the 8 Pro, the power efficiency of the new Tensor G4 really shines here. Charging speed has gotten better, but only for the 0-30 minute dash and when using Google's 45W charger.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-vs-google-pixel-9-pro-xl-software-2">Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra vs. Google Pixel 9 Pro XL: Software</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="4gpMuHf4NvR79YBDgV2mkc" name="samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-good-lock-module.jpg" alt="S24 Ultra showcasing Good Lock modules" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4gpMuHf4NvR79YBDgV2mkc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nick Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>One of the big talking points of the Galaxy S25 Ultra is going to be the software. It's slated to run <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsungs-android-15-update-gets-an-up-close-reveal-in-this-one-ui-7-hands-on-video">One UI 7</a>, which is supposed to be massively overhauled, based on what we've seen so far. Samsung should be releasing a beta for it before the year ends, but you should expect a new look for the notification shade and toggle buttons, new icons and UI elements, and most importantly, more AI integration in the form of notifications summaries and more.</p><p>Samsung should also be finally implementing <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-seamless-update-support-rumor">Google's seamless update</a> tech for smoother update installations. You can expect a lot of talk about new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-galaxy-ai">Galaxy AI</a> features which should be even more tightly integrated within the UI, along with new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-review">Android 15</a> features. The S25 Ultra should also be getting seven years of OS and security updates. Keep in mind that One UI 7 will eventually come to the S24 Ultra, but it's possible some features will be kept exclusive for the S25 series.</p><p>The Pixel 9 Pro XL launched with Android 14 but was one of the first phones to get the Android 15 update. Google will also be supporting this phone for the next <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-pixel-9-software-updates">seven years</a> in terms of software updates. Google's AI features in the 9 Pro XL are nothing short of amazing. The Reimagine tool especially is incredibly fun to play with as it lets you modify the environment around your subject in a very realistic manner.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-vs-google-pixel-9-pro-xl-which-one-should-you-get-2">Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra vs. Google Pixel 9 Pro XL: Which one should you get?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="nA3naoxQorm7Jzh2wwgaZB" name="google-pixel-9-pro-pixel-9-pro-xl-8.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro and Pixel 9 Pro XL in tree" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nA3naoxQorm7Jzh2wwgaZB.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>If you are a current Samsung user still holding on to the S23 Ultra, then the S25 Ultra should be a good upgrade. Be prepared to shell out a hefty premium though, which I'm guessing you probably won't mind having skipped a generation. The Galaxy S25 Ultra will no doubt be yet another <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phone</a> in 2025 as it's a proper all-rounder tackling photography, productivity, and gaming, in a single device.</p><p>For the majority of users who don't care about the S Pen or need a gaming smartphone, the Google Pixel 9 Pro XL will serve you a lot better. The cameras are simply amazing, the design is unique, battery life is stellar, and it has some of the best software in the Android space. Prices of all the variants should be a lot more competitive as well, compared to the S25 Ultra.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="febd2b34-ceba-48ca-a387-7708d3ebf98d">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fKeeGDWPo8JDB6FZFgJBYk.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL official render - Obsidian - back"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 Pro XL</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The people's choice</strong></em></p><p>The Pixel 9 Pro XL offers most of the flagship features of the S25 Ultra, but at better prices. It excels in departments like software, cameras, and battery life, which is something every user cares about.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="700d475d-35e6-4dab-a99e-54019f5b4f7b">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/us5uBzbMSjqWPB8urvEEEf.jpg' alt="Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Cutting-edge comes at a cost</strong></em></p><p>The Galaxy S25 Ultra will be more powerful than the Pixel for sure, but all this comes at a steep premium. You'll also need to wait till Jan 2025 before it goes on sale, by when, we could see bigger discounts on the 9 Pro XL.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-vs-google-pixel-9-pro-xl</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Galaxy S25 Ultra will be a powehouse of a phone, but that will come at a steep cost. Is the Pixel 9 Pro XL the better buy right now? ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">7oqwNPoMTKYPvzPXFcxFC3</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MQrYufS9as73w4WJyzPu4.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 20:24:37 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ roydon.cerejo@gmail.com (Roydon Cerejo) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MQrYufS9as73w4WJyzPu4.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra cameras]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra cameras]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Upgrading to a new phone? Android can now keep your apps signed in after restoring from a backup ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google is introducing an Android feature called Restore Credentials, which transfers your apps' sign-in credentials to a new phone.</li><li>The feature copies existing functionality on iOS, and will make the experience of switching from one Android phone to another more convenient, regardless of device brand.</li><li>The process is built into the Android device backup and restore mechanism, so no manual user action is required.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google is adding a new Android feature that will keep your apps signed in after restoring from a backup or switching to a new device, it announced in a post on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2024/11/maintain-strong-user-relationships-with-restore-credentials.html"> Android Developers Blog </a>. It's called Restore Credentials, and it's built right into the existing Credential Manager API. Best of all, it requires no manual action from the user, as it is handled on the app and Android side automatically.</p><p>Here's how it works. When a user signs into their app account on an Android phone, app developers can create a restore key for the user. It's saved locally, and can be uploaded to the cloud if the user has agreed to back up the app's data. Then, when a user <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-transfer-data-your-old-android-phone-your-new-phone">starts restoring from a backup</a> on a new device, the app's data and its restore key are transferred. The app can be signed into the app, without the Android user even needing to open it. In other words, your phone <em>should</em> be just how you left it.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/everything-ios-18-stole-from-android">Similarly to the iOS feature</a>, it's likely that not all apps will automatically retain their sign-in status after restoring from a backup. Developers will need to add the new functionality in the Credential Manager API to their app, which may take some time. Google explains how to do this in its post, and recommends developers delete restore keys after a user manually signs out of an app.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:55.63%;"><img id="aKDL8PYQd8gReFRFitD4V5" name="Restore-Credentials-Feature-Android" alt="A graphic showing how Restore Credentials work on Android." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/aKDL8PYQd8gReFRFitD4V5.png" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1600" height="890" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Restore Credentials are based on Google's existing implementation of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/upgrade-to-passkeys-on-pixel-with-google-password-manager">passkeys</a>, and incorporate standards from the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://fidoalliance.org/passkeys/" target="_blank">FIDO Alliance</a>.</p><p>All this happens during the backup and restore process, with the idea being that you should be automatically signed into your apps after the restore process is completed. Google says that the introduction of Restore Credentials should make it easier to switch between Android phones, regardless of manufacturer. It claims that 40% of U.S. users reset or replace their phones each year, so eliminating friction in the restore process is crucial.</p><p>Being that Restore Credentials mimics a fan-favorite iOS feature, it's likely that Android users will appreciate this new functionality the next time they reset their device, or switch to a new one.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/upgrading-to-a-new-phone-android-can-now-keep-your-apps-signed-in-after-restoring-from-a-backup</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google finally figured out a way to save your app login status when switching to a new device.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">emrFwQEtEeMCirtMMKfuDG</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZRLcTa3GHMDsECK3AvtSDH.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 19:56:45 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZRLcTa3GHMDsECK3AvtSDH.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Judy Sanhz / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung Smart Switch home page on a Galaxy A34 5G]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung Smart Switch home page on a Galaxy A34 5G]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>