<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 13:04:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Early look at RCS on iPhones shows that Apple has some work to do ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>An early dive into Apple's coming RCS support for iPhones in iOS 18 shows green bubbles, single and group chat functionality alongside file transfers.</li><li>Unfortunately, early RCS support on iPhones lacks proper E2EE for group chats and emoji reactions only work for iPhones.</li><li>Proper message replies aren't working as iPhone users can't send them and replies they receive appear as regular texts.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Shortly after Apple&apos;s usual WWDC event, those enrolled in its iOS 18 beta were able to surface its upcoming RCS support.</p><p>X user <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/dhinakg/status/1802405645955567958">Dhinak</a> made the discovery and posted a lengthy thread breaking down its availability and present features in the iOS 18 beta (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/rcs-ios-18-early-look-3451995/">Android Authority</a>). Early evidence shows that green bubbles are still used to denote Android users despite the existence of RCS — but <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/apple-announces-rcs-support-coming-to-iphone#section-update">that was expected</a>.</p><p>Users on Android can message those on iPhone through a single RCS chat and group chat. Additionally, the X user discovered that file transfer work, meaning higher-quality audio files, photos, and other forms of media can be shared.</p><p>However, there are a few areas in which Apple drops the ball early on, beginning with a lack of E2EE (end-to-end encryption) in group chats. Emoji reactions seem to operate as a one-way street as only the iPhone user will see a "proper" reaction.</p><p>If an iMessage user reacts to an Android user&apos;s message, the latter will receive a new message saying "Liked," followed by your text in quotes.</p><p>Dhinak responded to a comment asking about replies — which don&apos;t work properly either. According to the tipster, replies appear "as regular messages" on an iPhone, and Apple users can&apos;t send replies, either.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">RCS comes to iPhone.h/t https://t.co/X2mRxhGcr1 pic.twitter.com/LL4ATIWDza<a href="https://twitter.com/dhinakg/status/1802405645955567958">June 16, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>Some technical details in the thread show that the RCS standard is limited to iPhones on T-Mobile and AT&T networks. Android phones attempting to use RCS with an iPhone user need to be on a T-Mobile plan, at least for now. </p><p>More digging revealed that RCS is disabled by default on iPhones, meaning users must navigate to the settings to turn it on.</p><p>We&apos;ve been expecting RCS support on Apple&apos;s iPhone ever since the company <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/apple-announces-rcs-support-coming-to-iphone">confirmed it was coming</a> last November. Google has been pushing for it through its #GetTheMessage campaign for quite a while. Apple said that through RCS, it would " offer a better interoperability experience when compared to SMS or MMS." However, this early look shows that there&apos;s still more that needs polishing.</p><p>Apple also left its coming RCS support for iPhones in iOS 18 as <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/apple-made-rcs-messaging-an-afterthought-at-wwdc-why-wouldnt-it">little more than a footnote</a> during its WWDC presentation this year. Another unfortunate side effect is that Apple announced an array of new iMessage features for its users, which won&apos;t play well with the RCS standard.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/early-look-rcs-support-apple-iphone</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A user surfaced an early look at Apple's RCS support on iPhone, which still needs work. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">uUsVc39hFg3TmycQAU83cB</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YcMNVPGPdvh6VTJEcfRgGW.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 12:23:57 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YcMNVPGPdvh6VTJEcfRgGW.jpeg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Daniel Bader / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[An iMessage chat showing blue and green bubbles]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[An iMessage chat showing blue and green bubbles]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Realme GT 6 review: A well-rounded mid-ranger ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p> </p><p>Realme’s GT series of phones is its top-tier lineup, and we’ve seen some pretty memorable models in the past. After a two-year long hiatus, Realme is finally releasing global variants of its GT series in select markets, once again. We first got the Realme GT 6T in India in May, which was a rebadged GT Neo 6 SE from China (with 120W charging). Now, Realme has launched the GT 6 in select Southeast Asian markets, which is similar to the GT Neo 6, but with a tweaked camera configuration. </p><p>The GT series has always been about sheer performance, and the new Realme GT 6 packs the most popular SoC of the season, the Qualcomm Snapdragon 8s Gen 3. We’ve already seen it in phones like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/poco-f6-review">POCO F6</a>, the recently announced <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-edge-50-ultra-launch">Motorola Edge 50 Ultra</a>, and Xiaomi 14 CIVI. The GT 6 goes beyond raw power, as it debuts Realme’s take on AI in phones, which it calls ‘Next AI.’ There’s a lot to unpack, so let’s begin with the pricing.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-realme-gt-6-price-and-availability"><span>Realme GT 6: Price and availability </span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="snxqbtXkms4Rwbsrs59kiF" name="Realme-GT-6-review-11.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/snxqbtXkms4Rwbsrs59kiF.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>India will be getting three variants of the GT 6, starting with 8GB RAM and 256GB of storage for ₹40,999 (around $492). The second variant gets 12GB of RAM and 256GB of storage for ₹42,999 ($516), while the top-spec variant comes with 16GB of RAM and 512GB of storage, priced at ₹44,999 ($540). With the launch offers and discounts in place, you can knock about ₹5,000 from the prices, which makes the phone seem more attractive. </p><p>The Realme GT 6 does not have a microSD card slot, so it’s best to choose your variant wisely from the get go. Also, all variants are said to have UFS 4.0 storage and LPDDR5X RAM. The phone comes in two colors — Razor green and Fluid silver — and both look very nice. </p><p>The glossy finish of the rear glass is a major pain to keep clean, as it attracts fingerprints very easily. Thankfully, there’s a case in the box to help mitigate this. You also get the 120W fast charger with the phone, which we’ll talk more about in a bit. </p>

<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-realme-gt-6-what-i-like"><span>Realme GT 6: What I like</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="bUW3CahZ4XvSPCWWiVCgJ6" name="Realme-GT-6-review-9.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bUW3CahZ4XvSPCWWiVCgJ6.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The display on the Realme GT 6 is something that will immediately grab your attention. It’s a flagship-grade AMOLED screen measuring 6.78 inches, with a 1.5K (2,780x1,264) resolution. The 120Hz refresh rate is also truly adaptive thanks to the LTPO tech, which allows it to scale to 1Hz when there’s no touch input or app running in the foreground. This 10-bit display supports the DCI-P3 color gamut, 2,160Hz PWM dimming when the brightness is low (DC dimming when brightness is above 70 nits), and Dolby Vision and HDR10+ playback. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="pMia4LKQkG3CHFiH8g5qrm" name="Realme-GT-6-review-5.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pMia4LKQkG3CHFiH8g5qrm.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The GT 6 also has one of the brightest displays in its segment, with a 6,000 nits local peak brightness rating, and 1,000 nits typical brightness. Rounding off this impressive spec list is Gorilla Glass Victus 2 for scratch and shatter protection. The curved edges on the sides of the display complete the flagship look.</p><p>I found the display to be very legible even under harsh sunlight. Colors have just the right amount of saturation with the default color profile and there isn’t any noticeable color shift when viewing the display off-axis. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="YgCLAanMELcciVEqhtFykP" name="Realme-GT-6-review-4.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YgCLAanMELcciVEqhtFykP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The display settings lets you enable “Extra brightness” if you need it, and you can set the threshold for minimum brightness in low light, which is a very useful feature. For those who wish to conserve some battery, can drop the resolution lower, although this isn’t really needed. HDR videos look great on the GT 6, and Realme’s Photo’s app supports ProXDR viewing for still images. Finally, there’s an optical in-display fingerprint sensor which works well, but its placement is a bit too low for my liking.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="fxNGa5ebUvmmeeKXvqdVZB" name="Realme-GT-6-review-12.jpg" alt="Realme gt 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fxNGa5ebUvmmeeKXvqdVZB.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Performance has always been the core strength of the GT series, and the latest Snapdragon 8s Gen 3 in the GT 6 hits the spot. We’ve already talked about it in our POCO F6 review, but in short, it’s a scaled down <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-3">Snapdragon 8 Gen 3</a> SoC with a different CPU cluster (1+4+3) configuration and lower clock speeds, a lower rung GPU and 5G modem, and lower memory frequency. While all this adds up to lower performance compared to the 8 Gen 3, it’s still the most powerful SoC in the mid-range segment, besting even last year’s flagship 8 Gen 2 in some benchmarks. </p>

<p>The Realme GT 6 posted higher benchmark numbers than the POCO F6, which has the same SoC. Temperatures were also well under control when running these tests, which shows that the vapor cooling system was doing its job well. The 8s Gen 3 is not too far behind last year&apos;s flagship 8 Gen 2 SoC, as seen in the 12R&apos;s scores. However, the latest 8 Gen 3&apos;s GPU and more powerful CPU clusters manages to keep a good lead over the 8s Gen 3, as seen in the scores of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/asus-zenfone-11-ultra-review">Zenfone 11 Ultra</a>. </p><p>Games ran just fine on the GT 6, with little to no stutter. Asphalt 9: Legends looked great and ran at a steady 60fps. First-person shooters like Battle Prime pushed the temperatures higher, with an indicated 42 degrees, but this was still manageable without the case. Genshin Impact looked gorgeous at the ‘Highest’ graphics setting and 60fps enabled. Once again, the indicated phone temperature went up to 43 degrees, but nothing beyond that even after about 20 minutes of gameplay. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="dGq6bEyGVqRJPcsBtwmeXe" name="Realme-GT-6-review-15.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dGq6bEyGVqRJPcsBtwmeXe.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>General performance of the GT 6 was also top-notch. The phone rarely skipped a beat with multi-tasking and the interface and apps felt fluid to interact with. The stereo speakers are loud and sound good, the haptic engine offers good tactile feedback, and there’s an IR blaster on the top of the frame for controlling things like your TV or air purifier. Wireless and 5G performance was also solid as calls and network coverage was good in the few weeks I used the phone. The GT 6 has dual-SIM support, Bluetooth 5.4, NFC, and Wi-Fi 6. The chassis is also IP65 rated for dust and water resistance. </p>
<p>Battery life is another major plus point for the Realme GT 6. The massive 5,500mAh capacity easily lasted me a good two days on average with light to medium usage. Even with heavy gaming and camera usage, I could still get up to a day and a half before I had to charge it. I rarely had battery anxiety with the GT 6 when I stepped out of the house, even if it wasn’t fully charged. Wireless charging is missing, but I doubt anyone will really miss it when you get a 120W fast charger in the box. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="7x5JVeAezUcHuS4LADBVGA" name="Realme-GT-6-review-18.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7x5JVeAezUcHuS4LADBVGA.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>With the battery at roughly 11%, I could charge it up to 97% in just 30 minutes, which is bonkers. The only issue is that the charger is massive and you’ll need this special SUPERVOOC charger only to be able to achieve such speeds. Luckily, you’ll still be able to get 80W or 65W fast charging if you have older fast chargers from OnePlus or OPPO lying around, as they all use the same charging technology. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="S3h7gRyktaLYJ8Tcp5aEjJ" name="Realme-GT-6-review-10.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/S3h7gRyktaLYJ8Tcp5aEjJ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Considering it is a performance-focused phone, the Realme GT 6 packs some neat cameras, and even gets an additional telephoto camera over the China-only model. The primary camera uses a 50MP Sony LYT-808 module with an f/1.69 aperture and OIS; the ultrawide has an 8MP Sony IMX355 with an f/2.2 aperture (fixed focus); while the telephoto is a 50MP Samsung JN5 with an f/2.0 aperture with stabilization. The selfie camera uses a Sony IMX615 32MP sensor. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="sUwAAaf2A9thnsRZYdqmnJ" name="Realme-GT-6-review-2.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sUwAAaf2A9thnsRZYdqmnJ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In daylight, all the rear cameras of the GT 6 capture detailed photos but with slightly varying white balance. The main sensor gets the truest representation of the scene, while the ultrawide has a warmer tone and the telephoto has a cooler one. The ultrawide captures slightly softer textures and grain is more noticeable in shadow regions, but you’ll only see these drawbacks if you zoom into the photo. </p><p>The telephoto’s optical magnification of 2x produces sharp portraits, and details are still decent till about 10x zoom, after which it starts to weaken. I noticed some minor metering issues too under harsh lighting at 2x zoom, where whites were blown out. Zooming in a bit more tended to fix this, but with a slight drop in quality. </p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 17</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4096px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="yEwu33GMoBnqZBNMsWzSaA" name="IMG20240606064056.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yEwu33GMoBnqZBNMsWzSaA.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4096" height="3072" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="caption-text">Main camera  </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 17</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3264px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="DDYG437M9Ksh6zfBGCuZt" name="IMG20240606064058.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DDYG437M9Ksh6zfBGCuZt.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="3264" height="2448" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="caption-text">Ultrawide camera </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 17</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4096px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="eNyhcju9DuJePQYksD6o64" name="IMG20240606064105.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/eNyhcju9DuJePQYksD6o64.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4096" height="3072" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="caption-text">Telephoto camera (2x zoom) </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 4 of 17</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4096px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="YF7c7pmBiK6k89UAJF3iwH" name="IMG20240608132915.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YF7c7pmBiK6k89UAJF3iwH.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4096" height="3072" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="caption-text">Main camera  </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 5 of 17</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3264px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="ouU2RV4xyustD75hBXnB8C" name="IMG20240608132917.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ouU2RV4xyustD75hBXnB8C.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="3264" height="2448" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="caption-text">Ultrawide camera </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 6 of 17</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4096px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="HTe3GTJ6txFWT7j7Ka7hN5" name="IMG20240608133010.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HTe3GTJ6txFWT7j7Ka7hN5.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4096" height="3072" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="caption-text">Main camera  </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 7 of 17</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4096px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="JtqQmvKXvrV94dcAHKvPWF" name="IMG20240616112401.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JtqQmvKXvrV94dcAHKvPWF.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4096" height="3072" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="caption-text">Main camera  </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 8 of 17</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4096px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="Kg7gLrVXb3rcJ57exCqLdD" name="IMG20240608135556.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Kg7gLrVXb3rcJ57exCqLdD.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4096" height="3072" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="caption-text">Main camera  </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 9 of 17</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4096px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="4HT4BCq4t7HnscZhUgyh5L" name="IMG20240608134425.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4HT4BCq4t7HnscZhUgyh5L.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4096" height="3072" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="caption-text">Main camera  </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 10 of 17</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3264px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="rqTmEwMVqqssQ8KPT2VFg6" name="IMG20240608134429.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rqTmEwMVqqssQ8KPT2VFg6.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="3264" height="2448" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="caption-text">Ultrawide camera  </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 11 of 17</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4096px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="xJ6e3hPHYhoykoN3hugNvF" name="IMG20240608134435.jpg" alt="Realme Gt 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xJ6e3hPHYhoykoN3hugNvF.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4096" height="3072" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="caption-text">Telephoto camera  </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 12 of 17</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4096px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="YWFCMbxGHUguGUScQTAdBN" name="IMG20240611230554.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YWFCMbxGHUguGUScQTAdBN.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4096" height="3072" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="caption-text">Main camera  </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 13 of 17</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3264px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="AP8S9TfGnXvb6nhsEEAjs7" name="IMG20240611230601.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AP8S9TfGnXvb6nhsEEAjs7.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="3264" height="2448" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="caption-text">Ultrawide camera  </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 14 of 17</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4096px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="voy6AkTrKZE2HCAHXs2G49" name="IMG20240611231805.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/voy6AkTrKZE2HCAHXs2G49.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4096" height="3072" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="caption-text">Main camera  </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 15 of 17</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4928px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:133.12%;"><img id="EotrjLgShxymygEWrbEKNQ" name="IMG20240611231649.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/EotrjLgShxymygEWrbEKNQ.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4928" height="6560" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="caption-text">Selfie camera  </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 16 of 17</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:6560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.12%;"><img id="ZXjG6HQ4HDRaGs7YEJVtZT" name="IMG20240606104439.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZXjG6HQ4HDRaGs7YEJVtZT.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="6560" height="4928" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="caption-text">Selfie camera  </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 17 of 17</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:6560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.12%;"><img id="XBFYa7ku3FWnCbg97DSziW" name="IMG20240606161545.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XBFYa7ku3FWnCbg97DSziW.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="6560" height="4928" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="caption-text">Selfie camera  </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>The GT 6 produces sharp visuals in low light too, thanks to a very effective night mode. A slower shutter speed is automatically engaged which helps bring out the details and colors of objects in the dark. This works quite well with the ultrawide camera too. The phone will only switch to the telephoto camera at night if your subject is well lit, else, it’ll simply digitally zoom in using the main camera. </p>
<p>The optical stabilization of the main sensor is quite impressive at night, as it keeps your subject in sharp focus even with a long exposure shot. The main and telephoto cameras, both, bin images down to 12MP by default. You can shoot full 50MP images with the two of the rear cameras using the ‘HI-RES’ mode.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="tpJbCDheqxpvR9bREMgctP" name="Realme-GT-6-review-8.jpg" alt="Realme Gt 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tpJbCDheqxpvR9bREMgctP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I’m not a big selfie person, but I’d say most users should be more than happy with the quality of photos it captures. Daylight shots pack in plenty of details, colors are well represented, and Portrait mode works well. Photos are above-average even with indoor lighting. At night, the long-exposure shots produce decent details and colors. Beauty filters are enabled by default, and while I didn’t find them to be too intrusive, you can disable them altogether. </p>
<p>Video recording is quite impressive too. The Realme GT 6 can record up to 4K 60fps and up to 4K 30fps Dolby Vision HDR videos with the main and telephoto cameras. The selfie camera can also capture 4K 30fps standard videos, making this a good phone for vlogging. The ultrawide is the only camera that’s limited to 1080p 30fps for recording, which is a shame. I wish Realme had used a better sensor for the ultrawide camera in order to complete the experience. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="9FjRVPjeSXchuZNuYjcqoC" name="Realme-GT-6-review-16.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9FjRVPjeSXchuZNuYjcqoC.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Daylight video quality is very good from the main and telephoto cameras. HDR videos especially look good on the GT 6’s display. Videos captured at night are decent if there’s enough light, but walking about introduces quite a bit of jitter. Videos shot using the ultrawide camera are strictly average in the day and are just about usable in low light.  An ‘AI night vision’ toggle pops up in the viewfinder in really low-light conditions, which helps in getting brighter videos but this also adds noise to the footage. It’s worth noting that this AI feature can be used even at 4K 30fps. </p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-realme-gt-6-jumping-on-the-ai-bandwagon"><span>Realme GT 6: Jumping on the AI bandwagon </span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="4EByA7jrKQn6SkJnGjfwWP" name="Realme-GT-6-review-14.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4EByA7jrKQn6SkJnGjfwWP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It seems like Realme didn’t want to miss out on the AI boom, so it’s adding its own flavor to its phones. Called ‘Next AI’, this software-based feature debuts with the GT 6 and will be rolled out to the GT 6T, and possibly other models too via an update. There are four AI features to start off with, which are AI Smart Removal, AI Night Vision, AI Screen Recognition, and AI Smart Loop. The latter two features need to be enabled, and can be found under ‘Special features’ in the Settings app.  </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1200px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="Xa95iUeJuKT8Vc9HT8e6nn" name="Realme-GT-6-review-19.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Xa95iUeJuKT8Vc9HT8e6nn.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1200" height="675" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="caption-text">AI Smart Loop in action on the GT 6  </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>AI Smart Loop is kind of a quick-share pop-up carousel, which lets you share images or text directly from one app to the other. You can manually add up to five apps to the drawer or let the system decide based on your usage pattern. To share something quickly, you simply long-press the file or photo and drag it to either edge of the display to bring up your apps. This method has its quirks at times though, like when you hold the display to pause an Instagram story and the system thinks you want to share it instead. </p>
<p>AI screen recognition works on screenshots or directly within certain supported apps. This can be activated by various gestures, and it lets you share or save images and text individually. The AI Eraser feature uses <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/oppo-introduces-ai-center">OPPO’s AndesGPT</a> platform for processing edits in the cloud. Similar to Google’s Magic Eraser, you can remove objects from the scene or blur out imperfections on objects. The end result is pretty decent most of the time. I can see the screen recognition and editing features being handy, and more Realme phones should benefit from this soon. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1743px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:73.44%;"><img id="8zCqfsNAU2NJaTeXJQbGkj" name="realme-gt-6-review-AI-features.jpg" alt="Realme Gt 6 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8zCqfsNAU2NJaTeXJQbGkj.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1743" height="1280" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="caption-text">1) AI Screen Recognition feature in action. 2) Options in the AI Eraser menu. 3) Objects removed using the Smart Lasso tool </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The GT 6 runs Realme UI 5.0 which is based on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review">Android 14</a>. Realme has committed to three years of OS upgrades and four years of security patches, which is not bad. One thing I did notice was far less spam and app clutter when I first set it up, which is a step in the correct direction. Many unnecessary apps are still present, but it’s organized in a way where you don’t immediately notice them. </p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-realme-gt-6-what-i-don-t-like"><span>Realme GT 6: What I don’t like </span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="yoMTTydWDLGwZjRocPYFV6" name="Realme-GT-6-review-7.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yoMTTydWDLGwZjRocPYFV6.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While the Realme GT 6 gets most things right, there are a few areas where it could have done better. It’s not a very thick phone, but it weighs 199g and that is noticeable in your pocket. The other issue I have is with the rear glass panel. It certainly gives the phone a premium feel, but the glossy nature makes it a magnet for fingerprints and it ends up looking untidy after a few minutes of holding it. </p><p>The mirror-like strip across the cameras doesn’t help its cause either. My other gripe is with the glass itself, as Realme says it’s a standard panel with no rated scratch or shatter resistance. This means, you most certainly will need to use this phone with a case. </p>
<p>The outer frame of the GT 6 is polycarbonate, which does reduce the impact of heat on your fingers when gaming, but an aluminum frame would have elevated the touch experience and given it a more premium feel. Finally, there’s the crippled ultrawide camera which simply doesn&apos;t match up to the capabilities of the other two rear cameras. </p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-realme-gt-6-competition"><span>Realme GT 6: Competition </span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="PWh4RSCyLQjqp6NNQA5nzf" name="poco-f6-review-22.jpg" alt="POCO F6 back view with cameras highlighted" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PWh4RSCyLQjqp6NNQA5nzf.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Realme GT 6 has plenty of competition, but I think it packs enough merit to separate itself from the rest. First, you get the new set of mid-range flagships with the Snapdragon 8s Gen 3 posing as the GT 6&apos;s immediate rivals. There’s the POCO F6, which offers amazon value for its low starting price of just ₹30,000 (about $360). Just like the GT 6, it too has a terrific display, strong primary camera, and is a great all-rounder. </p><p>The Xiaomi 14 CIVI is a recent entrant starting at ₹43,000 ($515). Its unique selling points are the Leica-branded cameras, and slim and lightweight design. </p>
<p>If you want a good looking phone, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/nothing-phone-2-review">Nothing’s Phone 2</a> is a great deal right now with the top-end variant down to Rs. 39,999 ($480). What it lacks in raw power, it certainly makes up with one of the best Android implementations outside a Pixel phone. The OnePlus 12R is another solid offering that starts at the same price. It has flagship-level specs, slick software, excellent battery life, and a wonderful main camera. </p><p>If you&apos;re in the U.S., then the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-review">Pixel 8a</a> is probably the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-android-phones">best pick under $500</a>. It has a compact design, the best software, excellent cameras, and is destined to get software updates for the next seven years. </p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-realme-gt-6-should-you-buy-it"><span>Realme GT 6: Should you buy it? </span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="EqcWTj3XW9VAETeiaRP5eW" name="Realme-GT-6-review-17.jpg" alt="Realme GT 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/EqcWTj3XW9VAETeiaRP5eW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>You should buy it if...</strong></p>
<ul><li>You need strong mid-range gaming phone </li><li>You want versatile cameras  </li><li>You need the quickest possible charging  </li><li>You need a bright and vivid display </li></ul>
<p><strong>You shouldn&apos;t buy it if...</strong></p>
<ul><li>You need a good quality ultrawide camera   </li><li>You want a lightweight phone </li><li>You hate wiping off fingerprints  </li></ul>
<p>Realme could have taken the lazy route and simply rebadged the GT Neo 6 for the global market and called it a day. It would have still been a good product, but probably less impactful against the competition. By adding the 50MP telephoto, the GT 6 has become a more competitive offering in its segment. Nearly all of its cameras are highly competent and capture quality shots, with the ultrawide being the exception. Dolby Vision video recording is a nice bonus to have. The GT 6 looks stylish, has very good gaming performance for its class, a bright display, and excellent battery life. Those looking for AI features will find a few useful ones here too. </p><p>If it’s just the processor you’re after, then the POCO F6 has everyone beat offering the best value for money. On the other hand, if you want a decent telephoto camera, more effective cooling system for gaming, and better battery life, I think it’s worth spending a bit more to get the GT 6.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="88563dc4-809b-40f6-ba4d-c329b9076ef0">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3MhmnvqbHiwYrJiPtkfMNE.jpg' alt='Realme GT 6'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Realme GT 6</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="90" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>A powerful mid-range contender </strong></em></p>
<p>The Realme GT 6 checks most of the right boxes for its segment,  giving you a feature-packed phone with little to complain about. You get a stunning display, excellent performance, great battery life, and very main and telephoto cameras. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/realme-gt-6-review-a-well-rounded-mid-ranger</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Realme GT 6 aims to set the bar for mid-range performance and features. Is it enough to take down the likes of POCO and Xiaomi? We have all the answers in our review.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">LXgSJ3WV2GDutzxfB3rFhc</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/C2H7SutfKuEUsp8sktVhPB.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 09:00:26 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/C2H7SutfKuEUsp8sktVhPB.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Roydon Cerejo/ Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Realme GT 6]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Realme GT 6]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 could pack a game-changing camera upgrade ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A leaked video shows the Razr Plus 2024 will have a large 4-inch external display, dubbed the "largest, most intelligent display" on a foldable phone.</li><li>The Razr Plus 2024 is also expected to have an IPX8 rating, a significant upgrade from the current model's light spray protection.</li><li>The upcoming foldable may also incorporate AI-powered functionalities, including an "AI-powered" camera and Motorola's "Moto AI" suite.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Motorola is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-2024-razr-foldables-june-launch-confirmed">set to launch the next Razr series next week</a>, but a new leak already hints at exciting features like a telephoto lens and improved water resistance, among others.</p><p>A short video clip, leaked by @MysteryLupin on X (formerly Twitter), has surfaced, revealing the next-generation Razr Plus&apos; cover screen (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/06/19/motorola-razr-leak-reveals-telephoto-camera-better-water-resistance-and-ai-video/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a>). The teaser claims it to be the "largest, most intelligent display" on a foldable phone, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-50-series-renders-reveal-cover-screen-changes">matching earlier rumors of a significant 4-inch external display</a> on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2024">Razr Plus 2024</a>. In comparison, the standard Razr 2024 is rumored to have a slightly smaller 3.6-inch external display.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">flip the script pic.twitter.com/MBI8YQj229<a href="https://twitter.com/MysteryLupin/status/1803576873735299387">June 19, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>This larger display would dominate nearly the entire front of the upcoming Razr Plus. The leaked video also gives us a sneak peek at the slightly thinner bezels on the Razr Plus 2024&apos;s cover display compared to the 2023 model. Despite this minor tweak, the display still looks very similar to its predecessor.</p><p>We also get a glimpse of better water resistance for the device, with the teaser mentioning "underwater protection." This clue, along with a small disclaimer at the bottom of the video referring to an IPX8 rating, suggests the phone can handle submersion in water for a certain period of time.</p><p>Meanwhile, the current <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-review">Moto Razr Plus</a> only offers basic water protection with its IP52 rating, handling only light sprays. While it might not be dustproof, the boost in water resistance is a welcome upgrade.</p><p>Mobile photography enthusiasts will be excited to see a telephoto zoom lens in the Razr Plus 2024&apos;s camera setup, as shown in the leaked video. Rumor has it that Motorola is moving away from the dual-12MP setup, opting instead for a 50MP primary sensor paired with a 50MP telephoto lens offering 2x zoom.</p><p>The 2023 Moto Razr Plus features a standard camera and ultrawide sensor combo, but it misses out on telephoto capabilities. The new model seems to be changing the game by including a telephoto zoom lens, a rare feature for foldable flip phones.</p><p>Motorola&apos;s smartphones have often fallen short in the camera department, including the Razr series. However, the upcoming Razr Plus 2024 could mark a new chapter for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">foldable phone</a> photography under the Motorola brand.</p><p>The Razr Plus 2024 also aims to carve out a niche in a market of AI-powered smartphones. The leaked video hints at an "AI-powered" camera and Motorola&apos;s "Moto AI" suite, suggesting advanced image processing and some AI features.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-motorola-razr-plus-2024-could-pack-a-game-changing-camera-upgrade</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A new leak suggests the Moto Razr Plus 2024 might bring a killer camera upgrade and even survive a splash or two. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">NAkPbsxKMWy9Acv92rtEjU</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mWiM9VAoEkfWBC8xusH4E4.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 08:41:40 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mWiM9VAoEkfWBC8xusH4E4.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[ Arsène Lupin / X]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Motorola Razr Plus 2024 cover screen]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Motorola Razr Plus 2024 cover screen]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google's Gemini AI is finally available for more Android phones in Messages ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Gemini in Google Messages is now available on any Android phone with at least 6GB of RAM, the latest app version, a Google account, and RCS messaging enabled.</li><li>Gemini is now accessible in Messages in over 165 countries, including India, supporting English and French (in Canada).</li><li>Google also launched the standalone Gemini app and Gemini Advanced in India, supporting English and nine Indian languages.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google&apos;s Gemini in Messages is now available on any eligible Android phone after being initially limited to Google Pixel and Samsung Galaxy devices.</p><p>On one of our devices, such as the Infinix Note 40 Pro 5G, Gemini&apos;s welcome message has recently popped up, signaling the feature&apos;s wider availability. Google has <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/messages/answer/14599070#countries&zippy=%2Ccountries-where-gemini-in-messages-is-available" target="_blank">updated its documentation</a> to outline four key requirements for using Gemini in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/top-5-tips-and-tricks-google-messages">Google Messages</a>: at least 6GB of RAM, the latest version of the app, a Google account, and Rich Communication Services (RCS) messaging enabled (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/06/17/gemini-google-messages-android/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a>).</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:333px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:225.23%;"><img id="EqrFdLznJt9tKAz8TJpVVN" name="gemini-google-messages.jpg" alt="Google Gemini in google messages" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/EqrFdLznJt9tKAz8TJpVVN.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="333" height="750" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Jay Bonggolto / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:333px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:225.23%;"><img id="KREUgESx4wg9bQTDTAzdPN" name="gemini-google-messages-2.jpg" alt="Google Gemini in google messages" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KREUgESx4wg9bQTDTAzdPN.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="333" height="750" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Jay Bonggolto / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:333px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:225.23%;"><img id="FaUuKVzjiHWASQVJQFJTGN" name="gemini-google-messages-3.jpg" alt="Google Gemini in google messages" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FaUuKVzjiHWASQVJQFJTGN.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="333" height="750" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Jay Bonggolto / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Google&apos;s conversational AI <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-messages-gemini-integration-capabilities-detailed">allows you to do things like draft messages or ask questions on various topics</a>. Initially, Gemini was only available on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">fan-favorite Android phones</a> like the Google Pixel 6, 7, and 8, and Samsung&apos;s Galaxy S22 series, including its recent foldable phones. Now, it&apos;s accessible on a broader range of devices.</p><p>Starting a chat with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini</a> is a no-brainer. Just tap the "Start chat" button in the Messages app, and you&apos;ll see the option to talk to Gemini right at the top. If you&apos;ve talked to Gemini before, you can jump back into the conversation right from your existing message thread.</p><p>Gemini is currently accessible in Messages in over 165 countries, including India. It only supports English for now, with French available only in Canada. Google recognizes this limitation and says it is committed to broadening Gemini&apos;s language support and global availability in the future.</p><p>Alongside this expansion, Google has launched the standalone Gemini app and its premium version, Gemini Advanced, in India. The app supports English and nine popular Indian languages.</p><p>In a recent <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.google/intl/en-in/company-news/technology/gemini-in-india-now-on-mobile-multilingual-and-more-powerful-for-your-everyday-tasks/" target="_blank">blog post</a>, Google highlighted the crucial role of the Indian market, celebrating Gemini&apos;s highly successful debut year. The post pointed out how users all over the country have been enthusiastically using Gemini for all sorts of tasks.</p><p>While India is the main focus of Google&apos;s recent Gemini expansion, the reach goes beyond its borders. The standalone Gemini app and Gemini Advanced have also been launched in other South Asian and Eurasian countries like Turkey, Bangladesh, Pakistan, and Sri Lanka.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/googles-gemini-ai-is-finally-available-for-more-android-phones-in-messages</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google broadens Gemini's reach in Google Messages to more devices and introduces the app in India. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">V4z4wipdL9omQ9dsodhhxD</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qSHqwRNvnGYqfTGUVpnExj.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 05:31:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qSHqwRNvnGYqfTGUVpnExj.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Gemini in google messages]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Gemini in google messages]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Earbuds with solid-state audio drivers are about to go mainstream ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>I have a lot of audio products in the house, ranging from $15 neckbuds to $1,499 custom IEMs with 12 drivers in each earbud. While there&apos;s a lot of differentiator when it comes to materials, tuning, and features, the unifying trait amongst all earbuds I have is that they use traditional dynamic drivers that use a magnetic coil to generate sound.</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Hardwired</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="5u6gVPowTCuSQ8NJeoktj7" name="lloyd-hardwired.png" caption="" alt="Android Central's LLoyd with a bionic eye" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5u6gVPowTCuSQ8NJeoktj7.png" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">In <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/hardwired">Hardwired</a>, AC Senior Editor Harish Jonnalagadda delves into all things hardware, including phones, storage servers, and routers.</p></div></div>
<p>That&apos;s changing with the introduction of solid-state audio drivers, such as those seen in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/creative-aurvana-ace-2-review">Creative Aurvana Ace 2</a>. The earbuds use a regular 10mm driver that&apos;s joined by an xMEMS solid-state driver that handles the treble and some of the mid-range frequencies the dynamic driver isn&apos;t able to hit.</p><p>Hybrid driver designs are a mainstay with IEMs, but what&apos;s different about xMEMS is that it uses silicon membranes combined with a monolithic piezo drive to produce sound, and that allows the driver unit to be considerably smaller. This means you can get earbuds with bigger batteries or other additional features that are the same size as existing designs.</p><p>What&apos;s interesting now is that xMEMS is rolling out a new solution dubbed Harding that makes it significantly easier for audio brands to get started with solid-state drivers. In an email interaction, I asked Mike Housholder, xMEMS&apos;s VP of Marketing and Business Development, about any design wins secured by the reference design.</p><p>"The Harding design files have been requested by and delivered to several ODMs as the starting point for their own 2-way design with xMEMS," noted Housholder. "Even before Harding, though, ODMs have already been replicating the core 2-way speaker module design for their own xMEMS-based projects. For example, the Creative Aurvana Ace and Ace 2 utilize a similar module design as Harding for their 2-way implementation."</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="dUeQxt9tnUfr8AQ3c34Gth" name="creative-aurvana-ace-2-26.jpg" alt="Creative Aurvana Ace and Ace 2" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dUeQxt9tnUfr8AQ3c34Gth.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Essentially, Harding is a reference design that uses the brand&apos;s Cowell driver, and its introduction should pave the way for plenty of new products that leverage the tech. The Aurvana Ace 2 also uses xMEMS&apos;s Cowell driver mated to a dynamic driver, and I asked about the difficulties involved in integrating the silicon driver with a traditional design. </p><p>Housholder said that the only challenge was in "taking a thoughtful approach to keeping the speaker module thin while designing the proper acoustics to enable each speaker driver to shine and deliver to their maximum potential. This was all achieved without compromising the mechanical design of the earbud and the fit of the other system components."</p><p>In addition to its Cowell driver, xMEMS has another product called the Montara Plus, and I&apos;m particularly interested in seeing that in a consumer product as it is a full-bandwidth transducer. Housholder mentioned that there are several IEM designs based on the Montara Plus in the works, and that they will be releasing within the next few months.</p><p>There has been a lot of innovation in the audio segment in recent years, and the introduction of solid-state tech has the potential to catalyze the industry — I can&apos;t wait.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/earbuds-with-solid-state-audio-drivers-are-about-to-go-mainstream</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Most earbuds have regular dynamic drivers, but solid-state audio drivers that use silicon are about to gain momentum.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Y5eF8dUpRuzoHBxH8qGgCE</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gX79PPyZY8FmGf6ZfSMP7j.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 03:02:42 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gX79PPyZY8FmGf6ZfSMP7j.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Creative Aurvana Ace 2 earbuds next to Ace]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Creative Aurvana Ace 2 earbuds next to Ace]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ 5 key ways to customize your Google Discover feed ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Google Discover offers a convenient bundle of relevant content that fits your interests without having to sift through a bunch of websites. But you may need to help Discover figure out what those interests are or steer it away from boring topics its algorithm <em>thinks</em> you like.</p><p>You can find Google Discover in several locations: the Google mobile app on Android, iOS, or iPad, in your mobile web browser of choice at google.com, or if you swipe right from your home screen on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phones</a>. Google has <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-discover-feed-for-desktops-in-the-works">tested Discover on desktop</a> but hasn&apos;t rolled out this feature officially.</p><p>Wherever you use Discover, we&apos;re here to help improve your experience. This is how to personalize your Google Discover feed, manage interests and topics, create collections of content to return to, like and save stories, and more.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-save-your-web-app-activity"><span>Save your Web & App activity</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="pKxuRTLLM4oc64FmHi9yTT" name="google-web-and-app-activity-screenshots.jpg" alt="Enabling web & app history in the Google app" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pKxuRTLLM4oc64FmHi9yTT.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The more collective, unified data Google has on your search results, the better your Google Discover results will be. Google usually pings and prods you into personalizing and sharing your Google data, but here&apos;s what to do if you haven&apos;t already done so.</p><p>In the <strong>Google app</strong>, tap your <strong>Profile pic or initials</strong>. Tap <strong>Your data in Search </strong>or <strong>Search History</strong>, whichever option is visible. Then tap the <strong>Controls</strong> tab and <strong>turn on Web & App Activity</strong> if you haven&apos;t already done so. You may also want to toggle <strong>Subsettings,</strong> like including your Google Assistant search results or including "activity from sites, apps, and devices that use Google services."</p><p>Then scroll further down the page and turn <strong>Personal results</strong> to On. Without this, your Discover feed won&apos;t include stories based on your search history. </p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-follow-sites-or-searches"><span>Follow sites or searches</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="rxTT8uVRMNztEkeFE9mviU" name="google-discover-follow-topics-screenshots.jpg" alt="How to follow topics and searches in Google Discover" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rxTT8uVRMNztEkeFE9mviU.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google Discover pulls its article suggestions from your entire Google browsing history. Some ways to customize Discover can only be done through Chrome.</p><p>Set Chrome as your default browser on Android and then go to any website you&apos;re interested in; if you tap the <strong>More (...) button</strong>, you&apos;ll see an option to <strong>Follow</strong> that website at the menu&apos;s bottom. That site&apos;s content should appear more frequently in Discover, in addition to the "Following" tab in Chrome.</p><p>Another simple method is to tap any story in Discover; it should open in Chrome (your default browser), where you can then tap the More button and follow that site.</p><p>Following isn&apos;t solely for websites. Let&apos;s say you frequently search for news or leaks of your favorite show or celeb — aka "Squid Game season 2 news" — or deals on a specific device. Simply enter that search term in Chrome or the Google app and then <strong>scroll down</strong> repeatedly until Google stops showing new results. At the very bottom, you&apos;ll see "More results" and <strong>Follow this search</strong>. Tap the second option, and Discover will prioritize news on that topic moving forward.</p><p>When you follow sites, your Discover feed will often show recent articles grouped together, which can help you keep track of things you may have missed.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-like-save-and-organize-articles"><span>Like, save, and organize articles</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="UTLVnmPgRH4pu3c7mH2S6U" name="google-discover-interests-screenshots.jpg" alt="The Interests tab in Google Discover, showing Likes, Topics, and Collections." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/UTLVnmPgRH4pu3c7mH2S6U.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It&apos;s worth spelling out the obvious here, even if most of you know this step already: telling Google that you like something is the best way to get future content in that same vein. If you tap on a Discover article, Google will assume that you find it interesting; you can make that assumption more concrete by "liking" articles afterward.</p><p>After you tap a Discover article and find it interesting, tap the <strong>X or ﹀ icon</strong> to return to Discover, then tap the <strong>heart icon</strong> to save it to your <strong>Liked</strong> articles in the <strong>Interests</strong> tab. </p><p>In Interests, you can <strong>+ Create</strong> a collection of your choosing. The tab will automatically create certain groupings for you based on Discover links, Google Maps addresses, or other saved/liked content. You might want to save your favorite restaurants or places you want to go or create a list of important articles to reference for your work. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="VgLcRV3R4vJ24Us6cqDoPU" name="google-discover-create-collection-screenshots.jpg" alt="How to create Collections of Liked articles in Google Discover" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VgLcRV3R4vJ24Us6cqDoPU.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Once you&apos;ve created that list, search for a relevant site, product, or page in the <strong>Google app</strong> and tap the <strong>save icon</strong> in the top-right corner, and it&apos;ll save that page to your latest collection. If you want it to go to a different collection, tap <strong>Edit</strong> in the "Saved to Collection" pop-up that appears and choose the right collection. </p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-unfollow-topics-and-sites"><span>Unfollow topics and sites</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="PqrPRWYjrZAjgrzkzEWPhT" name="google-discover-unfollow-topics-screenshots.jpg" alt="How to unfollow topics and websites on Google Discover" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PqrPRWYjrZAjgrzkzEWPhT.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Your first instinct using Discover will be to scroll past things you&apos;re uninterested in. Early on, my recommendation is to take the time to tell Google that you don&apos;t like certain websites or topics. </p><p>Under each Discover link, you&apos;ll see icons for <strong>liking</strong>, <strong>sharing</strong>, or <strong>more options</strong> (the ellipsis). That last button lets you tell Google that you&apos;re uninterested in a <strong>specific article</strong>, in a <strong>topic</strong>, or in <strong>content from a specific site</strong>. </p><p>Google might know that you&apos;re a gamer but not know that you&apos;re uninterested in Elden Ring or find one site untrustworthy, which is an important distinction. You may also like seeing YouTube results in Discover but decide to tap <strong>Don&apos;t show content from [Channel name] on YouTube</strong> instead of blocking all YouTube links. </p><p>If Google Discover tries to sell you something, you can tell Google you&apos;re uninterested or <strong>not shopping</strong> for this category, or to <strong>don&apos;t show product results for 30 days</strong> if you&apos;re uninterested in all marketing. </p><p>Don&apos;t worry if you say you&apos;re uninterested in a topic by mistake or change your mind. Tap <strong>more options > Manage your interests > Not interested</strong> under any article, and you&apos;ll find a list of topics and sites that are "hidden." Then tap the red icon next to any of them to make those results visible again. </p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-update-the-discover-carousel"><span>Update the Discover carousel</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="X2VE5fyBvkbbMRJrL6KD5V" name="google-discover-customize-carousel.jpg" alt="How to customize the Google Discover carousel" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/X2VE5fyBvkbbMRJrL6KD5V.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>At the top of Google Discover, you&apos;ll find a carousel showing your local weather and air quality, stocks and market trends, and sports scores. Google guesses what you&apos;re interested in, but you can make that clearer. </p><p><strong>Swipe left</strong> to the end of the Carousel and tap <strong>Settings</strong>. You can check or uncheck boxes for specific topics or tap <strong>Manage your sports/ finance interests</strong> to add specific stocks, funds, currencies, sports leagues, or teams to follow. </p>
<h2 id="figuring-out-how-to-personalize-your-google-discover-feed-isn-apos-t-complicated-2">Figuring out how to personalize your Google Discover feed isn&apos;t complicated</h2>
<p>Google doesn&apos;t have many hidden Google Discover tricks. Unlike Chrome, which has many more features and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini AI</a> tools, Discover is meant to be a straightforward feed for you to glance at and spot interesting, curated articles in a few seconds.</p><p>Making your Discover feed more personalized gives Google more data to build an advertising profile, which you might find annoying. But it also means less time scrolling through results that you find uninteresting or at sites that know how to game SEO but don&apos;t have anything worthwhile to tell you.</p><p>If you&apos;re looking for other guides on making better use of Google apps, check out our guide on our <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/top-google-chrome-tips-and-tricks">top 15 tips and tricks for Google Chrome</a> or how to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-customize-google-search-widget">customize the Google Search widget</a>.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-personalize-google-discover-feed</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google Discover takes your Google Search data and curates a useful list of articles, but Google will still get things wrong. For a better Discover experience, you need to weed out the junk and mark which articles you truly enjoyed. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">5orCjsnSLEDxiSQAN2oHK4</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fYGT9UPqiDFkuJgLgn2wke.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 18:39:29 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fYGT9UPqiDFkuJgLgn2wke.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Discover feed]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Discover feed]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Before you buy a Quest 2 on Prime Day, consider why you shouldn't ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The Meta Quest 2 (once called the Oculus Quest 2) is nearing its fourth birthday, and we&apos;re expecting to see some major deals happen this year, particularly once Amazon Prime Day rolls around, which we expect may happen in the coming weeks. We&apos;ve seen the headset hit as low as $99 leading up to the expected <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/amazon-prime-day-2024-dates-early-deals-and-what-to-expect-from-the-sale">Prime Day 2024</a> date, and a price like that is the only time you should still consider picking one up.</p><p>That&apos;s because, like any console that&apos;s been around for a while, buying one at a discount means you&apos;ll be missing out on some of the best new games and features that 2024 has delivered so far. Several <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/upcoming-meta-quest-games">upcoming Meta Quest games</a> will be Quest 3-exclusive, like Hitman 3 VR: Reloaded, Alien: Isolation, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/batman-arkham-shadow-gameplay-story-interview">Batman Arkham Shadow</a>, to name a few.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>Several upcoming games will be Quest 3-exclusive, but the Quest 2 can still play the classics.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>FOMO is a real thing, and seeing lots of new Meta Quest games come out with no Quest 2 support might make you regret your purchase. As a gamer, there are only a few reasons I&apos;d still recommend picking up a Quest 2 at a crazy discount this year.</p><p>First, it&apos;s a great way to get into VR gaming without spending much cash. The Quest 2 still runs 99% of Meta Quest games, including <em>all</em> of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-meta-quest-games">best Meta Quest games</a>. If you&apos;re currently not a VR gamer and just want to give it a try, this is an excellent way to do that.</p><p>I <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/you-should-play-more-video-games-with-your-kids">play VR games with my son</a> all the time, and he uses a Meta Quest 2. We have yet to run into any games that we want to play that don&apos;t support a Quest 2. While that&apos;ll eventually happen, the vast majority of games play on it just fine.</p><p>If you find that you enjoy the experience, I&apos;d recommend picking up a new headstrap and a new face pad from our list of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-accessories-oculus-quest-2">best Quest 2 accessories</a>.</p><p>Other folks might want to consider a potential $99 Quest 2 as a secondary headset for local multiplayer or even as a dedicated PCVR headset. The Quest 2 can be used <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-play-steamvr-quest">as a SteamVR headset</a> indefinitely, even when Meta eventually discontinues support for it in the future, giving the device some added longevity.</p><p>That would give you access to Half-Life: Alyx and many other games that aren&apos;t on Quest at all, although it won&apos;t solve the problem of giving you access to Meta-developed titles like Batman Arkham Shadows since that&apos;s Quest 3-exclusive.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="4PVrYFvAAVDASvrXjjVVeg" name="batman-arkham-shadow-official-trailer-still-batman-mob.jpg" alt="A still captured from the official story reveal trailer of Batman Arkham Shadow" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4PVrYFvAAVDASvrXjjVVeg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Camouflaj)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Not only that, but mixed reality content is only available on the Quest Pro and Quest 3. The Quest 2 does have passthrough video so you can see the room around you when you put the headset on, but it&apos;s very low resolution and only in black and white.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>PCVR gamers might want to consider the Quest 2 as a cheap option.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>All the latest mixed reality and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/an-update-just-fixed-the-biggest-quest-3-mixed-reality-problem">passthrough quality improvements</a> have been made for the Quest 3 since that headset features substantially higher-resolution cameras and delivers full-color video passthrough vision, as well. In other words, while the Quest 3 is a mixed-reality headset that helps meld the virtual and real worlds together, the Quest 2 is very much a VR-only headset that&apos;ll make you feel more isolated.</p><p>If newer games or mixed reality sound like things you want—but you still don&apos;t want to spend $500 on a regular Quest 3—rumor has it that Meta is launching the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-lite">Meta Quest 3s</a> later this year.</p><p>That headset is purported to pack in the same powerful processor as the more expensive Quest 3—which means it would support all Quest 3-exclusive games like the ones mentioned above—but pack in the Quest 2&apos;s last-generation lenses and some other cost-savings to keep the price around $299 or less.</p><p>That&apos;s obviously a lot more than a potential $99 Quest 2 sale, but if you can keep it around for a few years and still get access to all the latest games, it might very well be worth waiting for.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/why-you-should-not-buy-meta-quest-2-prime-day</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Getting a great Meta Quest 2 Prime Day deal will likely be possible this year, but you might not want to jump on it immediately. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">AbUeWcrjqLPKqxsvLJvjwV</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oRJJ7e7xYY5ufLnWTWxhGh.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 18:36:43 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oRJJ7e7xYY5ufLnWTWxhGh.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A Meta Quest 2 headset in front of a Meta Quest 3]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A Meta Quest 2 headset in front of a Meta Quest 3]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ US Surgeon General calls for a warning label on social media sites, citing mental health harms ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The U.S. Surgeon General Vivek Murthy published an op-ed in The New York Times this week, calling for a warning label on social media sites.</li><li>Murthy says the mental harms of social media sites warrant the label, which has been used in the past to highlight the dangers of substances like alcohol and tobacco. </li><li>The U.S. Surgeon General cannot require the warning label by himself. That would require a bill passed by Congress. </li></ul>
<hr>
<p>The debate of whether social media is linked to the declining mental health of adolescents has been raging on, and it reached new heights this week. It stated when Vivek Murthy, who is the U.S. Surgeon General, published an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/19/health/social-media-kids-mental-health.html" target="_blank">op-ed</a> in The New York Times calling for a warning label to be placed on social media sites, like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/instagram">Instagram</a> or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/us-bill-to-ban-tiktok-signed-into-law">TikTok</a>. Warning labels like the one proposed for social media have been used for alcohol and cigarettes in the past.</p><p>"It is time to require a surgeon general’s warning label on social media platforms, stating that social media is associated with significant mental health harms for adolescents," explained Murthy. "A surgeon general’s warning label, which requires congressional action, would regularly remind parents and adolescents that social media has not been proved safe."</p><p>Murthy cited the effectiveness of warning labels for tobacco products, as well as studies that referenced the harms associated with social media use. One <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamapsychiatry/fullarticle/2749480" target="_blank">study</a> found that children and teens who spent more than three hours daily on social media are twice as likely to face anxiety. Murthy notes that the average social media use for adolescents as of Summer 2023 was well above this threshold, at 4.8 hours. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="kZXxVkNFAG79iMrjjfKfaR" name="social-media-apps.jpg" alt="Social Media Apps" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kZXxVkNFAG79iMrjjfKfaR.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Source: Daniel Bader / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>However, Murthy&apos;s two statements — that "social media is associated with significant mental health harms for adolescents" and "social media has not been proved safe" — are two very different claims. It&apos;s somewhat agreed upon that we don&apos;t know the full effects of social media use at young ages, and we may not know the full effects for years or decades. The claim that social media has a direct association with mental health harms is more controversial.</p><p>"The results have been really mixed, with probably the consensus being that no, it’s not related," said Mitch Prinstein, a doctor who is the chief science officer for the American Psychological Association, in a New York Times <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/19/health/social-media-kids-mental-health.html" target="_blank">article</a>.</p><p>"It’s kind of like saying, &apos;Is the number of calories that you eat good for you or bad for you?&apos;" Prinstein continued. "It depends. Is it candy, or is it vegetables? If your child is spending all day on social media following The New York Times feed and talking about it with their friends, that’s probably fine, you know?"</p><p>Social media sites, and the companies and executives that run them, have already faced heavy congressional scrutiny. In fact, Prinstein himself <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.judiciary.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/2023-02-14%20-%20Testimony%20-%20Prinstein.pdf" target="_blank">testified</a> in front of the U.S. Senate Judiciary Committee about the effects of social media on children in February 2023. It is Congress, not Murthy, who has the authority to place a Surgeon General&apos;s warning label on social media sites and apps. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="nrtbBKVQkHk8G92xTx7MDR" name="Instagram-Threads-app-cover-screen-02.jpg" alt="The cover screen for the Instagram Threads social app on a Motorola Edge+ (2023)" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nrtbBKVQkHk8G92xTx7MDR.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>However, Murthy&apos;s position on social media does hold significant weight among lawmakers and government leaders. Gavin Newsom, the governor of California, already banned phone use in state schools following Murthy&apos;s call for a warning label. Even if the Surgeon General&apos;s warning label does not get passed by Congress, this conversation will certainly affect how governments and the public view social media sites.</p>
<h2 id="is-a-warning-label-the-right-call-2">Is a warning label the right call?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="8ZKDJUHPgucMghz5HGKrQZ" name="Instagram-logo.jpg" alt="Instagram logo on a smartphone lying flat on a table" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8ZKDJUHPgucMghz5HGKrQZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Jay Bonggolto / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Murthy makes a lot of good points about how to combat social media use among adolescents, but the warning label may be the least effective one. As one of Android Central&apos;s youngest resident "Gen Z-ers," I&apos;ve grown up with social media. I got my first internet-connected device when I was in elementary school and my first <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">smartphone</a> in middle school. However, that&apos;s different than what kids coming up today are facing. I had roughly 10 formative years without technology, the internet, and social media being a major part of my life. Younger generations will be lucky to get a few. </p><p>The best example of why a surgeon general&apos;s warning label will only be a small part of deterring social media usage by adolescents, ironically, is how it was used on cigarettes and tobacco products. Going through high school and college, I had never even heard of someone my age smoke an old-fashioned cigarette. It wasn&apos;t even talked about. </p><p>People in my generation knew about the dangers of cigarettes from a young age, watched loved ones and family friends who smoked suffer from potentially-fatal health problems, and saw what felt like an endless slate of ad campaigns against tobacco use throughout our early years. I&apos;d argue that it wasn&apos;t the Surgeon General&apos;s warning labels that all but eliminated cigarette use among adolescents. It was other things, from the age requirements, to the known health risks, to most importantly the change in public perception. </p><p>There&apos;s no reason to think combatting social media will require a different approach. A warning label only sparks a discussion, but the discussion has been front-and-center for years already. It&apos;ll take a change in behavior, with a bit of regulation, to make a real difference. That&apos;s why Murthy&apos;s other guidance — including "phone-free" zones, waiting until middle school to start social media usage, and education by parents and doctors — are likely to have a much greater effect than his proposed warning label. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/us-surgeon-general-calls-for-a-warning-label-on-social-media-sites-citing-mental-health-harms</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The addictive qualities of social media, as well as their associated mental health effects, are prompting U.S. health leaders to take action. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">eUFpGAZtgTT7NteHerrCuR</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XWYAStdB7tewzGVkxFGbAR.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 16:39:48 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XWYAStdB7tewzGVkxFGbAR.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Chris Wedel/Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Instagram logo on OnePlus 9]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Instagram logo on OnePlus 9]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ What is Lockdown mode, and why would you need it? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Phone makers offer several different ways to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-customize-your-lock-screen-on-android-14">unlock your phone</a> and all the various methods have pros and cons. You probably use biometrics to do it, but did you know you could use a built-in Lockdown mode to force your phone to fall back to the PIN or password on a one-time basis?</p><p>It&apos;s one of those things you might not have known about and maybe have no idea why anyone would want such a thing. It&apos;s also one of those things you need to know about before it&apos;s time to use it.</p>
<h2 id="what-is-lockdown-mode-2">What is Lockdown mode?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:117.04%;"><img id="evNrfy3xkB6qUVg9edeSu4" name="Lockdown.png" alt="Lockdown mode" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/evNrfy3xkB6qUVg9edeSu4.png" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1080" height="1264" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Future)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>When you set up <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">your new phone</a>, you&apos;re given the opportunity to set up a lock screen. You&apos;ll need to set a password or a PIN (Personal Identification Number), and you can then add a way to unlock your phone <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-does-android-save-your-fingerprints">using your fingerprints</a> or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-face-unlock-upgrade">face unlock</a>. </p><p>Most people choose to do this because it&apos;s convenient. Unlocking your phone decrypts its contents and it&apos;s also the method used for things like your bank&apos;s app or to spend money on digital purchases from Google Play or the App Store. Both Google and Apple have spent a lot of time to make sure <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/android-11s-new-biometric-security-means-all-your-apps-can-work-pixel-4s-face-unlock">biometrics are secure</a> and easy to use.</p>
<p>Every so often you need to enter that password or PIN to unlock your phone even if you have a fingerprint set. How often depends on which phone you have, but you&apos;ll see this at least once per day. You can force this behavior at any time by enabling <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-enable-and-use-lockdown-mode-pixel-4">Lockdown mode</a>.</p><p>Different phones have different ways to enable it. On a Google Pixel, just hold the power button for more than one second and you&apos;ll see it in the menu. On <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-enable-lockdown-mode-your-samsung-galaxy-phone">a Galaxy phone</a>, you enable it in the settings under <strong>Biometrics and Security</strong> then an icon will appear in your quick settings. On an iPhone, it&apos;s not called Lockdown mode, but you can disable FaceID on a one-time basis by pressing the side button and a volume button at the same time.</p>
<p>On <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phones</a>, lockdown mode disables biometrics and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/how-use-wear-os-watch-unlock">trusted devices</a>, voice recognition, and lock screen notifications. Every phone maker offers a way to enable it, and you probably didn&apos;t even know it was there.</p>
<h2 id="why-should-i-use-this-2">Why should I use this?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:66.75%;"><img id="gRmv4zTpYQ8pHa9K9G5vdM" name="samsung-galaxy-s21-ultra-fingerprint.jpg" alt="Samsung Galaxy S21 Ultra Fingerprint" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gRmv4zTpYQ8pHa9K9G5vdM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="534" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Source: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>You should use lockdown mode whenever you want to make sure the only way to unlock your phone is by knowing and entering the passcode. A lot of people will have a specific need for it such as being a heavy sleeper with sneaky roommates, but there is one common (and controversial) use case that some people call "cop mode."</p><p>In the United States, law enforcement <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://jsberrylaw.com/blog/can-police-officers-force-you-to-unlock-your-cellphone/">can force you</a> to place your fingertip on a sensor or keep your eyes open and head still to unlock your phone. However, they can not force you to provide a passcode. Lockdown mode is an easy way to keep law enforcement out of your phone.</p>
<p>I&apos;m not going to jump into the argument over this being good or bad because only you know if you want to give authorities access to your device. It&apos;s your phone, and it&apos;s filled with your information, so you get to decide who to share it with. Having said that, it&apos;s equally important to provide people who choose not to share it with a method to do so.</p><p>We see anecdotes about police or border agents rifling through someone&apos;s phone regularly on social media or YouTube. I&apos;m going to imagine the ones doing the rifling think they have a good reason for doing it. Some of us may disagree. Either way, it&apos;s a thing that does happen, so you need to decide how you feel about it before it can happen.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.38%;"><img id="J6zG83s5Ph6y4Nh3toQMYU" name="google-io-wallet-drivers-license.jpg" alt="screen shot from Google I/O" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/J6zG83s5Ph6y4Nh3toQMYU.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="451" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I happen to think that nobody, including law enforcement, should have free rein over my phone, but don&apos;t expect anyone to agree with me—you do you. If you think like me, know that some potential issues may arise.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet-to-expand-digital-drivers-license-support">Digital driver&apos;s licenses</a> are already here in some places and will be coming to your state/country eventually. However, there are some things you should be aware of. You cannot show your digital ID or a barcode to an officer if your phone is in Lockdown mode. You can&apos;t show proof of insurance via a digital ID card if your phone is in Lockdown mode. Failing to provide either of these things will lead to a situation that has you in violation of the law.</p>
<p>You also can&apos;t call your spouse or anyone else while your phone is in Lockdown mode, and entering Lockdown mode will stop any video recording in progress. It really does make your phone useless until you enter the passcode.</p><p>What&apos;s really important here is that phone makers and the people who write the software that powers them gave us a choice. You should know about it and how it works even if you have never decided to use it.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-is-lockdown-mode-and-why-would-you-need-it</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Lockdown mode requires a PIN or password to unlock your phone the next time it's used. Know how to do it and why you might want to before you need it. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">UoYfgWC7gVzzmgr6W3QTv4</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/H7pxJnSUSSLBy3dNadjs7M.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 16:06:28 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/H7pxJnSUSSLBy3dNadjs7M.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Amber Yellow Samsung Galaxy S24 colorway and its vibrant display]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Amber Yellow Samsung Galaxy S24 colorway and its vibrant display]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Xreal's new AR glass companion brings Android apps to life in 3D ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Priced at $200, the Xreal Beam Pro turns Play Store apps into 3D experiences when used with Xreal's AR glasses.</li><li>It works seamlessly with Xreal Air and Xreal Air 2 (Pro and Ultra models) via USB-C, transforming them into spatial computers.</li><li>The device is equipped with dual 50MP cameras for 3D images and videos, and dual USB-C ports for simultaneous charging and connection.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Xreal has introduced the Beam Pro, its newest AR product. But it&apos;s not another pair of AR glasses like before. Instead, it&apos;s an improved version of the Xreal Beam that tackles all the issues with the earlier model.</p><p>At this week&apos;s Augmented World Expo (AWE) in Southern California, Xreal <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/connecting-millions-of-apps-to-your-ar-glasses-xreal-launches-xreal-beam-pro-mobile-device-globally-at-awe-2024-302175517.html" target="_blank">unveiled</a> the Xreal Beam Pro. Priced at $200, this device turns Google Play Store apps into 3D experiences when used with Xreal&apos;s AR glasses.</p><p>The Beam Pro works with both the Xreal Air and Xreal Air 2, including the Pro and Ultra models. Just connect via USB-C to USB-C, and these AR glasses turn into powerful spatial computers, running on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review">Android 14</a> with Xreal&apos;s own NebulaOS on top.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:750px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="sdxZ2rkWWm4mAGufapWQQd" name="Xreal-Beam-Pro-plus-Xreal-Air-2-Ultra.png" alt="Xreal Beam Pro plus AR glasses" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sdxZ2rkWWm4mAGufapWQQd.png" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="750" height="750" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Xreal)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Xreal notes that the Beam Pro is the first AR device to seamlessly connect with the Play Store, letting users explore and enjoy a vast array of content in 3D environments.</p><p>The device might look like a regular <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phone</a>, but it&apos;s packed with features specifically for AR. Under the hood, it’s powered by a Qualcomm Snapdragon spatial companion processor.</p><p>It also sports a 6.5-inch 2400 x 1080 LCD display with a smooth 90Hz refresh rate. You can choose between 6GB or 8GB of RAM, and it offers 128GB or 256GB of storage.</p><p>The Xreal Beam Pro is more than just a companion device. Its touchscreen serves as a control center, letting you manage the visuals in your Xreal glasses. Plus, it still works like a regular smartphone screen, allowing you to handle Play Store apps and change your settings with ease.</p><p>But it stands out from regular smartphones with its dedicated focus on AR. Unlike typical phones, it features dual 50MP cameras designed to capture 3D images and spatial videos. It also comes with dual USB-C ports, so you can charge the device and connect your Xreal glasses simultaneously.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:66.68%;"><img id="pPncUgxAkEiZuTQLQWGUn7" name="Xreal-Beam-Pro.jpg" alt="Xreal Beam Pro back and screen" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pPncUgxAkEiZuTQLQWGUn7.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1707" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Xreal)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Beam Pro offers Wi-Fi 6 support and packs a 4300mAh battery. It will be available for a base price of $199, with shipments set to begin in mid-July.</p><p>Although future competition is uncertain, Xreal is on a mission to make AR accessible to everyone. The Beam Pro, with its affordable price, exemplifies this goal. This could be the tipping point that brings AR technology out of the niche market and into the mainstream.</p><p>That said, it&apos;s too soon to tell if intense competition is coming to the AR glasses market, but Xreal is clearly on a mission to make its augmented reality glasses accessible to everyone.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:57.17%;"><img id="vcCMmgjSr73xeA7DxnTDfA" name="Xreal-Beam-Pro-NebulaOS.jpg" alt="Xreal Beam Pro showing Play Store apps" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vcCMmgjSr73xeA7DxnTDfA.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1715" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Xreal)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Unlike Meta, which is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-horizon-os-announced-for-3rd-party-quest-headsets-xbox-asus-lenovo">having trouble filling its app store</a>, Xreal provides direct access to the vast library of Play Store apps in 3D, putting them at the forefront of the AR app ecosystem.</p><p>Additionally, Google&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/google-project-starline-astra-ar-glasses">recent showcase of AR glasses at this year&apos;s I/O conference suggests it&apos;s also ramping up its focus on AR</a>, which could lead to more competition.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/xreals-new-ar-glass-companion-brings-android-apps-to-life-in-3d</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ XReal has dropped a $200 mobile device that turns your Android apps into AR experiences. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">6hrbdQ3ZUDAP4vrXSuGG6N</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yhzdVLiTqUo3F9Pk4WedHU.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 13:40:47 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yhzdVLiTqUo3F9Pk4WedHU.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Xreal]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Xreal Beam Pro in hand]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Xreal Beam Pro in hand]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>