<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 18:26:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung's fine print teases a 'Tab S10 FE series' as rumors surface ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Rumors state Samsung is working on a set of Galaxy Tab S10 FE tablets as two model numbers are reportedly discovered.</li><li>The company then seemingly confirmed such a rumor as its U.S. website's fine print teases a "Galaxy Tab S10 FE series" in its promotion sector.</li><li>The Tab S9 FE launched with a 10.9-inch LCD in October 2023; however, it seems its next Fan Edition Tab could debut much earlier in 2025.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Samsung's next affordable tablet is reportedly on the way after being teased in the most unlikely way.</p><p>Initially, rumors from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.galaxyclub.nl/samsung/galaxy-tab-s10-fe/">Galaxy Club</a> (Dutch) claimed that Samsung was working on a "Galaxy Tab S10 FE" (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.gsmarena.com/samsung_galaxy_tab_s10_fe_series_gets_mentioned_on_samsungcom-news-65537.php">GSMArena</a>). The publication's alleged evidence is a set of model numbers: SM-X520 and SM-X526B, which are reportedly tied to the upcoming FE tablet. However, Samsung's U.S. website might've confirmed these suspicions.</p><p>The post highlights <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/tablets/galaxy-tab-s10/offers/#:~:text=a%20Tab%20S10%20series%2C%20or%20Tab%20S10%20FE%20series%20device%20by%207/31/2025.">the offer section</a> of the official Tab S10 page. Tucked in the fine print, the Korean OEM specifically mentions the Galaxy Tab S10 FE alongside the flagship S10 tablets.</p><p>More specifically, Samsung states, "The 1-year free access to Goodnotes offer is open to participants in the United States who purchase and activate a Tab S10 series, or Tab S10 FE series device by 7/31/2025."</p><p>This is the only mention the company makes of an FE tablet for the latest series on the page. The initial rumor states that the originally spotted model numbers could point to its support connectivity. The post adds that this could indicate that Samsung is creating a Tab S10 FE with basic connectivity (Wi-Fi/Bluetooth) and one that supports 5G connectivity.</p><p>Elsewhere, the publication can "confirm" that the Tab S10 FE will receive a "better main camera" than its predecessor, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/samsung-galaxy-tab-s9-fe-hands-on">Tab S9 FE</a>. The device will supposedly pick up a 12MP lens instead of the same 8MP camera.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="K5nzhcaMgzmwmzHGhVojnR" name="samsung-galaxy-tab-s9-fe-on-counter-1.jpg" alt="Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 FE on counter" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/K5nzhcaMgzmwmzHGhVojnR.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Samsung slipped up and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/samsung-accidentally-confirms-galaxy-tab-s9-fe">accidentally revealed</a> the Tab S9 FE and S9 FE Plus last year in August. The company's French website alluded to the devices, which rolled out two months after <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/samsung-galaxy-tab-s9-fe-hands-on">in October</a>. Seeing as it's happened again — albeit much sooner than last time — rumors are swirling about <em>when </em>it might launch.</p><p>The Tab S9 FE launched with a 10.9-inch LCD with a max 120Hz refresh rate. The company also plugged its midrange Exynos 1380 SoC into the tablets. Specification rumors are still unknown, but we can likely expect a wealth of Galaxy AI to enter whenever this next-gen FE tablet launches.</p><p>One possibility, as noted by the publication, could be a dual launch alongside the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/sasmung-galaxy-s25-fe-could-be-called-s25-slim">Galaxy S25 "Slim." </a>The launch of this thinner phone is still up in the air; however, tipsters claim it could occur "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/a-slim-galaxy-s25-might-be-samsungs-answer-to-apples-rumored-thin-iphone-17">a few months</a>" after the January 2025 debut of the main S25 flagship trio. If true, then perhaps we're looking at a spring (or summer) launch for Samsung's slimmer phone <em>and </em>its Fan Edition tablets.</p><p>The post speculates about a potential Tab S10 FE Plus, but there's nothing concrete (as of now) to support such a theory.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/samsung-teases-tab-s10-fe-series-rumors-surface</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung seemingly teased an upcoming Fan Edition Tab S10. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">t7MvVoHPugDw4V9ouMrdbh</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ctKWckFi7imNB8LD8YkbWA.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 18:21:07 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ctKWckFi7imNB8LD8YkbWA.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 FE in keyboard case with Galaxy S23 FE]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 FE in keyboard case with Galaxy S23 FE]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Messages will help you thwart ads and spam in a future update ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>In certain regions, RCS can be used by businesses to deliver unwanted ads and spam to users.</li><li>Google Messages now includes a <strong>STOP</strong> button on these chats, which simply reminds users you can often reply "Stop" to end these messages.</li><li>This option likely won't replace the "block and report" button for many RCS users.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google Messages already has plenty of built-in features that help users combat spam, but it may be getting a new option soon. In some places, verified businesses can send what are known as <strong>RCS Business Messages</strong>, which can be essentially advertisements and spam. Currently, the only way to avoid these messages are to block and report the sender when they arrive.</p><p>In a future update to Google Messages, that might be changing. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/google-messages-stop-button-rcs-ads-apk-teardown-3503991/" target="_blank">Android Authority</a> uncovered a new Google Messages feature in an APK teardown of <strong>Google Messages v20241125_04 beta</strong> that will let users opt-out of some spam messages with one click. This button reads <strong>STOP</strong>, and appears next to the <strong>Open link</strong> button in Google Messages RCS chats. It's a simple, but helpful, addition to Google Messages that could be made public in a new update to the app.</p><p>After you click the STOP button, Google Messages will send the "STOP" message to the sender of an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/what-rcs-and-why-it-important-android">RCS Business Message</a>. This <em>should</em> take you off the mailing list for the specific advertiser or spammer that sent the message, because STOP and START are two keywords that these bots often recognize. In other words, the upcoming Google Messages feature doesn't do anything more than make sending that STOP message quicker.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:322px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:217.08%;"><img id="3t8492NsspfzhmzbiQcwo9" name="Google-Messages-Stop-Button" alt="The stop button for RCS Business Messages in Google Messages." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3t8492NsspfzhmzbiQcwo9.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="322" height="699" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The reason this <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-messages-first-things-to-do">Google Messages</a> update might be helpful is that not every Android user knows about the STOP and START commands. There are plenty of people who either delete the messages as they come in, or block the sender. Both of these actions can get tedious over time, especially since the STOP button (in theory) unenrolls your phone number, which means pressing STOP will keep you free of spam regardless of what phone you're using or if you upgrade.</p><p>Because the new STOP button simply sends a text message, you can manually text START to receiving RCS Business Messages from that sender again. You still need to do this on a per-sender basis, unfortunately. Some users will likely want to use the <strong>report & block sender</strong> button too, which still appears above the compose field in Google Messages.</p><p>This change was spotted in a pre-release version of the Google Messages app, so it's unclear when (or if) it will release publicly. However, the fact that the feature is functional for beta testers is a good sign it could debut soon.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-messages-will-help-you-thwart-ads-and-spam-in-a-future-update</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Getting annoyed with the level of RCS ads and spam in Google Messages? A fix might be coming soon.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">ee87L8frAiCzCqufcvgGJJ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/orJ6J2eyFuqyP7yt24rCp7.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 18:17:16 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/orJ6J2eyFuqyP7yt24rCp7.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Magic Compose in the Google Messages app making my text more Shakespearean ]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Magic Compose in the Google Messages app making my text more Shakespearean ]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The best Kindle e-reader EVER just got its biggest discount EVER for Black Friday — how can this be? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Readers, rejoice — Amazon&apos;s Black Friday sale is officially here, and the iconic retailer has just dropped a truly unmissable Kindle deal. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CFPJYX7P"><strong>Go pick up the Kindle Paperwhite before the holiday sale ends and you&apos;ll get 19% off AND three free months of Kindle Unlimited</strong></a> at no additional cost. That&apos;s the biggest discount that the e-reader has EVER received from the retailer. </p>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/blackfriday"><em><strong>Amazon's Black Friday sale is LIVE —  see the full list of deals</strong></em></a></li></ul>
<p>The 12th-Gen Paperwhite topped our list of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-amazon-kindle">best Kindle e-readers</a>, and it isn&apos;t hard to see why. The lightweight device boasts the perfect blend of specs and versatility, with a 7-inch, 300ppi anti-glare display, an upgraded processor that&apos;s said to be 20% faster than previous generations, and up to 12 weeks of battery life on a single charge! The slab also weighs less than half a pound, so it&apos;s easy to travel with, plus you get IPX8 water resistance and Bluetooth support for Audible. </p>
<h2 id="save-paper-by-buying-the-paperwhite-this-black-friday-2">Save paper by buying the Paperwhite this Black Friday</h2>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="9a4451bc-4dac-4f60-9d58-0d3329216f35" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$159.99" data-dimension48="$159.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CFPJYX7P" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:785px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="46cgweRgjuodAM2PY4rpsa" name="Amazon Kindle Paperwhite black.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/46cgweRgjuodAM2PY4rpsa.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="785" height="785" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Kindle Paperwhite (16GB) 12th Gen, 2024:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CFPJYX7P" data-dimension112="9a4451bc-4dac-4f60-9d58-0d3329216f35" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$159.99" data-dimension48="$159.99"><del>$159.99</del> <strong>$129.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>The Kindle Paperwhite is arguably the best e-reader Amazon has ever produced, with ridiculously-good battery life, a display that's easy to read in any light, and 20% faster performance than its predecessor. Grab this slab from Amazon during the Black Friday sale and you'll enjoy a historic 19% off plus three months of Kindle Unlimited for free!</p>
<p>👀<strong>Alternate Black Friday deal: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CNV9F72P"><strong>Get 23% off the standard Amazon Kindle (16GB) at Amazon </strong></a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CFPJYX7P" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="9a4451bc-4dac-4f60-9d58-0d3329216f35" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$159.99" data-dimension48="$159.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Black Friday deals</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Black Friday Google Pixel deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Black Friday Motorola deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024">Black Friday Samsung deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Black Friday OnePlus deals</a></p></div></div>
<p>The purchase of this Kindle Paperwhite also comes with three months of Kindle Unlimited at no additional cost. That&apos;s a value of over $30 dropped straight into your pocket, not to mention instant access to millions of titles as soon as you boot up your device. If your New Year&apos;s resolution is to read more books in 2025, this is a great way to get started. </p><p>One problem with the Black Friday deal is that this particular model comes with Lock Screen Ads. While these advertisements won&apos;t interrupt you while you&apos;re reading, they <em>will </em>show up on the device&apos;s lock screen. If that&apos;s a problem, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DDZJS3SB"><strong>you can spend 20 more bucks to get the ad-free version of the device</strong></a>, which is also chilling with a 16% discount. </p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/the-best-kindle-e-reader-ever-just-got-its-biggest-discount-ever-for-black-friday-how-can-this-be</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Amazon's Black Friday sale is carving a record-smashing 19% off the Kindle Paperwhite, plus you'll get three months of Kindle Unlimited for free! ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">iYuPCWKRUDGGAodJSWTsXJ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bMQm9CwhVmTFhTs7za2UkR.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 17:15:31 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bMQm9CwhVmTFhTs7za2UkR.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Amazon]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Amazon Kindle Paperwhite 2024 lifestyle render]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Amazon Kindle Paperwhite 2024 lifestyle render]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Raycon's The Magic Power Bank Slim is indeed magically thin and 30% cheaper this Black Friday! ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>It&apos;s MagSafe, it&apos;s got Qi2 wireless charging, and it&apos;s literally the size of a credit card. Raycon&apos;s The Magic Power Bank Slim is a 5,000mAh power bank that usually costs about $50, but not this fine Black Friday. For a limited time, you can grab this sleek little power bank for 30% off, costing you only <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://rayconglobal.com/collections/power-tech/products/magic-power-bank-slim"><strong>$34.99 at Raycon</strong></a>.</p><p>I test hundreds of charging accessories of all sorts every year. It&apos;s my job to test gadgets and tell you whether they&apos;re worth buying, so you can trust my recommendations. The Magic Power Bank Slim is so aptly named because it is impossibly thin and lightweight. At 8mm thin, it is significantly more compact than my previous favorites, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/ecoflow-rapid-magnetic-power-bank-5000mah">EcoFlow Rapid Magnetic Power Bank</a> and the older <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/dont-sleep-on-these-zendure-charging-accessories-during-black-friday">Zendure SuperMini 10,000mAh</a>.</p><p>Whether you&apos;re buying a Samsung Galaxy Watch 7 or a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare#xenforo-comments-1072672">Google Pixel 9 Pro this Black Friday</a>, be sure to score a couple of knicknacks like this too. Accessories see healthy discounts during holidays like Black Friday and Cyber Monday, so make the most of it.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="9976a698-4234-43c5-a17e-069712ebabd2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Raycon The Magic Power Bank Slim: $49.99" data-dimension48="Raycon The Magic Power Bank Slim: $49.99" href="https://rayconglobal.com/collections/power-tech/products/magic-power-bank-slim" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:874px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="mrqxNRozCJcGfVqLdrpW5B" name="Raycon The Magic Power Bank Slim.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mrqxNRozCJcGfVqLdrpW5B.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="874" height="874" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Raycon The Magic Power Bank Slim: </strong><a href="https://rayconglobal.com/collections/power-tech/products/magic-power-bank-slim" data-dimension112="9976a698-4234-43c5-a17e-069712ebabd2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Raycon The Magic Power Bank Slim: $49.99" data-dimension48="Raycon The Magic Power Bank Slim: $49.99" data-dimension25=""><del>$49.99</del><strong> $34.99 at Raycon</strong></a></p>
<p>Charge your phone wirelessly via this Qi2 magnetic power bank on the go. Equipped with 15W Qi2 wireless charging as well as 20W USB-C PD wired charging, this portable battery pack is versatile, lightweight, and only 8mm wide. Score 30% off the Raycon The Magic Power Bank Slim while this Black Friday offer lasts.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://rayconglobal.com/collections/power-tech/products/magic-power-bank-slim" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="9976a698-4234-43c5-a17e-069712ebabd2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Raycon The Magic Power Bank Slim: $49.99" data-dimension48="Raycon The Magic Power Bank Slim: $49.99" data-dimension25="">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>you want a 5,000mAh portable power bank that is thin, lightweight, and Qi2 compatible.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>you want faster wired charging, larger capacity, or more ports.</p><p>There are hundreds, if not thousands of MagSafe power banks and chargers in the wild. But not all of them are worth your time and money. Brands like Anker and UGREEN make the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-battery-packs">best portable power banks and batteries</a>, but they also cost a pretty penny to purchase. Not with Raycon, though, because the brand&apos;s offerings are more budget-friendly.</p><p>The Raycon power bank might seem insufficient to some, but trust me, you don&apos;t need more than 5,000mAh on the go. When you run out for groceries, go to work, or maybe head to the gym for a workout session, you probably already have at least 50% battery on your phone. And even if it&apos;s dying, 5,000mAh is the size of the average phone battery, so it&apos;s good enough to top up your device to 100%.</p><p>Qi2 wireless charging is nice to have because this helps align your phone&apos;s wireless charging coils with the power bank. Magnetism ensures nothing moves around and energy is transferred efficiently. Of course, 15W isn&apos;t very fast, but recharging at that speed without a cable has its perks.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/raycons-the-magic-power-bank-slim-is-indeed-magically-thin-and-30-percent-cheaper-this-black-friday</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Need a power bank? You can get Raycon's The Magic Power Bank Slim 5,000mAh battery pack for less than $40 with this Black Friday deal! ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">fGoCdrPC2Kxh3aDrrxpJUe</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/EWTHbFMBM72KmNQsWV5rrk.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 16:52:23 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/EWTHbFMBM72KmNQsWV5rrk.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Raycon The Magic Power Bank Slim and EcoFlow RAPID Magnetic Power Bank 5000mAh]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Raycon The Magic Power Bank Slim and EcoFlow RAPID Magnetic Power Bank 5000mAh]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ FCC approves T-Mobile and Starlink's direct-to-cell service ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>T-Mobile and Starlink have been working since 2022 to bring direct-to-cell satellite service to T-Mobile subscribers.</li><li>Now, the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) has signed off, in an industry-first.</li><li>The commission says bringing satellite cell service to mobile customers has "critical public interest benefits."</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Following the program's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.t-mobile.com/news/un-carrier/t-mobile-takes-coverage-above-and-beyond-with-spacex?clickref=1100lzRCM8YV" target="_blank">announcement</a> in 2022, T-Mobile and Starlink are moving ahead with their plan to bring direct-to-cell satellite service to T-Mobile customers after gaining regulatory approval this week. The U.S. Federal Communications Commission signed off on the two companies' direct-to-cell service, with a few caveats, it said in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://docs.fcc.gov/public/attachments/DA-24-1193A1.pdf" target="_blank">filing</a>. Albeit limited, the FCC's approval is an industry-first for direct-to-cell connectivity (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/27/24307394/starlink-spacex-tmobile-direct-to-cell-satellite-fcc-approval" target="_blank">The Verge</a>).</p><p>The initiative is all about eradicating dead spots, in other words, the areas left uncovered or unreliable by traditional cellular service. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/carriers/t-mobile">T-Mobile</a> and Starlink, a network of SpaceX broadband satellites, want to help people connect their phones to space satellites when cell towers can't cut it.</p><p>We've seen similar implementations of this, like Emergency SOS via satellite by Apple and Globalstar. However, many of these implementations have been restricted to emergency use only, whereas T-Mobile and SpaceX want to bring the tech mainstream. Ben Longmier, the senior director of satellite engineering at SpaceX, said that an employee beta service should be activated "soon" in the U.S.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Thank you to @NASA , @NTIAgov , @NSF , for their coordination work with us, and all of our telco partners, especially @TMobile !

We hope to activate employee beta service in the US soon.<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1861496195988025853">November 26, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>Part of the reason the FCC gave T-Mobile and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/starlink-home-internet-review">Starlink</a> the green light is because the commission thinks it'll benefit the public. "The Commission recognized that satellite-to-device connectivity can support critical public interest benefits," it wrote in the filing, "including ubiquitous connectivity, access to 911 service from remote areas, technological advancement, and innovative spectrum use."</p><p>However, SpaceX is still awaiting approval for a few specific measures. It wants to boost radio emission power to support more demanding use cases for satellite connectivity, like video calls. The FCC hasn't granted approval for this yet, and the other major carriers are pushing back. AT&T and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/carriers/verizon-wireless">Verizon</a> worry that the higher radio emission power of its satellites could interfere with their cellular networks.</p><p>Meanwhile, those two companies are working with AST SpaceMobile <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/after-a-string-of-carrier-service-outages-satellite-messaging-could-bring-stability">to develop a competing service</a> to T-Mobile and Starlink's upcoming offering.</p><p>“The FCC is actively promoting competition in the space economy by supporting more partnerships between terrestrial mobile carriers and satellite operators to deliver on a single network future that will put an end to mobile dead zones," said Jessica Rosenworcel, the chair of the FCC, in a statement to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/us-agency-approves-t-mobile-spacex-license-extend-coverage-dead-zones-2024-11-26/" target="_blank">Reuters</a>.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/carriers/fcc-approves-t-mobile-and-starlinks-direct-to-cell-service</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The FCC says supplementing cell towers with satellites has "critical public interest benefits." ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">epJvjUrnuZxXFYmwoDh9yH</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/du63zwPBbYBDFHWBTnwQEF.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 16:30:27 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Carriers]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/du63zwPBbYBDFHWBTnwQEF.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The T-Mobile Logo on a Google Pixel 8 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The T-Mobile Logo on a Google Pixel 8 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ This modern Game Boy runs Android and is on sale for Black Friday ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Anbernic is probably a company you've never heard of, but it offers a wide array of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/best-android-gaming-handheld-consoles">gaming handhelds</a> in different shapes and sizes. The RG406V is one such example, as it's basically a Game Boy on steroids, and is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/RG406V-Handheld-Multi-Touch-Emulator-Bluetooth/dp/B0DH267157/"><strong>$50 off for Black Friday</strong></a>.</p><p>Unlike some of Anbernic's more retro-focused handhelds, the RG406V is running Android, offering more versatility than you'd expect. It's powered by the Unisoc T820 paired with 8GB of RAM, letting you many of your favorite Android games, along with those retro classics.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="6c24d27f-69f1-4607-ad56-fa688aa55354" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Did you know that the world of gaming handhelds goes far beyond the likes of the Steam Deck or ROG Ally? The Anbernic RG406V is an incredible and modern Game Boy powered by Android and is on sale for $50 off over at Amazon." data-dimension48="Did you know that the world of gaming handhelds goes far beyond the likes of the Steam Deck or ROG Ally? The Anbernic RG406V is an incredible and modern Game Boy powered by Android and is on sale for $50 off over at Amazon." data-dimension25="$199.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/RG406V-Handheld-Multi-Touch-Emulator-Bluetooth/dp/B0DH267157/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="sNhTKTgyPmURvdAAcGLCiC" name="anbernic-rg406v-square" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sNhTKTgyPmURvdAAcGLCiC.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="800" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>Did you know that the world of gaming handhelds goes far beyond the likes of the Steam Deck or ROG Ally? The Anbernic RG406V is an incredible and modern Game Boy powered by Android and is <strong>on sale for $50 off</strong> over at Amazon.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/RG406V-Handheld-Multi-Touch-Emulator-Bluetooth/dp/B0DH267157/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="6c24d27f-69f1-4607-ad56-fa688aa55354" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Did you know that the world of gaming handhelds goes far beyond the likes of the Steam Deck or ROG Ally? The Anbernic RG406V is an incredible and modern Game Boy powered by Android and is on sale for $50 off over at Amazon." data-dimension48="Did you know that the world of gaming handhelds goes far beyond the likes of the Steam Deck or ROG Ally? The Anbernic RG406V is an incredible and modern Game Boy powered by Android and is on sale for $50 off over at Amazon." data-dimension25="$199.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Black Friday</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text"><strong>-</strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare"><strong>Black Friday Google Pixel deals</strong></a><strong><br>-</strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024"><strong>Black Friday Samsung deals</strong></a><strong><br>-</strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more"><strong>Black Friday Motorola deals<br></strong></a><strong>-</strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals"><strong>Black Friday OnePlus deals</strong></a></p></div></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>You want a modern Game Boy that runs Android so you can enjoy both modern and retro games.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>You're looking for a handheld that's a bit more powerful or one that isn't quite as massive.</p>
<p>Along with looking like a massive Game Boy, the RG406V sports a 4-inch IPS display, along with a 5,500mAh battery that will last for at least eight hours. As for controls, we have the full gamut, complete with dual joysticks to go with the traditional D-pad and ABXY buttons.</p><p>One of the potential concerns when playing games on any handheld is overheating. The RG406V combats this with a built-in fan and "automatic heat dissipation." However, it's really not something that I've ever really dealt with, as it's not like I'm trying to emulate <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://amazon.com/dp/B0CHBN8QD9">Switch</a> games or higher-end titles.</p><p>When it comes to storage, the RG406V offers 128GB of built-in storage, but there's also a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-micro-sd-card-android">microSD card slot</a>, which is simply wonderful. While you can't install apps and games to the microSD card, it's perfect for being able to access and store your retro gaming library.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/this-modern-game-boy-runs-android-and-is-on-sale-for-black-friday</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Anbernic RG406V lets you play many of your favorite retro and modern games in a familiar form factor and is on sale for Black Friday. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">pU2PY7XLaJcfpy6QurmUFH</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TcunmhdCkXXt3neJb5zYSa.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 16:05:50 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ andrew.myrick@futurenet.com (Andrew Myrick) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TcunmhdCkXXt3neJb5zYSa.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Anbernic RG406V next to Game Boy DMG playing Pokemon Yellow]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Anbernic RG406V next to Game Boy DMG playing Pokemon Yellow]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Amazfit Balance review: Weeks of battery life in a featherweight body ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Amazfit refreshes its vast lineup of affordable smartwatches and fitness trackers on a regular basis. There are so many releases happening all the time that it's hard to keep up with all of them sometimes.</p><p>The Amazfit Balance is a fairly new entrant to the brand's portfolio that "takes the baton" from the popular GTR and GTS series. It seems to be very similar to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/amazfit-gtr-mini-review">Amazfit GTR Mini</a>, which I also reviewed, but it clearly costs more and has a lot more to offer. Next to the very <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch">best Android smartwatches</a>, the Balance is super budget-friendly.</p><p>If you were to judge this wearable solely based on the design, you would be deceived for it is far lighter than it looks. Yet somehow, Amazfit packed an enormous battery into this lightweight smartwatch. The Amazfit Balance brings a lot to the table, but can it compete with a Wear OS smartwatch? Let's find out.</p>

<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-price-and-availability"><span>Price and availability</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4096px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="S9ZHSccc36QHj6CCdA4RoV" name="Amazfit Balance" alt="Amazfit Balance smartwatch" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/S9ZHSccc36QHj6CCdA4RoV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4096" height="2304" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Amazfit Balance was released in September 2023 and retails for $199.99 generally. It is widely available to purchase from various retailers such as Amazon, Best Buy, and Walmart.</p><p>You can buy the Amazfit Balance in Midnight Black with a dark case and a black silicon band or in Sunset Grey with a light gray case and an adjustable, multicolored woven band.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-all-the-pros"><span>All the pros</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4096px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="B9JwRoTvztHzE7tBEaTfdV" name="Amazfit Balance" alt="Amazfit Balance smartwatch" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/B9JwRoTvztHzE7tBEaTfdV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4096" height="2304" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Amazfit Balance intends to succeed two of the brand's most successful smartwatch series, the GTR and GTS models. No wonder the Balance combines all the best elements of the two lineups, delivering a durable yet lightweight design at an amicable price.</p><p>Despite its huge 1.5-inch AMOLED screen, the Amazfit Balance still manages to weigh a mere 35g. This, combined with the woven band, make the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-amazfit-smartwatch">Amazfit smartwatch</a> extremely comfortable for daily wear. It's easy to forget that you have a smartwatch on your wrist.</p><p>As you'd expect, the Amazfit Balance has over 150 sports modes, SpO2 tracking, heart rate monitoring, sleep tracking, menstrual tracking, and a wide array of other health and fitness tracking metrics and sensors. It's quite durable too, touting 5 ATM water resistance.</p><p>What will definitely blow your mind, as it did mine, is the insane battery life. This thing can go on for two weeks easily with a single charge, even with moderate to heavy use. And if you're a light user, this can easily go up to 20 days in my experience.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3485px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="3EeQpiajkQnqWGS3tyyuRV" name="Amazfit Balance" alt="Amazfit Balance smartwatch" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3EeQpiajkQnqWGS3tyyuRV.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="3485" height="1960" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4096px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="8sN2PwAwAovu4As5JMDUgV" name="Amazfit Balance" alt="Amazfit Balance smartwatch" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8sN2PwAwAovu4As5JMDUgV.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4096" height="2304" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Amazfit tried its utmost to bolster the Amazfit Balance with a healthy selection of apps and features. There are many more third-party apps available via the Zepp app on smartphones. At long last, Amazfit also added the ability to respond to messages on the Balance smartwatch. Users can type out a response using the wearable's QWERTY keyboard, pick one of the preset responses, or even use AI's help to reply to messages.</p><p>The Amazfit Balance has a microphone and speaker onboard, so you don't have to rely on your phone. Local storage and Bluetooth enable you to store music on the watch and stream it to your earbuds or headphones directly from the watch itself.</p><p>Speaking of AI, Amazfit followed in the footsteps of Samsung, Google, and Apple by incorporating AI-based features into the Amazfit Balance. You can use Alexa on your watch or change the assistant to Zepp Flow, which is powered by GPT-4o. Other AI-based features of the watch include Zepp Coach and Zepp Aura. AI is baked into the core of the Balance, collecting and compiling your health and fitness data to intelligently make recommendations.</p><p>Some features require you to update the Amazfit Balance. Although it runs Zepp OS 3.5 out of the box, you can upgrade it to the latest Zepp OS 4 immediately to get all the latest features.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-unignorable-cons"><span>Unignorable cons</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="gZ6MJ9aGTXkz5D5HSDv4oA" name="Amazfit-Balance-apps" alt="The Amazfit Balance on a man's wrist above a steering wheel, showing the full app drawer." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gZ6MJ9aGTXkz5D5HSDv4oA.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Faud Satmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While the Amazfit Balance is chock full of fitness tracking options, not all of them work perfectly. The pedometer does not count steps accurately, logging incorrect numbers randomly at times.</p><p>And while I am grateful for the newly incorporated ability to respond to messages or notifications on the watch, the feature gets stuck a lot. I faced this issue with Slack and Gmail where the Amazfit Balance refused to let me respond. Hopefully, future patches will smoothen out such glitches.</p><p>The watch has other caveats as well. Sure, NFC payments are available, but only through the Zepp Pay app. There's no option to install Google Wallet, Samsung Pay, or Apple Pay. No matter how secure Amazfit promises Zepp Pay to be, not everyone will trust such a lesser-known app with their financial details. In all honesty, I did not enter my details into it either. Not to mention, not every region's banks and cards will support the app either.</p><p>Lastly, Amazfit should seriously consider adding an LTE variant of the watch. If it has contactless payments, the Amazfit Balance can be used on its own without relying on a smartphone. It's ideal for non-intrusive workouts where you don't want to bring your phone along, so an LTE smartwatch can sub as a replacement for payments, navigation, and emergency calls. You can't use the Amazfit Balance for any of that unless it's connected to a phone that has an internet connection.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-competition"><span>Competition</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="o4GsGQG7Rcu7KwiCTcj763" name="samsung-galaxy-s24-fe-galaxy-watch-fe-3.jpg" alt="Samsung Galaxy Watch FE with Galaxy S24 FE" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/o4GsGQG7Rcu7KwiCTcj763.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Although the Amazfit Balance is already very cheap, you can get an even more capable smartwatch for the same retail price. I'm talking about the Samsung Galaxy Watch FE, a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wear-os-watch">Wear OS smartwatch</a> that comes with Wear OS 4 installed out of the box.</p><p>Even though the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-fe-launch">Galaxy Watch FE</a> is basically a revamped version of the Galaxy Watch 4, it has access to hundreds of apps thanks to Wear OS 4. Equipped with a more powerful processor and flagship-level sensors, the Samsung smartwatch beats the Amazfit Balance without a doubt.</p><p>The one arena where Amazfit stands a chance is the battery life, which is unbeatable when it comes to the Amazfit Balance. Your Galaxy Watch FE won't go on for more than a day and a half or two days at max.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-should-you-buy-it"><span>Should you buy it?</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3477px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.26%;"><img id="Es9iPAU24vJG67ekXrUXmV" name="Amazfit Balance" alt="Amazfit Balance smartwatch" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Es9iPAU24vJG67ekXrUXmV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3477" height="1956" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>You should buy it if...</strong></p>
<ul><li>You prioritize battery life above all else</li><li>You're on a sub-$200 budget</li><li>You want loads of fitness modes</li><li>You prefer lighter watches</li><li>You need a bright and large display</li></ul>
<p><strong>You shouldn't buy it if...</strong></p>
<ul><li>You're expecting unfettered third-party app support like Wear OS</li><li>You want to use other apps for NFC payments</li><li>You need an LTE smartwatch</li><li>You're a serious athlete</li></ul>
<p>My final verdict is this: the Amazfit Balance has an awesome battery life rivalled by no other. If you're a light or average smartwatch user with basic needs, you'll be content with this wearable. It charges fast and feels comfortable, plus you can frequently score a nice discount to knock 15% to 20% off the price tag.</p><p>However, if you're looking for a Wear OS smartwatch with access to hundreds and hundreds of apps, the Amazfit Balance probably won't cut it for you. It doesn't have Spotify or WhatsApp, NFC payments are restricted to a single app, and the software is somewhat buggy. There's no LTE model either.</p><p>This isn't a smartwatch for serious users. If you have used the Amazfit GTS or GTR series, you're the right target audience for this watch. Just wait for a good sale before buying the Amazfit Balance for $200, though, because that'll improve its value prospect significantly.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="0082269f-c1ac-4dc4-aae4-6b4d2dfde022">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pezmQeG4BtLgLcGiqi6mQ3.jpg' alt="Render of the Amazfit Balance smartwatch"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Amazfit Balance</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="80" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>It's all about balance</strong></em></p><p>The Amazfit Balance is the ultimate battery champion among wearables. This smartwatch can go on and on for weeks on a single charge. Another big advantage of this deceptively large watch is its lightweightedness. You also get loads of health and fitness tracking features as well as NFC for contactless payments and Alexa built-in.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/amazfit-balance-review</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Amazfit Balance boasts a big and beautiful screen powered by an insanely long-lasting battery. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">3b9YXqRhvH5Spcj4jBBQSL</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NfopaUXyDgyVNcuw8jotcV.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 15:51:34 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NfopaUXyDgyVNcuw8jotcV.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Amazfit Balance smartwatch]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Amazfit Balance smartwatch]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google is making it easier to report police spottings in Maps ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google Maps made changes to its incident reporting options, renaming "speed traps" to a more general "police."</li><li>Now, the incident reporting options list has been reshuffled, placing "police" near the top.</li><li>"Police" appears right under "crash" and "slowdown," while less-important options, like "construction," have been moved lower.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google is making a few quality-of-life changes that should make incident reporting a lot easier in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-maps">Google Maps</a>. They started earlier this week by renaming the "speed trap" option in Maps with a more general "police" button, which covers a more wide variety of police activity you can see on the roadways. However, the police button was still too low on the list of incident reporting options, requiring drivers to scroll down on their screens while driving in order to report police activity.</p><p>Now, as <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/11/28/google-maps-android-auto-police-update/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a> reports, an update to Google Maps on Android Auto shakes up the list of incident reporting options. The most crucial options, "crash" and "slowdown," are still at the very top. However, the refreshed "police" option is now directly underneath those two buttons. Other options, like "construction," are moved lower down.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="9CjKbkmiF9o3kcwsXYsbTd" name="Android-Auto-Mercedes-Waze-map.jpg" alt="Android Auto running split-screen with Waze in Mercedes." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9CjKbkmiF9o3kcwsXYsbTd.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ted Kritsonis / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>A big reason why people use navigation apps like Google Maps, Waze, and Apple Maps is to be in-the-know on things that happen on the road. These incident reports help drivers know when to expect a crash ahead or a slowdown, press the brakes to avoid a ticket, or drive safer in a construction zone. But if it submitting an incident report in Google Maps on Android Auto requires drivers to take their eyes off the road to scroll through a list of options, this functionality can create new problems.</p><p>Speed traps appear to be one of the most common types of incident reports on navigation apps, at least anecdotally. This change won't solve Google Maps' problems on every screen — Android Auto displays vary in sizes and aspect ratios — but it should make it easier for most people to report policy activity in the app.</p><p>9to5Google notes that this change looks to be part of a server-side update that doesn't require Google Maps or Android Auto to be updated. The change may also apply to the Google Maps app on Apple CarPlay.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-is-making-it-easier-to-report-police-spottings-in-maps</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Following the renaming of "speed traps" to "police" in Google Maps, the button is now easier to press. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">APBXqbq4yWNFQb5iBiChTc</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NE5UkZwH7g85cR74V5DUbN.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 15:51:16 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NE5UkZwH7g85cR74V5DUbN.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Electric vehicles with Google built-in will share battery information with Google Maps.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Electric vehicles with Google built-in will share battery information with Google Maps.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ I use the OnePlus 12R every day and it's worth every penny, especially with $100 off ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The mighty <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12r-review">OnePlus 12R</a> is the mother of all budget phones. Heck, it&apos;s a midrange master. While one would usually have to spend $499.99 to acquire the 128GB variant, today&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">OnePlus Black Friday sales</a> have <strong>slashed that price tag by $100</strong>. If you want the best budget phone of the year, you can get the OnePlus 12R for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oneplus-12r-128gb-unlocked-iron-gray/6571130.p"><strong>$399.99 at Best Buy</strong></a>.</p><p>If you&apos;ve been eyeing the Cool Blue colorway, there&apos;s bad news and good news. The bad news is, the 128GB variant is sold out and you can only get it in Iron Gray. However, the good news is that you can get the better 256GB version for a discounted price too, saving you $100 off the original price. If that sounds good, go ahead and buy the Cool Blue OnePlus 12R with 256GB of storage for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CQ9SZJN6"><strong>$499.99 on Amazon</strong></a>.</p><p>The OnePlus 12R has a lovely and very vibrant 6.78-inch LTPO AMOLED screen with PWM dimming, so it&apos;s friendly to sensitive users. Another bonus point is that the phone boasts a robust IP64 water and dust-resistant rating.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="b7245835-f472-4289-a06b-c4178178074a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="OnePlus 12R 128GB: $499.99" data-dimension48="OnePlus 12R 128GB: $499.99" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oneplus-12r-128gb-unlocked-iron-gray/6571130.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="Rxy5RqYz7L5eAVG3FMuHeY" name="OnePlus-12R-square-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Rxy5RqYz7L5eAVG3FMuHeY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1500" height="1500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>OnePlus 12R 128GB: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oneplus-12r-128gb-unlocked-iron-gray/6571130.p" data-dimension112="b7245835-f472-4289-a06b-c4178178074a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="OnePlus 12R 128GB: $499.99" data-dimension48="OnePlus 12R 128GB: $499.99" data-dimension25=""><del>$499.99</del><strong> $399.99 at Best Buy</strong></a></p>
<p><strong>OnePlus 12R 128GB: </strong><a href="https://amazon.com/dp/B0CQ9SZJN6"><del>$599.99</del><strong> $499.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>Powered by last year's flagship Snapdragon 8 Gen 2 chipset, the OnePlus 12R has fantastic cameras, an excellent 5,500mAh battery, insane 80W fast charging, and an absolutely stunning AMOLED screen with PWM dimming.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oneplus-12r-128gb-unlocked-iron-gray/6571130.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="b7245835-f472-4289-a06b-c4178178074a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="OnePlus 12R 128GB: $499.99" data-dimension48="OnePlus 12R 128GB: $499.99" data-dimension25="">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>you&apos;re an audiophile who wants LDAC support, hi-res audio, wireless charging, a long battery life, and an ergonomic design.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>you want wireless charging and expandable storage.</p><p>You really never settle with the OnePlus 12R. This device is a performance beast. Depending on the memory specs, you either get 12GB or 16GB of RAM. Last year&apos;s Snapdragon 8 Gen 2 delivers unbelievable performance for gaming, multitasking, and anything in between. There&apos;s no app or task this phone can&apos;t handle.</p><p>Although not as fast as the Asian variant, you still get a blazing quick 80W fast charging speed coupled with a gigantic 5,500mAh battery. It lasts me all day and then some with very heavy use. The only feature lacking is wireless charging, but with a phone that charges this fast and lasts this long, you won&apos;t miss it.</p><p>I can&apos;t say the cameras are better than my Pixel 8, but they are surely good enough to keep up with cheaper phones. I was honestly very taken aback by how good the 50MP camera&apos;s picture quality is, and even the videos are quite nice.</p><p>The OnePlus 12R comes with Android 14, but you can upgrade to Android 15 right away. OnePlus promises three major OS updates, so you can rest assured it&apos;ll be good to go until Android 16. It is easily the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-android-phones">best affordable Android phone</a> that money can buy right now.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/i-use-the-oneplus-12r-every-day-and-its-worth-every-penny-especially-with-usd100-off</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ I daily drive the OnePlus 12R and cannot recommend it enough. Good news, Black Friday has knicked $100 off it! ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">4pVox68CdpQJQpV2S5VhP4</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Muk9dtqpJUJVBd5rWnGja8.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 15:27:29 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Muk9dtqpJUJVBd5rWnGja8.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus 12R Sunset Dune next to Cool Blue model]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus 12R Sunset Dune next to Cool Blue model]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung Galaxy S25, S25 Plus colors seemingly confirmed as SIM card trays leak ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Colors for the Samsung Galaxy S25 and Galaxy S25 Plus appear to have leaked in an interesting way.</li><li>Per report, an online Samsung repair parts dealer already has access to select Galaxy S25 series parts.</li><li>Those include the SIM trays for the Galaxy S25 and Galaxy S25 Plus, which are color-matched to each colorway.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>The expected release date for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25">Samsung Galaxy S25 series</a> is fast approaching, and that means leaks are heating up. We've learned a lot about the Galaxy S25 lineup in recent days and weeks, down to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-s25-series-fcc-listing-details-confirmed">the official FCC listings for the devices</a>. Now, it appears the colors for the Galaxy S25 and Galaxy S25 Plus have leaked, albeit in an unusual way.</p><p>A parts dealer claims to already have replacement SIM card trays for the Galaxy S25 and Galaxy S25 Plus, and these trays are color-matched to each phone's colorway — giving us our first look at this year's color options. This comes from Roland Quandt, a leaker who shared images of the SIM trays in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://bsky.app/profile/rquandt.bsky.social/post/3lbzejv7muk27" target="_blank">post</a> on Bluesky (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidpolice.com/samsung-galaxy-s25-colors-leak-sim/" target="_blank">Android Police</a>).</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="Gier4UPjsfgPqqLjkDsrKn" name="Galaxy-S25-SIM-Leak-4" alt="SIM card trays for the Galaxy S25 series." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Gier4UPjsfgPqqLjkDsrKn.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1000" height="1000" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roland Quandt / Bluesky )</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="3zVKYHij8Mvm8i2m9h3iKn" name="Galaxy-S25-SIM-Leak-3" alt="SIM card trays for the Galaxy S25 series." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3zVKYHij8Mvm8i2m9h3iKn.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1000" height="1000" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roland Quandt / Bluesky )</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="W5H3Axt5CUzpDAtAbxVLKn" name="Galaxy-S25-SIM-Leak-1" alt="SIM card trays for the Galaxy S25 series." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/W5H3Axt5CUzpDAtAbxVLKn.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1000" height="1000" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roland Quandt / Bluesky )</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 4 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="QTRpueG7thQ6en6jZ7GVKn" name="Galaxy-S25-SIM-Leak-2" alt="SIM card trays for the Galaxy S25 series." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QTRpueG7thQ6en6jZ7GVKn.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1000" height="1000" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roland Quandt / Bluesky )</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 5 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="7sqTPqEgVxjSeNdGKH6yKn" name="Galaxy-S25-SIM-Leak-5" alt="SIM card trays for the Galaxy S25 series." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7sqTPqEgVxjSeNdGKH6yKn.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1000" height="1000" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Roland Quandt / Bluesky )</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>This leak appears to be credible because the colors depicted appear to match up with the previously-reported names for Galaxy S25 colorways. <strong>Midnight Black</strong>, <strong>Sparkling Green</strong>, <strong>Sparkling Blue</strong>, <strong>Silver Shadow</strong> and <strong>Moon Night Blue</strong> were the rumored Galaxy S25 and Galaxy S25 Plus colorways, with Midnight Black potentially being a Galaxy S25 Plus exclusive option. Based on the leaked images above, these are likely the color choices you'll have if you are in the market for a Galaxy S25 or Galaxy S25 Plus device.</p><p>These colors are expected to be the widely-available options for the Galaxy S25 and Galaxy S25 Plus that you can buy at any retailer. This leak doesn't include the Samsung-exclusive colorways, which are only available from the company's online store. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-series-color-options-tipped">According to a prior leak last month</a>, there will be three Samsung online exclusives for the Galaxy S25 and Galaxy S25 Plus: Coral Red, Pink Gold, and Blue/Black.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">In non-political news, I got more Galaxy S25 colors which are at much lower volumes:

S25 and S25+
Coral Red
Pink Gold
Blue/Black

S25U
Titanium Blue/Black
Titanium Jade Green
Titanium Pink Gold<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1854320141838037359">November 7, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>This also only applies to the Galaxy S25 and Galaxy S25 Plus, not the larger Galaxy S25 Ultra. That model will be more expensive and features a titanium finish. While we don't have a full picture of the Galaxy S25 Ultra color options yet, Titanium Blue/Black, Titanium Jade Green, and Titanium Pink Gold appear to be at least a few options to be available on Samsung's online store.</p><p>Samsung is tipped to launch the Galaxy S25 lineup sometime around mid-January. As that date gets closer, we'll learn nearly everything about the devices, so stay tuned.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-s25-plus-colors-seemingly-confirmed-as-sim-card-trays-leak</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A strange leak appears to confirm the five colors for the Samsung Galaxy S25 and Galaxy S25 Plus ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">MxpC62ePjNnBHrPSRSHWqL</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/G2jTwQ3PkYe4RjaFE8FhMm.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 15:25:01 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/G2jTwQ3PkYe4RjaFE8FhMm.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Looking at the different colorways of the Samsung Galaxy S24]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Looking at the different colorways of the Samsung Galaxy S24]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>