<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 17:02:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Best Moto G Stylus 5G 2024 screen protectors 2024 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>You need one of the best Moto G Stylus 5G 2024 screen protectors to safeguard its stunning 6.7-inch 120Hz OLED display. It might be reinforced by Gorilla Glass 3, but that layer isn&apos;t strong enough to sustain direct blows or repetitive scratches from things like keys in your bag.</p><p>Motorola has promised one major Android update as well as three years of security updates for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/moto-g-stylus-5g-2024-review">Moto G Stylus 5G 2024</a>. If you want to retain the highest trade-in value a few years down the line, you&apos;d better grab one of these sturdy screen guards for it.</p>
<h2 id="keep-scratches-and-cracks-at-bay-with-these-protective-screen-guards-2">Keep scratches and cracks at bay with these protective screen guards</h2>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="8e956094-1d4b-4d1d-8a53-5e8505ed8c98">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TUcr2pZd5kqya6spQojudd.jpg' alt='amFilm 3 Pack Moto G Stylus 2024 5G Tempered Glass Screen Protector'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">amFilm 3 Pack Moto G Stylus 2024 5G Tempered Glass Screen Protector</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best overall</strong></em></p>
<p>Year after year, amFilm's affordably-priced glass screen protectors keep on winning our hearts. This three-pack gives you a trio of sturdy tempered glass pieces with round cutouts for the Moto G Stylus 2024's front camera. There are wet wipes, dust wipes, and an installation guide included.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="93aa079a-78dd-482f-9e34-708ed6b526d4">
            <a href="https://www.motorola.com/us/motorola-essentials-glass-screen-protector-for-moto-g-stylus-5g-2024/p" data-model-name="null"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nd9EEujAVRKC3XYvD2Fm9m.jpg' alt='Motorola Essentials Glass Screen Protector for Moto G Stylus 5G (2024)'></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Motorola Essentials Glass Screen Protector</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best first-party</strong></em></p>
<p>The Motorola Essentials Glass Screen Protector fits the Moto G Stylus 5G (2024) to perfection. It's a scratch-proof, notch-less panel of tempered glass that repels fingerprints, keeping your display clean and tidy. You get a single unit and a USB-C alignment tool.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="dda50e17-8cf8-4319-9b05-14917fbc4c3e">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2hJh6T2dSiegE7vxwQ8nE.jpg' alt='Supershieldz Moto G Stylus 5G 2024 PET Screen Protector'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Supershieldz Moto G Stylus 5G 2024 PET Screen Protector</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best plastic film</strong></em></p>
<p>This cheap three-pack from Supershieldz gives you three self-repairing PET screen protectors made out of high-grade plastic. If you dislike the thick layer glass screen guards add, this is a thinner option for your Motorola device.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="6a27d857-4307-49d7-82a0-2cfb486eb3a6">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jdBUVB3XjuAp5dHD7a4i8o.jpg' alt='TQLGY 3 Pack Screen Protector for Moto G Stylus 5G 2024 with Camera Lens Protector'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">TQLGY 3 Pack Screen Protector for Moto G Stylus 5G 2024</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best value</strong></em></p>
<p>TQLGY's three-pack of glass protectors is a little more expensive compared to some other options, but it also gives you the most value for your money. You get three tempered glass screen protectors as well as a trio of camera lens protectors.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="f125d513-4545-4ef9-ba43-9c4ca527e778">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DkYrVCXpVuNC7W9rZVYngR.jpg' alt='Mr Shield Screen Protector for Moto G Stylus 5G 2024 3-Pack'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Mr Shield Screen Protector for Moto G Stylus 5G 2024 3-Pack</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best cheap pick</strong></em></p>
<p>For seven bucks, Mr Shield offers a fantastic bargain. The brand's Screen Protector for the Moto G Stylus 5G 2024 includes three pieces of Japanese tempered glass, boasting a 9H hardness rating. Each unit has an oleophobic layer, repelling solids and liquids.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="118ee790-0cd7-4136-8587-1dcc8e772f6a">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6CgFHk2te3ZmpNdE6S8nj3.jpg' alt='sorlnern 2 Pack Privacy Screen Protector for Moto G Stylus 5G 2024'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">sorlnern 2 Pack Privacy Screen Protector for Moto G Stylus 5G 2024</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best for privacy</strong></em></p>
<p>This duo of darkened tempered glass protectors appears clear up close and nearly black from a distance. It's ideal for privacy-focused individuals looking to thwart wandering eyes from their Moto G Stylus 5G 2024 while protecting it.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<ul><li><a href="#main"><strong>Back to the top ^</strong></a></li></ul>
<h2 id="there-apos-s-a-diverse-selection-of-moto-g-stylus-5g-2024-screen-protectors-available-2">There&apos;s a diverse selection of Moto G Stylus 5G 2024 screen protectors available</h2>
<p>A lot of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-moto-g-stylus-5g-2024-cases">Moto G Stylus 5G 2024 cases</a> come with free screen protectors, but we suggest getting dedicated ones as they have much better quality. The best Moto G Stylus 5G 2024 screen protectors are scratch-resistant, case-friendly, and ideally come with installation guides or frames. It helps to have oleophobic properties too, since that repels solid and liquid particles like dirt and fingerprint stains.</p><p>With that in mind, the best overall Moto G Stylus 5G 2024 screen protector is amFilm&apos;s three-pack of highly durable tempered glass screen guards. These glass protectors are extremely thin, delivering good levels of touch sensitivity. This doesn&apos;t deter sturdiness, as you still get scratch resistance. Each of the three screen guards has an oleophobic layer and you get a complete set of installation tools in the box such as various wipes and a guide. Let&apos;s not forget that the below-$10 price bracket is awesome too.</p><p>If you don&apos;t mind shelling out a bit more for a first-party option, naturally you&apos;ll be happy with the Motorola Essentials Glass Screen Protector for the Moto G Stylus 5G 2024. There&apos;s a single tempered glass screen protector in the package which touts 9H hardness and has an oleophobic layer on top. Motorola provides a unique USB-C alignment tool along with this screen guard.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-moto-g-stylus-5g-2024-screen-protectors</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The fine Moto G Stylus 5G 2024 has a beautiful OLED screen that brings utter joy to look at. Maintain its beauty with a solid screen protector. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">M9TMx7czMYsdr4oBjynaNd</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FGt5ZF8Ud78tznEGxbNJJZ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 16:35:27 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FGt5ZF8Ud78tznEGxbNJJZ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Multitasking on the Moto G Stylus 5G 2024]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Multitasking on the Moto G Stylus 5G 2024]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google TV introduces another set of ads for advertisers through its network ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google is detailing new ways advertisers can showcase their ads to more and new audiences through its Google TV network.</li><li>Through the network, advertisers can reach 20 million active Google TV and Android TV viewers.</li><li>Those serving ads will soon gain non-skippable and six-second bumper ads, alongside new tools through Google Ads and Google Display & Video 360.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google is introducing a few new ways advertisers can start taking advantage of its TV network to reach new target audiences and access more channels.</p><p>As detailed in a press release, the Google TV network (GTV) is giving advertisers even more ways to "personalize" their ad campaigns to users. Ads under the FAST category (free ad-supported TV) have continued to rise, catalyzing the newest updates. The post states that the GTV offers in-stream video inventory for more than 125 channels built into Google TV.</p><p>These channels include live sports, TV shows, and movies. Beginning today (June 7), the new network will give advertisers access to CTV ad formats, including non-skippable ads and six-second bumper ads. Google states that there are more ad formats to come.</p><p>To reach new audiences, Google adds that advertisers its services deliver targeted, in-stream inventory across 20 million active TV and Android TV OS devices.</p><p>The company&apos;s new TV network is available to advertisers through Google Ads and Google Display & Video 360. Advertisers can purchase, plan, and measure their Google TV campaigns alongside "existing digital video campaigns."</p><p>The post states that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-tvs">Google TV&apos;s</a> newest ad offers will give advertisers access to 10,000 apps involving live TV, shows, and movies. More importantly, through its free channels, viewers spend an average of 75 minutes per day watching FAST ads. A study conducted by Deloitte in 2023 showed that roughly 60% of U.S. households view free, ad-supported TV content through streaming.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="WY4yfzi9skDmnBbckCvcu" name="chromecast-with-google-tv-review-7.jpeg" alt="Chromecast With Google TV" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WY4yfzi9skDmnBbckCvcu.jpeg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Source: Joe Maring / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The company&apos;s announcement reiterates the ad offerings available to advertisers through YouTube. On that platform, brands can take advantage of non-skippable ads and other buffer ads that play before video content. According to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/displayvideo/answer/9224914?hl=en">YouTube&apos;s ad campaign</a> support page, these ads are anywhere between six and 15 seconds.</p><p>Moreover, Google has expanded ads for advertisers to continue to reach new audiences <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-shorts-machine-learning-vertical-ads">through Shorts</a>. The company introduced new tools for companies to create "unique" vertical ads through customized templates and Machine Learning techniques.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/google-tv-streaming-ad-offerings-advertisers-network-announcement</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google highlighted new ways advertisers can reach new heights through its TV network with ads. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">biqB4mTvm3QCWC7S7UZzLc</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/23bLDhnM2gUdZqpSn25EnV.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Streaming &amp; TV]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/23bLDhnM2gUdZqpSn25EnV.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Walmart]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[onn. Google TV 4K Streaming Box product lifestyle]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[onn. Google TV 4K Streaming Box product lifestyle]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Max raises the prices of its Ad-Free and Ultimate plans ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Max's Ad-Free tier pricing now starts at $16.99, and the 4K plan at $20.99 per month.</li><li>The yearly plans of the same tier have also been increased, now costing $169.99 and $209.99 per year, respectively.</li><li>New plans will apply to Max's subscribers starting July 4.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Max, formerly known as HBO Max, has released updated rates for its current ad-free plans. The rates show a $1 bump in the cost of the tier plans overall and the ad-free ones in particular.</p><p>According to Max&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://help.max.com/US/Answer/Detail/000002547">support page</a>, the Ad-Free plan starts at $16.99 per month and $169.99 per year, a significant bump from the previous $15.99 per month and $149.99 per year, respectively. Similarly, the Ultimate plan, also known as the 4K plan, will now cost $20.99 per month, and the annual plan will see a $10 rise, making it $209.99 per year.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:550px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:66.18%;"><img id="Zvtyk5GizdywnZVBcvr3HV" name="westinghouse-roku-tv.jpg" alt="Smart TV" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Zvtyk5GizdywnZVBcvr3HV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="550" height="364" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Westinghouse)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Users must bear in mind that these prices don&apos;t include applicable taxes. The plans with ads will remain the same, costing $9.99 per month and $99.99 per year. For people who opt for the streaming subscription directly through Max or from the app store, the new rates are applicable after July 4. </p><p>However, some carriers like Verizon <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/verizon-rumored-to-combine-max-and-netflix-cheaper-plans">also offer</a> Max streaming subscriptions — they individually will let users know about the change in subscription prices whenever applicable.</p>
<p>To make up for its losses in 2022 and 2023, Max, like most other streaming providers, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/max-prepares-password-sharing-crackdown">announced</a> intentions to restrict password sharing for its users early this year. </p><p>Max believes that Netflix&apos;s password crackdown strategy has been successfully adopted, and Max also ought to make plans to crack password sharing later this year with a larger rollout scheduled for next year. Shoppable advertising will be among the "ad format enhancements" that users may see, as Max is also considering introducing them.</p><p>The hike in pricing has been a common trend across the streaming giants over the past year. More recently, Peacock has also <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/peacock-raises-monthly-subscription-price-two-dollars">announced</a> a rise in subscription plans just in time for the Olympics, as users would have to shell out more starting from July 18 (for new consumers), which is applicable for existing consumers on August 17.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Streaming deals: </strong><a href="https://www.disneyplus.com/"><u><strong>Disney+</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.max.com/"><u><strong>Max</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.sling.com/"><u><strong>Sling</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://geni.us/YkQAuWd"><u><strong>Fubo</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.peacocktv.com/blackfriday"><u><strong>Peacock</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.paramountplus.com/"><u><strong>Paramount+</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/max-shares-new-rise-in-prices-for-ad-free-and-ultimate-plans</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Max shared new prices for its standard and ultimate plans; while both see a price hike for monthly and yearly plans, the ad-based plan remains unchanged. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">7QXPLAHh6JW6ZLf8dFqkgB</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/n5jtnR94r3mLynD2mEF6S4.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 15:48:55 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Streaming &amp; TV]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/n5jtnR94r3mLynD2mEF6S4.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[MAX]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[MAX logo with blue gradient background]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[MAX logo with blue gradient background]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Best Moto G Stylus 5G 2024 cases 2024 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Say hello to all the best Moto G Stylus 5G 2024 cases to level up your newest Motorola phone&apos;s game. From clear bumper covers to thin cases, this selection is wide and wonderful.</p><p>The sleek <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/moto-g-stylus-5g-2024-review">Moto G Stylus 5G 2024</a> is the best entrant to Motorola&apos;s stylus-bearing series to date. We&apos;re in love with the device and highly recommend it. And if you&apos;ve bought one for yourself, be sure to encase this budget-buster with a protective case for longevity and bolstered defenses.</p>
<h2 id="cases-with-panache-and-flair-2">Cases with panache and flair</h2>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="5558f0ff-dbd4-466b-baff-a19d11dfa1a4">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xRWzyhiUkWWaNPafXjJrLR.jpg' alt='Poetic Guardian case for Moto G Stylus 5G 2024'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Poetic Guardian for Moto G Stylus 5G 2024</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best overall</strong></em></p>
<p>The Poetic Guardian case is the best overall choice for your Moto G Stylus 5G 2024. It comes with a built-in screen protector, grippy scored sides, an impact-absorbing frame, 20ft drop protection, and three color options for a fantastic price.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="895c156a-6083-4c9f-8e13-847662018bb2">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DAdBk7BfHVCYAQjrKBbmKV.jpg' alt='TUDIA DualShield for Moto G Stylus 5G 2024'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">TUDIA DualShield for Moto G Stylus 5G 2024</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best value</strong></em></p>
<p>TUDIA has long been a favorite when it comes to budget phone case brands. The dual-layered TUDIA DualShield case adds a nice coat of paint as well as military-grade shockproofing to your device without breaking the bank.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="fd621012-e734-488b-b63b-1aad81989dc8">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qtnz4bCGMXztBuafTHHL4H.jpg' alt='FNTCASE Moto G Stylus 5G 2024 Shockproof Case'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">FNTCASE Moto G Stylus 5G 2024 Shockproof Case</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best slim</strong></em></p>
<p>FNTCASE gives you slim protection in the form of its Moto G Stylus 5G 2024 Shockproof Case. This cover is a fabulous bargain, adding a reinforced layer of impact resistance, and that too for under $10!</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="e973a337-fb37-4f76-9b42-421e76ac28ff">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/X7GoZTpmhGrHDVJ24bSu68.jpg' alt='Poetic Revolution for Moto G Stylus 5G 2024'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Poetic Revolution for Moto G Stylus 5G 2024</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best rugged</strong></em></p>
<p>This is one chonky phone cover, but it comes with perks to make up for the bulk. These include 20ft drop protection, a built-in screen guard, a kickstand, and a sliding camera cover. Talk about being thorough!</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="26c909d0-66d9-4108-addc-f2b62e8995a9">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PgyEdDoX9QELprN3FTPALj.jpg' alt='KUGEW Magnetic Moto G Stylus 5G 2024 Clear Case'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">KUGEW Magnetic Moto G Stylus 5G 2024 Clear Case</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best clear case</strong></em></p>
<p>It's a mouthful to read out, but this clear case from KUGEW deserves your attention. You get a MagSafe ring baked into the back, opening up the possibility of using MagSafe wireless chargers with your Moto G Stylus 5G.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="c5d8c694-00ba-414d-afae-63e3336e7b4f">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YCLiKNCnUq4bgzZsrZScJ3.jpg' alt='SUPCASE Unicorn Beetle Pro for Moto G Stylus 5G 2024'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">SUPCASE Unicorn Beetle Pro for Moto G Stylus 5G 2024</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best belt clip case</strong></em></p>
<p>Another one of the most reliable case series is the SUPCASE Unicorn Beetle Pro. Happily, this rugged case is available for the Moto G Stylus 5G 2024. Not only do you get a stand, a screen protector, and heavy-duty protection, but you also get a belt clip slash holster.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<ul><li><a href="#main"><strong>Back to the top ^</strong></a></li></ul>
<h2 id="choose-a-case-based-on-how-clumsy-you-are-x2014-or-aren-apos-t-2">Choose a case based on how clumsy you are — or aren&apos;t!</h2>
<p>All the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-motorola-phones">greatest Motorola phones</a> are made to last, but we cannot forget that they are usually priced under $500, which means cutting corners at times. The Moto G Stylus 5G 2024 is a stellar Android phone in its own right, but it&apos;s certainly not invincible to foes like scratches, nicks, and drops. That&apos;s exactly why you need one or two of the best Moto G Stylus 5G 2024 cases.</p><p>The Poetic Guardian case for the Moto G Stylus 5G is an all-rounder. Priced around $16 to $17, this high-quality phone case showcases the design of your design without endangering it. The clear back puts your lovely Moto on display while the grippy bumper frame protects it from drops and impacts. Plus, there&apos;s a a built-in screen guard to cover the stunning 120Hz OLED display too.</p><p>If you&apos;re not very concerned about protection and just want something cheap and clear, the KUGEW Magnetic Moto G Stylus 5G 2024 Clear Case is a good choice too. It&apos;s a very simple and cheap see-through silicone case with one extremely exciting feature: a MagSafe adapter on the back. This gives you the opportunity to explore the world of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-magsafe-accessories-for-android-phones">MagSafe accessories for Android</a>!</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-moto-g-stylus-5g-2024-cases</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Style your latest Moto G Stylus with all the best the current market has to offer. These are the best Moto G Stylus 5G 2024 cases. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">vPuPR8Te78truj9XmjF2dU</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4k7qUctEzQQcrDjppv7TtQ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 15:29:40 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4k7qUctEzQQcrDjppv7TtQ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Poetic]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Poetic Guardian case for Moto G Stylus 5G 2024]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Poetic Guardian case for Moto G Stylus 5G 2024]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Nothing will prioritize AI over Phone 3, but is that the right call? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Nothing's CEO, Carl Pei, gave an update on the company's plans for AI and Phone 3 in a video update posted to X (formerly Twitter) on Wednesday, June 5.</li><li>The company says that Phone 3 will not come this year, and will instead be released sometime next year with AI at the center.</li><li>Phone 1 debuted in July 2022 and Phone 2 was released in July 2023, so this move is a departure from Nothing's annual release schedule.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>If you had been hoping to see what the Nothing Phone 3 has in store, this week was probably a disappointing one. Nothing CEO Carl Pei took to X (formerly Twitter) to give an update on the company&apos;s mobile plans. Unsurprisingly, it involves a whole lot of artificial intelligence. But Pei also mentioned the existence of Phone 3 for the first time, albeit in passing, and said it won&apos;t be coming this year. </p><p>That&apos;s a departure from the yearly release schedule for Nothing phones that the company established during its brief history as a brand. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/nothing-phone-1-review">Nothing Phone 1</a> debuted in July 2022, and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/nothing-phone-2-review">Nothing Phone 2</a> was a neat follow-up in July 2023. Unfortunately, there won&apos;t be a Nothing Phone 3 coming out next month. </p><p>"For the last two months, we’ve been designing and prototyping AI interactions. Today, I want to show you some initial concepts to give you a better idea of what I’m talking about," Pei wrote in the post. "Expect this to be improved and gradually introduced, starting with Phone (3) next year. It’s important we get the product right, integrating hardware and AI in a way that is both useful and brings a smile to people’s faces."</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">There's been a lot of hype around AI. Some great, some confusing. It’s great to see new companies rethinking the user experience and form factors. However, there is no doubt that smartphones will remain the main consumer AI form factor for the foreseeable future. With over 4… pic.twitter.com/ERJc7xhwBa<a href="https://twitter.com/getpeid/status/1798369533889302576">June 5, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>Based on these comments, it feels like Nothing is delaying the release of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/nothing-phone-3-qualcomm-chip-price-rumors">Phone 3</a> to make sure its ambitious AI features are ready to go. That isn&apos;t a bad strategy, per se. In fact, it&apos;s a lot better than the approach other companies have taken — I&apos;m looking at you, Humane and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/rabbit-r1-first-impressions">Rabbit</a> — which began with underwhelming and expensive products and culminated with potentially-dangerous batteries in the hands of AI Pin users.</p><p>Still, I think it&apos;s worth questioning whether Nothing is making the right call here. Despite being a fairly young company, Nothing already has made three phones and five pairs of earbuds by its main brand. Throw in the CMF by Nothing sub-brand, and you&apos;ve got more earbuds, a smartwatch, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/nothings-cmf-phone-1-might-have-a-little-surprise-in-store">a to-be-released smartphone</a>. I have to wonder whether the company would be more successful if it just stuck to one or two product categories while it grew, rather than trying to tackle so many different products and markets at once.</p>
<h2 id="it-apos-s-a-better-approach-to-ai-than-we-apos-ve-seen-from-other-companies-2">It&apos;s a better approach to AI than we&apos;ve seen from other companies</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="359xkZdkT5m79Y3mZ9LneH" name="rabbit-r1-nothing-phone-2-1.jpg" alt="Rabbit R1 next to Nothing Phone 2" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/359xkZdkT5m79Y3mZ9LneH.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>A few companies have tried to create standalone products with AI as the centerpiece, but it hasn&apos;t worked out too well so far. To be fair, companies like Humane and Rabbit aren&apos;t entirely wrong. There&apos;s so much less money to be made in an AI app than there is in a hardware product. However, as the launch of the Humane AI Pin and Rabbit R1 have shown, rushing AI products to be "first" doesn&apos;t mean anything if they aren&apos;t actually any good. </p><p>Nothing is saying out loud what many in the industry have been speculating for a while. When the dust settles, we won&apos;t be using AI apps or other hardware devices. The artificial intelligence will be incorporated right into your mobile operating system, whether that&apos;s stock Android, iOS, or a skin like Nothing OS. In a way, we&apos;ve already seen this concept in action with ChatGPT integration on Nothing devices.</p><p>The company is likely making the right move in trying to make AI the focus of its smartphones. "It’s great to see new companies rethinking the user experience and form factors," Pei wrote. "However, there is no doubt that smartphones will remain the main consumer AI form factor for the foreseeable future. With over 4 billion users and over 1 billion smartphones shipped every year—the numbers speak for themselves."</p><p>The question is whether delaying Phone 3 to make AI features instead is the right move, and that remains to be seen.</p>
<h2 id="what-will-ai-on-phone-3-look-like-2">What will AI on Phone 3 look like?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="N6ar7DdLJ7GdNFfCtgzLXY" name="Nothing-Phone-3-Teaser.jpg" alt="An example of an AI-based UX on Nothing Phone 3." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/N6ar7DdLJ7GdNFfCtgzLXY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Carl Pei / Nothing)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Nothing only showed off a proof-of-concept of what AI might look like in Nothing OS. It looks a lot like OpenAI&apos;s implementations of AI-based voice assistants. There is one white orb that becomes the UI for the initial AI voice assistant setup, just like the voice mode for ChatGPT. However, Nothing also takes notice of what Rabbit aimed to do with the R1 and its large action model concept. </p><p>"The way we use our smartphones needs to be redefined. The current user experience hasn&apos;t evolved for more than a decade," said Pei. "The next era needs a highly personalized, dynamic, and cross-device interface. One that also creates a human connection that makes tech feel more at ease to interact with."</p><p>Eventually, Nothing wants to create a mobile OS experience that frees you from apps, but it notes that won&apos;t happen immediately.</p>
<h2 id="delaying-phone-3-might-be-proof-nothing-is-spread-too-thin-2">Delaying Phone 3 might be proof Nothing is spread too thin</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="xDqritNrp2g3PCarh9HXVS" name="nothing-phone-2a-3.jpg" alt="Nothing Phone 2a review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xDqritNrp2g3PCarh9HXVS.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Ideally, Nothing could work on adding AI features to Nothing OS while also releasing Phone 3 on its usual annual schedule. Assuming that most of the company&apos;s planned AI features don&apos;t run on device, like its competitors, there&apos;s no reason they couldn&apos;t be shipped as a software update later. The delay could mean Nothing is trying to bring on-device AI processing to the Phone 3, or that it wants AI features to be the main reason you go out and buy Phone 3. Either way, it seems weird that Phone 3 appears to be delayed while Nothing devotes its time to AI software and budget CMF products instead.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/nothing-will-prioritize-ai-over-phone-3-but-is-that-the-right-call</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ In a post on X (formerly Twitter), Nothing CEO Carl Pei explained that Phone 3 will be all about AI, but it won't come this year. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">mAP6xkuDcMz2H8fZvZxJWG</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CqoaiemQLuCy6AzPJ2chVL.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 13:23:32 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CqoaiemQLuCy6AzPJ2chVL.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Nothing Phone (2)&#039;s colorways with glyph lights on]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Nothing Phone (2)&#039;s colorways with glyph lights on]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ How to edit texts in Google Messages ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>When you know how to edit texts in Google Messages, you can quickly go back and make the necessary changes. You also save time since you don&apos;t have to rewrite the message for it to make sense. Android users can now edit their messages when using RCS messages in Google Messages, and the good news is that the steps to do it are beginner-friendly. </p><p>The new feature is part of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/june-2024-android-feature-drop">June Android feature drop</a>, but if you don&apos;t see it yet, ensure you <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://forums.androidcentral.com/threads/a-way-to-update-apps-that-have-been-put-to-deep-sleep.1057489/">update your Android apps</a> to get the latest features. Remember, you only have a maximum of 15 minutes to edit your messages. WhatsApp users also have the same amount of time to edit their messages. But if you proofread your messages shortly after sending them, that should be more than enough time.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-edit-a-message-sent-on-google-messages-2">How to edit a message sent on Google Messages</h2>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> The feature only works with RCS messages, and your wireless carrier must offer RCS in its text message technology. This will also not work with a message sent from Android to iPhone since an older MMS or SMS technology is used.</p><p>You can quickly and easily modify your message on Google Messages by doing the following:</p><p>1. <strong>Long-press</strong> on the sent <strong>message</strong>.</p><p>2. <strong>Tap</strong> the <strong>pencil icon</strong> at the top.</p><p>3. <strong>Make</strong> the <strong>necessary changes</strong> in the text box with the edit message label.</p><p>4. When you&apos;re done editing, tap the <strong>checkmark button</strong> to the side.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:594px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:101.01%;"><img id="FrnUUxWUCKChbSdrZTLWph" name="Google-Messages-Edit-Box-Text.jpg" alt="Steps to edit messages in Google Messages" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FrnUUxWUCKChbSdrZTLWph.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="594" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Once you edit texts in Google Messages, you&apos;ll see an "Edited" tag below it, which may or may not make users happy. The other person can see that you&apos;ve made changes and may or may not ask you what you changed. Remember that you can&apos;t edit SMS and MMS messages in Google Messages. If you make a mistake, the only way to send the other person the correct information is to resend it.</p><p>Google hasn&apos;t released a list of countries where the editing feature is available, but it&apos;s slowly rolling out. Still, by regularly checking for updates, you can ensure you&apos;ll get it as soon as it&apos;s available in your region. And soon be able to edit texts in Google Messages.</p>
<h2 id="why-can-apos-t-i-send-rcs-messages-2">Why can&apos;t I send RCS messages?</h2>
<p>If you cannot send RCS messages, here are some possible reasons. You need an internet connection to send an RCS message, unlike SMS, which doesn&apos;t need it. Also, making Google Messages your default messaging app is required to use all available RCS features. You don&apos;t have to have one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a> out there to use this feature, but more recent models like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review">Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra</a> are compatible.</p><p>You may also have RCS turned off in Google Messages. To check if it&apos;s on:</p><p>1. <strong>Open</strong> Google Messages. </p><p>2. <strong>Tap your profile picture</strong> at the top right.</p><p>3. Choose the <strong>Messages settings</strong> option near the bottom.</p><p>4. Select <strong>RCS chats</strong> at the top and <strong>toggle on</strong> the feature.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1440px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:111.11%;"><img id="dNduorxNCd2NUFfVRLyE9E" name="How-to-turn-on-RCS-messages.jpg" alt="Steps to enable RCS messages" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dNduorxNCd2NUFfVRLyE9E.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1440" height="1600" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Judy Sanhz)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>As soon as it&apos;s on, other greyed-out features, such as Send read receipts and Show typing indicator, will be accessible. You&apos;ll also see a status indicator showing you that it&apos;s connected.</p><p>The advantage of using RCS is that your messages can be encrypted, making sending information more secure. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/messages/answer/9592174?hl=en#zippy=%2Chow-we-protect-your-data">Google uses Transport Layer Security</a> (TLS) to encrypt your messages. Using TLS means that anyone who tries to access your messages will only discover it&apos;s encrypted and unreadable.</p>
<h2 id="keep-on-editing-2">Keep on editing</h2>
<p>Editing text is a welcome feature that iOS users have been enjoying with iMessage. Hopefully, the 15-minute time frame will be expanded. Before, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-messages-text-editing-beta-changes-spotted">users had 30 minutes to edit</a> their messages, but for some reason, Google reduced it to 15. The first option was better for the user who doesn&apos;t realize their text needs editing until it&apos;s too late.</p><p>As you can see, editing messages is easy. If you know <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-edit-messages-in-whatsapp">how to edit messages on WhatsApp</a>, you know how to edit them on Google Messages. With a simple long-press, you can give your message the details it was missing in the first place.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="ce420a07-283f-4e34-8355-9d071aab5f44">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HwzfHgpGsXkMgRPCpTjqS.jpg' alt='google pixel 8 pro square render 1'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 8 Pro</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="90" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Seven years of updates</strong></em></p>
<p>With the<strong> </strong><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-pro-review">Google Pixel 8 Pro</a>, you get several system updates and ensure you get the latest Google features. You also get a tremendous 50MP primary camera and all the AI features that come with it, such as Magic Eraser.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-edit-texts-in-google-messages</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Discover how easy it is to edit text edit texts in Google Messages by following a few simple steps. Here are the beginner-friendly steps! ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">kPJuKvEySEhFKxgcCR2HgE</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RhVMHXF5HuTnsNxWm2sxz8.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 11:39:52 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ judysanhz30@gmail.com (Judy Sanhz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RhVMHXF5HuTnsNxWm2sxz8.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[An image depicting the edit button in Google Messages during its latest beta.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[An image depicting the edit button in Google Messages during its latest beta.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ You can no longer fix Samsung phones at Best Buy ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Best Buy is ending its program that allowed Geek Squad to repaid Samsung phones with originial Samsung parts.</li><li>This means customers can only get Samsung devices repaired as Best Buy if they have a Geek Squad protection and are willing to pay extra for parts replacements.</li><li>Samsung users are left with slim pickings of repair stores like uBreakiFix with both iFixit and Best Buy no longer offering repairs.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Best buy&apos;s Geek Squad is reportedly shutting down its dedicated Samsung repair service at Best Buy stores, according to a recent report by<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/6/24164777/best-buy-ends-samsung-repair-program-geek-squad"> The Verge</a>. Samsung&apos;s Authorized Service Provider program (ASP) lets certain Best Buy stores repair phones with original Samsung parts, tools, and training— allowing users to schedule an appointment online to get their phones fixed.</p><p>The news trickled down from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GeekSquad/comments/1cst3kr/samsung_asp/">Geek Squad&apos;s Reddit thread,</a> which indicated that Best Buy was canceling the program. </p><p>One of the users on the thread seemed to be taken aback by this and said, "In my precinct, I was the only one disappointed because I really like doing Samsung repairs, while everyone else was happy." </p><p>The user added that they enjoyed being the person who was fully trained to do the SASP repairs and didn&apos;t quite understand why Best Buy went ahead with this move since the program was doing so well at their location.</p><p>While other employees who were a part of this program really wanted it to end and were surprised how this didn&apos;t happen any sooner.</p><p>"I managed Geek Squad for close to 3 years and they rolled out Samsung repairs to us like 6 months into me being there. We had still not successfully completed a single repair when I left," another user added.</p><p>The publication further states that Best Buy will now only repair a Samsung device  purchased at Best Buy, and only for people who have a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://shop-links.co/link/?exclusive=1&publisher_slug=howtogeek&u1=UUhtgUeUpU2003529&article_name=Your+Galaxy+Phone+Is+Now+Harder+to+Get+Fixed&article_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.howtogeek.com%2Fyour-galaxy-phone-is-now-harder-to-get-fixed%2F&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fgeek-squad%2Fgeek-squad-protection%2Fpcmcat159800050001.c%3Fid%3Dpcmcat159800050001">Geek Squad Cell Phone Complete Protection insurance</a> and the replacement of any parts within the device would come at an added cost— which could be between $199 or $249.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:48.00%;"><img id="P5PPRZ2kp3f3mQpv8RbYtU" name="Samsung -ASP-error-message.jpg" alt="Best Buy ASP" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/P5PPRZ2kp3f3mQpv8RbYtU.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2400" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: The Verge)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In statements sent to the Verge, Samsung and Best Buy did not deny that they were going their separate ways. </p><p>“We’re in discussions with Best Buy to determine how Samsung can best support our customers moving forward,” reads a statement from Samsung head of mobile customer care Mario Renato de Castro, adding that Samsung has “more than 9,000 Samsung Mobile-certified technicians in the U.S. providing walk-in, mail-in and We Come to You van services.”</p><p>Katie Klister, Best Buy&apos;s spokesperson, said the company is evaluating the best way to support mobile customers with authorized services and repairs. </p><p>“We know how important it is to our customers that we’re there for them with the right services and expertise for their technology, and we’re currently working together with Samsung," Katie added.</p><p>According to several reports, Best Buy has taken down the option to repair Samsung phones on its website in the U.S. and only offers Apple repairs. That said, some Best Buy employees were seen putting two and two together <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GeekSquad/comments/1cst3kr/comment/l47l2c3/">on Reddit</a> regarding the end of the Samsung ASP program. </p><p>One employee confirmed 18 days ago, "worth mentioning Samsung also terminated their cell phone repair program with Geek Squad the other day with very little notice or information." </p><p>Another Best Buy employee provided an internal screenshot to The Verge stating that “Samsung ASP is ending in all SASP locations,” directing them to return the parts used for repairing devices.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:135.29%;"><img id="AKTsTzrVS5yXEgD8pDgcmU" name="Best-Buy-Employee-Screenshot.jpg" alt="Best Buy ASP" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AKTsTzrVS5yXEgD8pDgcmU.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2400" height="3247" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: The Verge)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>With <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-ifixit-breakup-highlights-google-efforts">iFixit</a> announcing in May that it would be ending its collaboration with Samsung, which allowed it to distribute OEM parts and repair guides, and now Best Buy following suit, it will become increasingly difficult to find authorized repair stores for when a Samsung device needs fixing. People now have to turn to third-party stores like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.ubreakifix.com/">uBreakiFix</a>, the only ones offering to repair Samsung devices.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/you-can-no-longer-fix-samsung-phones-at-best-buy</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Best Buy is doing away with its ASP program with Samsung's authorized service provider program (ASP), which lets certain Best Buy outlets repair your phone with Samsung parts and products. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Bxe6EcR9Hn32SYZyrzgBAV</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bVKWwrajQZTCksqxrC3dxG.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 22:17:15 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nandika.iyerravi@futurenet.com (Nandika Ravi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bVKWwrajQZTCksqxrC3dxG.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Best Buy]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Best Buy store]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Best Buy store]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Our favorite last-gen smartwatch is $100 OFF right now—but who knows for how long ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Looking for your next Android smartwatch deal? You can get <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-watch-silver-stainless-steel-smartwatch-41mm-with-charcoal-active-band-wifi-bt-silver-charcoal/6521699.p"><strong>$100 off for the Google Pixel Watch at Best Buy</strong></a> and other retailers right now, but there&apos;s no telling how long this deal will last. When it launched in 2022, it was one of our favorite smartwatches, so naturally we&apos;re not surprised that it stood the test of time and remains one of our favorite picks on the market — especially if you can pair it with a sweet deal.</p><p>The original Pixel Watch has one of the more comfortable and lightweight feels of any smartwatch out there, along with a simple design, rotating crown, and some extremely addicting haptics. Plus, it has a display that&apos;s easy to look at, along with a well-designed UI that&apos;s highly customizable.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="e7266d8e-d38c-492a-a1e4-53d350ae4aeb" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel Watch: $279.99" data-dimension48="Google Pixel Watch: $279.99" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-watch-silver-stainless-steel-smartwatch-41mm-with-charcoal-active-band-wifi-bt-silver-charcoal/6521699.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="5iFheMbbzXrvykno9Eyp73" name="google-pixel-watch-render-space.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5iFheMbbzXrvykno9Eyp73.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Google Pixel Watch: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-watch-silver-stainless-steel-smartwatch-41mm-with-charcoal-active-band-wifi-bt-silver-charcoal/6521699.p" data-dimension112="e7266d8e-d38c-492a-a1e4-53d350ae4aeb" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel Watch: $279.99" data-dimension48="Google Pixel Watch: $279.99"><del>$279.99</del> <strong>$179.99 at Best Buy</strong></a></p>
<p>You can currently get $100 off the last-generation <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-review">Google Pixel Watch</a> at Best Buy and other retailers right now. While it's not Google's latest-generation smartwatch, it was pretty well appreciated when it came out in 2022 and it's still a worthy contender at a lower price point than the Pixel Watch 2.</p>
<p>From the minimal design of the Pixel Watch to its user-friendly Wear OS, there are a lot of things worth appreciating here, even for a last-generation smartwatch.</p>
<p><strong>Price comparison:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-Watch-Smartwatch-Stainless/dp/B0BDSHFLMZ">Amazon - $179.99</a> | <a href="https://store.google.com/config/google_pixel_watch?hl=en-US&pli=1&selections=eyJwcm9kdWN0RmFtaWx5IjoiWjI5dloyeGxYM0JwZUdWc1gzZGhkR05vIiwidmFyaWFudHMiOltbIjIiLCJOQT09Il1dLCJ0cmFkZUluIjp7InNlbGVjdGlvbiI6M319">Google - 179.99</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-watch-silver-stainless-steel-smartwatch-41mm-with-charcoal-active-band-wifi-bt-silver-charcoal/6521699.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="e7266d8e-d38c-492a-a1e4-53d350ae4aeb" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel Watch: $279.99" data-dimension48="Google Pixel Watch: $279.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>you&apos;re looking for a comfortable, lightweight smartwatch and you don&apos;t mind going with one from the last generation; you&apos;re a regular user of the Fitbit app and want a watch that&apos;s already compatible.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if:</strong> you prefer going with a newer product and think the Pixel Watch 2 might be a better fit for you; you need automatic workout tracking or SpO2 tracking.</p><p>If you don&apos;t mind going with something that isn&apos;t the most recent release, the Google Pixel Watch is a pretty great option. It&apos;s the only last-generation smartwatch on our list of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch">best Android watches</a>, and there&apos;s more than one reason why.</p><p>The Pixel Watch boasts many of the classic health, GPS, and smart features associated with modern wearables. But it also has a good-looking AMOLED display, the user-friendly Wear OS, and convenient Fitbit app integration for those that already use the suite.</p><p>It&apos;s worth noting that the Pixel Watch doesn&apos;t have true automatic workout tracking or SpO2 tracking, but for most, it has everything needed in a smartwatch. And at $100 off, it&apos;s not hard to justify—even for a last-gen offering.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/our-favorite-last-gen-smartwatch-is-dollar100-off-right-nowbut-who-knows-for-how-long</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Right now, the capable Google Pixel Watch is $100 off from Best Buy and other retailers, offering a high-quality smartwatch at an economy-level price. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">er6iLWUtNCnkovcFw2xxRT</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kDYqMi4ND2BWE6ELFWo3Hb.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 21:40:53 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kDYqMi4ND2BWE6ELFWo3Hb.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Chris Wedel / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Pixel Watch on a charging stand at the Google Fall 2022 event]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Pixel Watch on a charging stand at the Google Fall 2022 event]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Galaxy AI experience will be further optimized for Samsung’s upcoming foldables ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung's EVP and Head of R&D Mobile Experience, Won-Joon Choi, said the company will "further optimize" Galaxy AI on the Flip 6 and Fold 6.</li><li>The company sees the foldables as the perfect places to begin showcasing "new possibilities" with its AI technology.</li><li>Samsung's "Live Translate" is also on tap to arrive in third-party messaging apps that support voice calls.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>A Samsung executive is getting candid about the company&apos;s plans to further improve its Galaxy AI experience on its foldables and other devices.</p><p>According to a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://news.samsung.com/global/human-centric-hybrid-ai-opens-up-new-possibilities">Newsroom post</a>, Samsung&apos;s EVP and Head of R&D Mobile Experience, Won-Joon Choi, said the company is interested in creating a "completely new and unique AI experience." While this started with the Galaxy S24 series, Choi said there are plans to expand on its foldables.</p><p>His post highlighted that Samsung will work to "further optimize the Galaxy AI experience" for its upcoming foldables. We&apos;re expecting the Galaxy Z Flip 6 and Fold, which the company calls "versatile" and "flexible." It&apos;s because of those devices&apos; versatility that Samsung views them as the perfect gateways to "new possibilities" surrounding Galaxy AI.</p><p>Beyond the stated plans, Samsung didn&apos;t have more to share as to what sort of new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-galaxy-ai">Galaxy AI</a> capabilities its foldables could see.</p><p>Elsewhere, Choi detailed the company&apos;s plans to expand its on-device AI features like "Live Translate." Samsung is working to enable Live Translate functionality on third-party <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-messaging-apps">messaging apps</a> with support for voice calls. Such apps could include WhatsApp and Telegram, but we&apos;ll have to wait and see as the company teases it will arrive "soon."</p><p>Since its AI language translation model does all the work on your device, the company states users can utilize it "without worrying" about privacy.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="kTAWL43CYbC2xDcA7GaAnP" name="samsung-galaxy-z-flip-5-cover-screen-clock-03.jpg" alt="The larger cover display of the Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 5" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kTAWL43CYbC2xDcA7GaAnP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Samsung debuted its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-samsung-galaxy-s24-live-translate">Live Translate</a> feature through Galaxy AI during its January Unpacked event. Consumers were able to see how the language translator takes in your conversation in real time to translate and transcribe the entire conversation. The feature on supported Galaxy devices can translate up to 13 languages, such as English, French, Japanese, Korean, Spanish, and more.</p><p>However, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-galaxy-ai-more-language-support-announced">more language support</a> is on the way, according to a press release in April.</p><p>In other news, Samsung&apos;s executive highlighting an expansion of Galaxy AI capabilities for its upcoming foldables is a welcome sight. Considering Samsung&apos;s efforts in AI, we were already expecting the devices to feature Galaxy AI, but what could be in store remains a mystery.</p><p>For now, we have the latest batch of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-and-z-flip-6-spotted-in-an-ad">leaked promotional imagery</a> for the upcoming Flip 6 and Fold 6, which should debut later this summer.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-ai-experience-optimized-upcoming-foldable-teased</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A Samsung executive teased new optimizations for its upcoming foldable phones and more for Galaxy AI. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">ZerCcdMzm9Ca2GArkARrrc</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/L3quxmvqF9QotvkCNqsbmN.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 19:42:06 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/L3quxmvqF9QotvkCNqsbmN.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Samsung]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[&quot;Galaxy AI is here&quot; in white font on a grey background]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[&quot;Galaxy AI is here&quot; in white font on a grey background]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google might bring AR directions and UWB support to Android's Find My Device ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A discovery from the Find My Device network app highlights Google's plans to bring AR-based directions and UWB support to Android users.</li><li>The AR directions would guide users to their UWB-supported tracker or device by layering its UI through a user's camera.</li><li>The app could give users access to AR-based directions for more than just UWB-capable trackers and devices.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>With Google still expanding the reach of its Find My Device network, signs in the app&apos;s code point toward new connectivity support.</p><p>A deep dive into version 3.1.078-1 of the Find My Device app by AssembleDebug, in conjunction with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/google-find-my-device-uwb-ar-upgrade-apk-teardown-3449281/">Android Authority</a>, spilled upcoming UWB and AR support. Starting with the former, strings in the app&apos;s code reference "precision finding" for a UWB adapter. The tipster discovered additional "libraries" about the app supporting UWB, with a string highlighting the "startRanging call" function.</p><p>With little else to uncover about the potential UWB portion of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/find-my-device">Find My Device</a>, the tipster detailed the app&apos;s AR-based location discovery.</p><p>Speculation suggests Google&apos;s implementation of AR technology (through ARCore) would pair well with its UWB functionality. Essentially, the company could let users use their <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phone&apos;s</a> camera in the app, showing a layered augmented reality UI with directions to guide them to their lost UWB device.</p><p>However, AR-based directions to guide users to their lost objects might not be restricted to UWB-support devices. The tipster&apos;s discoveries note that strings in the code don&apos;t reference the two methods as working exclusively together.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:269px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:223.05%;"><img id="yJxkznqjYeD9wZx4ZGK9Mf" name="samsung-galaxy-smarttag-2-ar-directions.jpg" alt="Samsung provides users with AR-based location directions on their device." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yJxkznqjYeD9wZx4ZGK9Mf.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="269" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google&apos;s AR and UWB support development is still ongoing, so we likely won&apos;t see it for a while.</p><p>The post notes that Samsung uses a similar AR-based direction UI with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/samsung-galaxy-smarttag-2-announcement">Galaxy SmartTag 2</a>. The only problem, as the publication notes, is that the feature requires a user to have a UWB-capable Galaxy phone. Google is seemingly moving toward convenience, bringing the UWB tech to the app instead.</p><p>At the end of May, Google <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-find-my-device-extra-user-security-spotted">was tipped to bolster</a> its Find My Device network&apos;s user security. A new biometric security option was discovered, giving users an extra layer of safety to their devices in case their phone is away from them. This will likely work well with the network&apos;s "don&apos;t ask again" option when signing into the app using a Google account.</p><p>Additionally, the app&apos;s code referenced Google&apos;s planned "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-io-2024-android-upcoming-security-privacy-layers">Remote Lock</a>" feature. Google had already teased it during I/O 2024, stating a user could lock down their phone using their phone number after completing a quick security challenge. This feature isn&apos;t expected to arrive until "later this year."</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-ar-directions-uwb-find-my-device</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google was spotted working on AR-based directions and UWB tracker support for its Find My Device app. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">XZWdSnwfeomCt2YfbdoFRj</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3vBXxerD7i88m5jioaP76S.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 19:03:24 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3vBXxerD7i88m5jioaP76S.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Find My Device list of devices on phone]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Find My Device list of devices on phone]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>