<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 21:47:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Gemini on lock screen lets users call anyone without unlocking their phone ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google is reportedly rolling out its "make calls and send messages" feature for Gemini on lock screen for Android.</li><li>Using the "Hey Google" command, users can instruct Gemini to "call" someone so long as the lock screen function is enabled.</li><li>Devices without this function will be prompted to unlock their device to progress.</li><li>Gemini on lock screen has received support to control alarms, media, timers, and more.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google teased new lock screen features for its AI model Gemini months ago and one of those tools is now arriving — at least, for some.</p><p>As spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/12/02/gemini-call-message-without-unlocking/">9to5Google</a>, the Gemini app on Android is picking up a setting that lets users "make calls and send messages." The publication states this feature is appearing in the recent beta version of the Google app (v15.48).  According to the post, this is tucked within the app's "Gemini on lock screen" settings page via a toggleable button.</p><p>However, the app warns users that the AI cannot function properly if their "calling and messaging" apps are not "turned on" in Gemini.</p><p>Once this is done, users can surface Gemini's small overlay from their lock screen to call someone. It seems that users can type or vocally speak who they would like Gemini to call. All that's required is that you begin your instruction with "call" followed by your contact's name.</p><p>Google states that users can produce Gemini on their lock screen by using the "Hey Google" command.</p><p>More importantly, the post notes that the Gemini on lock screen feature isn't available on every Android device. If your device does not have it, Gemini surfaces when called, but it will not fulfill the call request. Instead, the AI will prompt you to unlock your device <em>before </em>anything else can be done.</p><p>More testers should begin seeing this before the eventual debut for stable app folk.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:264px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:227.27%;"><img id="3pkDpWBVDAeo5XHjwjKVAJ" name="google-gemini-lock-screen-call-messaging-spotted" alt="Gemini on lock screen is pushing its calling/messaging function on the lock screen for beta testers." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3pkDpWBVDAeo5XHjwjKVAJ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="264" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: 9to5Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>We've seen glimpses of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-app-beta-gemini-lock-screen-ai-detailed">Gemini's new lock screen usage</a> in July before features started appearing. The early splash page detailed that the AI could "message, find music, get location-based information, and more with extensions." It was suspected that users would get a wide range of Gemini extensions to use on their lock screen. However, despite those tools being confirmed by Google, they've yet to appear for users.</p><p>What <em>has </em>arrived, per Google's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/gemini/answer/14576209?hl=en">support page</a>, is the ability for Gemini on lock screen to control your alarms, timers, flashlight, volume, and media. To see if your device has lock screen functions, Google recommends hopping into the <strong>Gemini app > Profile icon > Settings > Gemini on lock screen</strong>. If it's there, toggle it on to begin using such features.</p><p>The company started pushing <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini-spotify-extension-rollout-detailed">its Spotify extension</a> for the Gemini app late in November. Users can access commands under its "Play & Search" moniker. The extension lets users find songs based on artist, song title, playlist, or lyric. This new ability was listed alongside several more expected extensions for Gemini like Phone, Messages, WhatsApp, and more.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/gemini-on-lock-screen-call-messages--rollout</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google is reportedly pushing a new Gemini on lock screen feature for call and message control. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">HvY6iXJFW2Yh2kjSGdbVtY</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4sUeciYBZHaLoMa5KiYw7h.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 20:15:07 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4sUeciYBZHaLoMa5KiYw7h.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Gemini response on Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Gemini response on Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ These Beats earbuds are down to just $50 in a leftover Cyber Monday deal — it's the perfect stocking stuffer ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Beats attacked the budget earbuds market when it launched the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/beats-solo-buds-review">Beats Solo Buds</a> this year — they're the brand's smallest truly-wireless (TWS) earbuds ever and they only cost $79.99. That's why I was shocked to see the Solo Buds on sale for $30 off on Cyber Monday, and even more surprised to see that this deal is sticking around AFTER Cyber Monday.  At a discounted price of $50, I think the Beats Solo Buds are a no-brainer for a stocking stuffer, backup pair of earbuds, or even a budget-friendly daily driver.</p><p>There's no telling how long the Beats Solo Buds will be <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/beats-solo-buds-true-wireless-earbuds-matte-black/6501050.p?skuId=6501050" target="_blank">$49.99 ($30 off) at Best Buy</a>, so you should jump on this deal now if you're interested. By the way, this matches the lowest price we've ever seen for the Solo Buds.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="64c23b43-899d-4a9c-bd52-59f84d48f11a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Beats Beats Solo Buds" data-dimension48="Beats Solo Buds: $79.99" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/beats-solo-buds-true-wireless-earbuds-matte-black/6501050.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="wtqTYBwfLT7pwYiqzQGiAM" name="Beats-Solo-Buds-White-Render" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wtqTYBwfLT7pwYiqzQGiAM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1000" height="1000" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Beats Solo Buds: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/beats-solo-buds-true-wireless-earbuds-matte-black/6501050.p" target="_blank" data-dimension112="64c23b43-899d-4a9c-bd52-59f84d48f11a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Beats Beats Solo Buds" data-dimension48="Beats Solo Buds: $79.99" data-dimension25=""><del><u>$79.99</u></del><u> </u><u><strong>$49.99 at Best Buy</strong></u></a></p><p>The Beats Solo Buds are the company's newest pair of truly-wireless (TWS) earbuds, and they're also Beats' smallest ever. You get a carrying case (<strong>not</strong> a charging case) that's the smallest I've ever seen, decent sound, and feature parity on iOS and Android. Plus, I love that you can get a cool Transparent Red colorway for only $50 for a limited time. </p><p><strong>Price comparison:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Beats-Solo-Buds-Compatibility-Built/dp/B0D3JB14QS/" target="_blank">Amazon - $49.99</a> | <a href="https://www.target.com/p/beats-solo-buds-true-wireless-bluetooth-earbuds-arctic-purple/-/A-92146820" target="_blank">Target - $49.99</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/beats-solo-buds-true-wireless-earbuds-matte-black/6501050.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="64c23b43-899d-4a9c-bd52-59f84d48f11a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Beats Beats Solo Buds" data-dimension48="Beats Solo Buds: $79.99" data-dimension25="">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Leftover Cyber Monday deals</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Cyber Monday Google Pixel deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Cyber Monday Motorola deals<br></a>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/samsung-black-friday-2024-deals">Cyber Monday Samsung deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Cyber Monday OnePlus deals</a></p></div></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>you want a lightweight and compact pair of TWS earbuds; you want a pair of earbuds that won't break the bank; you want fast-pairing support on iOS and Android.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>you need earbuds with a charging case; you want more expensive earbuds with better sound.</p>
<p>I've reviewed all the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-earbuds">best earbuds</a>, from the AirPods Pro 2, to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/earbuds/samsung-galaxy-buds-3-pro-review">Samsung Galaxy Buds 3 Pro</a>, to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/oneplus-buds-pro-3-review">OnePlus Buds Pro 3</a>. Now, I'm not here to tell you that these earbuds, costing triple the price of the Beats Solo Buds, sound worse than the Solo Buds. That simply isn't true. But the Solo Buds have one advantage over ALL other earbuds on the market, and that's size. The earbuds' carrying case measures 2.6 x 1.4 x 0.9 in., which is so small you have to see it to believe it.</p><p>That means you can take them with you everywhere, whether that's in a small pocket, purse, or bag. As a trade-off, the Solo Buds come with a carrying case, not a charging case. There's no extra battery in the case, but that doesn't really matter, because each earbud gives you an outstanding 18 hours of battery life on a single charge. A five-minute recharge via USB-C gives the earbuds an extra hour of playback.</p><p>And the Solo Buds sound great for an $80 pair of earbuds, let alone a $50 pair of earbuds. The bass could be fuller, but these tiny earbuds are limited by driver size here. Otherwise, the mids and highs sound excellent. On top of that, you get advanced Beats features, like fast pairing with both iOS and Android.</p><p>I don't know how these earbuds are so cheap, but I know I'd buy them if I were you.</p>

<ul><li><strong>Headphone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/browse/3944_133251_1095191_1230614_1230477"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/promo/headphone-and-speaker-deals"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=headphones&crid=3JN832N1C6WXP&sprefix=headphones%2Caps%2C172&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.dell.com/en-us/search/headphones?p=1&c=8310%2C8318&f=true&ac=categoryfacetselect"><u><strong>Dell</strong></u></a></li><li><strong>Earbuds deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/promo/headphone-and-speaker-deals"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/browse/electronics/shop-headphones-by-type/3944_133251_1095191_1230614?sort=best_match&cat_id=3944_133251_1095191_1230614_1230476&stores=3081&ps=40"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=earbuds&crid=2RWE1G9N1EIF&sprefix=earbuds%2Caps%2C161&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/mobile/audio/all-audio/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.dell.com/en-us/search/earbuds"><u><strong>Dell</strong></u><strong><br></strong></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/these-beats-earbuds-are-down-to-just-usd50-in-a-leftover-cyber-monday-deal-its-the-perfect-stocking-stuffer</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Getting a pair of truly-wireless earbuds for $50 is unreal, and somehow this deal is still here. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">xq5R6nM3iNXp3owKZufa2Q</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gCEUCVnEG4Xv8pnVU9Pgtd.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 19:40:54 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gCEUCVnEG4Xv8pnVU9Pgtd.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Brady Snyder / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The transparent red Beats Solo buds on a ledge.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The transparent red Beats Solo buds on a ledge.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Wallet's Wear OS update turns your wrist into a useful room key ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google is pushing an update today (Dec 3) that lets users pair even more cards to the Wallet app on a Wear OS device.</li><li>The newly supported cards include hotel rooms, campus IDs, and "corporate badges" for offices.</li><li>Google Wallet as been busy expanding digital ID support to states like California alongside a teaser to bring in passports.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Having Google Wallet on your wrist is useful for quick payments, but this latest Wear OS update expands its card support.</p><p>As December gets underway, Google is rolling out its latest <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/product-documentation/answer/14343500">Play Services update</a> (v24.47), which is heavily focused on Android and Wear OS. The standout portion of this update regards Google Wallet's new expansion of card and country support for users.</p><p>Concerning the former, the company's support page states that Wear OS devices are receiving an update that brings access to cards for hotel rooms, campus IDs, and "corporate badges."</p><p>Additionally, the page details that "more countries" can now use Google Wallet. This involves the app's appearance on Android, as well as Wear OS watches.</p><p>It's worth noting that this expansion joins Wear OS device's support for credit and debit cards. There were also a few choices for transit that users could pop onto their watch, as well as Google Wallet's support <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/wearos/answer/14260807?hl=en">for passes via QR or barcode</a>.</p><p>The Play Services update is also rolling in a developer feature addition that lets "Google and third-party app developers to support Device Connectivity related processes in their apps."</p><p>The update started rolling out on December 2, so users should give it a few days before Google Wallet's new support hits their devices.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="MqR97nhWDLouM2SmndZgF3" name="add-card-to-google-wallet-pixel-watch.jpg" alt="Add new card to Google Wallet on Pixel Watch" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MqR97nhWDLouM2SmndZgF3.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4080" height="2294" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It's good to see Google extending Wallet support on Wear OS devices after it's been occupied with its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-will-soon-let-users-create-a-digital-id-in-wallet-from-their-passport">plans to incorporate passports</a> into digital IDs. The company teased such a possibility in September, stating it would begin "beta-testing" U.S. passports in Wallet. A digital ID like this isn't being accepted everywhere as Google stated only "select" Transportation Security Administration (TSA) checkpoints domestically will allow it.</p><p>Those discussions started a month <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/california-preapres-google-wallet-id-support">after California prepared</a> to enter the digital ID game for its residents. The state started testing such functionality with DMV employees before reaching out to regular civilians at a later date. It was stated that users could enter "Add to Wallet" and tap "ID Card" to add their state ID. Similar to the passport situation, California only allowed its digital IDs to be used at "select" terminals at San Francisco International Airport, San Jose International Airport, and Los Angeles International Airport.</p><p>California is joined by several more U.S. states that will soon accept digital IDs like Iowa, New Mexico, and Ohio, which have entered testing.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-wallet-wear-os-hotel-card-support-expansion-update</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google's latest Play Services update brings more card support to Wallet on Wear OS. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">JuzVJP5juzVHrFfSZeGrbh</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zaAk7gqKLE5HJtAN84akhh.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 19:38:17 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zaAk7gqKLE5HJtAN84akhh.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Google Pixel Watch 3 sitting on a rock with the Index Bold watch face]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Google Pixel Watch 3 sitting on a rock with the Index Bold watch face]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Here's everything Garmin added to its smartwatches in the December 2024 update ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Garmin's feature drop for December 2024 brings a total of five new features to select watches and computers.</li><li>The Garmin Fenix 7/Pro series, Epix Gen 2/Pro series, Enduro 2, Tactix 7 series, MARQ Gen 2, Quatix 7/Pro, D2 Mach 1/Pro, Fenix E/8 series, Enduro 3, Forerunner 165/255/265/955/956 series, Venu 3, Vivoactive 5, Edge 540/840/1040/1050 series, and Edge Explore 2 will all receive various parts of the update.</li><li>The rollout of the December 2024 feature drop is ongoing, but will continue over the coming weeks, according to Garmin.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Garmin is rolling out the December 2024 feature update to many of its smartwatches and computers, according to a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www8.garmin.com/wearables/PDF/WearablesSoftwareUpdate/2024/December2024.pdf?cjdata=MXxOfDB8WXww&zebratwo=CJ&cjevent=afdd050fb10b11ef82f0def90a1eba23&utm_source=CJ&utm_medium=Text" target="_blank">PDF breakdown</a> spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.notebookcheck.net/Garmin-details-December-2024-Feature-Drop-for-dozens-of-cycling-computers-and-smartwatches.926747.0.html" target="_blank">NotebookCheck</a>. Users of select Garmin models may already be able to download the update, and the rollout will continue "over the coming weeks." Among the most notable improvements are functional threshold power (FTP) auto-detection and lactate threshold auto-detection.</p><p>The update is available for a wide variety of Garmin models, including the Garmin Fenix 7/Pro series, Epix Gen 2/Pro series, Enduro 2, Tactix 7 series, MARQ Gen 2, Quatix 7/Pro, D2 Mach 1/Pro, Fenix E/8 series, Enduro 3, Forerunner 165/255/265/955/956 series, Venu 3, Vivoactive 5, Edge 540/840/1040/1050 series, and Edge Explore 2. However, not every watch and computer will receive every feature.</p><p>The following Garmin models will receive the December 2024 update, and get the following features:</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1972px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:46.35%;"><img id="3fKEJzWV8EtxxqdspGanHe" name="Garmin-December-2024-Feature-Drop" alt="A breakdown of the features coming to various Garmin models." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3fKEJzWV8EtxxqdspGanHe.png" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1972" height="914" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Garmin)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-fenix-8-review">Garmin Fenix 8</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/i-ditched-my-apple-and-galaxy-watches-for-a-garmin-and-you-should-too">Enduro 3</a> watches, plus the Forerunner 955/965 series, are the only smartwatches to receive every feature. That includes lactate threshold and FTP auto-detection, Garmin Coach strength training plans, workout execution score improvements, and meditation activity. However, it's worth noting that the Fenix 8 and Enduro 3 shipped with Garmin Coach strength training plans out of the box.</p><p>The new functionality will make it possible for wearers to get their lactate threshold heart rate, pace, and power from their Garmin watch, even without doing high-intensity workouts.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4480px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="kEM78AfQ7LiSm935yBkUfC" name="Garmin-Enduro-3-Screen-Zoomed" alt="The screen of the Garmin Enduro 3." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kEM78AfQ7LiSm935yBkUfC.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4480" height="2520" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Brady Snyder / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>At least one feature, workout execution score improvements, will also be coming to select Garmin Edge cycling computers. After the update is available for your device, you'll be able to download it and try out the latest features.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="047d6b8c-6ad9-4f77-b119-804145db75fb">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/86NvA3JryhDKJEYfBRWTeQ.jpg' alt="Render of the Garmin Enduro 3"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Garmin Enduro 3</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The longest-lasting Garmin ever</strong></em></p><p>Garmin's latest Enduro 3 watch features an impossibly-long battery life and a ton of advanced features. Plus, it's getting a few more as part of the December 2024 update, including lactate threshold and FTP auto-detection. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/heres-everything-garmin-added-to-its-smartwatches-in-the-december-2024-update</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Lactate threshold auto-detection, functional threshold power, and more are coming to select Garmin watches. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">L2UtpeXTXFnFAHRXYLVm4M</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/eJdCTaTDPe9awCzVhgfudX.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 18:30:45 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/eJdCTaTDPe9awCzVhgfudX.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A close-up side view of the Garmin Fenix 8 with the default watch face]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A close-up side view of the Garmin Fenix 8 with the default watch face]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google might bring its AI hosts to Gemini on Android for your documents ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A discovery in Android's Google app beta shows the company might roll out NotebookLM's Audio Overviews.</li><li>The feature operates similarly to how it does on the web; however, the early discovery is only delivering a text-based summary, not the audio file.</li><li>What's unclear is if Android will pick up NotebookLM's "Guide" for the AI hosts, which is debuted in October.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google is tipped to expand a useful AI-based feature to Android users that might save you time in lengthy documents.</p><p>In conjunction with X tipster AssembleDebug, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/gemini-audio-overviews-3504779/">Android Authority</a> reports that Google is seemingly working on bringing NotebookLM's Audio Overviews to Android. The discovery was made through the Google app's recent beta (v15.48.33.sa.arm64). According to the tipster, the Gemini app is preparing to introduce a "create_podcast" function for Android users.</p><p>Essentially, the code describes this as a "query," allowing users to tap on the button to prompt the AI to produce a generated audio file of the submitted document.</p><p>The tipster states the feature isn't working completely; however, a quick dip in shows the basic steps. It seems users will be able to upload a document from the writing field in the Gemini app by hitting the plus icon. After which, an option will supposedly appear above it stating "generative audio overview." Interacting with this will instruct the AI to scour through the given document to produce a more engaging file hosted by two AIs.</p><p>The publication notes a string in the code that mentions an "overview." This basic overview appears to concern the written summary the AI is also able to produce. AssembleDebug highlights that the specific Audio Overview feature isn't working in this early beta preview and that Gemini defaults to a "text-based summary."</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:268px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:223.88%;"><img id="qRDocmb63huNLPApAdFyKQ" name="google-notebooklm-android-audio-overview-upload" alt="NotebookLM may bring its Audio Overviews for documents to Android." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qRDocmb63huNLPApAdFyKQ.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="268" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:267px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:224.72%;"><img id="85DtcXQ2kheJaskDC2YVoT" name="google-notebooklm-android-audio-overview-early-preview-beta" alt="Currently, the beta discovery has the Audio Overviews defaulted to a text summary." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/85DtcXQ2kheJaskDC2YVoT.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="267" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Once this feature rolls out, it's likely that there will be a play option alongside the text-based summary. It's worth mentioning that the written summary appears quite brief. The full audio log <em>should </em>go into greater depth, especially if we consider how it works on the web.</p><p>Google launched its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/notebooklm-audio-overviews-radio-like-ai">Audio Overviews</a> as part of NotebookLM in September as an auditory alternative to learning. The feature operates like a radio talk show as the two AI hosts discuss the contents of a submitted document for you. The company highlighted that the AI hosts will also "make connections" about subjects, items, and more found within a submitted document.</p><p>When it rolled out, Google stated users on the web could upload slides, charts, and more alongside documents.</p><p>Android users are seemingly in line to receive the same support; however, it's unclear if Audio Overview's "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/notebooklm-guide-ai-hosts-business-pilot-program">Guide</a>" will enter, too. Shortly after in October, the company rolled out an additional function that lets users guide the AI in a specific direction when talking about a document. Users can write a detailed description to "guide the conversation."</p><p>The discovery of Android receiving NotebookLM's podcast-like feature shows space to write something extra <em>after </em>attaching a file. So, perhaps we can expect this; but we won't know for sure until it arrives.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/gemini-android-ai-overviews-spotted</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ NotebookLM's Audio Overviews may find a home on Android through Gemini. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">uWSZRwTEmYC8FmkToEpECn</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zzPTyYHBTjqpoen3vuSttM.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 18:24:22 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zzPTyYHBTjqpoen3vuSttM.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google launches a customizable button for the AI hosts in NotebookLM.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google launches a customizable button for the AI hosts in NotebookLM.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ How to use Google Wallet to make custom digital passes ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Google Wallet is a very useful app for organizing all your passes in a single app. Everything from boarding passes for your next flight, transit passes, to the loyalty card of your favorite coffee joint — all can be easily accessed from one place. When you first set up Wallet, it automatically scans your Gmail and picks up information on passes you might already have in emails. But even if it's not able to detect a certain pass or you don't see the 'Add to Google Wallet' option for a new online pass, there's a simple way to manually do it.</p><p>We'll also walk you through how you can add a new custom pass to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet">Google Wallet</a> via an image of a pass that you may have on your phone. Wallet automatically fills in all the pertinent information that would be needed and saves it as a card. The next time you need to scan your subway pass or a membership card at the gym, you can simply fire up the app and tap on the card you need, without worrying about the physical card or jumping through multiple apps. It truly is one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-apps">best Android apps</a> from Google, today.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-make-a-custom-pass-in-wallet-via-a-barcode-or-qr-code-2">How to make a custom pass in Wallet via a barcode or QR code</h2>
<p>1. Open the <strong>Google Wallet</strong> app.</p><p>2. Tap the <strong>Add to Wallet</strong> button with the '+' symbol in the bottom right corner.</p><p>3. Choose the type of card you want to add. We've selected '<strong>Loyalty card</strong>.'</p><p>4. Next, you'll see a list of popular options for your region.</p><p>5. For this example, we've chosen <strong>'Watsons Malaysia.'</strong></p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1200px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:73.33%;"><img id="VfiU62AVumRshuMGCaBJy6" name="add-custom-pass-google-wallet-1" alt="Google Wallet app showing steps to add pass via bardcode scanning" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VfiU62AVumRshuMGCaBJy6.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1200" height="880" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>6. Now, you can either manually enter your member ID and save it, or use the 'Scan your card' option.</p><p>7. Scanning is always better as it's a lot quicker. Simply point your camera's viewfinder to the barcode or QR code on the card and it should be done in a second.</p><p>9. Your newly added card should show up on Wallet's main page.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1706px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:70.34%;"><img id="2KCzYbezs3GbuDupxwYgbL" name="add-custom-pass-google-wallet-4" alt="Google Wallet app screenshot showing the newly added loyalty card" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2KCzYbezs3GbuDupxwYgbL.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1706" height="1200" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<h2 id="how-to-make-a-custom-pass-in-wallet-by-scanning-a-card-or-from-an-image-in-your-gallery-2">How to make a custom pass in Wallet by scanning a card or from an image in your gallery</h2>
<p>1. Follow the instructions above till the second step.</p><p>2. Here, choose the '<strong>Photo</strong>' option which should be separated from others by a wavy line.</p><p>3. If you have a physical card you wish to scan, hold the phone directly above it and <strong>press the capture button</strong>.</p><p>4. You can crop & rotate, add a filter, retake, or delete the photo if needed.</p><p>5. To add a photo of your card from your image gallery, simply press the <strong>symbol on the left</strong> of the shutter button to browse your gallery for the image of your pass.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1200px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:73.33%;"><img id="9mHR2eyrf9Z5YXt3fcJvWT" name="add-custom-pass-google-wallet-2" alt="Google Wallet screenshot showing adding pass by photo method" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9mHR2eyrf9Z5YXt3fcJvWT.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1200" height="880" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> Your card must have a barcode or QR code for it to be successfully added to Wallet.</p><p>Another thing we noticed was that if your pass or card has both a barcode and a QR code, the app gets confused and warns you about there being too many codes. An easy fix is to simply cover one of the codes and then try rescanning.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1598px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.09%;"><img id="ahjPLYtzdZ7PWZAkbTTw69" name="add-custom-pass-google-wallet-3-wide" alt="Google Wallet screenshot showing error due to multiple QR codes" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ahjPLYtzdZ7PWZAkbTTw69.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1598" height="1200" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<h2 id="manage-all-your-passes-from-google-wallet-2">Manage all your passes from Google Wallet</h2>
<p>Google Wallet has had a rocky history, with it first being an exclusive app for Nexus phones for contactless payments to eventually being killed off in favor of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-pay">Google Pay</a>. The Wallet app is here to stay though, at least for the foreseeable future as Google has <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-pay-changes-june-shutdown-announced">shuttered the Google Pay app</a> in the U.S. as of June 2024. Apart from peer-to-peer payments, the current Wallet app can do pretty much everything else.</p><p>You can store debit and credit cards in Google Wallet and Google just <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet-supports-42-additional-banks">added dozens of new banks</a> in 2024 alone. If you do plan on adding your banking cards, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-lock-down-google-wallet-cards">make sure it's secure</a> so it's not misused in the event you lose your phone. Other than adding your loyalty cards and boarding passes, you can also use Wallet to store additional items like digital car keys, corporate office passes, hotel keys, and so on. It's amazing how much use you can get out of a single app.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="6b0f1ddf-8220-4ab8-aa97-36f0535b28c9">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RGLzkSSEaGTvsjXvJayfZN.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro official render - Hazel - Front/Back"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 Pro</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Google's finest</strong></em></p><p>Enjoy apps like Google Wallet on a device made by the maker of the app. The Pixel 9 Pro comes with a wide range of AI features, superb cameras, and an excellent UI with meaningful tweaks and extras like the At a Glance widget.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-use-google-wallet-to-make-custom-digital-passes</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Need to have a loyalty card or bus pass handy with you at all times? You can simply digitize any pass with a QR code by following these simple steps in Google Wallet. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">iEtogFtJPnuDrXvCMCttYE</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xU2jTt7a6cy2axromnyaBS.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 15:51:13 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ roydon.cerejo@gmail.com (Roydon Cerejo) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xU2jTt7a6cy2axromnyaBS.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Roydon Cerejo / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Wallet app on loading screen]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Wallet app on loading screen]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung might finally give the Galaxy Z Fold 7 and Flip 7 the screen upgrades they need ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The Galaxy Z Fold 7 and Flip 7 are rumored to sport larger displays than their predecessors.</li><li>Samsung's upcoming Z Fold 7 could offer an 8-inch main display and a 6.5-inch cover screen.</li><li>Meanwhile, the Z Flip 7 is also in line for a bigger screen, with a 6.85-inch foldable display and a 4-inch cover screen.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Foldable phones are already big when unfolded, but next year’s Samsung foldables might push those limits with even larger screens.</p><p>Display industry expert Ross Young has shared some exciting updates on Samsung’s next-gen foldables. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-7">Galaxy Z Fold 7</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-7">Flip 7</a> are rumored to come with bigger screens than their current versions (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidpolice.com/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-7-flip-7-upgrade-been-waiting-for/" target="_blank">Android Police</a>). Interestingly, Young suggests the Fold 6 SE might have set the stage for the Fold 7, hinting at a fresh direction for Samsung’s foldable lineup.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Fold 7 should have same display sizes as Fold 6 SE. So, Fold 6 SE will basically become the Fold 7. Flip 7 should grow from 6.7" to 6.85" and cover display should be around 4".<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1863671122249818428">December 2, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>The Galaxy Z Fold 6 SE stands out with its slimmer design, a 6.5-inch cover screen rocking a consistent 21:9 aspect ratio, and a roomy 8-inch inner display, which is bigger than the standard Fold’s 7.6-inch screen.</p><p>If you’ve been eyeing the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-special-edition-announced">larger Special Edition Galaxy Z Fold 6</a> that was limited to South Korea and China, the Galaxy Z Fold 7 is your global ticket.</p><p>If the Z Fold 7 follows the Special Edition’s lead, we’re in for a serious screen upgrade. The main display will stretch to 8 inches, beating the Z Fold 6’s 7.6-inch screen, and the cover screen will jump to 6.5 inches—bigger than the 6.3-inch one on the previous model.</p><p>The Galaxy Z Flip 7 could be getting a screen upgrade too. Rumor has it the clamshell foldable's display will stretch to 6.85 inches, up from the 6.7-inch one on the Z Flip 6. Plus, the cover screen is tipped to grow to around 4 inches, way bigger than the 3.4-inch screen on its predecessor.</p><p>Samsung has been sticking to the same display size for its foldables for a while now. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Z Fold 6</a> did give the cover screen a tiny stretch, but it didn’t really change much.</p><p>While some of our <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">favorite foldable phones</a> went for bigger screens, Samsung kept it steady. But come 2025, it looks like the South Korean tech giant is finally jumping on the bigger display bandwagon with their next foldables.</p>
<hr>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="b844c5df-f056-43db-89aa-4eb6e128812d">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:98.61%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Qk9BrbQMCLYk6ofsRaMfP.jpg' alt="Galaxy Z Fold 6 render in white"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>Samsung’s cautious approach with the Fold 6 has made it a solid flagship, but it's starting to feel a bit behind. While it performs well and has handy S Pen support, the lack of major upgrades in display size and camera tech might not keep up with the rapid changes in foldables.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-might-finally-give-the-galaxy-z-fold-7-and-flip-7-the-screen-upgrades-they-need</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung might be giving the Galaxy Z Fold 7 and Flip 7 bigger screens in 2025. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">2jAWcYtvZuX6LKnNGj2zjc</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PrzagfR3vjSSkvhpUAwuS.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 15:30:21 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PrzagfR3vjSSkvhpUAwuS.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 inner screen]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 inner screen]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ This Snapdragon 8 Elite smartphone under $600 finally goes global ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The iQOO 13 has made its global debut, now available in India in two configurations: 12GB+256GB (₹51,999) and 16GB+512GB (₹56,999).</li><li>It features a 6.82-inch 144Hz LTPO AMOLED display, a 6,000mAh battery, and tough IP68/IP69K durability ratings, plus 120W fast charging.</li><li>Powered by Snapdragon 8 Elite and iQOO’s SuperComputing Chip Q2, it delivers smooth gaming with up to 144fps, even on games capped at 60fps.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/iqoo-13-review">iQOO 13</a>, fresh off its China debut, finally launches outside its home turf. The flagship phone has landed in India  in 12GB+256GB (₹51,999) and 16GB+512GB (₹56,999) configurations.</p><p>The global version sticks to the same top-tier specs as its Chinese version. It’s got a 6.82-inch 144Hz LTPO AMOLED display, a 6,000mAh battery, and serious durability with IP68 and IP69K ratings. Plus, 120W fast charging keeps it speedy all around (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.gizmochina.com/2024/12/03/iqoo-13-launches-in-india-snapdragon-8-elite-6000mah-battery-ai-features-and-4-years-of-os-updates/" target="_blank">Gizmochina</a>).</p><p>Under the hood, it's powered by a Snapdragon 8 Elite SoC paired with iQOO’s second-gen SuperComputing Chip Q2, which is designed to boost game resolution and frame rates more efficiently. Thanks to this chip, the phone can push gameplay up to 144fps on compatible games, even if they’re capped at 60fps.</p><p>The iQOO 13 brings a unique flair with its "Monster Halo" light strip circling the rear camera module. Taking a cue from Nothing’s design, this isn’t just for show—it handles notifications, call alerts, charging status, and even bumps along to your music. You can customize it with 12 colors and six breathing styles.</p><p>It packs a powerhouse camera setup with three 50MP sensors—a Sony IMX921 main, a telephoto, and an ultrawide lens. For selfies and video chats, there’s a 32MP front camera.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="Mp78Ap7pwQgGobyfkbH9Vf" name="iqoo-13-21.jpg" alt="iQOO 13 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Mp78Ap7pwQgGobyfkbH9Vf.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The camera is loaded with cool features like long exposure, slow-mo, Supermoon mode, tilt-shift, live photos, and even an Ultra HD Document mode for crystal-clear scans.</p><p>iQOO's latest <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phone</a> takes things up a notch from the iQOO 12 with a beefed-up VC cooling system—17% more cooling area, 10% better heat dissipation, and a 26% boost in efficiency.</p><p>The iQOO 13 runs on Funtouch OS 15, built on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a>. iQOO promises four years of major updates and five years of security patches, setting a strong standard for long-term support.</p><p>Sadly, the iQOO 13 isn’t hitting the US market since iQOO and Vivo don’t sell their devices there. For those who can snag one, it’s available in two sleek colors: Legend White and Nardo Grey.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/this-snapdragon-8-elite-smartphone-under-usd600-finally-goes-global</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ iQOO 13 lands in India with smart AI features and a flashy "Monster Halo" light ring on the back. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">r7PjKeENn2WQzUG3jKQgka</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GzSQV4NWeSHFAHFbqWeTKa.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 14:10:20 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GzSQV4NWeSHFAHFbqWeTKa.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[iQOO 13 review]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[iQOO 13 review]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The ONLY workout earbuds I'll ever wear are 31% off for Cyber Monday (for now!) ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Ever since I reviewed the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/shokz-openfit-review">Shokz OpenFit</a> last November, they became my irreplaceable companion for a dozen running races and hundreds of casual runs and walks. I've tried other fitness earbuds both professionally and casually; none of them match my OpenFits for casual, forget-they're-there comfort. And thanks to this going-going-gone Cyber Monday sale, they're <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/SHOKZ-OpenFit-Headphones-Microphone-Compatible/dp/B0BYSQDWRT"><strong>31% off ($124) for Cyber Monday</strong>.</a></p><p>Shokz specializes in bone conduction headphones like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/shokz-openrun-pro-review">OpenRun Pro</a>. Even though they leave your ear canals fully unobstructed, the through-bone sound has always been an adjustment for me, which is why the OpenFit's dolphin shape directing traditional speaker sound into your canals without blocking them was such a revelation for me! They'll <em>never</em> fall off, and they keep you aware of your surroundings during races or on busy trails with zooming cyclists.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="4e6c1774-accb-4615-898f-b24c67ed4d2a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="The Shokz OpenFit offer 7-hour battery life with a 28-hour case and a 1-hour charge to 100%. They have IP54 water resistance, good enough to withstand a year of my sweat and rainy days. Although the touch controls are somewhat finicky and you can't isolate your surroundings like with traditional earbuds, I still prefer their unique design to little pods that constantly fall from your ears during runs." data-dimension48="The Shokz OpenFit offer 7-hour battery life with a 28-hour case and a 1-hour charge to 100%. They have IP54 water resistance, good enough to withstand a year of my sweat and rainy days. Although the touch controls are somewhat finicky and you can't isolate your surroundings like with traditional earbuds, I still prefer their unique design to little pods that constantly fall from your ears during runs." data-dimension25="$124.95" href="https://www.amazon.com/SHOKZ-OpenFit-Headphones-Microphone-Compatible/dp/B0BYSQDWRT" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2034px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="tLRq9WH8Y8rtr9uYZkfbrW" name="Shokz-OpenFit-black-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tLRq9WH8Y8rtr9uYZkfbrW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2034" height="2034" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>The Shokz OpenFit offer 7-hour battery life with a 28-hour case and a 1-hour charge to 100%. They have IP54 water resistance, good enough to withstand a year of my sweat and rainy days. Although the touch controls are somewhat finicky and you can't isolate your surroundings like with traditional earbuds, I still prefer their unique design to little pods that constantly fall from your ears during runs.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/SHOKZ-OpenFit-Headphones-Microphone-Compatible/dp/B0BYSQDWRT" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="4e6c1774-accb-4615-898f-b24c67ed4d2a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="The Shokz OpenFit offer 7-hour battery life with a 28-hour case and a 1-hour charge to 100%. They have IP54 water resistance, good enough to withstand a year of my sweat and rainy days. Although the touch controls are somewhat finicky and you can't isolate your surroundings like with traditional earbuds, I still prefer their unique design to little pods that constantly fall from your ears during runs." data-dimension48="The Shokz OpenFit offer 7-hour battery life with a 28-hour case and a 1-hour charge to 100%. They have IP54 water resistance, good enough to withstand a year of my sweat and rainy days. Although the touch controls are somewhat finicky and you can't isolate your surroundings like with traditional earbuds, I still prefer their unique design to little pods that constantly fall from your ears during runs." data-dimension25="$124.95">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>If that cost is a little too high for you, its newer, cheaper sibling is also on sale: the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/shokz-openswim-pro-and-openfit-air-review">Shokz OpenFit Air</a>, which has a rebalanced design that's supposed to feel slightly more comfortable and a new sound balance that's especially good at mids and highs. As a downside, it has shorter battery life and less pronounced bass. At <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/SHOKZ-OpenFit-Air-Headphones-Resistant/dp/B0CRTMHVTJ"><strong>$99 (17% off), the OpenFit Airs</strong></a> are a solid compromise.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="8cb824ed-063f-4a78-a126-90b1d17d10cc" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="The OpenFit Air earbuds are normally $60 cheaper but are now only $25 cheaper thanks to Cyber Monday. These airy earbuds are technically heavier than the OpenFits but have a different balance that puts a bit less pressure on your ears. Our reviewer was impressed by their sound quality." data-dimension48="The OpenFit Air earbuds are normally $60 cheaper but are now only $25 cheaper thanks to Cyber Monday. These airy earbuds are technically heavier than the OpenFits but have a different balance that puts a bit less pressure on your ears. Our reviewer was impressed by their sound quality." data-dimension25="$99.95" href="https://www.amazon.com/SHOKZ-OpenFit-Air-Headphones-Resistant/dp/B0CRTMHVTJ" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="LS2ojsVxwqJLY8i7wB7PbZ" name="shokz-openfit-air-square.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LS2ojsVxwqJLY8i7wB7PbZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1080" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>The OpenFit Air earbuds are normally $60 cheaper but are now only $25 cheaper thanks to Cyber Monday. These airy earbuds are technically heavier than the OpenFits but have a different balance that puts a bit less pressure on your ears. Our reviewer was impressed by their sound quality. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/SHOKZ-OpenFit-Air-Headphones-Resistant/dp/B0CRTMHVTJ" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="8cb824ed-063f-4a78-a126-90b1d17d10cc" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="The OpenFit Air earbuds are normally $60 cheaper but are now only $25 cheaper thanks to Cyber Monday. These airy earbuds are technically heavier than the OpenFits but have a different balance that puts a bit less pressure on your ears. Our reviewer was impressed by their sound quality." data-dimension48="The OpenFit Air earbuds are normally $60 cheaper but are now only $25 cheaper thanks to Cyber Monday. These airy earbuds are technically heavier than the OpenFits but have a different balance that puts a bit less pressure on your ears. Our reviewer was impressed by their sound quality." data-dimension25="$99.95">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">More deals</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Cyber Monday Google Pixel deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Cyber Monday Motorola deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024-early-deals-and-how-to-prepare-for-the-big-sales">Cyber Monday Samsung deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Cyber Monday OnePlus deals</a></p></div></div>
<p>True audiophiles would probably scoff at the OpenFits sound quality compared to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones-working-out">best workout headphones</a> from brands like Jabra and Jaybird — many of which are on sale for Cyber Monday, too. But that's not my priority: With traditional earbuds, I always have to worry about them falling out of my ears unless I find the perfect cups, and all it takes is one fall to mess up an earbud's sound for good.</p><p>With the Shokz OpenFits, not only will they stay hooked no matter how hard your feet pound the pavement, but you'll eventually forget they're even there! Once I'm in the zone, I just <em>experience</em> the sound of my playlist while my ear canals relax and feel the wind passing me by.</p><p>While the sound isn't as loud as traditional earbuds, they're more than loud enough to hear everything clearly at the middle volume. And these OpenFits easily lasted for my <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/what-i-learned-running-20-mile-race-wearing-four-watches">20-miler race</a> with battery to spare, and after you get used to their presence, you'll forget that the OpenFits are even there as you settle into the zone.</p><p>That's why I'd recommend at least trying the OpenFits if you're a runner. If you're like me, you'll have trouble going back to regular earbuds after that!</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/headphones/the-only-workout-earbuds-ill-ever-wear-are-31-percent-off-for-cyber-monday-for-now</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ If you're an athlete who needs situational awareness but can't stand bone conduction, this is the best (only) solution I recommend, and it has a major discount. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">tTsUHdieFzQJpbvh26qtdR</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kZMhyt5BQKzinaVZchV3zi.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 05:03:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Headphones]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kZMhyt5BQKzinaVZchV3zi.jpeg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Shokz OpenFit]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Shokz OpenFit]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Tick-tock: The mouse ran up the Lenovo clock to save 50% on this Cyber Monday Chromebook deal before the clock struck 12 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Last-minute Cyber Monday Deals</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Cyber Monday Google Pixel deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Cyber Monday</a><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more"> Motorola deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Cyber Monday</a><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/samsung-black-friday-2024-deals"> Samsung deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Cyber Monday</a><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals"> OnePlus deals</a></p></div></div>
<p>Maybe you haven't had time to check out all of the different Black Friday and Cyber Monday deals, but I've got one more for you. This deal is absolutely crazy, and I don't know how it managed to fly under the radar, but Lenovo is on a different level with its last-minute "Doorbuster" deals.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.lenovo.com/us/en/p/laptops/ideapad/ideapad-300/ideapad-slim-3i-chromebook-gen-8-(14-inch-intel)/83bn001aus"><strong>IdeaPad Slim 3i Chromebook Plus is $300 off</strong></a>, with FREE shipping. It normally retails for $550, meaning that this sweet, sweet Chromebook can be yours for just $250.</p><p>No, there's nothing super-fancy about the Slim 3i Chromebook Plus, and it's not even the latest Chromebook to be released by Lenovo. So by that logic, you might be wondering why I'm even talking about it. It's simply because you're getting an excellent Chromebook Plus model, from Lenovo, for just $250.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="33d57dd2-bec5-4b7d-a0bc-346fe6bbba06" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="If you're even remotely interested in picking up a Chromebook, the IdeaPad Slim 3i Chromebook Plus should be at the top of your list. Especially considering that it's $300 off, and the Cyber Monday deal bonanza is just about to come to an end. The only thing I regret is not finding this deal sooner." data-dimension48="If you're even remotely interested in picking up a Chromebook, the IdeaPad Slim 3i Chromebook Plus should be at the top of your list. Especially considering that it's $300 off, and the Cyber Monday deal bonanza is just about to come to an end. The only thing I regret is not finding this deal sooner." data-dimension25="$249.99" href="https://www.lenovo.com/us/en/p/laptops/ideapad/ideapad-300/ideapad-slim-3i-chromebook-gen-8-(14-inch-intel)/83bn001aus" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="wtQi7tBSdQhsivpY4PiJgG" name="lenovo-ideapad-slim-3i-chromebook-square-render" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wtQi7tBSdQhsivpY4PiJgG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="500" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>If you're even remotely interested in picking up a Chromebook, the IdeaPad Slim 3i Chromebook Plus should be at the top of your list. Especially considering that it's $300 off, and the Cyber Monday deal bonanza is just about to come to an end. The only thing I regret is not finding this deal sooner. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.lenovo.com/us/en/p/laptops/ideapad/ideapad-300/ideapad-slim-3i-chromebook-gen-8-(14-inch-intel)/83bn001aus" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="33d57dd2-bec5-4b7d-a0bc-346fe6bbba06" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="If you're even remotely interested in picking up a Chromebook, the IdeaPad Slim 3i Chromebook Plus should be at the top of your list. Especially considering that it's $300 off, and the Cyber Monday deal bonanza is just about to come to an end. The only thing I regret is not finding this deal sooner." data-dimension48="If you're even remotely interested in picking up a Chromebook, the IdeaPad Slim 3i Chromebook Plus should be at the top of your list. Especially considering that it's $300 off, and the Cyber Monday deal bonanza is just about to come to an end. The only thing I regret is not finding this deal sooner." data-dimension25="$249.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>What makes the Chromebook Plus branding so great is that it helps weed out the potentially frustrating Chromebooks from the good ones. Google has a set of requirements that a Chromebook needs to meet in order to qualify for that branding, and the Slim 3i Chromebook Plus does just that.</p><p>It sports a 14-inch FHD touchscreen display, that even has an anti-glare coating which is great for those that need to work on the go. It's also powered by the Intel Core i3-N305, paired with 8GB of RAM and 128GB of storage, and even has a backlit keyboard.</p><p>But wait! There's more!</p><p>Battery life is rated to last for up to 11 hours, but we'd venture to guess you can squeeze even more out of it. And if not, fear not, thanks to the 65W charger that takes you from 0-80% in just one hour. Knowing how good <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-chromebook">Lenovo Chromebooks</a> are with battery life, I have a feeling you might only end up charging this once every three to four days, if not longer.</p><p>Oh, and I didn't even mention that the Slim 3i Chromebook Plus has a bunch of ports! There's a USB-C 3.2 Gen 2 port, two USB-A 3.2 Gen 1 ports, an HDMI 1.4 port, a 3.5mm audio combo jack, AND a Kensington lock slot.</p><p>Again, all of this for just $250. I mean, what more could you really ask for?</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/tick-tock-the-mouse-ran-up-the-lenovo-clock-to-save-50-percent-on-this-cyber-monday-chromebook-deal-before-the-clock-struck-12</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Stop what you're doing and go grab the Lenovo Slim 3i Chromebook Plus for $300 while you still can. Time's running out on Cyber Monday and you don't want to miss out on this one.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">qAHvyXphciUYJauz9tW3qH</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HujjkekXgkh2LoCRUtLMgG.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 04:09:47 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Chromebooks &amp; Laptops]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ andrew.myrick@futurenet.com (Andrew Myrick) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HujjkekXgkh2LoCRUtLMgG.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Lenovo]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Lenovo IdeaPad Slim 3i Chromebook Plus lifestyle render]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Lenovo IdeaPad Slim 3i Chromebook Plus lifestyle render]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>