<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 21:54:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ A 'Year in Search' highlights Google's top trends across AI and shows in 2024 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google highlighted its "Year in 2024" data for what users searched for the most in Search and AI.</li><li>Circle to Search and Lens were used to "identify items," shop, and translate items and users were the most curious about Benson Boone's song "Beautiful Things."</li><li>The top trending search in 2024 was Copa America while the most searched for movie was Disney's Inside Out 2.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>As the year winds down, Google is taking a look back at what users searched for the most across multiple categories.</p><p>In a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.google/products/search/google-year-in-search-2024/">Keyword post</a>, the company highlighted various top trending searches for various user interests, like AI. Google highlighted what users searched for the most in since the arrival of Circle to Search, as well as Google Lens. The post states users used both tools to translate, shop, and "identify items" in 2024.</p><p>Moreover, the company adds that users usually combined a search with "how to use" when searching for an item visually.</p><p>Google Maps was tossed in, as the post states users looked up information about the Las Vegas Sphere and Italy’s Arena di Verona this year.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-circle-to-search-ai-powered-multisearch-rollout">Circle to Search</a> launched earlier this year alongside the Galaxy S24 series and the Pixel 8 before hitting other phones. Additionally, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-lens-search-ads-video-function-update">Google Lens</a> grabbed some nifty upgrades like the ability for users to record videos.</p><p>Speaking of AI and Search, in Google's main "Year in Search" overview, the company highlighted what songs users hummed to its engine the most.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1066px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.29%;"><img id="TfFvviGDoa6xV5HMhYMpq5" name="google-search-year-in-review-2024-hum-to-search" alt="Google's top search results for users who utilized "Hum to Search" in 2024." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TfFvviGDoa6xV5HMhYMpq5.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1066" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<h2 id="top-trending-search-in-2024-2">Top Trending Search in 2024</h2>
<ol start="1"><li>Copa America</li><li>UEFA European Championship</li><li>ICC Men's T20 World Cup</li><li>India vs England</li><li>Liam Payne</li></ol>
<h2 id="top-trending-movies-in-search-2">Top Trending Movies in Search</h2>
<ol start="1"><li>Inside Out 2</li><li>Deadpool & Wolverine</li><li>Saltburn</li><li>Beetlejuice Beetlejuice</li><li>Dune: Part Two</li></ol>
<h2 id="top-trending-tv-shows-2">Top Trending TV Shows</h2>
<ol start="1"><li>Baby Reindeer</li><li>Fallout</li><li>House of the Dragon</li><li>Heeramandi</li><li>Shōgun</li></ol>
<p>Google's main "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://trends.withgoogle.com/year-in-search/2024/">Year in Search</a>" overview for 2024 continues with the top pieces of news for 2024. According to Google, its data shows that people searched for (in order) the U.S. Election, Excessive Heat, Olympics, Hurricane Milton, and 台風 気象 情報 台風 第 10 号 (Typhoon No. 10 around Japan) the most this year.</p><p>When it came to "People," Google states the top trending searches were Donald Trump, Catherine the Princess of Wales, Kamala Harris, Imane Khelif, and Joe Biden.</p><p>In "Sports," the New York Yankees took the top spot, followed by the Los Angeles Dodgers, Inter Miami CF, Bayer 04 Leverkusen, and the Boston Celtics. And, lastly, in "Gaming," the top trending searches were for Connections, Palworld, Infinite Craft, Sprunki, and Helldivers 2.</p><p>In November, Google detailed its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-play-unveils-its-top-apps-and-games-of-2024">top apps and games</a> via the Play Store for 2024. Partiful took the award for the "Best App of 2024" due to its reinvention of event planning. For mobile gaming, AFK Journey won "Best Game" while Max took the cake for "Best Multi-device App."</p><p>Other worthy mentions include Hoyoverse's Honkai: Star Rail for "Best Ongoing Game," PBS Kids Video for "Best for Cars," and Dragon Rider by Taran Matharu for "Favorite Fantasy" book in 2024.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-a-year-in-search-2024-highlights</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google takes users on a trip through 2024 and its top trending searches. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">FKNdnTnD55xgS68vQZjFb8</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sTgwYjKwGJHWQmc5VLM4G5.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 20:21:20 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sTgwYjKwGJHWQmc5VLM4G5.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google&#039;s &quot;Year in Search 2024.&quot;]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google&#039;s &quot;Year in Search 2024.&quot;]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Galaxy S25 rumored to fix what the S24 lacked: Qi2 charging support ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A rumor on Weibo claims the Galaxy S25 series could support the new Qi2 wireless charging standard, launched in 2023.</li><li>It was stated that the method would only a charging strength of 15W on the S25 series, which is what Qi Power stated during its launch.</li><li>Qi2 support was originally expected for the Galaxy S24 series; however, the only phone (and first) to adopt it is the HMD Skyline.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>A recent Galaxy S25 post spreads rumors about its potential (exciting) upgrade to its charging capabilities.</p><p>The rumors were reportedly started by Ice Universe on Weibo and highlighted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/Jukanlosreve/status/1866139989215760439">Jukanlosreve</a> on X (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.sammobile.com/news/galaxy-s25-qi2-magsafe-charging-accessories-rumor/">SamMobile</a>). Per the tipster, the Galaxy S25 series will supposedly utilize the new wireless charging standard, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qi-v2-wireless-certification-process-begins">Qi2</a>. Ice Universe supposedly discussed these details over private messages on Weibo.</p><p>The tipster added that the S25 series will support this method; however, devices charging wirelessly may only see 15W capabilities.</p><p>The stated charging strength isn't surprising as Qi Power announced as much when the Qi2 standard was launched late in November 2023.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Ice Universe: The S25 series will feature Qi2.<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1866139989215760439">December 9, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>Qi2 met a late 2023 holiday season launch and the Wireless Power Consortium highlighted its roots in Apple's MagSafe technology. It's worth mentioning that the tech hit the iPhone 15 series <em>before </em>Qi2 got around to Android devices. Qi Power "promised" that its new standard <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qi-v2-wireless-certification-process-begins">could provide</a> "greater energy efficiency, faster charging, and enhanced convenience" for Android.</p><p>Accessory manufacturers like Belkin, Mophie, Anker, and Aircharge entered certification to prepare for a market launch shortly after Qi2 was launched. We were excited, considering this meant Android phones could finally adopt its wireless charging method.</p><p>However, that has yet to happen — at least, in a widespread fashion. The first (and only) Android to support Qi2 wireless charging is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/hmd-skyline-qi2-launch">the HMD Skyline</a>.</p><p>It was also expected that Samsung would jump on this new wireless charging trend, but it <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/samsung-dropped-the-ball-qi2-galaxy-s24">dropped the ball with the Galaxy S24</a>. Instead, what we received was <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-s24-ultra-s-pen-magsafe-qi2-malfunction">S Pen malfunctions</a> with Qi2 magnet accessories, as noted by manufacturers trying to craft their latest products.</p><p>Qi2 is still a viable option for Samsung to deploy on its upcoming Galaxy S25 series. Though Android Central's Namerah Saud Fatmi <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/qi2-samsung-galaxy-s24-series">said the method</a> would keep the S24 series "exciting and alive," the same can probably be shifted over to the S25 flagship trio.</p><p>As always, we'll have to wait and see. The Galaxy S25 series is expected to launch during Galaxy Unpacked in January 2025.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-s25-qi2-wireless-charging-support-rumors</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Rumors claim Samsung could grant the S25 series Qi2 charging support. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">U5KLdqECCw4FbLSRBuJVfR</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BHXn8M9XogEBEEjMPs4BJG.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 19:29:07 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BHXn8M9XogEBEEjMPs4BJG.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nick Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Galaxy S24 Ultra with a case and MagSafe ring]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Galaxy S24 Ultra with a case and MagSafe ring]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ How I made my chicken coop smarter than my chickens ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Android Central Labs</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="7WCXSEZSk3FX9EmxxzaGE9" name="android-central-labs-lloyd-logo.jpg" caption="" alt="Android Central's Lloyd mascot wearing a lab coat for the Android Central Labs column" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7WCXSEZSk3FX9EmxxzaGE9.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text"><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/android-central-labs">Android Central Labs</a> is a weekly column devoted to deep dives, experiments, and a focused look into the tech you use. It covers phones, tablets, and everything in between.</p></div></div>
<p>Chickens are wonderful, lovable pets. I heartily recommend them to anyone who has space and is allowed to keep them, but they do require a fair bit of work. While they're certainly capable of taking care of themselves throughout the day — heck, they actually put themselves to bed at sundown — ensuring something doesn't eat them is practically a full-time job.</p><p>In the nearly six years since I've started keeping chickens, my flock has grown substantially. What started as three hens turned into 11, and while I've lost a few over the years to disease, it's nearly impossible to resist the urge to get new chicks every spring.</p><p>During that time, I've discovered many ways to keep my chickens safe and my caretaking job easier, most of which involve smart home devices I've either cobbled together or found along the way. Even if you don't have chickens, some of these ideas might be helpful for your other pets, especially if you'll be away from home on vacation during the holidays.</p>

<h2 id="starting-the-day-the-automated-way-2">Starting the day the automated way</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="mGpLEivWQeaxxyxY4x3PJi" name="Omlet-automatic-chicken-coop-door" alt="An Omlet Automatic Chicken Coop Door in the open position" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mGpLEivWQeaxxyxY4x3PJi.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>To prevent a predator-caused disaster, chickens have to be locked up at night. When we got our first three hens back in 2019, we kept them in an enclosed run at all times, so keeping the door closed at night wasn't important unless it was freezing outside.</p><p>But as our flock, coop, and run size grew, it made more sense to let them free range during the day. Of course, this introduces a number of potential issues, including waking up at the crack of dawn.</p><p>As the sun rises in the morning, my Omlet Automatic Chicken Coop Door opens by itself once the right amount of light hits its sensor. The latest version of the door connects to Wi-Fi and has an app that allows me to see if it's open or closed, plus remotely open and close it manually if I need to.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:60.30%;"><img id="vVQhbW7CK8YSaaqMeiGhfn" name="smart-home-chicken-coop-screenshots" alt="Screenshots of smart chicken coop apps including Omlet automatic door, Blink camera with temperature sensor, and Google Home with a Kasa Matter smart plug" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vVQhbW7CK8YSaaqMeiGhfn.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1235" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I specifically chose the Omlet brand because it not only has a great reputation for build quality and reliability, but I also preferred the design and safety measures built into the product.</p><p>Lots of automated chicken coop doors use what I call a guillotine-style store; they open and close vertically, and I can pretty easily imagine one of my hens sticking her head in it at just the wrong moment. Omlet's door slides side-to-side like a sliding glass door and features pressure-sensitive sensors that ensure errant hens sitting in the doorway don't get crushed.</p><p>The model I have has the option to use batteries or plug into an outlet, but the downside is that you have to choose one <em>or</em> the other. If you plug a plug into it, it bypasses battery power. I wish they would update it with the ability to plug it in and keep batteries as a backup for when power goes out.</p>
<p>You may not have chickens, but it's likely you might have another pet that needs to go outside from time to time. Whether it's a cat, dog, bunny, or something else entirely, an automated door like this could be a great solution for when you're away.</p><p>I've also got several cameras posted around the backyard, including in the coop and chicken run. This lets me check up on them throughout the day, make <em>sure</em> the door is opened or closed, and keep an eye on their food and water situation.</p>
<h2 id="smart-around-the-year-2">Smart around the year</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="mcmZ4fm9WY3fqfMFzwYrFi" name="Kasa-smart-plug-with-heater-plugged-into-it" alt="A ceramic heater attached to a Kasa Matter Smart Plug" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mcmZ4fm9WY3fqfMFzwYrFi.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>One of my all-time favorite smart gadgets for my chicken coop is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Blink-Outdoor-4th-Gen-1-Camera/dp/B0B1N5HW22/">Blink Outdoor cameras</a>. Blink is notable for its cost and long battery life (up to 2 years on a pair of AA batteries), but I love it specifically for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.blinkforhome.com/en_US/camera-settings/how-to-enable-temperature-alerts">temperature sensor inside</a>.</p><p>Each battery-powered Blink camera has a temperature sensor that you can monitor from the Blink app. Since my chicken coop is, well, outside, it's important for me to be able to monitor the temperature throughout the year. If it's getting too hot, I swap out the solid wood coop door for a more ventilated one to allow for additional breeze in the summer.</p><p>In the winter, the camera helps me keep track of how cold it is in the coop so I can turn on the heater as needed. I've got a ceramic heater designed for chicken coops (it mounts on the wall inside) plugged into a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Kasa-Smart-Monitoring-Compact-Certified/dp/B0BYGMR4DX/">Kasa Matter Smart Plug</a>, so I can turn it on and off remotely via the Google Home app or through voice commands.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="UffTNenpKq38xprokjQwEi" name="Blink-Outdoor-Camera-mounted" alt="A Blink Outdoor Camera mounted on the underside of a chicken run roof" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/UffTNenpKq38xprokjQwEi.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It looks like Amazon sells smart heaters <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/petnf-Chicken-Efficient-UL-Compliant-11-81x15-74/dp/B0D8QBKMWK/" target="_blank">that directly connect to Wi-Fi</a> these days, but my solution is quite ideal if you've already got the heater and just need a way to remotely control it.</p><p>We've also got heaters for our waterers hooked up to separate smart plugs since those waterers are in the run, not in the coop. I've got another Blink camera mounted in the chicken run that monitors the outdoor temperature and can send me alerts for when it drops below freezing, triggering the chicken waterer heater to turn on.</p><p>While I've reduced the number of smart light bulbs throughout my home because most of them use <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-is-pwm-display-flicker-tips-and-tricks">PWM dimming</a>, I've increased the number of smart appliances and plugs so I can automate and remotely control things to give me and my animals the best life possible.</p><p>One of these days, I'll get the Homey set up and further automate things but, for now, it's amazing to be able to remotely monitor and manage the coop when I'm out of town for the holidays or on one of the many business trips I take throughout the year.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="9a255056-6d7b-481d-8d27-f8b4719aff11" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="TP-Link Kasa KP125M smart plug 4-pack: $69.99" data-dimension48="TP-Link Kasa KP125M smart plug 4-pack: $69.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/Kasa-Smart-Monitoring-Compact-Certified/dp/B0BYGMR4DX/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1413px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:72.89%;"><img id="HbYXtDUpwVKgLvF6FLMRTd" name="kasa-smart-plug-4-pack-render" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HbYXtDUpwVKgLvF6FLMRTd.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1413" height="1030" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>TP-Link Kasa KP125M smart plug 4-pack: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Kasa-Smart-Monitoring-Compact-Certified/dp/B0BYGMR4DX/" data-dimension112="9a255056-6d7b-481d-8d27-f8b4719aff11" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="TP-Link Kasa KP125M smart plug 4-pack: $69.99" data-dimension48="TP-Link Kasa KP125M smart plug 4-pack: $69.99" data-dimension25=""><del>$69.99</del><strong> $36.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p><p>Feel smarter knowing you've eliminated those energy hogs around your home thanks to Kasa Smart plugs, now on sale for <strong>47% off </strong>even after Cyber Monday.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/Kasa-Smart-Monitoring-Compact-Certified/dp/B0BYGMR4DX/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="9a255056-6d7b-481d-8d27-f8b4719aff11" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="TP-Link Kasa KP125M smart plug 4-pack: $69.99" data-dimension48="TP-Link Kasa KP125M smart plug 4-pack: $69.99" data-dimension25="">View Deal</a></p></div>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/how-i-made-my-chicken-coop-smarter-than-my-chickens</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Smart home gadgets can do more than you think, and my chicken coop is proof. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">hmnV4QnB8F9eRYpzxnEwA6</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/EzXWD28JGupReUXdF6UALi.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 19:21:30 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Smart Home]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/EzXWD28JGupReUXdF6UALi.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A photo of chickens taken by a Nuu B30 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A photo of chickens taken by a Nuu B30 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google is suing to block CFPB oversight over Google Pay, calling it 'government overreach' ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The US Consumer Financial Protection Bureau recently finalized a rule that would place Google's payment services under federal supervision.</li><li>While supervision doesn't mean a particular company has engaged in wrongdoing, it does identify that it poses "risks to consumers."</li><li>Google is claiming that the basis for supervision, complaints regarding Google Pay, shouldn't stand since the service was shuttered in the US, and is no longer available.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>The US Consumer Financial Protection Bureau aims to supervise non-bank payment apps, mostly hosted by big tech companies, with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/consumer-financial-protection-bureau-finalizes-rule-to-supervise-apps-like-google-wallet">a finalized rule set to take effect next month</a>. Corporations that handle more than 50 million transactions per year will be subject to supervision, including the likes of Apple, Google, and Amazon. But one company, Google, is trying to block the move with a lawsuit filed last week, according to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/07/google-pushes-back-against-federal-supervision-of-its-payment-arm/" target="_blank">TechCrunch</a>.</p><p>The CFPB is targeting non-bank companies that host wallet apps and digital payment services because the body wants these corporations to follow the same rules, and supervisory examinations, as banks and credit unions. The Bureau claims it "always had enforcement authority over these companies." Now, the official rule gives it the explicit authority to conduct proactive examinations of these non-bank companies hosting such services.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/us-regulator-places-google-payment-corp-under-supervision-2024-12-06/" target="_blank">Reuters</a> reports that the CFPB took nearly 300 customer complaints into consideration when it determined Google's payment services posed "risks to consumers." It's important to note, however, that this does not mean the company has engaged in wrongdoing. Google Payment Corp., a subsidiary, failed to investigate customer complaints regarding errors and other violations, according to the CFPB.</p><p>Google Payment Corp., meanwhile, is suing on the basis that the CFPB's designation relied on "a small number of unsubstantiated complaints" about Google Pay, which is no longer offered in the US, per Reuters. "As a matter of common sense, a product that no longer exists is incapable of posing such risk," the company wrote in the filing.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-pay-changes-june-shutdown-announced">Google Pay was discontinued in the US in June</a>, and Google no longer offers peer-to-peer payment services in the country. However, some Google Pay offerings — such as contactless digital payments at retailers — are now available as part of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet">Google Wallet app</a>. Even though Google Pay is discontinued, the CFPB's rule says it requires oversight.</p><p>"Even when firms choose to discontinue offering payments to other consumers, or have not yet enabled that capability in the United States," the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2024/12/10/2024-27836/defining-larger-participants-of-a-market-for-general-use-digital-consumer-payment-applications" target="_blank">rule</a> explains, "their general-use digital payment applications still comprise part of the overall market described in the Final Rule, which includes but is not limited to digitally facilitating consumer payment transactions for purchases."</p><p>The rule was published in the Federal Register today, and will take effect on Jan. 9, 2025.</p><p>"This is a clear case of government overreach involving Google Pay peer-to-peer payments, which never raised risks and is no longer provided in the U.S., and we are challenging it in court," a Google spokesperson told TechCrunch.</p><p>As Google's lawsuit begins, there are a number of questions whether the CFPB's plan to supervise non-bank digital payment services will continue when President-elect Donald Trump's administration takes over next year. Under President Biden, the CFPB aggressively sought to make new rules, and this effort has reportedly continued even after Trump's election victory in November.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google/google-is-suing-to-block-cfpb-oversight-over-google-pay-calling-it-government-overreach</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Since Google Pay is no longer available in the US, Google doesn't think it deserves to be supervised. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">ABoAnDKodV6CJRHsJYuejP</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pWThapBgXmQHVgMJ7HiwjS.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 18:43:27 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pWThapBgXmQHVgMJ7HiwjS.jpeg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Pay app]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Pay app]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung's next rugged XCover sees jump in power capacity, per listing ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung's assumed XCover 8 Pro has appeared in the SafetyKorea database for battery certification.</li><li>The phone is listed with a 4,350mAh battery, which is a 300mAh upgrade over the previous two generations of rugged phones.</li><li>Samsung was reportedly developing two new Pro-level rugged devices, a phone and a tablet, in October, and rumors state both could debut in mid-2025.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>It seems that Samsung has another rugged phone in the works, but this one could improve one key element.</p><p>A Samsung device was spotted in the SafetyKorea certification database by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.galaxyclub.nl/samsung/galaxy-xcover-8-pro/">GalaxyClub</a> (Dutch), which is assumed to be a new rugged smartphone (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.gsmarena.com/samsung_galaxy_xcover8_pro_battery_certified_with_higher_capacity-news-65681.php">GSMArena</a>). According to the listing, it appears that the next device is the XCover  8 Pro. The publication spotted an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.safetykorea.kr/release/certDetail?certNum=XU102099-24104&certUid=5902500">uploaded photo</a> detailing the device's battery information.</p><p>Per the listing, it seems the XCover 8 Pro will debut with a lithium-ion battery capacity of 4,350mAh.</p><p>The listing also states that this battery will not be built into the phone when it launches. It seems consumers might expect a removable battery once again in the XCover 8 Pro, much like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-xcover-6-pro-announcement">XCover 6 Pro</a> and 7.</p><p>The publication reiterated the rumored existence of another rugged tablet from Samsung. The listing lacks any further information concerning a launch; however, the post speculates the OEM could launch the XCover 8 Pro (and potentially the tablet) in mid-2025.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:424px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:141.51%;"><img id="PK3VKwgt9asr6YUdJSjRHc" name="samsung-galaxy-xcover-7-scanning" alt="The Samsung XCover 7 scanning a box." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PK3VKwgt9asr6YUdJSjRHc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="424" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Samsung)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Samsung <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://news.samsung.com/in/samsung-launches-galaxy-xcover7-its-first-ever-enterprise-exclusive-smartphone-the-perfect-blend-of-military-grade-durability-work-continuity-and-productivity">launched</a> the XCover 7 earlier this year with a 6.6-inch FHD Plus display with one 50MP primary lens and a 5MP selfie camera. Internally, the company provided it with 6GM of RAM and 128GB of storage with the ability to jump to 1TB via a microSD. More importantly, the rugged phone only offered a 4,050mAh battery.</p><p>This was the same battery Samsung delivered in the XCover 6 Pro, but rumors today suggest a potential upgrade is in the cards for this area. If true, then we're looking at a (roughly) 300mAh jump, which should aid in the phone's overall battery life.</p><p>With the latest listing in our hands, we can return to a previous leak that claims Samsung is working on <em>two </em><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-next-gen-pro-rugged-devices-early-leak">Pro-level rugged devices</a>. The first is the supposed XCover 8 Pro as it was spotted with model number SM-G766B in October. The device was similar in internal name with the XCover 7, furthering suspicions about it being a successor.</p><p>Moreover, that leak also mentioned a Tab Active 5 Pro or "Tab Active 6 Pro." It was highlighted that Samsung rarely offers a "Pro" for the same generation, which is why some believe is could jump to "6 Pro." Little is known specification-wise about either of these devices (aside from the newfound battery specs).</p><p>Like the current rumors, the discovery from two months ago claims Samsung could launch the next-gen rugged devices in mid-2025.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-next-pro-rugged-phone-battery-certification</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung was spotted moving its next rugged smartphone through certification in South Korea. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">9o749qnUdiYADG3Zt4CoMf</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ENv2Dr52GmMNHt44AtFDLX.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 18:36:48 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ENv2Dr52GmMNHt44AtFDLX.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Samsung]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Samsung Galaxy XCover 7.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Samsung Galaxy XCover 7.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Pixel 9 Pro lands a sudden 40% discount during Mint Mobile's holiday sale — apparently 50% off wireless wasn't enough?  ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>I have seen a lot of amazing Google Pixel 9 deals over the past few months, but this holiday offer from Mint easily ranks as one of the best (and yes, I&apos;m including Black Friday in that list). <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9-pro/6810410/"><strong>Pick up the Pixel 9 Pro from Mint Mobile and you&apos;ll score a ridiculous $400 discount</strong></a>, knocking the price of the phone down to $599. You&apos;ll have to buy a year of Mint&apos;s unlimited tier to receive the savings, but the carrier is sweetening the deal by carving 50% off that plan, as well.</p><p>In other words, not only are you getting a record-smashing discount on one of the year&apos;s best phones, but you&apos;ll be getting one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/carriers/best-unlimited-data-plans">best unlimited plans</a> we&apos;ve ever used for only $15 per month ($180 upfront). Even Black Friday couldn&apos;t touch those savings. </p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="40c4ebdc-ec19-4147-b3db-938bee54a5d1" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 Pro 128GB: $999" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 Pro 128GB: $999" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9-pro/6810410/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="UD8dzz6ZtqsbyAGYpz4DtN" name="google-pixel-9-pro-official-render-obsidian-front-back.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/UD8dzz6ZtqsbyAGYpz4DtN.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="500" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Google Pixel 9 Pro 128GB: </strong><a href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9-pro/6810410/" data-dimension112="40c4ebdc-ec19-4147-b3db-938bee54a5d1" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 Pro 128GB: $999" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 Pro 128GB: $999"><del>$999</del><strong> $599, plus 50% off a year of Unlimited at Mint Mobile</strong></a></p>
<p>Order the Google Pixel 9 Pro during Mint Mobile's holiday sale and you'll score an incredible 40% off the device when you pair your purchase with one year of any data plan. As if that wasn't enough, Mint is also dropping 50% off the Unlimited plan, which means you could be getting one of 2024's <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a> AND a full 12 months of T-Mobile-powered wireless for as little as $779 (or $33 per month using affirm). That's cheaper than the phone was <em>by itself</em> during Black Friday! </p>
<p>👀<strong>Alternative holiday deal: </strong><a href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9/6810275/"><strong>Get $500 off the Google Pixel 9, plus 50% off a year of Unlimited at Mint</strong></a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9-pro/6810410/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="40c4ebdc-ec19-4147-b3db-938bee54a5d1" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 Pro 128GB: $999" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 Pro 128GB: $999">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>This offer is quite similar to a recent Mint Mobile deal that gives you <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9/6810275/"><strong>$500 off the base model Pixel 9</strong></a> when you buy the phone alongside some wireless, but if you need more power in your devices, this Google Pixel 9 Pro deal is tough to beat. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="V2yzWy8fgvx67dMdwW4Re8" name="google-pixel-9-pro-obsidian-back-02.jpg" alt="Holding an Obsidian Google Pixel 9 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/V2yzWy8fgvx67dMdwW4Re8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>As described in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-review">our 4/5-star review</a>, the Pixel 9 Pro triumphs by packing premium specs and AI-powered technology into a compact, easy-to-hold frame. Both the Pro and its XL big sibling come with seven years of guaranteed OS and security updates, plus you get unrivalled camera tech, the lightning-fast Tensor G4 chipset, and some truly remarkable battery life straight out of the box.</p><p>At full price, the Google Pixel 9 Pro may be a tough sell, but this Mint Mobile is changing everything. Let me put it this way: during Black Friday/Cyber Monday, the price of the unlocked Pixel 9 Pro dropped to $799, which was a record low at the time. By comparison, you can head to Mint Mobile right now and get the phone for a full $20 less, AND your phone bill will be covered for a year by one of the world&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-mvno-carrier">best MVNO carriers</a>. If you&apos;re in the market for a new wireless plan, yeah, it&apos;s that good. </p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-pixel-9-pro-lands-a-sudden-40-percent-discount-during-mint-mobiles-holiday-sale-apparently-50-percent-off-wireless-wasnt-enough</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Bundle the purchase of the Pixel 9 Pro with a year of wireless at Mint Mobile and you'll get 40% off the phone plus 50% off the unlimited plan.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">s2nDKncY63Zi9GmuFcixa7</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5cKPiQgE58zq7oLC5JvyC6.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 17:27:03 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5cKPiQgE58zq7oLC5JvyC6.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Taking a photo with the Google Pixel 9 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Taking a photo with the Google Pixel 9 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ So you bought an e-reader — here's how you can get the most out of it ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Gadget Weekly</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="DZLQ4jKZk9tEF5A3sqU5Jh" name="inspector-lloyd-square.jpg" caption="" alt="Inspector Lloyd" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DZLQ4jKZk9tEF5A3sqU5Jh.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">Join Namerah Saud Fatmi as she explores the cool, quirky, and sometimes downright odd world of smartphone accessories, gadgets, and other nerdy toys <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/gadget-weekly">every week</a>.</p></div></div>
<p>Black Friday and Cyber Monday were exceedingly long this year. In fact, some Cyber Monday deals are <em>still</em> around! If you took advantage of the sales and got yourself an e-reader, that's awesome. You might just kickstart a reading habit right in time for 2025.</p><p>Choosing the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-e-ink-tablet">right e-ink tablet</a> is no easy task. There are so many cool options to pick from, even if they're not as versatile as full-blown Android tablets from the likes of Samsung, Google, and OnePlus. If you just bought an e-reader, here are some tips and tricks to help you get the most out of your new device.</p><p>I've been mad about e-readers and anything E Ink since the days of the Sony Reader, c. 2006. Allow an avid bookwork such as myself to help you get the best possible reading experience from your fancy new reading tab.</p>

<h2 id="adjust-your-settings-2">Adjust your settings</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4096px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="2mBQWAp4hXku3mq32vqFR" name="Onyx Boox Page e-ink tablet and Kindle Oasis e-reader" alt="Onyx Boox Page e-ink tablet and Kindle Oasis e-reader" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2mBQWAp4hXku3mq32vqFR.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4096" height="2304" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nick Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Whether it's an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-amazon-kindle">Amazon Kindle</a> or an Onyx Boox, your new e-reader has various brightness, contrast, and light settings. Modern E Ink tablets all let you adjust the backlight and front light as well. This is the first thing to tweak right after setting up your new e-reader. Find the right balance of brightness and saturation to give you maximum eye comfort while reading.</p><p>I like to turn the brightness and warmth levels down to give my e-reader the most paper-like feel possible. This looks especially nice on color e-readers such as the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/onyx-boox-tab-ultra-c-review">Onyx Boox Tab Ultra C</a> or the Onyx Boox Note Air 4 C. Since these tabs have anti-glare displays, the papery look is absolutely fantastic with dimmer backlighting.</p><p>Of course, this is a subjective setting. My friend and colleague Nick Sutrich, for example, likes his settings to be on the warmer side as it's easier on his eyes.</p><p>After the display satisfies your eyeballs, customize any physical page-turning buttons that your e-reader may or may not have. You can also customize the gestures on your tablet for more efficient readability and usability.</p><p>For example, the latest Onyx Boox tablets have vertical swipe gestures along either side of the screen that can be personalized. I like mine to be set to brightness and volume adjustability. Swiping up along the right corner increases brightness, whereas swiping downwards along the edge of the display decreases it. It's the same thing for the volume settings but on the left side of the display. You get the gist.</p>
<h2 id="try-different-reading-apps-2">Try different reading apps</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4096px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="FGKYDpSBxanfAX97evwdN" name="Onyx Boox Page e-ink tablet and Kindle Oasis e-reader" alt="Onyx Boox Page e-ink tablet and Kindle Oasis e-reader" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FGKYDpSBxanfAX97evwdN.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4096" height="2304" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nick Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>If you're on an Android e-reader like a Boox or a Bigme, you're going to be very happy. One of the biggest reasons why I love Android e-readers like these is because I can download and use any of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-ebook-apps-android">my favorite reading apps</a> or just any of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-apps">best Android apps</a>, period. Amazon limits you from doing so, which I find stifling.</p><p>Open the Google Play Store on your Android E Ink tablet and go crazy kid. From the Kindle store and Manga Plus to Crunchyroll and Wattpad, you can go all out. It's one of the most exciting parts of setting up your new e-reader. Google Play Books is pretty great, too, and if you're in the North American region, you'll find great sales on the platform. You should also get local library apps, such as Libby, so you can borrow e-books from digital libraries in your neighborhood.</p><p>I like to install the Google Drive app as well so I can access my personal library of e-books, which I've been collecting and adding to for a decade now. If you're accessing a local library from your laptop or PC, I highly recommend <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://calibre-ebook.com/">Calibre</a> for computers. Not only does it help you convert e-book formats and add your preferred covers to them, but you can directly connect your e-reader to your computer and sort, arrange, import, export, convert, and edit e-books via Calibre. It's the ultimate e-book management tool, and it's free to use!</p><p>And don't forget to adjust screen settings per app once you're done decking out your e-reader. Some content, such as graphic novels and manga, require different profiles and contrast settings compared to apps like e-book readers or web browsers.</p>
<h2 id="goodreads-is-invaluable-2">Goodreads is invaluable</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4096px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="WLEBSqiWByjtuMYoXoAe4g" name="onyx-boox-note-air-4-c-goodreads-lifestyle" alt="Goodreads app on the Onyx Boox Note Air 4 C tablet" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WLEBSqiWByjtuMYoXoAe4g.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4096" height="2304" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi  / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>After you're all set with the right apps and tools, it's time to start reading! But don't forget, you can track your reading with the fabulous Goodreads app. Disagree with me all you want, but you probably didn't read 300 books in one summer, so I'm vetoing everyone. Goodreads is the perfect platform to track your reading progress, set reading goals, find new reads, and just talk about books in general.</p><p>My e-reader setup is incomplete without Goodreads on it. I don't know how I would keep up with my yearly reading goals without the platform. You can set a yearly reading challenge for yourself, and it is completely customizable. It's highly motivating to see how much you've read at any given point in the year.</p><p>The Goodreads community is warm, welcoming, and extremely passionate. There are community events where users can vote on the best books of the year in each category or create their own lists. You can even become a Goodreads librarian if you want. Be sure to check it out to help you find all the latest and greatest new releases in whatever genre of books you prefer.</p>
<hr>
<p>There's no limit or end to what you can do to make your e-reading experience better. These were my top tips and tricks based on countless e-readers and E Ink tablets that I have used and tested.</p><p>Keep playing around with your new e-reader and have fun with it; that's the most important thing. I hope you enjoy your reading sessions and find the perfect read for any mood. Now curl up in a cozy nook with a warm cuppa coffee, preferably a furry four-legged companion, and a soft blanket. Happy reading!</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="6b963ae3-2f54-475d-8bd6-ee3433fdd052">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Rjy4gBmzC2WS76Vowd2XtJ.jpg' alt="Onyx Boox Note Air 4 C square product render"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Onyx Boox Note Air 4 C</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Android supremacy</strong></em></p><p>Even in the world of e-readers, you get the best reading experience from an Android tablet. I've been testing the newest Onyx Boox Note Air 4 C and it's easily the best E Ink tablet or e-reader for anyone. Forget about a cheap Kindle, this tablet will level up your reading experience like no other without sacrificing your eyesight.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/getting-the-most-out-of-your-new-e-reader</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Just bought a new e-reader? Allow a seasoned reader to help you get the most out of it. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">nCg5mjJ6T2uhaaF9mXpEwj</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5FTaU4Ro7FHDCFDQSn2Hs.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 17:14:58 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5FTaU4Ro7FHDCFDQSn2Hs.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nick Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Onyx Boox Page e-ink tablet and Kindle Oasis e-reader]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Onyx Boox Page e-ink tablet and Kindle Oasis e-reader]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ OPPO Find X8 vs. Samsung Galaxy S24: Stick with the old, or get with the new? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[         <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="f26ec648-1ec9-4439-80cc-2f75ce9458f7">
            <a href="https://wondamobile.com/products/oppo-find-x8-5g-dual-sim?currency=USD&variant=42423311401048" data-model-name="Find X8"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PjSNVSDeJGhrHU2AuHgcfR.jpg' alt="A product render of the Oppo Find X8."></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">OPPO Find X8</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>All about excellent hardware</strong></em></p><p>The OPPO Find X8 brings quality display and camera hardware to a compact flagship form factor. The 6.59-inch screen makes the Find X8 easier to hold, while still being big enough to meet your needs. It's powered by the MediaTek Dimensity 9400 chipset and includes a capable telephoto lens that can shoot at 3x optical zoom. At under $900, it's a compelling alternative to the Samsung Galaxy S24.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Large battery capacity with 80W fast wired charging speeds</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>AMOLED LTPO display the can reach 120Hz</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Relatively compact and comfortable-to-hold design</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Powerful camera system highlighted by a 50MP main sensor and 3x optical zoom</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>MediaTek processor could be viewed as a downgrade compared to the Galaxy S24's Snapdragon chip</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Doesn't have the camera button available on the Find X8 Pro</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Hard to get in the US</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="fdc2629e-3f70-4b51-aa46-8c2df70feb19">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wcakyzfBmryzdrojQ3eEfa.jpg' alt="Render of the Galaxy S24"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S24</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Still Samsung's latest and greatest</strong></em></p><p>The Samsung Galaxy S24 didn't bring any major improvements over the Galaxy S23, outside of the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 for Galaxy chipset, One UI 6, and a longer software support guarantee. Those are also the three main reasons you'd want to choose it over the OPPO Find X8. Otherwise, the Galaxy S24 also has a lower price and a more compact form factor going for it.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Excellent battery capacity and battery life</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 for Galaxy chipset</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>One UI 6, Galaxy AI, and seven years of guaranteed OS upgrades</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Thin and compact form factor</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Limited improvements over older Galaxy S23 models</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Old camera hardware</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Poor value proposition with limited upgrades, and Galaxy AI available on other (older) phones</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<p>OPPO's Find X series has been a top alternative to Samsung's Galaxy brand for a while, especially in Europe and Asia. The company's newest base-model flagship, the OPPO Find X8, is its best yet, shipping with ColorOS 15 and plenty of OPPO AI features. So, how does it compare with Samsung's current Galaxy S24?</p><p>The bottom line is that there are more differences than similarities between these two phones. The Find X8 has a MediaTek processor, while the Galaxy S24 has a Qualcomm processor. The Galaxy S24 is widely available in the US and supports North American cellular bands, while the Find X8 does not, and so on. If you're lucky enough to be in a region where the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-oppo-find-x8-series-is-taking-the-fight-to-the-iphone-16-globally">OPPO Find X8</a> is readily available for purchase, it's a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">better phone overall</a> than the Galaxy S24 — but remember, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25">Samsung Galaxy S25</a> is right around the corner.</p><p>In this comparison, we'll break down the differences between the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24">Galaxy S24</a> and the Find X8, helping you figure out which is right for you.</p>
<h2 id="oppo-find-x8-vs-samsung-galaxy-s24-design-2">OPPO Find X8 vs. Samsung Galaxy S24: Design</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:5333px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="JRjcJ3VFsrBiMwS7Y859hT" name="OPPO-Find-X8" alt="OPPO Find X8" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JRjcJ3VFsrBiMwS7Y859hT.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="5333" height="3000" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OPPO)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The OPPO Find X8 and the Samsung Galaxy S24 are not massive flagship phones like the Find X8 Pro or the Galaxy S24 Ultra. However, the Find X8 and its 6.59-inch screen are decisively larger than the 6.2-inch Galaxy S24. Measuring 157.4 x 74.3 x 7.9 mm, the Find X8 won't feel absurdly large in the hand. It's significantly heavier than the Galaxy S24, which only weighs 168.1 grams and measures just 147.1 x 70.61 x 7.62 mm. By comparison, the 193-gram weight of the Find X8 is significant.</p><p>Otherwise, both phones have flat screens and rectangular chassis with curved corners. The OPPO Find X8 is available in Star Grey, Space Black, Shell Pink, and Blue, while the Galaxy S24 can be had in Onyx Black, Marble Grey, Cobalt Violet, or Amber Yellow.</p><p>In terms of durability, the Galaxy S24 is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/what-do-waterproof-dustproof-rugged-ip-rating-numbers-mean">IP68 water and dust-resistant</a>, which means it can handle submersion in shallow water for brief periods. The OPPO Find X8 <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-is-an-ip69-rating-and-why-should-you-care">meets the higher IP69 standard</a>, testing against high-temperature and high-pressure water jets. In other words, you probably won't notice the difference between these phones where durability is concerned.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="9h4qLmMGqc4uXuxtpH2esm" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-purple-frame-01.jpg" alt="Looking at the different colorways of the Samsung Galaxy S24" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9h4qLmMGqc4uXuxtpH2esm.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The design of the OPPO Find X8 is more understated than prior Find models, specifically on the back. The circular camera housing OnePlus and OPPO are known for is still here, but the two-toned materials and colorways are largely gone. This could make the Find X8 more approachable to people considering an OPPO phone for the first time, since the Find X8 is more widely available globally than its predecessor.</p><p>Still, Samsung's method of individual, vertically arranged camera lenses is more subtle than that of the Find X8.</p>
<h2 id="oppo-find-x8-vs-samsung-galaxy-s24-hardware-and-specs-2">OPPO Find X8 vs. Samsung Galaxy S24: Hardware and specs</h2>
<p>More so than the exterior, the big differences between the Find X8 and the Galaxy S24 are on the inside. Notably, the OPPO Find X8 uses the MediaTek Dimensity 9400 processor, paired with either 12GB or 16GB of memory. Samsung has the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-3">Qualcomm Snapdragon 8 Gen 3</a> inside the Galaxy S24, which I'd suspect many would view as superior to the MediaTek chip. However, it's worth noting that the MediaTek 9400 in the Find X8 actually beats the Snapdragon SoC in the Galaxy S24 in Geekbench 6 benchmarks.</p><p>For those considering the OPPO Find X8 in Europe, you should know that the Galaxy S24 models in your region will have an Exynos 2300 chip, not a Snapdragon processor. As such, the performance advantage of the Find X8 could be even greater.</p><p>The two phones have similar display specifications, both featuring AMOLED panels that can reach 120Hz. Of course, the Find X8's display is slightly larger than the Galaxy S24's screen. Crucially, the Find X8 is significantly brighter than the Galaxy S24. OPPO claims a 4,500-nit peak brightness rating on the Find X8, while Samsung claims a 2,600-nit peak brightness rating on the Galaxy S24. This will be most noticeable outdoors, where OPPO and OnePlus displays are often easier to see in direct sunlight than Samsung panels.</p>

<p>In terms of battery life and charging, OPPO crushes Samsung. The Find X8 ships with a 5,630mAh battery that should last longer than the 4,000mAh battery in the Galaxy S24. More importantly, the Galaxy S24 charges extremely slow. It can only do up to 25W wired charging, whereas the Find X8 supports up to 80W wired charging. The disparity is greater when wireless charging is considered: the Find X8 supports 50W, while the Galaxy S24 supports 15W.</p><p>With Wi-Fi 7 and Bluetooth 5.4 available on the Find X8, the comparison is clear. Oppo is offering better hardware on the Find X8 than Samsung will give you on the Galaxy S24.</p>
<h2 id="oppo-find-x8-vs-samsung-galaxy-s24-cameras-2">OPPO Find X8 vs. Samsung Galaxy S24: Cameras</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:5333px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="okMaYbDgRbWrvhhQigiAhT" name="OPPO-Find-X8" alt="OPPO Find X8" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/okMaYbDgRbWrvhhQigiAhT.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="5333" height="3000" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OPPO)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Camera hardware has long been a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/new-leak-claims-oppos-find-x8-ultra-will-be-a-camera-beast">key reason to buy an OPPO phone</a>, and that hasn't changed. The rear camera sensors on the back of the Find X8 are better than those on the Galaxy S24, which Samsung hasn't changed in years. Both phones offer 3x optical zoom with telephoto lenses, which are essential going into 2025, but the quality figures to be better from the Find X8.</p><p>All three rear lenses on the Find X8 are 50MP, including the main wide lens, ultrawide lens, and telephoto lens. The main sensor is a 50MP, f/1.8 lens with a 1/1.56-inch sensor size with optical image stabilization. On top of that, you also get the 50MP, f/2.0 ultrawide camera with a 120-degree field of view. Rounding out the offerings is a 50MP, f/2.6 telephoto lens capable of 3x optical zoom.</p><p>Compare that to the Galaxy S24's 50MP, f/1.8 main sensor, 10MP, f/2.4 telephoto lens, and 12MP, f/2.2 ultrawide lens, and it hardly feels like a fair fight. If camera quality is one of your biggest needs, choose the OPPO Find X8.</p>
<h2 id="oppo-find-x8-vs-samsung-galaxy-s24-which-should-you-buy-2">OPPO Find X8 vs. Samsung Galaxy S24: Which should you buy?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="H7pxJnSUSSLBy3dNadjs7M" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-display-lockscreen-03.jpg" alt="The Amber Yellow Samsung Galaxy S24 colorway and its vibrant display" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/H7pxJnSUSSLBy3dNadjs7M.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>If both the OPPO Find X8 and the Samsung Galaxy S24 are available in your region, it's a no-brainer. The Find X8 offers better specs, from a faster processor to a more capable camera system, at around the same price. The Galaxy S24 might feel more familiar to One UI users and definitely <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-galaxy-ai">packs more AI features</a>. However, if you're inclined to stick with Samsung, you should <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-s25-plus-colors-seemingly-confirmed-as-sim-card-trays-leak">wait for the Galaxy S25</a> in hopes that it can better compete with the OPPO Find X8.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="9348e03f-07eb-44e5-9187-de35bdfed530">
            <a href="https://wondamobile.com/products/oppo-find-x8-5g-dual-sim?currency=USD&variant=42423311401048" data-model-name="Find X8"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PjSNVSDeJGhrHU2AuHgcfR.jpg' alt="A product render of the Oppo Find X8."></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">OPPO Find X8</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>For Samsung users wanting to try something new</strong></em></p><p>If you've been waiting for an OPPO flagship good enough to make you want to ditch your Galaxy phone, the OPPO Find X8 might just be that device. While Samsung's progress is seemingly stalling, Oppo is doing great things with the Find X8, offering a great phone with an even better camera for a fair price.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="35d9960a-8841-4940-b218-5f61934b477e">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wcakyzfBmryzdrojQ3eEfa.jpg' alt="Render of the Galaxy S24"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S24</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Familiarity can be favorable</strong></em></p><p>The Samsung Galaxy S24 isn't winning every battle on the spec sheet, and it's soon to be replaced by the Galaxy S25. However, it's a familiar device for Galaxy users, and there's something to be said for that. It's also much easier to get in North America, and much cheaper.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oppo-find-x8-vs-samsung-galaxy-s24</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The OPPO Find X8 is a compact flagship with impressive hardware, and it might just dethrone the soon-to-be-replaced Samsung Galaxy S24. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">eVVhHNW7KCEJY6cvjWrATg</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DVbgv2hhgComHnpRFvzVff.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 14:19:17 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DVbgv2hhgComHnpRFvzVff.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[All four retail colorways of the Samsung Galaxy S24]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[All four retail colorways of the Samsung Galaxy S24]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung Galaxy S25 vs. OnePlus 13: Take your pick of 2025's flagships ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[         <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="cb8806b6-42b8-45c0-b908-b7141722dc70">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JyBHooJcxaVXhoASHXQEuc.jpg' alt="Leaked render of the Galaxy S25"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S25</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Samsung's next flagship Galaxy phone</strong></em></p><p>The official launch of the Samsung Galaxy S25 is quickly approaching, and we're starting to know all but exactly what this phone will offer. The highlights include a new Snapdragon 8 Elite chipset, One UI 7, a bigger screen, and slight tweaks to the phone's chassis and design. The real question is, how does it stack up to the OnePlus 13?</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Qualcomm Snapdragon 8 Elite processor (rumored)</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>One UI 7, based on Android 15, with seven years of software upgrade support</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>New and improved Galaxy AI features (assumed)</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Bigger screen and slight design tweaks (rumored)</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>More expensive, thanks to pricier Snapdragon 8 Elite chip (rumored)</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Currently not available, with expected launch window of mid-to-late January 2025</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Still some unknowns, like how the Snapdragon 8 Elite will fare in terms of thermals and battery life</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="be30add9-3337-4291-aa6d-378120825167">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5gei6QXNmvhsLVXjNE39SE.jpg' alt="OnePlus 13 China launch"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">OnePlus 13</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Samsung's biggest 2025 challenger</strong></em></p><p>The OnePlus 13 might have the best change to challenge Samsung's upcoming Galaxy S25 in North America. It also packs a Snapdragon 8 Elite chip, a flat display, and OxygenOS 15. For now, it's only available in China, but a US launch is slated for next month.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Snapdragon 8 Elite chipset</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Some AI features with OxygenOS 15 (based on Android 15) available at launch </li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Quick charging speeds, up to 100W wired</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Curved display is ditched for a flat panel </li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Not enough AI features to compete with Galaxy AI</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Potentially more expensive than the OnePlus 12</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Limited US availability even after launch; OnePlus phones are often unavailable through carriers</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<p>The fall season was packed with a ton of exciting releases, highlighted by the Google Pixel 9 series. However, we're already amidst the winter season, and that means new Samsung and OnePlus flagships are nearing release. The Samsung Galaxy S25 and OnePlus 13 figure to be two of the best Android phones in 2025, so how do they compare?</p><p>That's a complicated question. Although the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-13">OnePlus 13</a> is already available in China, we don't know everything about either upcoming flagship. For the OnePlus 13, we know the phone's exact specifications, but lack US pricing information. Meanwhile, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25">Galaxy S25's</a> specs are mostly known due to reliable rumors and leaks, but there are a few holes. With that being said, we have a pretty good idea of how these two phones stack up against one another, and there's one that appears to have an early edge.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-s25-vs-oneplus-13-design-2">Samsung Galaxy S25 vs. OnePlus 13: Design</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1408px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="GSTZrT4GF3toZ8EVFwdWhh" name="samsung-galaxy-s25-angled-side-early-alleged-rendering.jpeg" alt="Another alleged angled rendering of the Galaxy S25." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GSTZrT4GF3toZ8EVFwdWhh.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1408" height="792" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Samsung's Galaxy S25 lineup is set to include at least three variants: the standard Galaxy S25, the bigger Galaxy S25 Plus, and the flagship Galaxy S25 Ultra. On the other hand, the OnePlus 13 is the brand's only flagship model for 2025. It's important to remember that the OnePlus 13's 6.82-inch screen size and large form factor will feel more like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-vs-galaxy-s23-ultra">Galaxy S25 Ultra</a> in hand. However, OnePlus' flagships are usually priced like Samsung's base-model phones, which is why you may be choosing between a OnePlus 13 and Galaxy S25 next month.</p><p>Still, the size difference may be the biggest reason to choose one of these phones over the other. It's jarring. The Samsung Galaxy S25 is expected to roughly measure 146.9 x 70.4 x 7.2mm, according to the latest leaks and rumors. That's relatively miniature compared to the OnePlus 13, which measures 162.9 x 76.5 x 8.5-8.9 mm. If you like small phones, the choice is easy: go with the Galaxy S25. Want a phone that feels more like the Galaxy S25 Ultra on a budget? The OnePlus 13 is your pick.</p><p>There are a few other design and build differences worth noting. The OnePlus 13 has a circular camera housing that holds its triple-camera system and flash. It's physically loud, off-center, and large. By comparison, the Galaxy S25's camera lenses are separated and much more understated than the OnePlus 13's camera array.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="ZqNPMAWgWh5mcrJEhfyyXh" name="OnePlus-13-launch-teaser-02.jpg" alt="OnePlus 13 launch tease" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZqNPMAWgWh5mcrJEhfyyXh.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OnePlus)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Both phones will have excellent durability ratings; the Galaxy S25 is expected to have an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/what-do-waterproof-dustproof-rugged-ip-rating-numbers-mean">IP68</a> rating for dust and water-resistance, while <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/is-the-oneplus-13-waterproof">the OnePlus 13 will be IP69-rated</a>. The newer IP69 rating tests the OnePlus 13 against high-pressure and high-temperature water jets, and likely <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-is-an-ip69-rating-and-why-should-you-care">won't make a major impact during daily use</a>. The Galaxy S25 is also expected to have Gorilla Glass coverings for the front and rear glass, and the OnePlus 13 has a Crystal Shield glass front.</p><p>The two phones will have different fit and finish options, too. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-series-color-options-tipped">The Galaxy S25 is rumored to come in at least four colors</a>: Moon Night Blue, Silver Shadow, Sparkling Blue, and Sparkling Green. They'll be available on a glass back, whereas the OnePlus 13 can be configured with an eco-leather or glass back in either black, blue, or white colorways.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-s25-vs-oneplus-13-hardware-and-specs-2">Samsung Galaxy S25 vs. OnePlus 13: Hardware and specs</h2>
<p>According to the latest leaks, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-samsung-galaxy-s25-will-be-exclusively-powered-by-snapdragon-8-elite-leaker-claims">Samsung Galaxy S25 will exclusively be powered by Qualcomm chips this year</a>, in all regions. It's technically still possible that the phone could use the Exynos 2500 platform in some places, but it's unlikely at this point. This means that both the Galaxy S25 and OnePlus 13 will be powered by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/snapdragon-8-elite">Qualcomm's Snapdragon 8 Elite chipset</a>, which includes the company's custom Oryon cores for greater performance and efficiency.</p><p>While the Galaxy S25 and OnePlus 13 both use the same display technology (AMOLED, 120Hz), their screen sizes will be a key differentiator. The Galaxy S25 is expected to boast a larger screen than the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24">Galaxy S24</a>, at 6.3 inches, but that's still smaller than the 6.82-inch OnePlus 13. While the exact specs are unknown, the OnePlus 13's 4,500-nit peak brightness rating should be higher than that of the Galaxy S25.</p>

<p>At the moment, current rumors indicate that Samsung once again doesn't plan to upgrade the camera system on the Galaxy S25. That would mean the flagship will ship with a 50MP main sensor, a 12MP ultrawide, and a 10MP telephoto lens. By all indications, the OnePlus 13 should have the better camera system. With a 50MP main sensor, a 50MP ultrawide, and a periscope telephoto lens with 3x optical zoom, the OnePlus 13 looks to have better rear camera hardware in almost every way. Samsung could improve its image signal processing and computational photography to pull more out of the Galaxy S25's hardware, though.</p><p>The OnePlus 13 could also bring better connectivity options than the Galaxy S25, packing Wi-Fi 7, NFC, 5G, and Bluetooth 5.4. While we're hoping that the Galaxy S25 matches these specifications, that's uncertain.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-s25-vs-oneplus-13-performance-and-software-2">Samsung Galaxy S25 vs. OnePlus 13: Performance and software</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="kersukxmGC4L8iY6McykXa" name="oxygenos-15-8.jpg" alt="OnePlus 12 with OxygenOS 15" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kersukxmGC4L8iY6McykXa.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Theoretically, the OnePlus 13 and the Galaxy S25 should offer similar performance, since they are both powered by the Snapdragon 8 Elite chipset. Performance will be great on both devices, because the Snapdragon 8 Elite chip is significantly improved compared to its predecessor, the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3. It's always possible that Samsung manages to tune the Snapdragon 8 Elite to get more performance and optimization out of it, as the company has done in the past.</p><p>Both phones will be powered by Android 15, but different skins. The OnePlus 13 has <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/i-used-oxygenos-15-for-a-week-these-are-my-favorite-features">OxygenOS 15</a>, while the Galaxy S25 will get <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsungs-first-one-ui-7-beta-is-available-now-public-release-set-for-early-2025">One UI 7</a>. At the end of the day, which one you prefer will come down to preference. However, the Galaxy S25 has more AI features and will get longer software support. Samsung is expected to pledge seven years of OS upgrades, but OnePlus is only giving OnePlus 13 buyers four years of OxygenOS upgrades.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-s25-vs-oneplus-13-which-should-you-buy-2">Samsung Galaxy S25 vs. OnePlus 13: Which should you buy?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1412px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="j694D5wu5mdb9MzUKqC72V" name="samsung-galaxy-s25-angled-look-early-alleged-rendering.jpeg" alt="An angled, rumored rendering of the Galaxy S25." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/j694D5wu5mdb9MzUKqC72V.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1412" height="794" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The higher cost of the Snapdragon 8 Elite chip is creating some uncertainty, and we don't know exactly how much the Galaxy S25 or OnePlus 13 will cost. If the OnePlus 13 can match or near the Galaxy S25's price point, it has a good chance of earning a recommendation.</p><p>With a bigger screen and better camera hardware, the OnePlus 13 could be a Galaxy S25 Ultra alternative available at Galaxy S25 pricing. Until we test these phones for ourselves, we won't know for sure. Luckily, we'll learn more about both of these phones' US pricing and availability next month.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="fb8568a5-b316-48f6-ba7b-89635bc9531f">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JyBHooJcxaVXhoASHXQEuc.jpg' alt="Leaked render of the Galaxy S25"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S25</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Our top pick for Samsung fans</strong></em></p><p>Chances are, the Samsung Galaxy S25 will be a great option for people familiar with Galaxy phones and One UI. It'll have a new chip, bigger screen, and an ambitious One UI 7 software update. However, we'll need to wait for this phone to officially debut — and test it for ourselves — before knowing for certain how it compares to the OnePlus 13.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="5ce9ffcd-5921-4052-9df3-c7592faf696a">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5gei6QXNmvhsLVXjNE39SE.jpg' alt="OnePlus 13 China launch"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">OnePlus 13</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>A sneaky contender for 2025's phone of the year</strong></em></p><p>Last year, the OnePlus 12 competed with the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra, despite costing hundreds of dollars less. The OnePlus 13 is poised to do the same next month, packing Android 15 and a Snapdragon 8 Elite chipset. The big question here is how much it'll cost.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-vs-oneplus-13</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Both the OnePlus 13 and Samsung Galaxy S25 will be powered by Snapdragon 8 Elite, but which model is best? ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">c8GW7jvcEzfmfaj5GjinSP</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4QEnsjhSowEc2TZM3xYjhY.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 14:01:26 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4QEnsjhSowEc2TZM3xYjhY.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[OnePlus]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus 13]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus 13]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Solos AirGo Vision AI smart glasses are finally here to challenge Ray-Ban Meta ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The Solos AirGo Vision, first announced in July, are finally available for purchase from Solos' website and Amazon.</li><li>The modular smart glasses feature swappable frames with and without a camera.</li><li>Like prior Solos glasses, the AirGo Vision are characterized by a comfortable, lightweight design.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Solos promised that its next pair of smart glasses, powered by ChatGPT-4o, would arrive at some point this year <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/solos-airgo-vision-launch">when they were first announced in July</a>. As the year comes to a close, the company is making good on that promise — the brand-new Solos AirGo Vision are available starting today, Dec. 10, from Solos' official website and Amazon. The camera-equipped glasses are modular, allowing users to swap frames in and out based on their needs.</p><p>The prior Solos AirGo 3 glasses were unique in that each temple was modular, connecting to the main part of the frame with a USB-C port and connector. That introduced new possibilities, such as the ability to charge the glasses either with a proprietary cable or a standard USB-C cable.</p><p>With the new AirGo Vision, Solos is taking this modular smart glasses concept to the next level. It's selling the AirGo Vision with and without camera-equipped frames — meaning you can wear the same pair of glasses as audio-only smart glasses (like the AirGo 3) or camera-enabled smart glasses (like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/the-ray-ban-meta-smart-glasses-are-my-gadget-of-the-year-but-ill-never-wear-them-again">Ray-Ban Meta glasses</a>). A complete kit, including a camera frame and a standard frame, costs $349. The camera frame is available for $299 by itself, and the frame only retails for $149.</p><p>Solos' latest offering is a new way of thinking about wearable privacy. Instead of turning a switch and hoping your glasses aren't on, you can literally remove the camera from the AirGo Vision thanks to their modularity. Additionally, the company seems to have preserved much of what we loved about the AirGo 3, like the lightweight design. Both styles, Krypton 1 and Krypton 2, weight just 42 grams. By comparison, the heaviest Ray-Ban Meta frames weigh nearly 51 grams.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4780px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:65.21%;"><img id="RSChScTHNJtgmzuv2j7VLh" name="Solos-AirGo-Vision-frames .jpg" alt="Solos AirGo Vision" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RSChScTHNJtgmzuv2j7VLh.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4780" height="3117" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Solos)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>"One thing we promised to deliver on was allowing consumers to have control of their experience with AI and smart technology, particularly with privacy options in mind," said Kenneth Fan, who is a co-founder of Solos, in a press release. "That's why we developed frames that can easily be changed to decide when and where a camera may be appropriate without sacrificing any of the fun features."</p><p>Aside from their modularity, the Solos AirGo Vision pack <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/openai-gpt-4o-launch-demo">ChatGPT-4o</a> support for visual processing. The company also says that other frameworks, such as Claude and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini</a>, are available. It claims that you can get more than 2,500 AI interactions  on a single charge.</p><p>Crucially, Solos fixed one of the biggest flaws with its AirGo 3 glasses. Now, after opening the companion app once, you'll be able to use AI features on the AirGo Vision with the app running in the background. This solves arguably the biggest inconvenience with using the AirGo 3, and makes the AirGo Vision a much more capable competitor to the Ray-Ban Meta glasses.</p><p>You can find the AirGo Vision at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="http://solosglasses.com/" target="_blank">Solos' website</a> and at Amazon starting now.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/the-solos-airgo-vision-ai-smart-glasses-are-finally-here-to-challenge-ray-ban-meta</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Solos' latest pair of smart glasses are modular, making it possible to attach or remove camera-equipped frames situationally.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">GUHoRTw3aucxCZubpTT9MF</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tRyyXcgTspjB2FDSWxdbWH.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tRyyXcgTspjB2FDSWxdbWH.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Solos]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Solos AirGo Vision against a pink gradient background.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Solos AirGo Vision against a pink gradient background.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>