<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 09:47:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Why don't more smartwatches use this smart ring's seemingly obvious trick? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Sunday Runday</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="rV2GgqHS9nqccNipGMkWqB" name="lloyd-break-dancing.jpg" caption="" alt="Lloyd, the Android Central mascot, break-dancing" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rV2GgqHS9nqccNipGMkWqB.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">In this <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/sunday-runday">weekly column</a>, Android Central Wearables Editor Michael Hicks talks about the world of wearables, apps, and fitness tech related to running and health, in his quest to get faster and more fit.</p></div></div>
<p>I don't typically use alarms because I hate being jolted out of REM sleep, as if the noise punched me awake and left me sullen and sluggish. Waking up on my own isn't usually a problem, but on days I can't risk oversleeping, I'd sure love my phone alarm to have a target wake-up range, using my smartwatch or smart ring data to hold off until I'm in my light sleep stage.</p><p>[<em>Infomercial voice</em>] But wait, now I can!</p><p>I own the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/ultrahuman-ring-air-review">Ultrahuman Ring Air</a>, one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/best-smart-rings">best smart rings</a> for dependable health and sleep accuracy without needing a subscription. On Wednesday, the Ultrahuman team announced the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.ultrahuman.com/blog/2024-ultrahuman-holiday-update/">2024 holiday update</a>, including an upcoming "Smart Alarm" PowerPlug feature.</p><p>The feature is still "coming soon" in the app, but Smart Alarm will "sync with your sleep cycles, gently waking you up during light sleep, with wake-up tunes crafted with sleep and music science — ensuring the perfect start to your day."</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="MYtp36FGPzD8B72sYoBZX5" name="ultrahuman-smart-alarm-powerplug" alt="A marketing mock-up for the upcoming Ultrahuman PowerPlug called Smart Alarm on a smartphone. It shows the words "Wake Me Up When" followed by different options like "I complete my sleep cycles" and "I pay off sleep debt."" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MYtp36FGPzD8B72sYoBZX5.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="caption-text">You'll have different options for when your phone will wake you, all dependent upon your smart ring. </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ultrahuman)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/ultrahuman-ring-air-adds-afib-new-app-store-of-powerplugs">Ultrahuman PowerPlugs</a> are essentially optional widgets for Ring Air owners to add niche data like AFib detection, jet lag tracking, Vitamin D, ovulation, heart adaptability to stressors, or pregnancy insights to their normal Today tab. But this new Smart Alarm tool, as the name suggests, is more of a traditional "smart" feature that you'd get on a watch, which I appreciate.</p><p>I'm confident Ultrahuman's Smart Alarm can work. Why? Because I've already tried it...with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fitbit-charge-6-review">Fitbit Charge 6</a>, which — like most other Fitbits — has a Smart Wake alarm setting that begins looking for a light-sleep stage 30 minutes before your target wake-up. Even though <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/smartwatch-vs-smart-ring-sleep-tracking">I hate wearing watches to bed</a>, I tried it during my Charge 6 review and found it worked as intended, avoiding any sudden jolts awake.</p><p>But since I'm the Wearables lead, I switch brands from week to week. <em>Most</em> brands don't offer a similar feature, and Fitbit itself <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/pixel-watch-3-great-running-features-overshadowed-by-fitbit-watches-demise">won't make any more smartwatches</a>. Google, which owns Fitbit, hasn't ported Smart Wake to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-3-review">Pixel Watch 3</a>, only offering basic alarm scheduling. Most watch and band owners don't have a tool like it.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="b4NVuMAqDeSUHfBjgnSa9c" name="Fitbit-Charge-6-smart-wake" alt="The Fitbit Charge 6 sitting on a pillow, showing an alarm window of 5:30-6:00am, then the words "Alarm will wake you during light sleep within..." (the words cut off)" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/b4NVuMAqDeSUHfBjgnSa9c.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Nearly any <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch">Android smartwatch</a> (or Apple Watch) will have detailed sleep-stage breakdowns within a few minutes of waking up. So I'd imagine some simple if/then conditionals would make this feature possible: If the time is during the requested wake-up window, check the current sleep stage; if deep or REM, wait 1 minute, then check again; if light, trigger the alarm; and if users hit the end of the wake-up window while still in REM, trigger alarm anyways so they don't oversleep.</p><p>Ultrahuman's Smart Alarm also has the option to trigger an alarm once the user clears their <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.ultrahuman.com/blog/introducing-sleep-debt-manage-your-sleep-deficiency-with-the-ring-air/">sleep debt</a>, which I find very cool. My partner doesn't like setting alarms because she has occasional anxious, sleepless nights, but other nights she'll oversleep until she has an hour of <em>negative</em> sleep debt. Ultrahuman's conditional "only wake up when you're rested" alarm would be perfect for her.</p><p>So many brands today emphasize things like sleep coaching or daily energy scores. Imagine if your <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-garmin-smartwatch">Garmin watch</a> had a conditional alarm that only buzzed your wrist when you hit a high-enough Body Battery score. The same would apply to your <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oura-ring-4-review">Oura Ring 4</a> and its Oura Readiness score, your <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-7-review">Galaxy Watch 7</a> and its daily Energy Score, and so on.</p><p>I know some smart alarm clocks detect your stage by picking up movement, but those don't work as well for couples since either person could trigger the not-dreaming state. Apps like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/pixel-watch-3-great-running-features-overshadowed-by-fitbit-watches-demise">Sleep Cycle</a> that pick up movement noises with your phone mic may have the same problem, <em>and</em> wouldn't work as well if you use white noise apps to sleep. Basically, I'd rather use a watch's direct heart rate and movement data, and cut out the guesswork.</p><p>Since my partner and I both own Ultrahuman Ring Airs, we don't need to worry about other smartwatches or rings; we're getting this feature soon. But it's my job to care about my readers' needs, too, and I think a lot of people — and the loved ones suffering from their wrong-side-of-the-bed grumpiness — would benefit from more graceful wake-ups. Here's hoping that by the end of 2025, more brands will follow in Fitbit and Ultrahuman's footsteps with smarter alarms!</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="3d51ef89-cb4d-40c3-999b-d8bdd1cfe43c">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Nqko76tGAvmpRA62Tmmyzc.jpg' alt="The black Ultrahuman Ring Air"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Ultrahuman Ring Air</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Passive health insights</strong></em></p><p>The Ultrahuman Ring Air, like most smart rings, will give you in-depth insights into your sleep efficiency, consistency, restoration, stages, stress levels, and more. You'll also see stats like your 7-day HRV, skin temperature, resting heart rate, and so on — all without having to wear a watch at night.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/why-dont-more-smartwatches-use-this-smart-rings-seemingly-obvious-trick</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Ultrahuman is adding a new Smart Alarm feature reminiscent of Fitbit's Smart Wake feature, and I'd love to see it spread to more watches. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">i7BShd8xiTzffoqSho8WX9</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YfqvMSCCxKbLw7zSnUdfPb.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YfqvMSCCxKbLw7zSnUdfPb.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Ultrahuman Ring Air held in fingertips to show the Ultrahuman logo engraved inside.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Ultrahuman Ring Air held in fingertips to show the Ultrahuman logo engraved inside.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Apple did the bare minimum because it doesn't care about you either ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Normally, I'm quick to point out all the ways that Google shows a lack of respect for users inside its ecosystem. That's part of my job; if a Google exec scratches his or her butt, I need to see how it affects Google's portfolio and us since we're the ones using these products.</p><p>That means I rarely worry about what other companies, like Apple, do to their users. This time is different because Apple's disdain for consumers and lack of cooperation puts us all at risk, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/android-and-iphone-users-told-to-pause-texting-each-other-amid-major-security-threat">according to the FBI</a>, which <em>usually</em> knows what it is doing.</p><p>I'm talking about <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/what-rcs-and-why-it-important-android">RCS</a>. Of course, I'm talking about RCS because it's been at least a month since I had to talk about RCS.</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Android & Chill</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="6okfEqHJFPcbznZSbSNW3n" name="android-n-chill.JPG" caption="" alt="Android Central mascot" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6okfEqHJFPcbznZSbSNW3n.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Future)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">One of the web's longest-running tech columns, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/android-and-chill">Android & Chill</a> is your Saturday discussion of Android, Google, and all things tech.</p></div></div>
<p>Here's the deal: if you use an iPhone and message someone else who is using an iPhone, you're good. If you use an Android phone and message someone else using an Android phone, you're good, too. The problem is when an iPhone user messages an Android user or an Android user messages an iPhone user.</p><p>Those messages, using the default messages app built into the phone, are no more secure than the old way of sending a text was. Apple did incorporate RCS messaging into iMessage, but it did it in a way that's not secure and didn't work with Google to sort it out.</p>
<p>This happened because of RCS itself. The tech, in its current form, doesn't support any sort of encryption yet. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.gsma.com/newsroom/article/rcs-nowin-ios-a-new-chapter-for-mobile-messaging/">It's being worked on</a>, but if you implement RCS using only the current open standards, messages are no safer than they used to be.</p><p>On the other hand, Google <em>does</em> offer <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/what-encryption">encrypted</a> RCS messaging — but only between two Android phones or the Chrome browser tied to an Android phone. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-will-now-directly-offer-rcs-features-instead-waiting-carriers">It added this itself</a> because RCS has no encryption method in place.</p><p>Since about 80% of people worldwide who use a smartphone are using an Android smartphone, this was one of those times when Google did the right thing. Apple didn't. Apple offers iPhone users who talk to other iPhone users encryption and tells everyone else to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/3/21/24107676/buy-your-mom-an-iphone">just buy an iPhone</a>.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1200px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="Nvh4Py4UT6CG7cx7uQ7ewT" name="google-messages-rcs-chatting-lifestyle.jpg" alt="Google Messages RCS chatting on a Pixel 4a." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Nvh4Py4UT6CG7cx7uQ7ewT.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1200" height="675" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The FBI piping in to let everyone know there is a problem isn't unexpected. In fact, it's the opposite, and I'm surprised it took so long. I assumed exploits would pop up during the first week, just like spam and phishing messages supposedly from the post office did. You (probably) aren't special, and nobody is actively trying to steal your identity and hack your credit cards; they're just trying to steal everyone's identity and get everyone's credit card info. Casting a huge net is an easy way to scam regular people out of millions each year.</p><p>Apple and Google could have, and should have, prevented this. Instead, Google was worried about tossing barbs at Apple and then taking a victory lap even when it <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-get-the-message-campaign">didn't really get what it was demanding</a>. Meanwhile, Apple trudged along and did nothing <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/gadgets-news/the-chinese-connection-in-apples-support-for-googles-messaging-platform/articleshow/107784364.cms#:~:text=China%20has%20been%20pushing%20device,a%20condition%20of%20regulatory%20certification." target="_blank">until China said they had to</a> add <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/apple-ios-18-adds-rcs-support-android">RCS capabilities</a>. Apple will always try to appease China when it's easy to do it, just like Google would. Neither side cared about working together to help consumers like us because we were going to buy their shit anyway. 💰🐄</p>
<p>So what should you do? If you live outside the U.S. or Canada, you probably don't have to do anything because you likely don't even use <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/top-5-tips-and-tricks-google-messages">Google Messages</a> or iMessage. People here use them because texts are free, and, well, we just <em>do</em>.</p><p>If you use either, you should stop and switch to a secure and encrypted platform like the FBI says. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-messaging-apps">There are plenty,</a> but I'm partial to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/eu-makes-switch-signal-its-messaging-app-choice">Signal</a> because the people behind it only care about making a secure messaging service; they want to hook you on their product by making it great and not tying it to another service or looking to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/whatsapp-now-requires-you-share-data-facebook">sell it off to Meta</a>.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:644px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:44.72%;"><img id="o2JmVcGfDhuGhdDYEdt8tN" name="signal" alt="Signal messenger." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/o2JmVcGfDhuGhdDYEdt8tN.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="644" height="288" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: <a href="https://signal.org/install" target="_blank">Signal</a>)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>That's easier said than done. You could go through all of your contacts and ask them to switch to another platform, but they're not going to do it. They don't think they need to do it because they might not have thousands in the bank sitting around ripe for the taking, or they don't think they have anything to hide.</p><p>All you really can do is refuse to send any information through <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-messages-first-things-to-do">Google Messages</a> or iMessage that you don't want the world to read and wish the companies that made these things actually cared about their users.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/fbi-warns-about-ios-android-messaging-security-threat-and-im-not-surprised</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Because Apple and Google won't work together, the FBI says users should switch to a better messenger. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">wvDLRALCHeBHi6NNJsv45</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2WdULw6noDbNsWHtYwxQ5T.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2WdULw6noDbNsWHtYwxQ5T.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Messages on an Android phone atop an iPhone.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Messages on an Android phone atop an iPhone.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ News Weekly: Android XR announced with a Samsung headset, Gemini 2.0 drops, and the Galaxy S25 may get Qi2... sort of ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">News Weekly</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="h7AVxNX2TSFH3rYKHd2Vw" name="lloyd-news-weekly.jpg" caption="" alt="News Weekly Logo" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/h7AVxNX2TSFH3rYKHd2Vw.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text"><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/news-weekly">News Weekly</a> is our column where we highlight and summarize some of the week's top stories so you can catch up on the latest tech news.</p></div></div>
<p>This is Android Central's News Weekly, your go-to source for a concise roundup of the week's most significant tech stories. This is where we delve into the top headlines that provide the latest developments and innovations contributing to the digital landscape.</p><p>This week, Google had quite a few big announcements with the launch of Android XR, Gemini 2.0, and a price hike for YouTube TV. Plus, Sundar Pichai had some choice words about Microsoft and a new rumor claims the Galaxy S25 series might actually get Qi2 support, but with a catch.</p>

<hr>
<h2 id="android-xr-is-how-google-competes-with-meta-and-apple-2">Android XR is how Google competes with Meta and Apple</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.20%;"><img id="DRPgjWYXCq5R2PqDAfeiqD" name="Glasses_Translate-google-android-xr" alt="Translating a sign using smart glasses powered by Android XR" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DRPgjWYXCq5R2PqDAfeiqD.gif" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="500" height="281" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Read more </strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/android-xr-announcement"><strong>here</strong></a>.</p><p>It's been long teased that Google was working on an XR platform based on Android, with hardware coming from Samsung in partnership with Qualcomm. Now the cat's out of the bag with the announcement of Android XR, a new platform that's set to power smart glasses and XR headsets not unlike the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.imore.com/gaming/virtual-reality/apple-vision-pro">Apple Vision Pro</a> or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-3s-review">Meta Quest 3S</a>.</p><p>According to Google, the platform will launch first on headsets, with Samsung's Project Moohan set to release in 2025. This will enable users to "switch between being fully immersed in a virtual environment and staying present in the real world," not unlike how some of the best VR headsets work. Smartphone and tablet apps will also work, and Google is optimizing its own apps for the platform.</p><p>Google is also testing <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-smart-glasses">smart glasses</a>, as we saw with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/google-project-astra-ar-waitlist-opens-trusted-testers">Project Astra</a>. This will use Gemini to provide information about what you're looking at, and it's suggested that visual cues may also be available.</p><p>There seems to be <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/android-xr-is-the-most-exciting-new-version-of-android-in-years">a lot of potential with Android XR</a>, which makes it one of the most exciting things to look forward to in 2025.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="gemini-gets-the-upgrade-we-ve-been-waiting-for-2">Gemini gets the upgrade we've been waiting for</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4480px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="WK7yDjQB2kjcz6MAYd2y4C" name="Gemini-2.0" alt="The Gemini 2.0 graphic provided by Google." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WK7yDjQB2kjcz6MAYd2y4C.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4480" height="2520" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Read more </strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/googles-latest-ai-model-gemini-2-0-is-here-to-usher-in-the-agentic-era"><strong>here</strong></a>.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini</a> has been all over the place in 2024, but 2025 looks to be an exciting year for Google's AI efforts after it revealed a major update for its model. Gemini 2.0 is taking things to the next level by making it more capable than before, allowing it to better understand the world around you and complete tasks on behalf of the user.</p><p>What does this mean, exactly? This means that Gemini 2.0 is equipped to power experiences like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/google-project-starline-astra-ar-glasses">Project Astra</a>, which was shown on Google I/O earlier this year. It can visualize the world around you and even remember what it saw so you can recall something later. And with Project Mariner, Gemini 2.0 can complete complex, multi-step tasks for you by understanding what's on your screen, just as a virtual assistant should. We've seen companies like Motorola <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/motorola-is-testing-ai-that-skips-words-and-gets-straight-to-doing-what-you-ask">show off concepts</a> similar to this, so it'll be interesting to see how this evolves in 2025.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="qi2-could-finally-be-a-thing-in-2025-2">Qi2 could finally be a thing in 2025</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3919px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="TVQMRpPH6YLA2mafLsRjSV" name="samsung-qi2-lifestyle-2.jpg" alt="Mock Qi2 MagSafe ring on a Samsung Galaxy S22 Ultra" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TVQMRpPH6YLA2mafLsRjSV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3919" height="2204" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Read more </strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-s25-qi2-wireless-charging-support-rumors"><strong>here</strong></a>.</p><p>Qi2 has been out for a little while, but it's been mostly absent on Android, save for some <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/hmd-skyline-qi2-launch">HMD phones</a>. However, with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25">Galaxy S25</a>, this could change, as the latest rumors suggest the company might finally adopt the wireless charging spec in its upcoming devices.</p><p>If true, then the Galaxy S25 series will support the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qi2-wireless-charging-standard">Qi2</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-magsafe-accessories-for-android-phones">MagSafe accessories</a> available for iPhones, allowing them to charge wirelessly at the full 15W instead of being subjected to slower speeds.</p><p>That said, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://suomimobiili.fi/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-muisti-ja-variversiot-suomessa/">a separate rumor</a> suggests that the phones may not have Qi2 integrated into the phones themselves. Instead, the newer standard may only be accessible via compatible cases. This would be similar to what we've seen with recent OPPO phones and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-13">OnePlus 13</a>.</p><p>If true, it's unclear why companies are opting for this method, but given that many users will likely purchase cases for their phones, it may not be a huge deal. Still, it would be nice to have it integrated for those who may not want a case, but we'll have to wait and see what we get when the Galaxy S25 launches in early 2025.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="youtube-tv-continues-to-rise-in-the-worst-way-possible-2">YouTube TV continues to rise, in the worst way possible</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="GGeShzgoboKpPTK4qqCPFK" name="YouTube-TV-app-smart-tv.jpg" alt="YouTube TV app on a smart TV" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GGeShzgoboKpPTK4qqCPFK.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Read more </strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/youtube-tv-december-2024-price-hike-reported"><strong>here</strong></a>.</p><p>Price hikes for streaming services are nothing new, so the new base price for YouTube TV shouldn't shock anyone, but it will sting. The company announced this week that new users will immediately see the base price of $82.99, a $10 increase from the previous $72.99 that was <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/youtube-tv-2023-price-increase">introduced in early 2023</a>.</p><p>The company <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/youtubetv/answer/9285852">explained</a> that the updated price is due to the rising costs of content but that users can expect to retain their current features and benefits.</p><p>For new users, the price won't update until January 13, 2025, so there's some buffer time in case you want to consider your options or pause your membership. Otherwise, prepare to pay more in the coming month as streaming services continue to reach cable prices.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="google-vs-microsoft-the-ai-wars-2">Google vs. Microsoft: The AI wars</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3774px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="8wNc88sFgWN2ay2k6stBCo" name="Microsoft-logo.jpg" alt="The Microsoft logo at MWC 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8wNc88sFgWN2ay2k6stBCo.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3774" height="2123" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Read more </strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google/googles-ceo-blasts-microsofts-ai-efforts-says-theyre-using-someone-elses-models"><strong>here</strong></a>.</p><p>Google CEO Sundar Pichai threw a bit of shade at Microsoft during <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.nytimes.com/events/dealbook/sessions/sundar-pichai-building-the-future">The New York Times' DealBook Summit</a>. Journalist and author Andrew Ross Sorkin asked Pichai about his thoughts on where Google is compared to its competitors in the AI race, prefacing it with a quote from Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella, who said that Google should have been the default winner.</p><p>Pichai quickly responded by saying he would love to compare Microsoft's <em>own</em> models with Google's, noting that Microsoft is using someone else's.</p><p>It's no secret that Microsoft got a bit of a headstart in the AI space after <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/microsoft-bing-edge-openai-chatgpt">partnering with OpenAI</a> to integrate its models into the company's services like Bing. Meanwhile, Google was seen by many as having to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-is-still-being-slow-and-careful-with-ai-and-thats-still-a-good-thing">play catch-up</a> after losing some mindshare to the likes of ChatGPT.</p><p>That said, Google saw plenty of progress in 2024 with Gemini across various devices and services. However, Pichai noted during his talk that while he expects to see more advancements in 2025, we shouldn't expect it at the same pace we've seen.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="more-stories-this-week-2">More stories this week</h2>
<p>Those are some of the biggest stories from this week. Meanwhile, here are some other stories that are worth catching up on:</p>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet-adds-digital-id-support-in-yet-another-us-state">Google Wallet adds digital ID support in yet another US state</a></li><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/android-and-iphone-users-told-to-pause-texting-each-other-amid-major-security-threat">Android and iPhone users told to pause texting each other amid major security threat</a></li><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsungs-new-one-ui-7-beta-killed-a-handy-lock-screen-feature">Samsung's new One UI 7 beta killed a handy lock screen feature</a></li><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/launcher-10-android-phone-windows-phone-os-style">Launcher 10 lets you turn an Android phone into a Windows Phone</a></li><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-music-gains-a-crucial-feature-for-podcast-listening-and-sharing">YouTube Music gains a crucial feature for podcast listening and sharing</a></li><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-s24-series-december-2024-patch-rollout">Galaxy S24 series' latest security patch is just a One UI 7 waiting room</a></li><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9a-real-life-images-leak-again">Leaked Pixel 9a images reaffirm a curious design change</a></li><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-s25-series-alleged-sporadic-price-increase-rumored">The Galaxy S25 series will allegedly see sporadic price increases, per reports</a></li><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-galaxy-s25-ultra-could-bump-up-ram-in-its-higher-end-models">The Galaxy S25 Ultra could bump up RAM in its higher-end models</a></li><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-docs-adds-40-new-pageless-templates-with-more-coming-soon">Google Docs adds 40 new pageless templates, with more coming soon</a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/news-weekly-december-14-2024</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ This week, Google made several announcements, including its new Android XR OS and Gemini 2.0. Plus, new details suggest Qi2 is coming to the Galaxy S25 series. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">GCiExtb5GJZ2BkkE8jQqXT</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/b8LPWcVz3R46fgHnxagqGF.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ derrek.lee@futurenet.com (Derrek Lee) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/b8LPWcVz3R46fgHnxagqGF.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A look at the video player UI of Android XR running on a Samsung Project Moohan headset in mixed reality]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A look at the video player UI of Android XR running on a Samsung Project Moohan headset in mixed reality]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ New Pixel 9a leak details every last spec of the upcoming mid-range handset ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Pixel 9a full specifications surface way ahead of the launch, giving us every last detail.</li><li>The device will apparently ship with Tensor G4, a bigger 5100mAh battery, and dual rear cameras.</li><li>It will ship with Android 15 out of the box and is expected to offer seven years of OS upgrades.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google's next mid-range phone, the Pixel 9a, might still be many months from launch, but leaks are revealing everything the company is likely bringing to the table. The latest one includes every spec of the upcoming handset.</p><p>The leak comes from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidheadlines.com/2024/12/exclusive-pixel-9a-specs-confirmed-all-the-details.html">Android Headlines</a>, which cites a wireless carrier source and is further corroborated by an unknown source — both detailing the forthcoming Pixel 9a specs in detail.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:463px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:129.59%;"><img id="yK3x6r8HUB7PV9GDfFfxp9" name="Pixel-9a-leaked-specs-02" alt="Pixel 9a leaked specs" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yK3x6r8HUB7PV9GDfFfxp9.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="463" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:463px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:129.59%;"><img id="QtPum7wwhaivTWR8jTVvp9" name="Pixel-9a-leaked-specs" alt="Pixel 9a leaked specs" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QtPum7wwhaivTWR8jTVvp9.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="463" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:464px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:129.31%;"><img id="JyTtwAZQyB6jRq2nGawwp9" name="Pixel-9a-leaked-specs-01" alt="Pixel 9a leaked specs" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JyTtwAZQyB6jRq2nGawwp9.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="464" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>According to the leaked spec sheet, the Pixel 9a would be incorporating the latest <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-tensor-g4-is-a-key-piece-of-googles-smartphone-vision">Google Tensor G4</a> chipset — the same SoC that powered the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-series-hands-on">Pixel 9 series</a>. It will be paired with the Titan M2 security processor, and the configurations of the mid-range handset may include 8GB of RAM and 128/256GB of storage</p><p>The device is believed to ship with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-review">Android 15</a> out of the box as opposed to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16">Android 16</a>, and, like the flagship series, Google may offer seven years of OS upgrades and security updates.</p><p>The expected dimensions from the leaked spec sheet show that the Pixel 9a will measure 154.7mm x 73.3mm x 8.9mm, making it slightly taller and wider than the previous iteration, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-review">Pixel 8a</a>. The device might also be slightly lighter, around 185.9 grams.</p>
<p>The display, with a 120Hz refresh rate, would measure around 6.3 inches and is an AMOLED screen with Full HD+ resolution and a peak brightness of up to 2700 nits. It is believed to feature Gorilla Glass 3 protection on top. The dual cameras at the back will have a 48MP primary lens accompanying a 13MP ultra-wide lens. For selfies, the handset is likely to rely on a 13MP shooter.</p><p>A slightly bigger battery capacity will keep the lights on the Pixel 9a. It will host a 5100mAh battery with support for 23W charging alongside 7.5W wireless charging support. Lastly, the device may also feature an IP68 rating similar to the Pixel 9 series.</p>
<p>The handset is expected to cost $499 (the MSRP in the leaked sheet) and may be available in Obsidian, Porcelain, Iris, and Peony, the latter two being the newest color additions. The spec sheet also confirms the model numbers and device availability in the U.S., U.K., Canada, and India markets.</p><p>In addition to the leaked specifications, we have also seen what the Pixel 9a would look like — thanks to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9a-real-life-images-leak-again">recent real-life</a> images, which are believed to be prototypes. This isn't the first time we have seen it, as a similar <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9a-alleged-real-life-photos-leak">real-life image</a> was spotted indicating that the iconic Pixel camera visor design at the back has been removed, and the Pixel 9a will stick to a flat, flushed camera design.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="E4D8zdSoWLFvdYwmNZJ99o" name="Pixel-9a-real-life-image-leak" alt="Pixel 9a real-life image leak" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/E4D8zdSoWLFvdYwmNZJ99o.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Via OnLeaks)</span></figcaption></figure>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u><strong><br></strong></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9a-leak-reveal-every-last-spec-of-the-handset</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ We have been seeing several leaks of the Pixel 9a way ahead of the launch. The latest one, however, hits the nail on the coffin. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">8LSKDfXUhNCYUtmJtoGGvB</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Ri5t9SatZcsjr9hhZCJW7X.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 01:13:56 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Ri5t9SatZcsjr9hhZCJW7X.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Headlines]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A supposed rendering of the Pixel 9a.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A supposed rendering of the Pixel 9a.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The best Android phone of 2024 just crashed back to its lowest price EVER (and it'll arrive by Christmas) ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The holiday season has arrived, and if you&apos;re looking for a last-minute phone deal to stick under the tree, you&apos;re in luck: <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oneplus-12-256gb-unlocked-silky-black/6570636.p"><strong>the OnePlus 12 has just scored a $250 discount at Best Buy</strong></a>, the same price drop that we saw during the retailer&apos;s historic Black Friday sale. For just $549.99, you&apos;re getting Android Central&apos;s favorite phone of 2024 — just be sure to order today if you want it to arrive by Christmas. </p>
<h2 id="our-favorite-phone-of-2024-scores-a-250-discount-2">Our favorite phone of 2024 scores a $250 discount</h2>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="75ac5a96-eae1-42ec-8a61-a7d7cd18115e" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799.99" data-dimension48="$799.99" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oneplus-12-256gb-unlocked-silky-black/6570636.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="yf3PmQ3byJBHbWmMtoDrv8" name="OnePlus-12.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yf3PmQ3byJBHbWmMtoDrv8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>OnePlus 12 256GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oneplus-12-256gb-unlocked-silky-black/6570636.p" data-dimension112="75ac5a96-eae1-42ec-8a61-a7d7cd18115e" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799.99" data-dimension48="$799.99"><del>$799.99</del> <strong>$549.99 at Best Buy</strong></a></p>
<p>Who needs Black Friday? Head to Best Buy during its holiday sale and you'll score $250 off any configuration of the OnePlus 12, our favorite flagship phone released this year. The well-crafted device boasts a glorious 120Hz display with a Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 chipset and the best cameras ever built into a OnePlus phone, and now it's returned to a record-low price. No trade-in required, no strings attached. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oneplus-12-256gb-unlocked-silky-black/6570636.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="75ac5a96-eae1-42ec-8a61-a7d7cd18115e" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799.99" data-dimension48="$799.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/android-central-holiday-gift-guide-best-deals-2024"><strong>See Android Central's 2024 holiday gift guide! 20+ deals on smartphones, tablets, wearables, and more</strong></a></li></ul>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>you want a powerful flagship phone at a midrange price; great cameras and stylish design are important to you; you need over two days of battery life on a single charge.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>you&apos;re interested in the latest AI features or long software support; you need IP68 ingress protection in your devices. </p><p>The OnePlus 12 topped our list of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a> this year thanks to a sophisticated blend of thoughtful design choices, outstanding battery life, and Snapdragon-powered performance that could easily rival the best devices from Samsung or Google. </p><p>As senior editor Harish Jonnalagadda points out in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12-review">his 4.5/5-star review</a>, the phone really feels like a culmination of everything that OnePlus has learned over its past ten years of releases. The OnePlus 12 is a refinement more than a reinvention, and in this case, that&apos;s a very good thing.</p><p>Of course, everything isn&apos;t perfect with the flagship. You only get five years of guaranteed OS/security updates (compared to Samsung and Google&apos;s seven-year promise), and you won&apos;t enjoy any of the fancy AI features that have been dominating the airwaves lately. But if you simply want an incredible flagship experience with a record-smashing discount, then this OnePlus 12 deal is for you.</p>

<h2 id="holiday-sales-2024-x2014-quick-links-2">Holiday sales 2024 — quick links</h2>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/deals"><strong>Amazon: </strong>up to 54% off Amazon devices, discounted phones, and more</a></li><li><a href="https://www.walmart.com/shop/deals"><strong>Walmart: </strong>huge rollback savings on tech, laptops, and TVs</a></li><li><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/discover-samsung-event/"><strong>Samsung: </strong>enhanced trade-in credit, up to 50% off Galaxy wearables</a></li><li><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/top-deals"><strong>Best Buy: </strong>major savings on Motorola and Samsung, new Doorbuster deals daily</a></li><li><a href="https://mintmobile.com/deals/"><strong>Mint Mobile: </strong>up to $500 off Pixel 9 series, Unlimited for $15 per month</a></li><li><a href="https://www.verizon.com/deals/"><strong>Verizon: </strong>up to $1,500 of free tech when you bundle, new trade-in opportunities</a></li><li><a href="https://www.att.com/deals/"><strong>AT&T: </strong>Motorola phones from $0.99/month with eligible lines</a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-best-android-phone-of-2024-just-crashed-back-to-its-lowest-price-ever-and-itll-arrive-by-christmas</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Best Buy is currently carving $250 off the unlocked OnePlus 12,  our favorite phone of 2024. Order ASAP and it'll get here by Christmas! ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">pvty4mMwQGAmfHZVudSNLE</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RhhcQ4N6zLajzntorQmw7F.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 21:23:06 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RhhcQ4N6zLajzntorQmw7F.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus 12 camera module against colorful background]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus 12 camera module against colorful background]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung tipped to expand its Galaxy Ring size selection in January ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Rumors claim Samsung is preparing to introduce new extra Galaxy Ring sizes, 14 and 15, next year in January.</li><li>There is speculation that these larger sizes could feature "slightly" large batteries, but that remains to be seen.</li><li>A Galaxy Ring 2 patent suggests it could deliver a flexible internal structure and other rumors purport a longer battery life and a thinner profile.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Samsung's Galaxy Ring finds itself wrapped in a new rumor that claims there could be more of it on the way.</p><p>The rumors surfaced on X through a post by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/MaxJmb/status/1867578381803327678">Max Jambor</a> who claims Samsung is planning to introduce new ring size options (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.sammobile.com/news/galaxy-ring-two-more-size-options-january/">SamMobile</a>). Supposedly, the tipster discovered internal model numbers for these extra sizes: SM-Q514 and SM-Q515. Jambor claims that these model names are for Galaxy Ring sizes 14 and 15, respectively.</p><p>Both sizes weigh roughly 3.2 grams and with a diameter of ~23mm and ~23.8mm.</p><p>More importantly, Jambor states an announcement of these Galaxy Ring sizes could occur sometime in January alongside its market availability.</p><p>What's more, the publication speculates that these two extra Galaxy Rings could provide even larger batteries. Currently, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-ring">Galaxy Ring</a> is available in U.S. sizes ranging from five to 13. This affects its battery as the smallest size sees an 18mAh battery capacity while the 13 variant features a 23.5mAh capacity. Jambor didn't allude to any such changes; however, there could be a chance that the size 14 and 15 rings grab a <em>slightly </em>larger battery.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">New sizes will finally be available in January!Size 14 (SM-Q514): 3.2g, 23 mm inner diameter Size 15 (SM-Q515): 3.2g, 23,8 mm inner diameter https://t.co/GSyK3iFLaL<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1867578381803327678">December 13, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>This <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-ring-more-sizes-rumor">isn't the first time</a> Jambor has alleged an expansion in Samsung's Galaxy Ring size selection. In September, a post claimed that the Korean OEM was creating additional sizes — 14 and 15 — but that they would debut in "the coming weeks." It seems things have changed as nothing launched in October nor in November and with us in December, it seems Samsung set its sights on the new year.</p><p>Curiously, this extra Galaxy Ring selection <em>could </em>line up with the upcoming Galaxy Unpacked, rumored for January. Next month is expected to host the unveiling of the Galaxy S25 series. Perhaps, if the Galaxy Ring does make a quick appearance, it will be to announce the availability of these additional sizes.</p><p>The O.G. smart ring has been relatively quiet as all eyes have been on its next iteration, the Galaxy Ring 2, as rumors <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-ring-resizing-patent-discovered">suggest a resizing function</a>. A patent discovered in October claims the next Galaxy Ring could offer a "resizing structure" via its flexible internals that will only require Samsung to create one (outer) ring. The band would expand depending on the size of the user's finger for a comfortable fit.</p><p>Elsewhere, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/galaxy-ring-2-new-enhancements-launch-rumored">rumors claim</a> the Galaxy Ring 2 could receive an increased battery life and a thinner profile.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="976b8fcd-904e-44d8-b641-8b4dac9ae65d">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/scHNkBLecSo5rKDcEyjmJm.jpg' alt="Samsung Galaxy Ring - Titanium Black"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy Ring</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>Samsung's Galaxy Ring is the company's first entry into the world of smart rings. With on-board AI features, the Galaxy Ring delivers strong and useful health/fitness features for everyday use. Additionally, its assortment of available colors could hold something in store for everyone.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-ring-size-expansion-january-rumors</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Rumors suggest Samsung could add extra sizes to its Galaxy Ring early in 2025. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">pCoaX8tFdNiBPy5rqKd3SU</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KMbUhCn4bUehTLkmfqKTya.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 20:36:43 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KMbUhCn4bUehTLkmfqKTya.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Looking at the electronics on the inside of the gold Samsung Galaxy Ring]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Looking at the electronics on the inside of the gold Samsung Galaxy Ring]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Ends Sunday! Lyca Mobile's Unlimited plan drops to only $10 per month, just in time for the holidays ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>MVNO deals are a dime-a-dozen these days, but the T-Mobile-powered carrier Lyca Mobile just dropped a holiday offer that you might have missed if you weren&apos;t paying particularly close attention. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://lycamobileusa.sjv.io/c/221109/2107181/25589"><strong>Sign up for three months of the Unlimited plan at Lyca Mobile before December 15th and you&apos;ll score an 80% discount</strong></a>, knocking your bill down to only $10 per month. </p><p>The plan in question comes with unlimited talk, text, and data on T-Mobile&apos;s legendary 5G / 4G LTE network, plus you get some premium extras like unlimited calls and texts to over 100 countries worldwide and a 10GB mobile hotspot. Lyca Mobile supports nearly all of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a> and there are no contracts or pesky hidden fees to worry about. What you see is what you get, and what you&apos;re getting is a great deal on wireless. </p>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/android-central-holiday-gift-guide-best-deals-2024"><em><strong>Check out Android Central's 2024 holiday gift guide! 20+ deals on smartphones, tablets, wearables, and more</strong></em></a></li></ul>
<h2 id="unlimited-everything-for-only-10-bucks-2">Unlimited everything for only 10 bucks</h2>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="98db6a84-20d8-400c-af38-77f4d07ebe89" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Lyca Mobile Holiday Deal: Get three months of Unlimited for only $10/month" data-dimension48="Lyca Mobile Holiday Deal: Get three months of Unlimited for only $10/month" href="https://lycamobileusa.sjv.io/c/221109/2107181/25589" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:750px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="7iSFwohmdjbkXhiyj7R6jH" name="Lycamobile Artwork.png" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7iSFwohmdjbkXhiyj7R6jH.png" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="750" height="750" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Lyca Mobile Holiday Deal: </strong><a href="https://lycamobileusa.sjv.io/c/221109/2107181/25589" data-dimension112="98db6a84-20d8-400c-af38-77f4d07ebe89" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Lyca Mobile Holiday Deal: Get three months of Unlimited for only $10/month" data-dimension48="Lyca Mobile Holiday Deal: Get three months of Unlimited for only $10/month"><strong>Get three months of Unlimited for only $10/month</strong></a></p>
<p>Join Lyca Mobile on the Unlimited plan via this link and you'll only have to pay $10 per month for your first three months of service. The plan comes with unlimited talk, text, and data on T-Mobile's network, plus you get international perks and a free mobile hotspot. The best part is that there are no contracts or credit checks, so you can potentially just move on after the deal expires with zero hassle whatsoever. </p>
<p><em>Preferred partner (</em><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/content-funding-on-android-central"><em>What does this mean?</em></a><em>)</em><a class="view-deal button" href="https://lycamobileusa.sjv.io/c/221109/2107181/25589" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="98db6a84-20d8-400c-af38-77f4d07ebe89" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Lyca Mobile Holiday Deal: Get three months of Unlimited for only $10/month" data-dimension48="Lyca Mobile Holiday Deal: Get three months of Unlimited for only $10/month">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>There are plenty of great <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-mvno-carrier">MVNO carriers</a> to consider, but thanks to enticing promos like this, Lyca Mobile is quickly rising the ranks as one of the best options out there.</p><p>Of course, if you&apos;re happy with your current phone plan or you simply live in an area with poor T-Mobile coverage, then this Lyca Mobile deal isn&apos;t for you. It&apos;s also worth mentioning that data speeds will begin to slow after 40GB, so heavy data users may need wish to look elsewhere. For most folks, though, this is an excellent wireless opportunity for dirt cheap — just make sure you take advantage of this exclusive offer before midnight on December 15th.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/carriers/ends-sunday-lyca-mobiles-unlimited-plan-drops-to-only-usd10-per-month-just-in-time-for-the-holidays</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The T-Mobile-powered MVNO Lyca Mobile is running a holiday deal that gets you unlimited data for only $10 per month.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">S94bG8aSJDnMeZiC5E7zAY</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GfFt5hie6WwbeQwAbgUwz4.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 19:32:35 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Carriers]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GfFt5hie6WwbeQwAbgUwz4.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Lycamobile]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Lycamobile logo]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Lycamobile logo]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Gemini can now give you the TL;DR of your Google Drive folders ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google highlighted the rollout of Gemini in Drive, which aims to help summarize a user's folders, documents, spreadsheets, and more.</li><li>Users can write their query for a folder in Drive's side panel or they can navigate to a folder and hit the "summarize folder" button.</li><li>Google recently updated Docs with additional Gemini help for crafting formatted documents while also unveiling Gemini 2.0.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google is rolling out an update for Drive users that brings Gemini into its side panel with new tools.</p><p>The company highlighted the latest update in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://workspaceupdates.googleblog.com/2024/12/adding-folder-support-to-gemini-in-side-panel-of-google-drive.html">Workspace post</a>, stating Gemini can now summarize documents in Drive. Google explains that Gemini in Drive can only answer questions about your "text documents, PDFs, spreadsheets, and presentations."</p><p>More specifically, with Gemini entering Drive's side panel, Google states users can write their queries about a folder before the "@" symbol and the name of the folder; i.e., "summarize the files in @AndroidCentral."</p><p>Additionally, Google gives the example of asking about the "theme of the content" within a folder.</p><p>Writing your prompt to Gemini isn't the only avenue toward quick information as users will find a starry icon button in folders, too. Once you receive this update, navigating to a folder <em>should </em>display a "Summarize this folder" button beneath the navigation bar. Clicking this will automatically inform Gemini of your request and produce the side panel with its generated information.</p><p>There will also be a "suggestions" option alongside the likely ability for users to expand on what they'd like Gemini to surface via the text field.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:993px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:60.42%;"><img id="z95tR4SwVx4N6fBpCkRfyQ" name="google-drive-gemini-side-panel-folder-summaries" alt="Google Drive is receiving a Gemini update that lets it summarize the contents of folder, documents, and more." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/z95tR4SwVx4N6fBpCkRfyQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="993" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Alternatively, users can right-click on a document in their list and click "Ask Gemini" for information that way. The side panel expands its uses by letting users drag and drop documents into it instead of the "@" mention method.</p><p>The update started rolling out on December 11 for users under rapid and scheduled release domains. Workspace customers with Gemini Business, Enterprise, Education, Education Premium, and Google One AI Premium add-ons will have access to Gemini in Drive's side panel for summarization.</p><p>Moreover, the company states users need to have "smart features and personalization" enabled before this feature is usable. Admins can turn this on by default for users if need be.</p><p>Gemini's capabilities across Workspace have consistently grown, especially through its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-docs-is-tapping-into-gemini-to-whip-up-formatted-documents">recent update for Docs</a>. The AI utilizes a prompt — "help me create" — which is reminiscent of its recent <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/google-home-gemini-help-me-create-public-preview">smart home test</a> for Google Home. Regardless, the Google Doc version lets the AI help users create formatted documents from scratch. The AI can also easily grab files from your Drive and incorporate them into a new file for you.</p><p>Elsewhere, Gmail picked up extra Gemini help via "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/gemini-in-gmail-contextual-smart-replies-workspace">contextual smart replies</a>." The update to its AI-generated replies will take into account what's been said in your current line of messages <em>before </em>offering a quick suggestion. Additionally, Google unveiled <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/googles-latest-ai-model-gemini-2-0-is-here-to-usher-in-the-agentic-era">Gemini 2.0</a> this week, which prepares to usher in a new "agentic era."</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/gemini-tl-dr-summaries-in-drive-update</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google detailed what Workspace Drive users can expect from its recent Gemini update. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">nJ3JusevKoZUa3rYBho2SQ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2QiuuNUyS4KYbeiDi5mTJJ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 19:25:29 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2QiuuNUyS4KYbeiDi5mTJJ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Drive web gets dark mode]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Drive web gets dark mode]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Home Public Preview lets you test 'Gemini in Assistant' on Nest devices ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google detailed its recent "Gemini in Assistant" test for the Public Preview program in the Home app.</li><li>Users will find "AI-powered" answers from the Assistant as it leverages Google's LLM for answers covering a wide range of topics.</li><li>This test is only available on the Nest Audio or Nest Mini (2nd gen) speakers.</li><li>Google recently kicked off another Public Preview test, which involves the "help me create" prompt.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google is giving users a way to test Gemini in its AI Assistant on a few Nest devices.</p><p>The company <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/assistant/answer/15713030">detailed</a> its recent Gemini addition to the Public Preview of the Google Home app in a support document (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/12/11/gemini-google-assistant-nest-mini-audio/">9to5Google</a>). In this test, Google states users will find "new, more natural sounding voices" when leveraging Gemini's help for queries. More importantly, the "AI-powered" answers the Assistant delivers will be enhanced by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini</a>.</p><p>Concerning the AI-powered replies, the support document states the Assistant piggybacks off an LLM (large language model) for more "in-depth" answers on general topics.</p><p>The page delivers a few examples such as ones where a user can "learn more about a topic." This involves a wide range of possibilities; however, Google gives the example of learning about animals and their communication methods and habits. Assistant's Gemini-enhanced capabiltiies bring follow-up questions into this Public Preview test.</p><p>After asking, Google says users can follow up with "Hey Google" to throw another query into the equation. Users can also "interrupt" the Assistant's responses by saying "Hey Google" to ask for additional context or to change your question.</p><p>If you're interested in this test, the post instructs users to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/googlenest/answer/12494697">join the Public Preview</a> via the Google Home app. However, access to this Gemini in Assistant test is being awarded to Nest Aware subscribers (for now). Users must also opt into the experimental AI features alongside having one of the eligible Nest devices for this Gemini in Assistant test: <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/nest-audio-review">Nest Audio</a> or Nest Mini (2nd Gen) speakers.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:59.75%;"><img id="SmfaTRfVfbFuLkXoRnhZBm" name="nest-audio-review-3.jpg" alt="Nest Audio" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SmfaTRfVfbFuLkXoRnhZBm.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="478" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Source: Daniel Bader / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Those new "natural sounding voices" can be customized by heading into the <strong>Google Home app > Settings > Google Assistant (icon) > Assistant Voices & Sounds</strong>.</p><p>The company explains that its AI-powered answers from the Assistant are experimental. Google realizes that its software could get things wrong, which is why it's urging users to take caution when receiving information.</p><p>Gemini's appearance in the Public Preview for Assistant accompanies another test involving the "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/google-home-gemini-help-me-create-public-preview">help me create</a>" prompt. The purpose of the test is to give users an easy way to quickly set up automation for their smart home devices. Through "help me create," users can instruct Gemini to turn their lights on at a specific time or during a specific occurrence, like if they leave the house.</p><p>Right now, this AI feature only works with Nest cameras; however, Google states it is looking to expand its device support.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/google-home-public-preview-gemini-in-assistant-test</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google kicked off a test involving "Gemini in Assistant" for Nest devices. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">FabpHKqbDpRoDxww8CTP9M</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mDW3Lj2XFWRt7LUWkSEosA.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 18:29:51 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Smart Home]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mDW3Lj2XFWRt7LUWkSEosA.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Nest Mini]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Nest Mini]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Y'all, Google might be in trouble. Then again, maybe not ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title"> Beyond the Alphabet</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="74uXEL5FbSyzjPgHM9K6b7" name="lloyd-beyond-the-alphabet2.png" caption="" alt="Android Central's LLoyd with a projection with a Google logo" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/74uXEL5FbSyzjPgHM9K6b7.png" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text"><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/beyond-the-alphabet">Beyond the Alphabet</a> is a weekly column that focuses on the tech world both inside and out of the confines of Mountain View.</p></div></div>
<p>Shortly after Apple released the third iOS 18.1 Developer Beta, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/magic-eraser-comparison-apple-samsung">I decided to see</a> how well the new "Clean Up" feature would stack up against Google's Magic Eraser and Samsung's Object Eraser. What I ended up with was a thing of nightmares when trying to remove the harness from my dog in a picture.</p><p>Samsung and Google both did a good job, but that didn't come as much of a surprise, given that these tools have been available <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">on various phones</a> for some time. Truthfully, I didn't think Apple's Clean Up would be a viable option and that it would just disappear into the night.</p>

<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2070px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="TspK8cw2ucPMRV64qWaxHQ" name="apple-intelligence-prompt-imore.jpg" alt="Apple Intelligence prompt on iPhone" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TspK8cw2ucPMRV64qWaxHQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2070" height="1164" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Future)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>As it turns out, the complete opposite happened, as the stable build of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/everything-ios-18-stole-from-android">iOS 18.2</a> arrived this week, packed with "Apple Intelligence" features. Hidden in the midst of the new AI features was an update to the Clean Up tool, which Apple has been apparently working hard to improve.</p><p>After being prodded a bit, the most obvious way to see if Clean Up is actually better was to try it on the same picture from before, using my <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/apple-iphone-16-pro-max-review">iPhone 16 Pro Max</a>. Much to my surprise, Apple didn't try to mutilate my dog, and the entire process was a lot easier than I expected.</p><p>Because we're working with smaller objects, there's a lot of room for error when making selections. But after loading the picture and tapping the "Clean Up" option, it was as simple as just tracing a line along the harness. The tool then highlighted exactly what I wanted to have removed before automatically doing just that.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1350px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:148.15%;"><img id="rqGfiZdZjTeTMeS3XsnN5V" name="leia-in-yard-before-edits-2" alt="Leia standing in yard with harness and lead before edits" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rqGfiZdZjTeTMeS3XsnN5V.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1350" height="2000" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="caption-text">Leia is standing in the yard with a harness and lead before edits. </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:894px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:142.84%;"><img id="oxeKbZtkt6fLe4kFsmK9og" name="clean-up-iphone-leia" alt="Apple Clean Up results using iPhone 16 Pro Max - Leia" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oxeKbZtkt6fLe4kFsmK9og.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="894" height="1277" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="caption-text">Apple Clean Up results using iPhone 16 Pro Max.  </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>The results were more impressive than I thought they would be, so I figured I would try using <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-use-magic-eraser-non-pixel-phones">Magic Eraser in Google Photos</a>. Seeing as it's been a few months since the last time I tried this out, surely Google would still come out on top, right?</p><p>Nope.</p><p>First, I tried using Google Photos on my iPhone since it has Magic Eraser. The results were less than stellar, and it took longer because I had to select the harness in sections. Eventually, I got there, but you can obviously see where the edits were made.</p><p>Then, I thought that I might get better results by using Magic Eraser on my <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-fold-review">Pixel 9 Pro Fold</a>. After transferring the full-resolution photo and opening it in Google Photos, somehow the results were worse. There's some weird line along my dog's back, and her ear is even more crooked than normal.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1320px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:121.44%;"><img id="mXf9QHiRzhU3pHtNvBmiqg" name="magic-eraser-iphone-leia" alt="Magic Eraser results using iPhone 16 Pro Max - Leia" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mXf9QHiRzhU3pHtNvBmiqg.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1320" height="1603" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="caption-text">Magic Eraser results using iPhone 16 Pro Max </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1018px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:122.89%;"><img id="f3jhoAqEkEA5zdafimLxog" name="magic-eraser-pixel-9-pro-fold-leia" alt="Magic Eraser results using Pixel 9 Pro Fold - Leia" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/f3jhoAqEkEA5zdafimLxog.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1018" height="1251" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="caption-text">Magic Eraser results using Pixel 9 Pro Fold </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Maybe it's just a fluke or something to do with this picture specifically. So, I did the next logical thing, picking a different picture before using Clean Up and Magic Eraser. This time, I opted for something that would probably be more common — removing people from the background.</p><p>I'm not sure if it's just something that I'm doing wrong or what. However, neither the iPhone's Clean Up nor the Pixel 9 Pro Fold's Magic Eraser did a particularly great job. Both results look <em>fine</em> until you start to zoom in and pixel-peep where the people were removed.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1753px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.30%;"><img id="YM9JxGdzuqUSEuodS5Dbng" name="apple-store-before-edits" alt="Apple Store photo before making any edits" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YM9JxGdzuqUSEuodS5Dbng.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1753" height="1320" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="caption-text">Apple Store photo before making any edits </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1755px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.16%;"><img id="swnXmUercEsY2vouecivmg" name="clean-up-apple-store-iphone-16-pro-max" alt="Apple Clean Up results using iPhone 16 Pro Max" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/swnXmUercEsY2vouecivmg.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1755" height="1319" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="caption-text">Apple Clean Up results using iPhone 16 Pro Max </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1434px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.31%;"><img id="xr25gQdy4XMpgRt7MhgZmg" name="magic-eraser-apple-store-pixel-9-pro-fold" alt="Magic Eraser results using Pixel 9 Pro Fold" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xr25gQdy4XMpgRt7MhgZmg.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1434" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="caption-text">Magic Eraser results using Pixel 9 Pro Fold </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>When I started writing this, I didn't really have much more to add, hence the first half of the title. But then I went back into Clean Up to make sure that it actually recognized the entire harness at once and that I wasn't just imagining things.</p><p>So I pulled up the picture of my dog again, confirmed that the harness was highlighted, and then was greeted with the following.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1320px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:217.27%;"><img id="L3QyAUes9f2ysAsVYMBbtg" name="safety-filter-leia-iphone" alt="Safety Filter applied after using Apple Clean Up on iPhone 16 Pro Max" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/L3QyAUes9f2ysAsVYMBbtg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1320" height="2868" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Imagine my confusion when Apple applied a "Safety Filter" to the picture when all I was trying to do was remove the harness. I tried it again, just to double-check, and again, the Safety Filter was applied.</p><p>I understand the idea and premise of such a feature — and yes, it's a feature, not a bug — but this is the same picture that I had already been editing before, and it's just my dog standing outside with her harness and lead attached. So, I'm not even sure of the logic taking place here.</p><p>On the one hand, I commend Apple for including the Safety Filter to begin with. On the other, why was it that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/one-ui-7-beta-could-be-just-around-the-corner-with-an-apple-intelligence-like-twist">Apple Intelligence</a> was able to properly edit the photo 10 minutes before, only to incorrectly apply the filter on the <em>same image</em>? It's left me genuinely perplexed, and all I can hope is that this isn't a regular occurrence.</p><p>That being said, even with the aforementioned hiccup, it's tough to argue with the results. In just a few months, Apple has made some pretty big improvements to its Clean Up feature. Now, I have to wonder whether Google will lean on Gemini to improve its own Magic Eraser or if Apple will end up surpassing it.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://shop-links.co/link?id=pcmcat1563302848653&publisher_slug=future&exclusive=1&u1=ac-us-1451575709806471814&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Ftop-deals%2Fcell-phone-deals%2Fpcmcat1563302848653.c%3Fid%3Dpcmcat1563302848653&article_name=Does%20it%20matter%20that%20the%20Galaxy%20Z%20Fold%206%20didn%27t%20get%20the%20One%20UI%207%20beta%3F&article_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.androidcentral.com%2Fphones%2Fdoes-it-matter-that-the-galaxy-z-fold-6-didnt-get-the-one-ui-7-beta" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1943169/565706/9383?subId1=ac-us-7714140852083009676&sharedId=ac-us&u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fcp%2Fcell-phones%2F1105910%3Fpovid%3Dweb_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://shop-links.co/link?publisher_slug=future&exclusive=1&u1=ac-us-6786630307046754082&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.samsung.com%2Fus%2Fshop%2Fall-deals%2Fcell-phone-deals%2F&article_name=Does%20it%20matter%20that%20the%20Galaxy%20Z%20Fold%206%20didn%27t%20get%20the%20One%20UI%207%20beta%3F&article_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.androidcentral.com%2Fphones%2Fdoes-it-matter-that-the-galaxy-z-fold-6-didnt-get-the-one-ui-7-beta" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://target.georiot.com/Proxy.ashx?tsid=169923&GR_URL=https%3A%2F%2Famazon.com%2Fs%3Fk%3Dcell%2Bphone%26crid%3D19CKV7OMEPEMF%26sprefix%3Dcell%2Bphone%252Caps%252C222%26ref%3Dnb_sb_noss_1%26tag%3Dhawk-future-20%26ascsubtag%3Dac-us-3781774120014141406-20" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-100048248-15733793?sid=ac-us-1249765278893072143&url=https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-100048248-15735111?sid=ac-us-4098939603681729428&url=https://www.att.com/" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/revisiting-apple-clean-up-vs-google-magic-eraser</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Apple finally released iOS 18.2 to the masses, bringing with it a bunch of new AI features. This update also promises major improvements to Apple's Magic Eraser competitor, so we put it to the test.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">d6VDRY2GKYjpwgTgjFL8u5</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/voRDNE9qQds8gvhTYmT6gM.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 17:47:13 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ andrew.myrick@futurenet.com (Andrew Myrick) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/voRDNE9qQds8gvhTYmT6gM.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Magic Eraser on Pixel 9 Pro Fold and Apple Clean Up on iPhone 16 Pro Max]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Magic Eraser on Pixel 9 Pro Fold and Apple Clean Up on iPhone 16 Pro Max]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>