<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 17:41:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Metro Awakening is the horror game I didn't know I needed ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">AC thVRsday</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="LGmZZrc8DWcxmZm6RRUYbC" name="ac-thvrsday-logo.jpg" caption="" alt="AC thVRsday logo" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LGmZZrc8DWcxmZm6RRUYbC.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">In his <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/ac-thvrsday">weekly column</a>, Android Central Senior Content Producer Nick Sutrich delves into all things VR, from new hardware to new games, upcoming technologies, and so much more.</p></div></div>
<p>Metro Awakening is the horror game I didn't know I needed. I say that because, first off, I'm not exactly a fan of the horror genre. I've enjoyed the occasional scary movie or game from time to time, but those are exceptions rather than the rule. I've also never really gotten into the Metro series despite enjoying the theme and the original release of Metro 2033.</p><p>But Metro Awakening is something special. It's a narrative-heavy, linear first-person shooter — just like the rest of the series — that had me hooked from the moment its clever intro began. It's also the first made-for-VR entry into the storied series, developed entirely by veteran VR developer Vertigo Games, the same company behind VR classics like Arizona Sunshine and After the Fall.</p><p>Despite being from a different developer, Metro Awakening feels incredibly similar to Metro 2033 in all the right ways. As the story goes, it takes place primarily in the metro train tunnels under a once great city, where you'll find yourself uncovering the horrors that both radioactivity and desperate humans created. It's easily one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-meta-quest-games">best Meta Quest games</a> I've ever played.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="b0c78fc9-725f-49a6-a9e0-119d3514fd9d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Meta Horizon Store" data-dimension48="Meta Horizon Store" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="47CzHCHRx5e6EyRwem7qkf" name="metro-awakening-art-1x1" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/47CzHCHRx5e6EyRwem7qkf.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1000" height="1000" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><em><strong>Metro Awakening</strong></em></p><p>It's not just the first made-for-VR entry into the storied Metro series, it's also the most personal tale yet in the post-apocalyptic universe.</p><p><strong>Buy now at</strong> <a href="https://www.meta.com/en-gb/experiences/metro-awakening-deluxe-edition/5096918017089406/" data-dimension112="b0c78fc9-725f-49a6-a9e0-119d3514fd9d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Meta Horizon Store" data-dimension48="Meta Horizon Store" data-dimension25="">Meta Horizon Store</a> | <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2669410/Metro_Awakening/">Steam</a> | <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/metro-awakening/?">PlayStation Store</a></p></div>
<h2 id="feeling-vertigo-2">Feeling Vertigo</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="WbduR3w9vMrRioWPXtvYP9" name="metro-awakening-official-screenshot-01" alt="An official screenshot of Metro Awakening" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WbduR3w9vMrRioWPXtvYP9.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Vertigo Games)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>If you've played the Arizona Sunshine games or After the Fall, you'll immediately feel familiar with the mechanics in Metro Awakening. That's not to say things are identical — the dual backpack-based inventory system is a clever new design I haven't seen yet — but everything that's good about the company's previous apocalyptic shooters sits on display for players to experience in Metro Awakening.</p><p>Intuitive on-body inventory systems, where you can consistently depend on grabbing the same item every time you reach for it, make them feel as good as a hot bar in a flat-screen game.</p><p>This is particularly important given the level of fear the game consistently holds you in, as you'll be able to make better split-second decisions because you won't be fumbling with an unreliable inventory system. Healing is always on your left hip, a pistol always on your right, and reaching into the pocket on your chest always delivers the proper ammo or refill for the weapon you're holding.</p><p>That is, of course, so long as you've been able to hold on to enough ammo to get you through the next section. One of Metro Awakening's biggest strengths is its consistent difficulty level, which is directly relative to how much ammo you're given between any of the game's encounters.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X3GOkKkAW7U" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>Metro Awakening's combat encounters are as often about taking the stealthy approach as they are about blindly shooting at unseen enemies like a character in one of Ridley Scott's Alien movies. Most encounters with humans give you the option to be stealthy — which I'll encourage you to use — in order to save up as much ammo for the next encounter as possible.</p><p>But every single encounter — even the ones that very obviously imply a stealthy approach is best — can be run through Rambo style. Enemies' weapons can be taken after they are downed, and while ammo in those weapons is always severely limited, they allow skilled players to hop from enemy to enemy and piggyback in creative ways. Cans and bottles can be brought from place to place and used to distract enemies, so you can use a stealthy melee attack to take them out.</p><p>Despite the game's linear nature, these moments significantly enhance the level design and overall game mechanics.</p>
<h2 id="variety-and-a-bit-of-half-life-2">Variety and a bit of half life</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="4nh5Xz5qTZA5iqAUsqokKD" name="metro-awakening-screenshot-01" alt="A screenshot of Metro Awakening taken on a Meta Quest 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4nh5Xz5qTZA5iqAUsqokKD.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>There was never a time in Metro Awakening's 12-hour campaign where I felt like I was repeating the same old situation over and over again. Each hallway, air vent, metro tunnel, or other space you walk through feels unique in a way that's rarely achieved outside of something as good as Metroid Prime. While this isn't a Metroidvania by any stretch of the imagination, the variety of locales and the compelling story kept me coming back to the game for more each day.</p><p>Metro Awakening has you playing the community's doctor whose eccentric wife seems to always cause problems. When she starts hearing the voice of your long-dead son in the steam pipes, you know something bad's about to happen. The rest of the journey will have you wondering if she's sane, prophetic, or maybe somewhere in between the two. Either way, you'll be venturing further than your character's hard past has ever gone before.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="gmSprtaPc7XWtkK2taHUJD" name="metro-awakening-screenshot-02" alt="A screenshot of Metro Awakening taken on a Meta Quest 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gmSprtaPc7XWtkK2taHUJD.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Since many parts of the world you'll explore are radioactive, you'll need to occasionally put on a gas mask and keep track of how effective its filter is working. Finding and swapping out filters will let you explore these areas more, often helping you find survival supplies and a few collectible items. If there's any replayability in the game, it's for folks who love to re-experience specific events or to find all three postcards hidden in each chapter.</p><p>Despite not being a big fan of the horror genre, the macabre scenes depicted constantly throughout the game were fascinating in a way I didn't expect. Likewise, the horrifying creatures that had me jumping and blindly shooting were always interesting to encounter, and I regularly tried to find creative ways to dispatch them before they got too close.</p><p>While I wouldn't put Metro Awakening in the same general category as a horror game like Wraith: The Oblivion - Afterlife, there's no denying the importance of horror to the story and the overall atmosphere of the game. Even if you're not a fan of horror like me, I'd encourage you to try it. The Meta Quest store has a 2-hour return window, anyway, and you'll definitely get the feeling of the game in the first 30 minutes, let alone two hours.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="NqiY5JXo7uvd3UMkoK36ND" name="metro-awakening-screenshot-03" alt="A screenshot of Metro Awakening taken on a Meta Quest 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NqiY5JXo7uvd3UMkoK36ND.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>If I had to name one specific critique of the Quest version of the game, it would be that I expected to see the game running at a higher resolution than it does. I used Quest Games Optimizer to boost the resolution to 130%, and it looked downright breathtaking at times, all without any noticeable performance hitches. Hopefully, Vertigo Games can patch in something like this soon.</p><p>The VR community has had its share of ups and downs with big releases this year, but this last quarter has proven to pack a serious punch that gives me high hopes for the future of big-name VR games. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/batman-arkham-shadow-review">Batman Arkham Shadow</a> sits firmly at the top as game of the year, although Metro Awakening has already making me question which title will get the crown at the end of the year.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="46304147-8487-4786-950b-ed752428bf5c">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fCUPHg8DY6xth6JoYMuDGK.jpg' alt="An official product render of the Meta Quest 3S with its controllers"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Meta Quest 3S</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>Get the power of a Meta Quest 3 in a more affordable package with the Meta Quest 3S, the new VR headset from Meta. Plus, get Batman Arkham Shadow and three months of Meta Quest Plus when you buy one before April 2025.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/metro-awakening-review</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The first made-for-VR entry into the Metro 2033 game series is spectacular and frightening in equal portions. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">WpvxBjDFh9dA8yYLteTHzV</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kV46qBfT2ngeVcc22e8j3S.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 17:15:04 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kV46qBfT2ngeVcc22e8j3S.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central / Nicholas Sutrich / Vertigo Games]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A version of official Metro Awakening artwork featuring me wearing a Meta Quest 3 headset]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A version of official Metro Awakening artwork featuring me wearing a Meta Quest 3 headset]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google TV Streamer vs. NVIDIA Shield TV Pro 2019: Two solid streaming options ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[         <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="6456acb2-27d7-43ee-81a7-740f5cee4941">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:62.40%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/J2dSa85Rv9TiAtBQzByTbe.jpg' alt="Google TV Streamer render"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google TV Streamer</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Mainstream choice</strong></em></p>
<p>The Google TV Streamer may not be as powerful as the Shield TV Pro, but it touts considerable upgrades over the Chromecast Ultra, making it a great choice if you need a new streaming box. The interface doesn't have any lag in regular use, it has useful smart home controls, and comes with an HDMI 2.1 port at the back. The best part is the pricing — at $100, it is a terrific value.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Interface doesn't lag</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Built-in smart home controls and Matter integration</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>HDMI 2.1 out</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Great pricing</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Not as powerful as Shield TV Pro</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Doesn't have as many ports at the back</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No Wi-Fi 6</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="9e1005ce-2520-47c7-9748-b0e34c0bf944">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:114.75%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/f9ayJkTKz8dvGKTVPrDGTh.jpg' alt="NVIDIA Shield TV Pro 2019 render"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">NVIDIA Shield TV Pro 2019</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Still the best</strong></em></p>
<p>I bought three units of the Shield TV Pro 2019, and use the streaming box exclusively in my house. It has the best hardware of any streaming device, and thanks to the generous port selection, you can easily attach external storage. It also has the best AI-assisted upscaling, and if you have SD or older content, it looks great on the Shield TV Pro. As it launched it 2019, it misses out on AV1 decode, but that's a problem only with YouTube, and even though it's significantly costlier, the Shield TV Pro is the one I'd pick.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Still the best overall hardware</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Best AI-assisted image upscaling</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Can easily add storage drives</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Regularly gets updates</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No HDR in YouTube videos</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Costlier</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<h2 id="google-tv-streamer-vs-nvidia-shield-tv-pro-design-2">Google TV Streamer vs. NVIDIA Shield TV Pro: Design</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="sGYY2bzm62rz3yor3NUark" name="google-tv-streamer-review-37.jpg" alt="Google TV Streamer with Pixel 9 Pro Fold and Android Figure" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sGYY2bzm62rz3yor3NUark.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/google-tv-streamer-review">Google TV Streamer</a> has a design that integrates well with the rest of Google&apos;s smart home portfolio, and while it is no longer a dongle — unlike the Chromecast Ultra — it isn&apos;t ungainly in the least.</p><p>The remote has a design that&apos;s similar, and it has the usual buttons — including a customizable button and a dedicated option to launch smart home control. There&apos;s a button at the back of the Google TV Streamer that lets you locate the remote should you lose it.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="gTkQPmNLcmH7o2TYag59YU" name="nvidia-shield-tv-pro-5.jpg" alt="NVIDIA Shield TV Pro against green background" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gTkQPmNLcmH7o2TYag59YU.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>By contrast, the design of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/nvidias-shield-tv-pro-is-still-the-best-streaming-device-in-2024">Shield TV Pro</a> is decidedly gamer-focused, and the black-and-green color scheme doesn&apos;t really mesh into the background nearly as well as Google&apos;s product. That said, I like the aggressive design of the Shield TV Pro, and it has LED lighting as well.</p><p>I also like the wedge-style Shield TV Pro remote. It has backlit buttons and a great in-hand feel, and it is built to last — the remote took dozens of tumbles in the last five years, and it is still going strong.</p>
<h2 id="google-tv-streamer-vs-nvidia-shield-tv-pro-software-2">Google TV Streamer vs. NVIDIA Shield TV Pro: Software</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="8aqE83KaBccoTGvsBYotTY" name="google-tv-streamer-review-custom-ai-art-1.jpg" alt="Google Gemini AI Screensaver options on Google TV Streamer" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8aqE83KaBccoTGvsBYotTY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Google TV Streamer comes with the latest Google TV build, and you get useful extras. There&apos;s a dedicated smart home hub — similar to the Google Home dashboard — that lets you control smart home devices, and view footage from any security cameras.</p><p>There are no issues in daily use either; the Google TV Streamer has a smooth interface with no noticeable lag. That&apos;s a big deal in and of itself, because most streaming boxes tend to be laggy at times. Thankfully, that just isn&apos;t an issue here.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="2aBaSEzPF8Lyx6K9LjRvNU" name="nvidia-shield-tv-pro-4.jpg" alt="NVIDIA Shield TV Pro against green background" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2aBaSEzPF8Lyx6K9LjRvNU.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Talking about no lag, the Shield TV Pro continues to set the standard in this category. Even though the hardware is old at this point, there&apos;s absolutely no lag or stutter in regular use, and the device still gets regular software updates with system tweaks.</p><p>That said, the Shield TV Pro is still on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/android-11-review">Android 11</a>, and it isn&apos;t likely to switch to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review">Android 14</a>-based Google TV. I see this as a good thing as it means I get the ability to disable the Google TV interface entirely and use the older Android TV skin, so this isn&apos;t an issue in my own use case.</p>
<h2 id="google-tv-streamer-vs-nvidia-shield-tv-pro-performance-2">Google TV Streamer vs. NVIDIA Shield TV Pro: Performance</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="MDPwVpKzcsN8sxueXDcnhN" name="google-tv-streamer-review-17.jpg" alt="Google TV Streamer with Android figure and remote" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MDPwVpKzcsN8sxueXDcnhN.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Google TV Streamer is powered by MediaTek&apos;s MT8696 platform, and it comes with 4GB of RAM and 32GB of storage. The increased memory and storage absolutely make a difference, and it&apos;s great to see Google make the sensible choice in this regard and not shortchange users.</p><p>You also get 4K playback with Dolby Vision, HDR10, HDR10+, and HLG. What I like is that the device has an HDMI 2.1 port at the back, and while you don&apos;t get any additional ports other than a USB-C power connector and Ethernet, you can add storage drives by using a USB-C hub.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="3aiKBJ35Kmd5QLGhiYzw5U" name="nvidia-shield-tv-pro-2.jpg" alt="NVIDIA Shield TV Pro against green background" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3aiKBJ35Kmd5QLGhiYzw5U.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Shield TV Pro continues to have the best hardware, with the Tegra platform still holding its own. You get two USB-A ports at the back as well, and an SD card slot on the side, so if you need an easy way to connect external storage, the Shield TV Pro is the obvious choice.</p><p>While the Google TV Streamer gets a lot right, it doesn&apos;t include Wi-Fi 6, and that&apos;s annoying. It isn&apos;t a huge deal as you still get a reliable signal, but Wi-Fi 6 has inherent advantages with latency and device congestion, and you miss out on those benefits.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="YFbWonPbQGcRNDiUx9v6jf" name="google-tv-streamer-with-usb-c-hub-2.jpg" alt="Google TV Streamer with DockCase USB-C Hub" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YFbWonPbQGcRNDiUx9v6jf.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>When it comes to daily use, both the Google TV Streamer and Shield TV Pro do a great job. There&apos;s no issue with HDR content or installing utilities like Plex, Kodi, and Jellyfin, and I prefer the Shield TV Pro as it allows me to stream games with relative ease.</p><p>The only quibble with the Shield TV Pro is that it doesn&apos;t have AV1, so you don&apos;t get HDR videos in YouTube. This isn&apos;t an issue with other streaming platforms, and as the Google TV Streamer is newer, it has the codec, so you don&apos;t miss out in this regard.</p>
<h2 id="google-tv-streamer-vs-nvidia-shield-tv-pro-which-should-you-buy-2">Google TV Streamer vs. NVIDIA Shield TV Pro: Which should you buy?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="L7wwsTMZVAYRdX4CE3cyDU" name="nvidia-shield-tv-pro-3.jpg" alt="NVIDIA Shield TV Pro against green background" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/L7wwsTMZVAYRdX4CE3cyDU.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>When you look at the $100 price, it&apos;s obvious that the Google TV Streamer is a terrific all-round product. It may not have some of the more advanced options, but as a mainstream Google TV Streamer, it absolutely nails the essentials.</p><p>The Shield TV Pro may be older, but it still costs $199, or twice as much as the Google TV Streamer. It has much better hardware, and if I had to pick one, I&apos;d go with the Shield TV Pro — it just does a better job catering to my usage needs. But if you need the best value, the Google TV streamer is almost as good, and that&apos;s an achievement.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="dd8d930b-c038-4594-95e2-a6b793fdb57e">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:62.40%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/J2dSa85Rv9TiAtBQzByTbe.jpg' alt="Google TV Streamer render"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google TV Streamer</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Mainstream choice</strong></em></p>
<p>The Google TV Streamer is a great choice if you need a reliable streaming solution that doesn't cost a lot of cash. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="1405ddc5-03ba-4a51-be2a-30e78d2e05ce">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:114.75%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/f9ayJkTKz8dvGKTVPrDGTh.jpg' alt="NVIDIA Shield TV Pro 2019 render"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">NVIDIA Shield TV Pro 2019</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Still the best</strong></em></p>
<p>The Shield TV Pro is still my go-to recommendation if you need a powerful streaming box. It may not have the latest codecs, but it still does a brilliant job in daily use. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/google-tv-streamer-vs-nvidia-shield-tv-pro-2019</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ NVIDIA's Shield TV Pro continues to be a terrific streaming device. Can Google dethrone the device with its alternative? Let's take a look.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">zcLMsX8ZYgJZvbZ4USCLNF</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3aiKBJ35Kmd5QLGhiYzw5U.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 15:40:03 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Streaming &amp; TV]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3aiKBJ35Kmd5QLGhiYzw5U.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[NVIDIA Shield TV Pro against green background]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[NVIDIA Shield TV Pro against green background]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Google Pixel 9 is a hit: Pixels earn double-digit market share for the first time  ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>According to research firm Statcounter, Google Pixel market share more than doubled in the span of a month.</li><li>The recent spike in Pixel market share can likely be attributed to the success of the Google Pixel 9 series.</li><li>Additionally, Counterpoint reports Google phone shipments increased 20% year-over-year  on the back of the Pixel 9 series.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9">Google Pixel 9 series</a>, which includes four phones at various price points, received rave reviews from the media when it launched in August. However, that isn't always indicative of how a lineup of flagship phones will resonate with consumers. A variety of factors can determine whether a phone is successful, even if the hardware and software are both excellent.</p><p>Well, a pair of reports from two research firms suggest that the Google Pixel 9 was a hit, however you look at it. Counterpoint Research's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.counterpointresearch.com/insight/post-insight-us-smartphone-sellin-down-4-yoy-in-q3-as-demand-remains-muted/" target="_blank">results</a> from the third quarter of 2024 revealed that Google smartphone shipments increased 20% year-over-year. For reference, the Pixel 9 series debuted nearly two months earlier in 2024 than the Pixel 8 series did in 2023. Google's shipments represented just four percent of phones shipped overall in Q3 2024.</p><p>“The Pixel 9 series had a staggard launch this year starting at the end of August with the Pixel 9 and 9 Pro XL, followed by the 9 Pro and 9 Pro Fold in the beginning of September," said Maurice Klaehne, a senior analyst at Counterpoint, in a press release. "We expect GenAI smartphones to perform well in Q4 as more software updates for both iOS and Android get released.”</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="LHz4r4kjv3nPsuHeqarvFP" name="google-pixel-9-pro-xl-1.jpg" alt="Pixel 9 Pro XL back view against colorful background" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LHz4r4kjv3nPsuHeqarvFP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Counterpoint also revealed that the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/pixel-9-pro-xl-two-months-later">Pixel 9 Pro XL</a>, the biggest of Google's new flagships, was in the top ten of the best-selling premium phones in Q3 2024.</p><p>However, it's Statcounter's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://gs.statcounter.com/vendor-market-share/mobile/north-america" target="_blank">market share figures</a> from October 2024 that give us a better idea of how the Pixel 9 series is performing. Google's mobile vendor market share in North America is 12.4% as of October 2024, which is the first time the company's smartphone market share crossed into double-digit territory. More importantly, it spiked from 4.76% in September 2024 to 12.4% in October 2024. That kind of jump in the span of a month signals that the Pixel 9 series is finding immense success.</p><p>Google's apparent winner in the Pixel 9 is great news for Android as a whole. There is growing skepticism that Samsung, which <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/is-samsung-sorry-for-failing-to-innovate-or-just-sorry-sales-are-down">recently apologized for failing to innovate</a>, can disrupt Apple's stronghold on the premium phone market in North America. The market share spike Google earned last month could be a reason for optimism that it, not Samsung, can challenge the iPhone.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="dcbbf8d8-fd3e-4172-ba00-34e6eaec005d">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tnQGJNQVqF2XVQV4KfMbN8.jpg' alt="google pixel 9 square render"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>The Google Pixel 9 is an excellent Android smartphone with plenty of AI features, and it's flying off the shelves, according to two new reports.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-google-pixel-9-is-a-hit-pixels-earn-double-digit-market-share-for-the-first-time</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google Pixel, a brand that got a late start to the smartphone raced and has struggled to take off, seems to have found success. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">hdsr9qHg2iKEWzDSZ4bQtF</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kpwXQ7avAaS9vB9H8gVcVP.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 15:31:31 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kpwXQ7avAaS9vB9H8gVcVP.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro XL beside Pixel 8 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro XL beside Pixel 8 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google's testing a conversational search feature that updates results in real time ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google is working on a conversational version of Google Search that will refresh results in real time as you speak.</li><li>The unreleased update was shared by Android tinkerer AssembleDebug on X (formerly Twitter), and brings Google Search functionality closer to Gemini Live.</li><li>This new way of searching could feel more natural to modern users familiar with voice assistants and chatbots, and might be best suited for mobile.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google is increasingly testing ways to shift its strategy with Google Search, the company's main moneymaker, to match consumer trends. Thanks to the emergence of voice assistants and AI chatbots, people don't have to turn to Google Search as often as they may have in the past. This could have a negative effect on two of Google's primary businesses: Search and Ads.</p><p>According to avid Android tinkerer <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/AssembleDebug/status/1853461439022760220" target="_blank">AssembleDebug on X (formerly Twitter)</a>, Google is testing a voice search mode that will refresh results in real time. As you continue to talk with the Google app, the results page will adjust based on your conversation. The functionality appears to be similar to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/gemini-live-pixel-9-pro-grocery-list">Gemini Live</a> and Meta AI, but specifically for web results.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">The demo of new conversational search in Google app. It continuosly listens to your voice where you can ask followup questions while performing a search.#Android #Google pic.twitter.com/DgXnMx5DU4<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1853461439022760220">November 4, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>You can already use your voice to search Google; however, it is limited to individual queries. Tapping the microphone icon in the Google app calls up a voice-to-text visualizer, just like the one showcased in the AssembleDebug tweet. But after you finish speaking, Google will fetch your search results and the conversation ends there.</p><p>You can use the voice search option again, of course, but the experience isn't continuous. Meanwhile, Google's own Gemini Live experience and Meta's conversational mode on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/ray-ban-meta-smart-glasses-review">Ray-Ban Meta glasses</a> provide a more streamlined way of communicating.</p><p>The sample screen recording provided by AssembleDebug showcases how the experimental conversational mode allows users to ask follow-up questions using their voice. For example, someone could ask for the names of members of a band and subsequently ask when the band was formed, all without needing to start the search from scratch.</p><p>This feature isn't publicly available yet, and we don't have a timeline for when (or if) conversational search in the Google app will release publicly. Considering that Google already offers conversational speech support with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-gemini-app-android">Gemini </a>and its smart devices, matching that functionality in Search would be a natural next step.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/googles-testing-a-conversational-search-feature-that-updates-results-in-real-time</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google's latest experiment is to make Search more like a conversational voice assistant. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">gSz6cuFExCESmzKHEqL3vg</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/o9PEwKZCbvXt6TEUKSTMr.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 15:14:57 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/o9PEwKZCbvXt6TEUKSTMr.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Pixel 8a]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Pixel 8a]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google's Pixel November update squashes the first round of Android 15 bugs ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google is beginning to roll out the November 2024 update for Pixel phones running Android 15, which will continue over the next week in a phased rollout.</li><li>Pixel 6 and newer phones running Android 15 are eligible; however, rollout timeline can vary based on your carrier and device model.</li><li>Additionally, the November 2024 update includes three patches for security vulnerabilities with a severity level of "High," according to Google.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Starting today, Nov. 6, Google is beginning to issue the first <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a> update for Pixel phones. The November 2024 update is available for Google Pixel 6 and newer devices and will continue to rollout over the next week. The exact timeline an vary based on your carrier and device model, but you can check if your Pixel phone has received the November 2024 patch now. Since the update includes critical security fixes, it's important to update your phone to the November 2024 version of Android 15 as soon as possible.</p><p>The update will only be available for users who have already <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/9-android-15-features-you-should-check-out">updated their devices to Android 15</a>. If you aren't seeing it, make sure your device isn't still running a version of Android 14. Google lists the full breakdown of versions for each supported device model on a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/pixelphone/thread/305744117/google-pixel-update-november-2024?hl=en&sjid=11128271663939068219-NC" target="_blank">support page</a>:</p>
<ul><li>Pixel 6:                  AP3A.241105.007</li><li>Pixel 6 Pro:           AP3A.241105.007</li><li>Pixel 6a:                AP3A.241105.007</li><li>Pixel 7:                  AP3A.241105.007</li><li>Pixel 7 Pro:           AP3A.241105.007</li><li>Pixel 7a:                AP3A.241105.007</li><li>Pixel Tablet:         AP3A.241105.007</li><li>Pixel Fold:            AP3A.241105.007</li><li>Pixel 8:                 AP3A.241105.007</li><li>Pixel 8 Pro:          AP3A.241105.007</li><li>Pixel 8a:               AP3A.241105.007</li><li>Pixel 9:                 AP3A.241105.008</li><li>Pixel 9 Pro:          AP3A.241105.008</li><li>Pixel 9 Pro XL:    AP3A.241105.008</li><li>Pixel 9 Pro Fold: AP3A.241105.008</li></ul>
<p>The update doesn't include any new features, and is rather intended to fix the initial set of Android 15 bugs. Specifically, the update will fix a few issues plaguing the new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9">Pixel 9 series</a>. One problem that caused a strange tilting effect while recording video and zooming between cameras has been resolved with this patch.</p><p>Additionally, a bug limiting Bluetooth range in certain situations was fixed. A few issues with the display and Adaptive Brightness are now corrected. Finally, a bug that caused pressing the dismiss keyboard button to not work as expected is resolved.</p><p>Those are just the bug fixes for the Pixel 9, Pixel 9 Pro, Pixel 9 Pro XL, and Pixel 9 Pro Fold. There are a few more that cover all Pixel devices eligible for the November 2024 update, which Google vaguely describes as "general improvements for performance and stability in certain UI transitions and animations."</p><p>Pixel 8a users will be happy to know that a problem causing the display brightness to flicker under certain conditions is resolved, too. This issue only affected the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-review">Google Pixel 8a</a>, the company says.</p><p>More importantly, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://source.android.com/docs/security/bulletin/pixel/2024-11-01" target="_blank">Pixel Security Bulletin</a> for November reveals that this patch includes three fixes for security vulnerabilities with a "High" severity level. These are tracked as CVE-2024-47038, CVE-2024-47040, and CVE-2024-47039. Due to the security contents of this update, we recommend applying it as soon as it becomes available for your Pixel 6 or newer device.</p><p>To check if your device has received the Pixel November 2024 update, open the <strong>Settings app</strong> and tap <strong>System</strong>. Then, press <strong>Software update</strong> and tap <strong>System update</strong>. You can press <strong>Check for update</strong> in the bottom right corner of the screen to force your device to refresh. Once the update appears, follow the on-screen prompts to install and apply it.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/googles-pixel-november-update-squashes-the-first-round-of-android-15-bugs</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Having a few problems with Android 15 on your Pixel? Google's latest November 2024 update might help. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">AZSBPxWk3XjTWRKkCXrEZk</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/C7zTvtoXoCMSCMi5d4u3n3.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 15:10:53 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/C7zTvtoXoCMSCMi5d4u3n3.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android 15 Easter egg on Pixel 9 Pro XL, Pixel 9, and Pixel 9 Pro Fold]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android 15 Easter egg on Pixel 9 Pro XL, Pixel 9, and Pixel 9 Pro Fold]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The OnePlus 12 is now getting the stable Android 15 update ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>OnePlus fast-tracked the stable Android 15 release for the OnePlus 12, skipping the beta phase in some areas like North America.</li><li>OxygenOS 15 brings AI-powered features, smoother animations, and the Open Canvas feature, which was previously exclusive to the OnePlus Open.</li><li>New AI features are still being tested and will be released gradually throughout November.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>OnePlus has officially launched the stable OxygenOS 15 update, and it's now being rolled out globally to OnePlus 12 devices.</p><p>The OEM has surprisingly fast-tracked the OxygenOS 15 rollout for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12-review">OnePlus 12</a> devices across multiple regions, including North America, India, and Europe. This quick release follows the recent <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/oneplus-releases-android-15-based-oxygenos-15-heres-when-your-phone-will-get-the-update">launch of the Open Beta program in several markets</a>, with some areas like North America skipping the beta phase altogether.</p><p>OnePlus has admitted that the early launch of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a> update may have been influenced by competition, with other <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phones</a> getting the same treatment more quickly than before. The company confirmed that the update will be rolled out to users in phases over the course of the week.</p><p>Android 15-based OxygenOS 15 brings a host of AI-powered features and smoother animations. One standout addition is the Open Canvas feature, which was previously only available on the OnePlus Open.</p><p>Although OxygenOS 15 brings plenty of improvements, OnePlus has noted that new AI features are still being worked on. These are in testing now and will be gradually rolled out to users throughout November.</p><p>While the AI features aren’t in this first release, OxygenOS 15 still <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/i-used-oxygenos-15-for-a-week-these-are-my-favorite-features">packs plenty of cool new features and upgrades</a>. For example, updated icons and rounded corners bring sharper, cleaner visuals to the Home screen and system.</p><p>Furthermore, there are new, customizable themes with fluid animations across your Home screen, Lock screen, and Always-On Display. Plus, new gestures make multitasking easier with resizable windows and intuitive controls.</p><p>Charging limit also keeps your battery at 80% to help it last longer, with reminders for protection. Holo Audio improves sound quality for online calls and meetings.</p><p>The centralized safety hub and organized Private Safe provides easier access to personal data and apps. Overall, OxygenOS 15 is all about smooth visuals, better multitasking, and personalizing your device. You can view the full changelog on OnePlus' <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://community.oneplus.com/thread/1723669843116294150" target="_blank">website</a>.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-oneplus-12-is-now-getting-the-stable-android-15-update</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Stable Android 15 arrives on the OnePlus 12, but not without a hitch. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">NknDYqGig3v5sowWEEh2cG</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5YihoisE3ixZ3LsaxmhxfG.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 09:18:22 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5YihoisE3ixZ3LsaxmhxfG.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus 12 camera island with light reflection]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus 12 camera island with light reflection]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ A 'mini' version of the OPPO Find X8 could be in the works ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>OPPO might be adding a compact "Mini" model to its Find X8 series, which recently launched in China.</li><li>Known leaker Digital Chat Station hinted that both the Find X8 Mini and a premium Find X8 Ultra could be on the way.</li><li>While details on the Mini's screen size are under wraps, it’ll likely have a smaller battery than the 6.59-inch Find X8’s 5630mAh capacity.</li><li>The Ultra is expected to go global, but it’s uncertain if the Mini will be available outside China.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Rumor has it that OPPO might be expanding its flagship Find X8 lineup with a new compact model. This possible addition would join the standard Find X8 and the high-end Find X8 Pro, both of which just <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-wait-is-over-oppos-find-x8-and-x8-pro-are-launching-globally">launched in China last month</a>.</p><p>Well-known leaker Digital Chat Station has claimed on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://m.weibo.cn/detail/5095939679191523" target="_blank">Weibo</a> that we might see an OPPO Find X8 "Mini" soon, possibly alongside the anticipated Find X8 Ultra (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.smartprix.com/bytes/oppo-hasnt-shelfed-plans-for-a-mini-flagship-find-x8-mini-could-arrive-in-2025-tipster/" target="_blank">Smartprix</a>). While it’s still unconfirmed, Digital Chat Station’s solid track record with leaks gives this rumor some weight.</p><p>While the prospect of a "small screen flagship" (machine-translated) is enticing, specific details regarding its screen size are yet to be revealed.</p><p>The tipster hasn't shared any specs, and OPPO hasn't officially confirmed either the Find X8 Ultra or the Find X8 Mini. If these models do come out, they’ll join OPPO's newest contenders to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">leading Android phones</a> out there, rounding out the lineup to four models.</p><p>Vivo, OPPO’s sister brand under BBK, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/vivo-takes-things-to-a-whole-new-level-with-the-x200-series">recently launched a compact flagship</a> with a 6.31-inch display and a light 187g design. In contrast, the standard Find X8 packs a bigger 6.59-inch screen and a 5630mAh battery. With these specs in mind, it’s likely that the rumored Find X8 Mini will come with a somewhat smaller battery.</p><p>On the other hand, the Find X8 Ultra is expected to sport a dual periscope telephoto setup with tweaked focal lengths, allowing for up to 10x hybrid zoom.</p><p>OPPO has a habit of saving its Ultra models for after the main flagship launch, a move that’s done wonders for the Find series. The Find X8 Ultra is likely to arrive between December and January, and if the rumors of a smaller ‘Mini’ version hold true, we could be in for an unexpected addition to the lineup.</p><p>It’s still unclear if this compact flagship will go global or stay exclusive to China. Meanwhile, the Find X8 Ultra is expected to get a broader international launch.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/a-mini-version-of-the-oppo-find-x8-could-be-in-the-works</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ OPPO's Find X8 family could grow with a compact addition. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">CCQ4dGN7rjRJLdLowvNKKo</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hUSavqmWDbuwQHdeJnAj9m.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 07:46:21 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hUSavqmWDbuwQHdeJnAj9m.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OPPO Find X7 Ultra review]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OPPO Find X7 Ultra review]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Qualcomm reports $10.2B in FY Q4 revenue thanks to strong headset sales, automotive push ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Qualcomm announced its fiscal year Q4 2024 revenue with $10.2 billion for the quarter.</li><li>Mobile chipset sales increased by 12%, while automotive grew an impressive 68% compared to the same quarter in 2023.</li><li>Qualcomm just launched the Snapdragon 8 Elite, which is already landing in new smartphones from Xiaomi, OPPO, OnePlus, and more.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Qualcomm is ending its 2024 fiscal year on a high note, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://investor.qualcomm.com/files/doc_financials/2024/q4/FY2024-4th-Quarter-Earnings-Release.pdf">reporting</a> a 12% growth in Q4 revenue to $10.2 billion. That brings its total 2024 revenue to $39 billion, up 9% compared to fiscal year 2023.</p><p>“We are pleased to conclude the fiscal year with strong results in the fourth quarter, delivering greater than 30% year-over-year growth in EPS,” said Qualcomm CEO Cristiano Amon in a prepared statement.</p><p>“We are excited about our recent product announcements at Snapdragon Summit and Embedded World, as they continue to extend our technology leadership and position us well across Handsets, PC, Automotive and Industrial IoT. We look forward to providing an update on our growth and diversification initiatives at our Investor Day on November 19.”</p><p>Throughout the quarter, Qualcomm saw the launch of several flagship Android phones utilizing its last-gen flagship chipset, including the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-6-review">Galaxy Z Flip 6</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Galaxy Z Fold 6</a>, and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2024-review">Razr Plus 2024</a>. Amazon's first Prime Day sales event also likely contributed to impressive headset sales during the quarter.</p><p>Qualcomm has also pushed heavily in other markets, with its automotive solutions seeing an impressive 68% uptick in revenue and expectations that it will continue to grow in 2025, particularly with the new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/qualcomm-announces-snapdragon-cockpit-elite-ride-elite-for-ai-in-cars">Cockpit Elite</a>. During the earnings call on Wednesday, Amon further highlighted the company's efforts in AR/VR and partnership with Meta, with the recent launch of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-3s-review">Quest 3S</a> seen as an "important milestone in increasing the scale of this opportunity."</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2610px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="rRUXiFcY6iXrsZAHShZKPR" name="Snapdragon-8-Elite-Gaming" alt="A photo showing a gaming phone with the Snapdragon 8 Elite logo hovering above it" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rRUXiFcY6iXrsZAHShZKPR.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2610" height="1468" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Qualcomm)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>With the recently unveiled <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/snapdragon-8-elite">Snapdragon 8 Elite</a>, Qualcomm already feels well-poised for a better 2025, with Android OEMs already unveiling their latest flagship powered by the chip.</p><p>"We are extremely pleased with this Snapdragon 8 Elite design traction with successful launches at Xiaomi, Honor, OPPO, and Vivo," Amon said during the call.</p><p>Qualcomm CFO Akash Palkhiwala noted that this will have a positive impact on the company's FY Q1 revenue. He expects year-over-year headset growth, thanks to "greater than 40% sequential revenue growth from Chinese OEM and the acceleration of flagship Android handset launches," particularly phones adopting the Snapdragon 8 Elite.</p><p>Amon also highlighted upcoming launches from ASUS and Samsung. The latter has been rumored to be considering adopting its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-models-to-opt-for-flagship-exynos-soc-again">Exynos chips for some Galaxy S25 models</a>. That said, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25">Galaxy S25</a> is not expected to launch until Qualcomm's FY Q2, which could help boost sales following the holiday season, although that could also depend on the share of Snapdragon-powered models.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-fy-q4-2024-earnings</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Qualcomm's yearly revenue has increased by 9%, closing in on $40 billion. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">dRBaFkuGMqe69qDWEPs3uf</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TZk2Z8sFDhzmSjwRii4wCS.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 21:56:02 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ derrek.lee@futurenet.com (Derrek Lee) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TZk2Z8sFDhzmSjwRii4wCS.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Qualcomm logo at MWC 2024]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Qualcomm logo at MWC 2024]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Play Protect's new feature tipped to remove the worry about side-loading apps ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-32">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The latest APK teardown of the Google Play Protect app has revealed a temporary pause button that could venture soon.</li><li>Users who side-load apps and generally turn off Play Protect to do so can now have a temporary time frame.</li><li>The upcoming feature would enable Play Protect feature after a day even users disable it for side loading of apps.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google Play Protect on Android phones plays a significant role in preventing malicious apps from being installed. According to its latest app findings, the tool might be getting a nifty upgrade for additional security.</p><p>Folks at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/google-play-protect-pause-3496795/">Android Authority</a> have managed to perform an APK investigation of the Google Play Store app version <strong>43.4.23-31</strong>, which revealed interesting changes coming to the app.</p><p>For starters, Play Protect is essential to safe-check Android apps that are being installed on your phones. However, while side-loading apps, it needs to be disabled momentarily as it can obstruct the third-party app installation.</p>
<p>Users can turn on Play Protect through their phone settings after installing the side-loaded apps. However, those who tend to forget might be at risk from malicious apps that can unknowingly get installed and cause problems. To fix this, the latest APK findings reveal that Google might be bringing a temporary pause option for the Play Protect feature on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phones</a>.</p><p>Per the screenshot shared by the publication, the Google Play Protect feature now has a new “Pause” button right next to “Turn off,” which was the only option for users earlier. Once the feature rolls out, it would likely be very handy for users to enable this option, who often install third-party or side-load apps without worrying about malware getting installed later.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:270px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:222.22%;"><img id="ptoC58i7RyvUUZVbwnq7Kc" name="New-Pause-Play-Protect-button" alt="Google Play Protect Pause button" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ptoC58i7RyvUUZVbwnq7Kc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="270" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>“When paused, Play Protect will no longer scan apps available outside of Google Play for malware. Play Protect will automatically turn on again the next day.”</p><p>It is still unclear if the timeframe for pausing the feature will increase later, yet having an option is still a plus, to say the least. Since it is found in the testing phase, the rollout might be soon for all Android devices, or the company could entirely skip it, as pausing the feature even for the suggested timeframe might still put the devices at risk from malicious apps during that period.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-play-protect-could-be-put-on-a-temporary-pause-in-future</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Google Play Protect feature is essential on your Android phone as it blocks malicious apps. The new feature in testing might ease things a bit. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">uRyrZymGHjQa6d9XwRcoae</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JtT6RUBnjWdpzsRzAkLpwS.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 20:52:49 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JtT6RUBnjWdpzsRzAkLpwS.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Pixel 9 Pro XL home page showing icons]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Pixel 9 Pro XL home page showing icons]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Galaxy S25 'Slim' might've made a cameo in an early database listing ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-37">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung's Galaxy S25 "Slim" might've appeared in a recent database listing.</li><li>The device is reportedly named "SM-S937U" and the "U" tag may indicate a device aimed at the U.S. market.</li><li>This "slim" variant was rumored to debut in Q2 2025 with a 6.7-inch dynamic AMOLED display and MediaTek's powerful Dimensity 9400 SoC.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Speculation of a "slim" Galaxy S25 continues to swirl as a recent finding might hold enough evidence to solidify its existence.</p><p>The alleged model number of Samsung's rumored Galaxy S25 "Slim" was discovered in a database by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.smartprix.com/bytes/samsungs-mysterious-galaxy-s25-slim-smartphone-officially-spotted-for-first-time/">SmartPrix</a>. According to the publication, the thinner device was supposedly given model number "SM-S937U." This number fits the recent discovery of the Galaxy S25 model names. A <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-plus-discontinued-rumors">previous database listing</a> showcased SM-S931, SM-S936, and SM-S938 for the Galaxy S25, S25 Plus, and S25 Ultra.</p><p>With the model numbers appearing so similar, it seems almost certain that this is the fourth S25 phone we've been hearing about.</p><p>More importantly, the publication notes that this particular number with the "U" tag indicates the U.S. version.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1288px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:24.46%;"><img id="znpXiHZmPezkAwensrfB2e" name="samsung-galaxy-s25-slim-rumored-model-number" alt="The supposed model number of the Galaxy S25 "Slim" has reportedly appeared in a database listing." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/znpXiHZmPezkAwensrfB2e.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1288" height="315" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: SmartPrix)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>A Korean <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/a-slim-galaxy-s25-might-be-samsungs-answer-to-apples-rumored-thin-iphone-17">report surfaced</a> at the beginning of November, doubling down on the chance for a "Galaxy S25 Slim." The device is expected to be "thinner" than the rest of the upcoming S25 cast and battle against Apple's rumored iPhone 17 "Air." It's still too early to tell <em>how </em>thin Samsung's phone will be, but what's clear is that it would need to arrive somewhere under the S24's 7.6mm measurement.</p><p>Additionally, the report claimed Samsung will launch the "Slim" phone in Q2 2025. The flagship trio is expected to drop in January or February, but a Q2 theory for the thinner device could put it anywhere from April to June.</p><p>SmartPrix states that Samsung's past behavior indicates that it typically places new devices (model numbers) in the GSMA database "six to seven months" before release. With that, the rumored Q2 release might be true, but take this with a grain of salt.</p><p>Of course, rumors of a "Slim" instead of a "Galaxy S25 FE" <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/sasmung-galaxy-s25-fe-could-be-called-s25-slim">started in October</a>. It was theorized that Samsung decided to shift gears with branding as it looks to debut a phone with a thinner form factor. Additional rumors state the device could launch with a 6.7-inch dynamic AMOLED display and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/mediateks-dimensity-9400-is-the-biggest-challenger-to-qualcomm-yet">MediaTek Dimensity 9400</a> SoC.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-s25-slim-early-database-listing-appearance</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Galaxy S25 "Slim" reportedly appeared in a database listing. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">2pXYVF5KhSq54VTgz6UR8T</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/G2jTwQ3PkYe4RjaFE8FhMm.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 20:45:56 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/G2jTwQ3PkYe4RjaFE8FhMm.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Looking at the different colorways of the Samsung Galaxy S24]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Looking at the different colorways of the Samsung Galaxy S24]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>