<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 00:30:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Calendar is adding new chips to make hopping between months a breeze ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google Calendar's Android app now includes a dropdown menu beneath the current month's view, offering quick access to navigation chips for seamless month switching.</li><li>Users can preview up to four months ahead and easily scroll left or right to select a desired month.</li><li>Despite being part of a specific app version, the update is likely rolled out server-side, ensuring widespread availability.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google Calendar just ironed out a pesky little annoyance we&apos;ve often faced when planning months ahead. The Android app now makes switching between months a breeze with new navigation chips.</p><p>On one of our devices with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-calendar">Google Calendar</a> (version 2024.13.1-624115131-release) installed, there&apos;s a new dropdown below the current month&apos;s view. Tapping on it brings up a row of chips that allow you to jump between months on the go.</p><p>You can check out about four months ahead (but it might vary based on how big your screen is), and you can scroll left or right to pick a month quickly, whether it&apos;s in the future or the past.</p><p>The change was first spotted by former Android Police editor Manuel Vonau, who noticed these chips in the Schedule view on the app (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/04/24/google-calendar-months-chips-android-update/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a>). You can find them snugly nestled between the monthly calendar and the agenda list. The same is true for the <em>Day </em>and <em>Week </em>views.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Google Calendar just added month chips for me below the month section in the agenda view 👀 I bet it's server-side, but I'm on version 2024.13.1-624115131-release pic.twitter.com/xbZ1hYKxlw<a href="https://twitter.com/ManuelVonau/status/1783200919208812982">April 24, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>As you can see in the screenshots below, the chips do take up a bit of space in those views, but it&apos;s not really a big deal given how small they are. Meanwhile, the chips are located right above the dates in the <em>Month </em>view.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:590px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:127.12%;"><img id="ZVWdtF7SaZJ3fhUqqfci2J" name="Google-Calendar-months-chips.jpg" alt="Google Calendar navigation chips" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZVWdtF7SaZJ3fhUqqfci2J.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="590" height="750" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Jay Bonggolto / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="ocswXzrvrzGLCZ9Lazz9sH" name="Google-Calendar-months-chips-agenda-view.jpg" alt="Google Calendar navigation chips" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ocswXzrvrzGLCZ9Lazz9sH.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="600" height="750" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Jay Bonggolto / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:580px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:129.31%;"><img id="m5yR3j8tvNCiLJDpkyqhkH" name="Google-Calendar-months-chips-week-view.jpg" alt="Google Calendar navigation chips" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/m5yR3j8tvNCiLJDpkyqhkH.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="580" height="750" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Jay Bonggolto / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>This new bar seems to let you scroll all the way ahead, so you can zoom into the future by years, or even decades, in a flash.</p><p>While the feature is present in version 2024.13.1-624115131-release, Vonau points out that it&apos;s likely a server-side update.</p><p>The Calendar app already lets you swipe left and right to move through the months, but these new chips make it way easier to hop to a particular month.</p><p>Chips <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google/google-unveils-update-to-ai-chip">play a big role in the Android experience</a>. Some, like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-workspace-material-design-smart-chips">smart chips on Sheets</a> and other <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/everything-you-need-know-about-google-workspace-spaces-and-smart-canvas">Google Workspace</a> apps, pack a punch. Then there are search chips, which <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-drive-search-chips-beta-testing">landed on apps like Google Drive not too long ago</a>, helping users find their files in a flash.</p><p>With these fresh chips popping up in Calendar, it&apos;s clear Google has a ton of options for using chips in its ecosystem.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-calendar-is-adding-new-chips-to-make-hopping-between-months-a-breeze</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google Calendar is getting a handy update for switching between months in a jiffy. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">vmmh6sxdWQh6scLorZDBMT</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/iNuANvV6bCvn3D8Md52mLZ.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 00:16:57 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/iNuANvV6bCvn3D8Md52mLZ.jpeg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Calendar app on an Android phone]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Calendar app on an Android phone]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Meta Q1 2024 earnings highlight AI focus amid strong Quest sales ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Meta announces Q1 2024 earnings, topping estimates amid warnings of a lighter Q2.</li><li>Revenue for Meta's Family of Apps increased to more than $17 billion, while Reality Labs losses shrunk slightly to $3.8 billion.</li><li>Sales of Quest headsets helped increase Reality Labs revenue by 30%, despite overall losses.</li><li>Meta recently made several large announcements related to AI and its new Ray-Ban smart glasses.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>After a rather exciting week for the company, Meta announced its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://investor.fb.com/investor-news/press-release-details/2024/Meta-Reports-First-Quarter-2024-Results/default.aspx">Q1 2024 financial earnings</a> on Wednesday, revealing rather impressive numbers despite a worrying forecast. Revenue was up year over year to $36.45 billion, led mostly by Meta&apos;s Family of Apps and increased ad spend. However, VR also played a role, thanks to improved Quest sales.</p><p>Reality Labs, Meta&apos;s division focused on VR and AR, was up by 30% as a result of sales of its VR headsets like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-3-review">Quest 3</a>, despite continuing to bleed cash. The division lost more than $3.8 billion during the quarter as the company continues to invest in its platform. Just this past week, Meta announced that it is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-horizon-os-announced-for-3rd-party-quest-headsets-xbox-asus-lenovo">expanding the Meta Horizon OS</a> to third-party headsets, which should not only expand the company&apos;s offerings but open it up to more types of headsets.</p><p>We expect to see headsets from companies like Lenovo and ASUS ROG, and there will even be an Xbox-inspired headset.</p><p>"I think that our first-party Quest devices will continue to be the most popular headsets, as we see today," Meta CEO Mark Zuckerberg said during the earnings call. "And we&apos;ll continue focusing on advancing the state-of-the-art tech and then making it accessible to everyone, but I also think that opening our ecosystem and opening our operating system will help the overall mixed reality ecosystem grow even faster."</p><p>But beyond VR, Meta has also increased its investments in AI, which is an area the company hopes will expand throughout its products. Recently, Meta announced its improved <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/meta-ai-apps-llama-3-launch">Llama 3 model</a>, which can now be accessed via Meta AI on apps such as Facebook, Instagram, and WhatsApp.</p><p>"We are also starting to see our AI initiatives increasingly overlap with our Reality Labs," Zuckerberg added, highlighting the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/ray-ban-meta-smart-glasses-multimodal-ai-video-calling-update">new AI capabilities</a> rolling out on the well-received <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/ray-ban-meta-smart-glasses-review">Ray-Ban Meta smart glasses</a>. With this update, users will be able to make video calls and perform multimodal searches, which incorporate voice and visuals to help users learn about what&apos;s around them.</p><p>This essentially means Meta has two major investments going forward as it looks to bolster its VR platform and its position in the ongoing AI race. As a result, and adding in other factors like an upcoming trial over <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.texasattorneygeneral.gov/news/releases/paxton-sues-facebook-using-unauthorized-biometric-data">facial recognition tech</a>, the company expects a more modest Q2 as we begin to see these strategies take shape.</p><p>Despite this, Meta says it will "invest significantly more in infrastructure over the coming years" to support its AI ambitions, which will be crucial as companies like Google and Microsoft continue to inject their AI models across their products and services.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-earnings-q1-2024</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Meta released its Q1 2024 earnings on Wednesday, beating revenue expectations with increased ad spend and strong Quest sales. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">73eikvVAddKbR69tNhc42B</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kLJqu6dt5YsCmz9TTyNorJ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 23:19:53 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ derrek.lee@futurenet.com (Derrek Lee) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kLJqu6dt5YsCmz9TTyNorJ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A Meta Quest 2, Meta Quest 3, Viture One, Solos AirGo 3, and a regular pair of glasses together]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A Meta Quest 2, Meta Quest 3, Viture One, Solos AirGo 3, and a regular pair of glasses together]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ HMD debuts its first original Pulse series phones with 'Gen 1' repairability ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>HMD has debuted its first original lineup of phones under the "Pulse" series.</li><li>The trio features the same Unisoc T606 CPU and Android 14. However, the Pulse Pro offers a set of 50MP cameras and a 5,000mAh battery with 20W fast charging.</li><li>HMD launches its Pulse series in international markets, though the company plans to bring the "HMD Vibe" to the U.S. market.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>HMD Global announces the launch of its "first original" trio of devices dubbed the Pulse series.</p><p>According to a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.hmd.com/en_int/press/hmd-pulse-press-release">press release</a>, HMD states the new Pulse series is the beginning of its commitment to bring self-repairable devices to consumers. Under the "Gen 1 repairability" title, the company adds its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.hmd.com/en_us/self-repair">partnership with iFixit</a> should help users quickly find the parts they need if anything goes wrong.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1685px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.26%;"><img id="qGeEYEg45sCmaujaHr8tU4" name="hmd-pulse-pro-purple-hue.jpg" alt="The HMD Pulse Pro model in a purple hue." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qGeEYEg45sCmaujaHr8tU4.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1685" height="948" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: hm)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The HMD Pulse Pro leads the trio with a 6.6-inch HD+ display. The back of the phone contains a vertical dual camera array featuring a 50 MP AF Dual camera and a 2MP depth sensor. HMD states consumers will find a Super Night and Tripod mode alongside Flash Shot and AI HDR.</p><p>The company adds that the Pulse Pro&apos;s AI Super Portrait mode should help reduce any blurring found during nighttime shots. The front of the device offers a 50MP selfie camera, as well.</p><p>Powering the device is the Unisoc T606 CPU. Additionally, consumers can grab 6GB of RAM and 128GB of internal storage. The phone supports microSD expansion of up to 256GB.</p><p>HMD packed a 5,000mAh battery into the Pulse Pro, which is estimated to last up to 59 hours and is capable of 20W fast charging. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review">Android 14</a> will greet users out of the box. HMD states it has committed to providing the device, and the rest of the series, with two years of OS updates.</p><p>The HMD Pulse Pro will be available soon in international markets in Glacier Green, Twilight Purple, and Black Ocean.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1785px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:42.97%;"><img id="yDvSDvHs3ALGiq8DfPKiRm" name="hmd-pulse-plus-model-blue.jpg" alt="The HMD Pulse Plus in a blue colorway." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yDvSDvHs3ALGiq8DfPKiRm.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1785" height="767" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: HMD)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>For the HMD Pulse Plus, consumers will see the same 6.6-inch HD Plus display with a 90Hz refresh rate as the Pulse Pro. However, the Pulse Plus comes with a lower 8MP front-facing selfie camera. The device&apos;s sleek back panel contains a vertical dual camera array with a 50MP AF Dual Camera and a depth sensor to help "snap quality pictures with ease."</p><p>Interestingly, HMD has kept the same Unisoc T606 CPU for the Pulse Plus, like its Pro sibling. Internally, the device will offer 4GB of RAM, 128GB of internal storage, and up to 256GB of expandable storage via microSD.</p><p>Those interested in the HMD Pulse Plus will find the same 5,000mAh battery inside, though it features slower 10W charging capabilities.</p><p>This model is available now in Apricot Crush, Midnight Blue, and Glacier Green.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1791px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:47.96%;"><img id="F8XwFccGgXyXyJvk8PgdcX" name="hmd-pulse-vanilla-model-pink.jpg" alt="The HMD Pulse model in Dreamy Pink." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/F8XwFccGgXyXyJvk8PgdcX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1791" height="859" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: HMD)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The last of the trio, the HMD Pulse, remains the same in terms of CPU and display capabilities. The smallest sibling differs with its dual camera array as the device offers a 13 MP AF Dual camera. The front selfie camera remains the same at 8MP.</p><p>HMD has packed the same battery as the Pulse Plus inside the vanilla model with 10W charging and an estimated 59-hour runtime.</p><p>The base model drops slightly for memory and storage as HMD puts it up with 4GB of RAM and only 64GB of internal storage. The device still retains its microSD slot, capable of holding up to 256GB of extra storage.</p><p>Much like the Plus model, the HMD Pulse is available now for international markets. Consumers can find it in Dreamy Pink, Meteor Black, and Atmos Blue colorways.</p><p>While HMD&apos;s initial trio of devices are only for overseas countries, the company informed <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidpolice.com/hmd-pulse-pro/">Android Police</a> that it will bring one to the U.S. While specifics weren&apos;t given, it was stated that U.S. consumers will receive the "HMD Vibe," a play-off the HMD Pulse and Pulse Plus models. The device will reportedly go for $149 whenever it finally arrives.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/hmd-pulse-series-phones-debut</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ HMD debuted its first original set of devices under the Pulse series. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">SdGTHKGLJByCGqdmv9Qvuh</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rVzNLUAueodrT7fcxGkN6K.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 20:12:13 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rVzNLUAueodrT7fcxGkN6K.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[HMD]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The HMD Pulse Pro in Glacier Green.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The HMD Pulse Pro in Glacier Green.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Glance is coming to the US, whether we like it or not ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Reports suggest Glance is preparing to debut in the U.S. "later this year" following its pilot program with Motorola and Verizon.</li><li>Sources state Glance will not capture data, but will instead leverage a user's "patterns" to offer recommendations.</li><li>Glance states it will not show ads in the U.S., opting for news stories, and it will look to offer a subscription service for "premium news."</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google-backed Indian startup Glance is preparing to finally make its U.S. debut, bringing a unique lock screen experience to Android.</p><p>Unnamed sources reportedly told <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/04/23/india-glance-pilots-android-lockscreen-platform-in-us/">TechCrunch</a> that Glance has started a "pilot program" with Motorola and Verizon in the U.S. Glance works to deliver recommendations to users like ads, news articles, and more on the lock screen. Sources state the company&apos;s platform does not collect or use user data.</p><p>Instead, Glance operates off a user&apos;s "patterns" in order for the software to operate.</p><p>Moreover, the platform is supposedly discussing ways to build an AI-backed lock screen experience with Qualcomm. Such a move would help Glance reduce the amount of data it requires to function while also moving to on-device processing.</p><p>With Glance moving into the U.S. from India, there are plans to collaborate with telecom operators, CNN, and the NBA. The lock screen experience will reportedly arrive "later this year."</p><p>A statement from Glance to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidpolice.com/lock-screen-ads-coming-to-android-phone/#update-2024-04-24-08-09-est-by-rajesh-pandey">Android Authority</a> says the company "does not intend" to ads on consumer devices in the U.S. Glance will side with offering a subscription service where users can pay for "premium news" on their lock screens every month.</p><p>It&apos;s worth noting that users will have the ability to disable Glance on their device once it officially arrives.</p><p>Android Central has reached out to Glance regarding more information surrounding its subscription service. We did not hear back in time for publication but will update this article once we hear back.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3971px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.26%;"><img id="QM6XmV8aWcztyKhotvLXnU" name="Moto-G-Power-5G-2024-review-10.jpg" alt="The Moto G Power 5G 2024 backside" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QM6XmV8aWcztyKhotvLXnU.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3971" height="2234" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The pilot program source alluded to for Glance in the U.S. has already arrived on some devices, including the Moto G Power 5G. In our <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/moto-g-power-5g-2024-review">Moto G Power 5G 2024 review</a>, Glance&apos;s appearance on the device was questionable at best, and it felt a little intrusive. What&apos;s more, the platform tosses news recommendations at you, which seems a little redundant, considering Google&apos;s Discovery page is a swipe away from your home screen.</p><p>Fortunately, you can disable Glance on the phone, but we found that the service would occasionally produce a full-screen prompt on the lock screen, encouraging you to re-enable the feature.</p><p>We first heard about Glance in 2022, and it&apos;s not entirely clear what&apos;s taken the company so long to arrive in the U.S. It was stated two years ago that the company amassed 400 million users before it set eyes on the U.S. market.</p><p>Glance will seek to make a profit through the aforementioned subscription and if users interact with its "product of the day."</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/glance-reportedly-us-bound-later-2024</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Sources claimed Glance is finally ready to debut in the U.S. but it seems ads will take a back seat. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">QwnXMJ23ETXUUXwD8Bj9wf</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zGeZGZBBSVSp9ftcBJwoP6.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 20:06:22 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zGeZGZBBSVSp9ftcBJwoP6.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Glance on the Moto G Power 5G 2024]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Glance on the Moto G Power 5G 2024]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Galaxy S25 could get a major AI upgrade from Google ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A report following an interview with Samsung's executive director, Cho Cheol-min, states Samsung is having discussions with Google about "evolving" on-device AI.</li><li>It was claimed that Google's Gemini Nano version 2 will be available on the Galaxy S25 series when it launches next year.</li><li>Cho stated that Samsung is still focused on AI and that the company is looking to double its team focus on developing on-device AI for its Exynos chipset.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>A recent report suggests Google will upgrade its Gemini Nano AI model in time to roll out with Samsung&apos;s Galaxy S25 series next year.</p><p>The report stems from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://v.daum.net/v/20240417104601886">Daum Herald Economy</a> (Korean) following an interview with Samsung&apos;s executive director of systems, Cho Cheol-min (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/galaxy-s25-gemini-nano-2-ai-features-3436802/">Android Authority</a>). It was stated that discussions between Samsung and Google have already started as the brands look to "evolve" on-device AI in the next trio.</p><p>Cho stated, "We have started discussing how to implement version 2 of Google’s ‘Gemini Nano’ in on-device AI." He added that Samsung would have a "private" meeting with the company to discuss how they could further develop AI for the Galaxy S25.</p><p>Samsung continues to focus on its AI efforts, with Cho reportedly expressing how AI has allowed consumers to "actually experience AI." The company feels that phones are a better outlet than PCs for users to experience AI&apos;s capabilities.</p><p>Cho stated that the company is looking to double the number of people working toward on-device AI capabilities through its Exynos chipset. He stated around 200 people are involved in developing on-device AI for Exynos. He hopes that number reaches 400 "within the year."</p><p>Additionally, Samsung&apos;s executive director teased the possibility of a solution that blends on-device AI with cloud-based AI services.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="FFvZEBujRzeeVAA4ZSMsMf" name="google-gemini-mwc-sign.jpg" alt="Google Gemini on Android at MWC 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FFvZEBujRzeeVAA4ZSMsMf.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>For context, Google&apos;s Gemini Nano model is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini-unveiled">the smallest of the three</a> the company created. Nano is designed to handle the smaller, on-device tasks efficiently. The model was designed with the intention of landing on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phones</a>, which Google turned and did <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-pixel-feature-drop-december-2023">with its Pixel 8 series</a>.</p><p>Samsung&apos;s Galaxy AI leverages Gemini Nano and Gemini Pro&apos;s LLM (large language model) to help users with their on-device tasks. However, the company piggybacks off Qualcomm&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-3">Snapdragon 8 Gen 3</a> SoC to do the heavy lifting, making such AI capabilities possible. Rumors suggest Samsung is interested in boosting its Exynos chip&apos;s AI capabilities, which could occur on the Exynos 2500.</p><p>Earlier this year, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-exynos-2500-soc-specs-leak">some information about Samsung&apos;s next chip leaked</a>, highlighting a likely increase in speed and performance. Rumors claim the chip will clock in at 3.2 or 3.3GHz.</p>
<ul><li> <strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="e013f3a8-c6b7-4173-ba95-642556dbec64">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.52%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QQfCey54Mda248SVrvmGSn.jpg' alt='The yellow Galaxy S24 Ultra'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>A vivacious return to the top</strong></em></p>
<p>Samsung's Galaxy S24 Ultra continues to refine what users experienced with the S23 Ultra. The device's speed and performance are enhanced, thanks to Qualcomm's latest flagship chip. Software-wise, the S24 Ultra boasts the company's Galaxy AI, which brings several on-device AI tools for users.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini-nano-v2-galaxy-s25-report-claim</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A report claimed that Google will upgrade and roll out version 2 of its Gemini Nano model on the Galaxy S25. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">e5kqeEBK7FVSVb8CnsPBgF</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/k8uq6C3DgSNoTTnwmaav7V.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 18:30:55 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/k8uq6C3DgSNoTTnwmaav7V.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Using Google Circle to Search on a Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Using Google Circle to Search on a Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Not enough people are talking about this phone's weird display ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>In the world of displays, it&apos;s often said that faster refresh rates are better. We&apos;ve seen smartphones widely adopt 120Hz displays in the past few years, while the PC gaming side of things has seen monitors launch at 360Hz and beyond. But the refresh rate you see with your eyes isn&apos;t the only refresh rate you should care about.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-6-pro-review">Honor Magic 6 Pro</a> recently launched with a PWM refresh rate of 4,320Hz, eclipsing the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-90-and-magic-5-pro-display-benefits">previous record Honor set</a> with the Honor 90 and Honor Magic 5 Pro last Summer. That number is becoming more and more important as <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12-display">ultra-bright phone displays</a> are becoming more common, helping to alleviate eye strain when using these phones in bed at night.</p><p>But while an increasing number of companies are starting to advertise elevated PWM refresh rates, very few of them are willing to talk about the technology behind the glass. It&apos;s great to see attention paid to a topic that could affect millions of smartphone users, but it&apos;s also frustrating to see a lack of transparency from the companies behind the change movement.</p>
<h2 id="secrecy-and-proprietary-methods-2">Secrecy and proprietary methods</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="97Coz23KXFD9Xqx5xFipuh" name="honor-magic-6-pro-23.jpg" alt="Honor Magic 6 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/97Coz23KXFD9Xqx5xFipuh.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Industrial espionage is a term for a reason. Companies that develop complicated, profit-making products don&apos;t want to reveal their secrets to the rest of the world to be easily copied. That problem has accelerated tenfold in an era where products can be cloned on production lines and sold under a random brand name on Amazon.</p><p>In just the past two years, we&apos;ve seen substantial competition in the display market from names like BOE, China Star, and Visionox, names you may have never even heard of until this article. Until these companies came along, an OLED panel on your favorite device was almost assuredly made by Samsung or LG.</p><p>However, Samsung&apos;s dominance in the AMOLED market meant that any decisions the company made ultimately trickled down to companies using Samsung displays in their products. As any <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-is-pwm-display-flicker-tips-and-tricks">PWM-sensitive</a> person will tell you, Samsung AMOLED panels are the worst type of display for eye health.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>Honor uses a BOE panel that gets to 5,000 nits brightness under the right conditions, yet it uses fascinating technology to ensure it's not searing your retinas.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>Unironically, none of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/best-phones-for-pwm-flicker-sensitive">best phones for PWM-sensitive people</a> have displays made by Samsung. That&apos;s because some of Samsung&apos;s biggest features rely on flickering the display to trick your eyes into seeing something that&apos;s not actually there, and it wreaks havoc in some people&apos;s brains — including myself.</p><p>That&apos;s part of why I was so excited to get to use the Honor Magic 6 Pro, as its PWM rate is 10x the refresh rate <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-pwm-refresh-rate">of the Galaxy S24 series</a>, ensuring that I&apos;m able to use it for long periods of time.</p><p>While that&apos;s great — and it means I can finally use a phone with a comfortable display <strong>and</strong> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-6-pro-camera-review">a good camera</a> — Honor&apos;s method of achieving this high rate is far from conventional. In short, that means it doesn&apos;t work for everyone.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_QUgEftJtMQ" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>Without getting into the weeds, my light meter can&apos;t properly read the backlight refresh frequency of the Honor Magic 6 Pro&apos;s display, even though I can see what&apos;s happening with a camera. It&apos;s a side effect of Honor doing something "weird" with its display, so I asked the company to go into a bit more detail on it.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>Honor's display panel works differently from any other I've tested, and while that works well for me, it doesn't for some folks.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>Unfortunately, all I was met with was a disappointing "sorry, we can&apos;t provide further details on this technology."</p><p>This makes it difficult to understand why this phone works incredibly well for my eyes but instantly causes pain for other flicker-sensitive users. It&apos;s a problem I&apos;ve had with other companies, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-pro-display-pwm-frequency">like Google</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/my-phone-is-making-me-sick-and-im-not-alone">Samsung</a>, who both have refused to comment or provide additional details on how their displays work beyond what each company&apos;s marketing department provides.</p><p>Meanwhile, Motorola continues to be one of the only companies that will discuss the topic at length with me. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-5-display-flickering">They even boasted</a> how their flicker-reduction technology ensures that the display is on 99.51% of each duty cycle, a more technical term I&apos;ve never heard from any other company.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="iteBDJ5eAY4RZ4N9yBiN5U" name="Motorola-Edge-Plus-2023-display-playing-games-genshin-impact.jpg" alt="Playing Genshin Impact on the Motorola Edge+ (2023)" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/iteBDJ5eAY4RZ4N9yBiN5U.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<figure><blockquote><p>Motorola is one of the only companies talking about how it actively performs market research to find out how much of its customer base is negatively affected by display flicker.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>Motorola has even disclosed to me that it performs market research studies specific to display flicker in an attempt to figure out how many Motorola customers are negatively affected by flicker.</p><p>This is the kind of market-leading behavior I expect from a company like Samsung that could potentially negatively affect the health of hundreds of millions of people around the world. It&apos;s just as important as ensuring that phones don&apos;t emit harmful radiation, something <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.fcc.gov/general/specific-absorption-rate-sar-cellular-telephones">all manufacturers have to do</a> before getting approval by governing bodies like the FCC.</p><p>Thankfully, I was able to sit down with Bill Maffucci from Kopin Corporation, a company that specializes in creating displays and lenses for XR devices, to discuss some of the finer points of how displays work. It was a refreshing conversation and it helped me understand the tenuous relationship between technologies like PWM and LTPO.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>Technologies like PWM and LTPO complicate the already complicated nature of OLED panels, and companies aren't particularly willing to divulge how these work together.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>Maffucci explained that an OLED display can light up and turn off in microseconds — one microsecond is one millionth (0.000001) of a second — meaning that companies now have options for dimming that they never had with LCDs. Couple that with the fact that reducing voltage on an OLED panel too much can cause bad color reproduction and noise, and you&apos;ll quickly understand why companies have started using PWM — which flickers the display on and off rapidly — more often to control brightness.</p><p>However, this becomes even more complicated when you throw <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-does-ltpo-mean-and-why-is-it-important-on-your-device">LTPO</a> into the mix, a technology that adjusts the refresh rate of the display based on what&apos;s happening on screen. But while this sounds like it would interfere with the "backlight" cycle on an OLED, Maffucci confirmed to me that most LTPO OLEDs don&apos;t actually adjust the refresh rate of the display itself.</p><p>Rather, what&apos;s being adjusted is the graphics driver&apos;s rendering rate, and it&apos;s usually performed at a number that divides evenly into the display&apos;s <em>actual</em> refresh rate. For Honor, that means the 360Hz rate further complicates the situation in ways the company isn&apos;t willing to divulge.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3822px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:45.97%;"><img id="vaLAyta5rHuonWbvKkQSdg" name="honor-keep-your-secrets-frodo.jpg" alt="A meme of Frodo Baggins" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vaLAyta5rHuonWbvKkQSdg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3822" height="1757" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central / New Line Cinema)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I&apos;ve noticed that more people than ever are flocking to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://reddit.com/r/PWM_Sensitive/">PWM-sensitive online communities</a>, and I think it&apos;s both a combination of more flickering displays than ever plus people&apos;s raised awareness that this is a real issue — not just something in their imagination.</p><p>Even Google is playing around with new brightness controls at the system level, purportedly baking in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-beta-even-dimmer-setting-spotted">new "even dimmer" option</a> into <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a>. While that <em>could</em> help some people, the existing "extra dim" option in Android seems to wreak havoc on sensitive eyes.</p><p>However, the trend for more eye-friendly mobile displays has substantially improved over the past year. Companies like Motorola are leading the way, but display manufacturers like BOE, Visionox, and China Star all seem to recognize that something needs to change to prevent more widespread problems from happening.</p><p>Now, if we could only get companies to be a little less secretive about things that are problematic to their users&apos; health, that would be great. Regardless, I&apos;m happy to see companies like Honor trying to make better displays, even if the company doesn&apos;t want to reveal its secrets just yet.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-6-pro-interesting-display-tricks</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Honor Magic 6 Pro is the first phone with 4,320Hz PWM brightness adjustment, but does that automatically mean it's better for your eyes? ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">irAEA2CnSmdVsSWhQLqoCP</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LKNBQv4wzvZNHtRCWmx8eW.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 18:00:51 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nicholas.sutrich@futurenet.com (Nicholas Sutrich) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LKNBQv4wzvZNHtRCWmx8eW.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Holding the Honor Magic 6 Pro and looking at the PWM rate at 30% brightness]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Holding the Honor Magic 6 Pro and looking at the PWM rate at 30% brightness]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ TikTok's days are literally numbered in the US as bill to ban app is signed into law ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>After swiftly passing through the House and Senate, U.S. President Joe Biden has signed a foreign aid package that includes a bill targeting TikTok.</li><li>The bill gives TikTok owner ByteDance a year to divest the app, or else mobile app stores will be forced to remove it.</li><li>TikTok CEO has responded on the platform, saying that the app "isn't going anywhere."</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>President Biden has signed a bill into law that could lead to a nationwide TikTok ban, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/04/23/tech/congress-tiktok-ban-what-next/index.html">CNN reports</a>. This comes just days after the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/tiktok-ban-just-got-the-houses-nod-and-it-might-be-law-real-soon">House approved the bill</a> and a day after the Senate voted in favor of it.</p><p>Nestled within a foreign aid package, the bill would make it so that app stores such as Google&apos;s Play Store and Apple&apos;s App Store can not legally offer TikTok within the United States. However, the ban does not happen overnight, as the bill gives TikTok owner ByteDance less than a year (270 days) to divest the app and find a potential buyer.</p><p>In response to the bill being signed into law, TikTok CEO Shou Chew took to the app to express his thoughts on the matter, saying, "We aren&apos;t going anywhere."</p>

                    <blockquote class="tiktok-embed" cite="https://www.tiktok.com/@tiktok/video/7361448925972155679" data-video-id="7361448925972155679" style="max-width: 605px; min-width: 325px;">
                        <section>
                            <a target="_blank" title="@tiktok" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@tiktok">@tiktok</a>
                            <p>Response to TikTok Ban Bill</p><a target="_blank" title="♬ original sound  - TikTok" href="https://www.tiktok.com/music/original-sound-TikTok-7361449109087128350">♬ original sound  - TikTok</a></section>
                    </blockquote>
                
<p>Chew points out that of the more than 170 million users on the platform, more than 7 million business owners rely on TikTok for their livelihoods and urges users to post videos about how the app impacts their lives. He also notes that TikTok will continue to invest in keeping its community "vibrant, exciting, and safe."</p><p>"Through our U.S. security efforts, we have built safeguards that no other peer company has made. We have invested billions of dollars to secure your data and keep our platform free from outside manipulation."</p><p>TikTok has been under fire over the past several years for its close ties to the Chinese government via parent company ByteDance, with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/why-us-lawkmakers-want-tiktok-banned">lawmakers expressing concerns about U.S. data</a>. The U.S. has already <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/us-senate-bans-tiktok-app-from-government-devices">banned the app on government-issued devices</a>. Meanwhile, efforts to alleviate these concerns have largely failed, leaving the future of TikTok unclear for the app and its users. The question also remains whether or not ByteDance will be allowed to divest TikTok.</p><p>Android Central has reached out to TikTok for a comment on the bill being signed into law but did not receive a response in time for publication. However, a TikTok spokesperson told CNN that the company found the ban "unconstitutional" and that TikTok would continue to challenge the decision.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/us-bill-to-ban-tiktok-signed-into-law</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The U.S. government has signed a new bill into law that could lead to a nationwide ban of TikTok. The company has less than a year to divest the app and find a potential buyer. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">EkRuCo3PrmPTZXSULNKRjE</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/grNeVRDB3Cyt4cKWUcd9QL.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 16:51:42 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ derrek.lee@futurenet.com (Derrek Lee) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/grNeVRDB3Cyt4cKWUcd9QL.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[TikTok app logo on Android]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[TikTok app logo on Android]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Does it help to force close apps on your phone? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>So you&apos;re done using a big bloated app and want to make sure you get all those precious phone resources back. Most of us just move on to the next app and forget about it, but plenty of other folks think you should dig in there and make sure it&apos;s fully closed. Which way is right?</p><p>Both are fine. Force-closing an app isn&apos;t going to hurt anything, and sometimes I do it. I&apos;ll say up front that if I grant any <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/android-11-features-we-love-one-time-permissions">one-time permissions</a> to an app when I open it, I&apos;ll swipe that app away as soon as I&apos;m finished. Even <em>that</em> is probably unnecessary, though.</p>
<p>Let&apos;s take a look at what&apos;s happening and why you may want to just let Android do it&apos;s thing instead of trying to manage one more thing on your phone.</p>
<h2 id="what-does-force-closing-an-app-really-mean-2">What does force closing an app really mean?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="EbiLxT6SNFKqGuToJnVNmN" name="samsung-galaxy-z-flip-5-cover-screen-multitasking-04.jpg" alt="The larger cover display of the Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 5" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/EbiLxT6SNFKqGuToJnVNmN.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>When used as a computing term, force-closing means terminating a running process. Depending on the platform, you might see the words kill, SIGHUP, SIGKILL, or SIGTERM used to mean the same thing. All these do the same thing—send a signal to the operating system to terminate (not suspend) a running process, though they do it in slightly different ways.</p>
<pre class="line-numbers language-bash" language="bash" ><code>killall -o 30m chrome

# This sends a request for a graceful shutdown 
# of all instances of Chrome that have been 
# running longer than 30 minutes</code></pre>
<p>However, this doesn&apos;t mean an app is closed because many apps use more than one process. Apps doing tasks in the background (not visible on your screen) act differently and have different rules. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/latest-android-compatibility-definitions-prohibits-using-androids-camera-apis-alter-facial">Android&apos;s APIs</a> are built around this; unless you have <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-phone-rooting-and-modding">rooted your phone</a> or are <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://llamalab.com/automate/doc/block/app_kill.html">using an app with elevated privileges</a>, this is how it works. </p><p>If you&apos;re doing either of these things, you&apos;re probably not reading an article like this looking for answers. For our purposes, force closing means opening the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-beta-2-teases-app-pair">overview of your open apps</a> and swiping one or more away. This closes the process of that app running in the foreground, and as far as we can tell, it&apos;s closed.</p>
<p>Back to the multiple processes used by most apps. Apps periodically do things even if they aren&apos;t "open" or you haven&apos;t used them recently. Sometimes, these are useful things, like a social media app telling you about notifications that you asked it to tell you about. </p><p>Other times, it&apos;s not so useful, like free ad-based apps that get your location and report it.</p><p>I&apos;ll reiterate — unless you&apos;re doing something that elevates permissions, you can&apos;t stop this from happening. It&apos;s how the operating system works because it&apos;s how an operating system <em>has</em> to work. All computer operating systems that have any sort of multitasking allow processes to open to perform background tasks. And yes, this can have an effect while it&apos;s happening, but it soon finishes. You will probably never notice it.</p>
<p>We&apos;re not able to control these processes, but what about the ones we can see on our screen? Once it isn&apos;t in our face, it&apos;s mostly suspended, but we can push it out of view by swiping it away and forcing it to be closed. But you don&apos;t really need to do it.</p>
<h2 id="resource-management-2">Resource management</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2960px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:62.43%;"><img id="ZuVZHoWYcrZkBtLbo6nYPK" name="multiple-windows-samsung-dex-classic-1.jpg" alt="Multiple app windows open in Classic DeX" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZuVZHoWYcrZkBtLbo6nYPK.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2960" height="1848" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Android was designed to be very aggressive regarding killing processes and freeing resources. Since it was designed for machines with mobile application processors, no real way of keeping them cool, and only a battery to power them, it can&apos;t let things run amok. </p><p>One of the ways <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-makes-pixel-more-memory-efficient-first-feature-drop">Android manages resources</a> is by killing processes that aren&apos;t being used to open new ones. You could keep opening process after process until you run out of memory, but your device would perform horribly.</p>
<p>The company that made your device fine-tuned these settings to keep processes alive as long as possible (in case they are needed again) while keeping performance acceptable. Some of these settings deal with background processes so everything that needs to be done <em>can</em> be done, and others deal with what we see on our screens.</p><p>If you swipe an app away to try and push it out of your memory, that space won&apos;t stay free for long. The operating system doesn&apos;t want it to stay empty because this is one of those times where free RAM really is wasted RAM. Having available memory with nothing in it doesn&apos;t benefit you in any way. Some systems, like Microsoft Windows, were designed to have a set amount of RAM free and empty if possible. Your Android device isn&apos;t one of them.</p>
<p>Swiping apps away as soon as you&apos;re done using them isn&apos;t going to hurt anything. It&apos;s also not really helping anything. This is one case where you can safely ignore it and just enjoy using your phone.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/should-you-force-close-your-apps</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Your phone's operating system manages apps and resources on it's own, and it's pretty good at doing it.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">6N3t5xsnAYJTNEE4HndpTb</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DzxrNPvMuDfJMkyzy9QBQY.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 15:00:54 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DzxrNPvMuDfJMkyzy9QBQY.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Future]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android app overview]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android app overview]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ OnePlus Open 2: Leaks, rumors, specs, and release date ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-open-review">OnePlus Open</a> debuted to much fanfare at the end of last year, and it went on to become one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">best foldables</a> available today. A lot of that is down to the hardware; the Open has a gorgeous design, smooth hinge with no visible crease, excellent internal hardware, a larger battery than the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-5-review">Galaxy Z Fold 5</a>, 67W charging, and terrific cameras.</p><p>While there were software issues out of the box, these have been addressed with updates. With the Open gaining decent momentum, it&apos;s now time to take a look at what the Open 2 could bring to the table once it launches later this year. </p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-oneplus-open-2-design"><span>OnePlus Open 2: Design</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="5YPXRoyAY3swpXj75cfitK" name="oneplus-open-35.jpg" alt="OnePlus Open review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5YPXRoyAY3swpXj75cfitK.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>OnePlus designed the Open in collaboration with OPPO, and that&apos;s immediately evident when viewing the device next to the Find N2. In fact, the Find N3 is identical to the Open, with the only difference being that it is limited to China, whereas the Open is sold in global markets. </p><p>As such, it is unlikely we&apos;ll see any major design change with the Open 2. While OPPO likes to switch up the design of its Find X devices — the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oppo-find-x7-ultra-review">Find X7 Ultra</a> has a distinct design that stands out — it has maintained the same styling to all of its foldables, and that isn&apos;t likely to change. </p><p>What could be different is a new hinge that is even lighter than the previous generation. Honor has the distinction of the thinnest foldable in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-v2-review">Magic V2</a>, and as this is a key area of contention between all the Chinese manufacturers, it is entirely likely the Open 2 will feature a redesigned hinge. </p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-oneplus-open-2-specs"><span>OnePlus Open 2: Specs</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="otdGLT6rYiTxVh5oAktd2H" name="oneplus-open-25.jpg" alt="OnePlus Open review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/otdGLT6rYiTxVh5oAktd2H.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The OnePlus Open has an outstanding hardware package, and that is set to continue with the Open 2. The upcoming foldable will be powered by the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3, and it should retain the same 67W charging tech. </p><p>OnePlus isn&apos;t messing with battery tech this year, and while it has 150W charging available, it isn&apos;t usable in North America, so for devices that are launching globally, it is limiting the charging potential to 100W or 67W. Considering the limited room on a foldable, I don&apos;t see any changes in this area. </p><p>Having said that, the Open 2 is likely to include a larger battery that lasts noticeably longer. There hasn&apos;t been any confirmation about the battery size, but OnePlus is said to offer up to a 5000mAh battery on the foldable. </p><p>The rest of the hardware is likely to be unchanged, but I&apos;ll update this post once we have credible details. </p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-oneplus-open-2-cameras"><span>OnePlus Open 2: Cameras</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="MFbv8pqxhAinWWcVKYewKD" name="oneplus-open-9.jpg" alt="OnePlus Open review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MFbv8pqxhAinWWcVKYewKD.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>OnePlus did all the right things when it comes to the Open cameras, with the foldable offering a fabulous set of lenses at the back. With 2024 phones pushing the boundaries of camera tech — the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12-review">OnePlus 12</a>, Find X7 Ultra, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/xiaomi-14-ultra-review">Xiaomi 14 Ultra</a> all have sizeable gains — the Open 2 should have some of these gains baked in. </p><p>Then again, considering the launch window of the Open 2, it could be a while before we know what camera hardware the device is packing to any reasonable degree. What you need to know at this point is that the cameras should be on the same level as the OnePlus 12, and that&apos;s a terrific starting point. </p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-oneplus-open-2-release-date"><span>OnePlus Open 2: Release date</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="GkuiDi9EL2qQjKaytP7bEC" name="oneplus-open-2.jpg" alt="OnePlus Open review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GkuiDi9EL2qQjKaytP7bEC.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>OnePlus is targeting the same launch window as last year, but it is moving things up a little, so get ready to see the Open 2 sometime before the month of October. </p><p>An earlier launch positions the Open 2 against the likes of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6">Galaxy Z Fold 6</a>, and with OnePlus following a similar stance with the OnePlus 12 at the start of the year, the Open 2 should debut before the end of Q3 2024. </p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-oneplus-open-2-what-i-want-to-see"><span>OnePlus Open 2: What I want to see</span></h2>
<h2 id="oneplus-needs-to-add-wireless-charging-2">OnePlus needs to add wireless charging</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="Fy7EdSSW3TzME3zjwU23HM" name="oneplus-open-39.jpg" alt="OnePlus Open review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Fy7EdSSW3TzME3zjwU23HM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I don&apos;t know who signed off on not including wireless charging on the OnePlus Open, but it is the biggest limitation on the device. Sure, the phone was designed in conjunction with OPPO, and the Chinese manufacturer doesn&apos;t offer wireless charging on its own devices — so you don&apos;t get one here.</p><p>However, the Open is sold in a lot of global markets, and with OnePlus positioning it as the ideal alternative to Samsung in North America, it needed to nail the table stakes features. While the battery life itself is much better than Samsung&apos;s foldables, the fact that it is limited to wired charging — no matter how fast — makes it a little less enticing.</p><p>With the Open 2, OnePlus has to rectify this particular issue and offer wireless charging out of the box. While it&apos;s okay for a device like the OnePlus 11 to miss out on it, the Open costs nearly thrice as much at $1,699, and not having the ability to charge wirelessly is a shortsighted move.</p>
<h2 id="polished-software-out-of-the-box-2">Polished software out of the box</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="XfwHZfFvCTHoKYvZ8dSYcF" name="oneplus-open-23.jpg" alt="OnePlus Open review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XfwHZfFvCTHoKYvZ8dSYcF.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>This is a regular complaint with all OnePlus phones, but I want to see better software out of the box with the Open 2, not a few months down the line. Yes, the ColorOS integration made things that much more difficult, but it&apos;s been two years now, and that cannot be the excuse to deliver shoddy software on every new phone.</p><p>OnePlus has shown that it can deliver; the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12-review">OnePlus 12</a> was devoid of any major bugs, and it was optimized for the hardware. I know achieving the same on a foldable is twice as hard as there are two screens to deal with and numerous scaling issues, but the Open 2 has to do better. And while we&apos;re at it, can I get a 5x5 grid? I still don&apos;t understand why that isn&apos;t available on the Open.</p>
<h2 id="ipx8-water-resistance-2">IPX8 water resistance</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="U8WKGQq2BDu7mHJeTEyR4C" name="oneplus-open-1.jpg" alt="OnePlus Open review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/U8WKGQq2BDu7mHJeTEyR4C.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The OnePlus Open has IPX4 water resistance, and that means that it can withstand an occasional splash of water. OnePlus says that the hinge automatically ejects any dust that manages to get in, and even though it isn&apos;t tested, it should do a decent job with any dust ingress as well.</p><p>That said, I&apos;d like to see IPX8 water resistance on the Open 2. That would make the foldable that much more resilient to the elements, and bring it to parity with Samsung&apos;s foldables.</p>
<h2 id="stylus-integration-would-be-nice-to-have-2">Stylus integration would be nice to have</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="otdGLT6rYiTxVh5oAktd2H" name="oneplus-open-25.jpg" alt="OnePlus Open review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/otdGLT6rYiTxVh5oAktd2H.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>This is another one of those features that feels motivated by OPPO. As the brand doesn&apos;t pay particular attention to global markets, adding stylus integration wasn&apos;t a priority, and the Open misses out on it. I&apos;m not saying the foldable should have come with a stylus in the box — even Samsung isn&apos;t that generous — but the ability to use a stylus with the inner screen makes the foldable that much more useful.</p><p>Even if OnePlus decides it doesn&apos;t want to bother making its own stylus, there are plenty of aftermarket styli that do a great job with note-taking and doodling. I have a half-dozen styli in the house, and while I don&apos;t really use them as much as I should, having the option to do so on the Open 2 would go a long way.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="58b33d6a-a65d-4fff-9af3-4709d7fd834e">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/i72maMJpZUbzyf2vtKk88i.jpg' alt='An official render of the OnePlus Open in both colorways'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">OnePlus Open</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>The OnePlus Open is one of the best foldables you can buy today. It has terrific hardware combined with stellar cameras, the best hinge in this category, and standout battery life. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-open-2</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The OnePlus Open is here, and it is amazing. Here's what you need to know about the second-gen model.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">ERv6bKuiWZZtQNJ9oAh3z4</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VWt54kP4N2G3vsMUqzSpCH.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 07:08:55 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VWt54kP4N2G3vsMUqzSpCH.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus Open review]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus Open review]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google really needs to launch a new Nest Hub Max, and it might just happen ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-32">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A new report uncovered references to a new Nest Hub Max smart display in an update to the Google Home app.</li><li>The release of the Pixel Tablet, which includes a speaker dock and has smart display functionality, was expected to doom the Nest Hub lineup's future.</li><li>However, the surprising indication that Google may refresh the Nest Hub Max is a good thing because the Pixel Tablet and Nest Hub Max are products for different use cases.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>There was a bittersweet feeling for fans of Google&apos;s Nest Hub lineup when it unveiled the Google Pixel Tablet because it seemed to doom the future of the company&apos;s dedicated smart displays. However, there are now indications that the five-year-old <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/nest-hub-max-review">Nest Hub Max</a> might finally receive a much-needed refresh. While the current Nest Hub Max is still a solid smart home controller despite being released first in 2019, there are a few things about the display that make it feel ancient.</p><p>In version 3.16 of the Google Home app, references to a new and unreleased Nest Hub Max model were uncovered in an APK teardown by the team at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/04/23/new-nest-audio-hub-max-spotted/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a>. The report says that the unknown device is clearly listed as a Nest Hub Max in code for the Google Home app, leaving little room for different interpretations. It also notes that this new device won&apos;t be powered by Android, and will instead use the same Fuchsia OS that powers current Nest Hub displays.</p><p>This all but confirms that a potential next-generation Nest Hub Max will still keep its smart display identity and not follow in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/google-pixel-tablet-review">Pixel Tablet</a>&apos;s footsteps. That device runs Android but also features a smart display mode that makes it comparable in functionality to Nest Hub devices. Google could have easily pivoted its strategy with a subsequent Nest Hub Max, ditching Fuchsia for its new Android smart display mode.</p><p>That said, it certainly looks like Google is planning to freshen up its smart home offerings this year. The same report reveals that a new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/nest-audio-review">Nest Audio</a> product might be on the way, while a prior report shared that Google is likely planning to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/chromecast-with-google-tv-4k-successor-may-come-soon-new-remote">launch a new Chromecast with Google TV 4K</a>. </p><p>We don&apos;t know when (or if) this upgraded Nest Hub Max might launch. Still, let&apos;s take a look at why the smart display still has a place in Google&apos;s 2024 product lineup and what we want to see.</p>
<h2 id="why-the-pixel-tablet-and-nest-hub-max-need-to-coexist-2">Why the Pixel Tablet and Nest Hub Max need to coexist</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:5472px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="bi7MhZGQa4eW7r5ZWBEvcF" name="google-pixel-tablet-nest-hub-max.jpg" alt="Nest Hub Max next to Pixel Tablet on countertop" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bi7MhZGQa4eW7r5ZWBEvcF.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="5472" height="3078" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>If you <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/google-pixel-tablet-nest-hub-max-kitchen-test">compare the Pixel Tablet and the Nest Hub Max</a>, it might be easy to declare the Pixel Tablet as the clear winner at first glance. However, in reality, it&apos;s much more complicated than that. The obvious difference between these two devices is the price: the Pixel Tablet starts at $500, while the Nest Hub Max costs $230. Both devices are frequently available at a discount, but the Nest Hub Max can be bought for under $200 easily during deals holidays like Black Friday. </p><p>So, the Pixel Tablet is not a one-size-fits-all solution for your smart home needs simply because it costs double the price of the Nest Hub Max. It&apos;s true that the Pixel Tablet is, well, a tablet — and that makes it a great value for people who are in the market for <em>both</em> an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-tablets">Android tablet</a> <em>and</em> a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-smart-display">smart display</a>. I was in the market for something like a Pixel Tablet or a Nest Hub Max late last year, but when it came down to it, I ended up buying the latter because I simply didn&apos;t need a tablet. </p><p>The Pixel Tablet has clear versatility benefits, but it isn&apos;t the best for every situation. For starters, the included speaker docking station generally doesn&apos;t sound as good or as loud as the Nest Hub Max. Additionally, the Pixel Tablet doesn&apos;t include a Thread radio, so you can forget setting up your Nest Audio hardware as the device&apos;s default speaker outputs. If you need a smart home controller first and foremost, the five-year-old Nest Hub Max is still the cream of the crop. </p>
<h2 id="what-i-want-to-see-in-a-nest-hub-max-refresh-2">What I want to see in a Nest Hub Max refresh</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="dbdsrJHiobNCod6MigjEqP" name="Nest-Hub-Max-1.jpg" alt="The Nest Hub Max sitting on a table" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dbdsrJHiobNCod6MigjEqP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>That&apos;s not to say that the current Nest Hub Max isn&apos;t desperately in need of a refresh. The display is perhaps the biggest thing in need of an upgrade, especially when compared to the Pixel Tablet. The white bezels of the Nest Hub Max display are massive and look incredibly outdated compared to the slimmer bezels on the Pixel Tablet. </p><p>The Nest Hub Max can also feel slow at times and doesn&apos;t respond to requests perfectly in others. A hardware upgrade and software improvements would be greatly appreciated by Nest Hub Max owners, and these might prepare the Nest Hub Max to move away from Google Assistant. Google appears to be <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">shifting away from Assistant and moving to Gemini</a>, and new internal components might help Gemini power a new smart display. </p><p>Google will likely take notes from the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/nest-hub-2nd-gen-review">second-generation Nest Hub</a>, which added a new sensor for tracking sleep quality. This probably doesn&apos;t matter as much on the Max because it is better suited for countertop use, but it seems like an easy inclusion.</p><p>We hope that pricing for a second-gen Nest Hub Max will remain competitive and ideally stay at $230. If there&apos;s a true and meaningful overhaul, a price of around $250 is still justifiable, but a price bump that nears $300 would overlap with the Pixel Tablet. </p>
<hr>
<p>With rumors swirling about various unreleased Google hardware products, all eyes are on Google I/O, as we expect to see at least one of them at the developer-focused event. The budget <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-live-images-show-mint-and-bay-colors">Pixel 8a</a> smartphone looks to be the most likely product to launch at I/O, but it&apos;s also possible Google surprises us with something like a Chromecast or Nest device. Even if no smart home hardware products debut, Google might discuss its software strategy at I/O instead. Either way, if you&apos;re interested in Google&apos;s smart home efforts, it&apos;s worth keeping tabs on I/O and our coverage of the mid-May event.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/possible-nest-hub-max-refresh-spotted</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A new Nest Hub Max model was identified in an update to the Google Home app, and signs point to a refresh being on the horizon. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">YrcYJxPfNEsurZdtSjPACW</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FcJ45yEJ5Fu6xYopeJU4jn.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 07:00:12 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Smart Home]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FcJ45yEJ5Fu6xYopeJU4jn.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[@tshakaarmstrong]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[nest hub max vs pixel tablet]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[nest hub max vs pixel tablet]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>