<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 18:11:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Here's how Google will help you score Black Friday deals with Shopping, Lens, and more ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Black Friday and Cyber Monday is arriving early, and we're already seeing some of the best deals of the year on our favorite products.</li><li>Google wants to help you in your holiday shopping with Google Lens and Google Shopping, both of which can tell you whether the deal you're getting is truly a good one.</li><li>The company is using the Google Shopping Graph, a database of over 45 billion product listings, to help you in your search.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>The days of standing in line on Thanksgiving night to get a first stab at Black Friday deals are (mostly) over. Black Friday and Cyber Monday now start much earlier, and many of the best deals are available online ahead of time. In fact, we're already tracking the discounts you can get today, including deals on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-amazon-black-friday-sale-has-finally-fixed-the-google-pixel-9s-price-problem">Google Pixel 9</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12-camera-impressions-why-it-replaced-my-pixel-9">OnePlus 12</a>, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/black-friday-fitbit-deals-2024-charge-sense-pixel-watch-more">Fitbit trackers</a>. But if you're someone who needs to know you're getting the absolute best deal, Google thinks it can help.</p><p>In a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.google/products/shopping/black-friday-cyber-monday-shopping-tips-2024/" target="_blank">blog post</a> today, Google shared a few tips on how to use Google Lens and Google Shopping to secure your wish list and holiday shopping goals. Both leverage the Google Shopping Graph,  a database of over 45 billion product listings. The company wants to do the hard work for you, sorting through the deals that are just okay and finding the ones that are truly outstanding.</p><p>There are plenty of price-checking tools on the web, and that's why Google Lens is there to fill in the gap when you're shopping in-store. All you need to do to check a price while you're shopping Black Friday deals in person is tap the <strong>Lens</strong> button and snap a picture of the product you're considering. Then, Google will pull up results including best prices around the web, price history, and customer reviews. The idea is that a quick price check can eliminate the possibility of getting a bad deal.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:594px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:152.53%;"><img id="ciXwt6F2dbLnDgyfafFXRY" name="Google-Lens-Shopping" alt="Scanning a product in person with Google Lens." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ciXwt6F2dbLnDgyfafFXRY.png" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="594" height="906" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It'll be even easier to do this on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a>, because <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/circle-to-searchs-fresh-look-streamlines-translation-song-recognition-and-google-lens">Lens is built right into Circle to Search</a>. Tap the navigation bar, press the button to the right of the Circle to Search pill, and tap Lens to start price checking.</p><p>Additionally, the Google Shopping site and Google app page provide similar functionality for online shoppers. There's a <strong>Google Shopping Deals </strong>page available that aggregates top deals with price comparisons and histories. There's a search bar at the top that allows users to search for the exact thing you're looking for, or curated items for easy browsing. It's kind of like Amazon, but with prices from all major online retailers. Plus, there are price histories, customer reviews, and customer images available as you do your research.</p><p>Of course, Google Ads and Google Shopping are key revenue sources for Google, and the company has a clear incentive for helping you complete your Black Friday purchases with its services. However, some users might genuinely find Google Shopping Deals and Google Lens helpful as they start deal-hunting. The ease-of-use of these services make it much simpler for people who aren't savvy at uncovering deals have a successful Black Friday and Cyber Monday.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u><strong><br></strong></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/heres-how-google-will-help-you-score-black-friday-deals-with-shopping-lens-and-more</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google wants to give you a few ideas about how to use its service to get Black Friday and Cyber Monday steals.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Y2CYyG2JmEj7S5r8rWgtn9</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9PczZrYwu4MAxM7SNCk6uT.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 17:48:36 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9PczZrYwu4MAxM7SNCk6uT.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central / Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Shopping tools for Black Friday.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Shopping tools for Black Friday.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Ditch your old wearable! This 'best runner's watch' by Garmin just got a hit with a MAJOR discount during Best Buy's Black Friday sale ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>It's officially the season of epic smartwatch deals as we approach Black Friday, and if GPS (or just running in general) is your priority, you're in luck. Best Buy is offering <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/garmin-forerunner-965-gps-smartwatch-47-mm-fiber-reinforced-polymer-carbon-gray-tlc-titanium/6544443.p?skuId=6544443" target="_blank"><strong>$100 off the Garmin Forerunner 965 GPS smartwatch</strong></a>, which is one of the few Garmin watches bearing dual-band GPS. It's also one of the more expensive smartwatches from the company, so getting it while it's on sale is highly recommended.</p><p>One of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-running-watches">best runner's watches</a> on the market, the Forerunner 965 has a beautiful AMOLED touch display that's upgraded from other Garmin models, and it also has hyper-accurate readings for both GPS and heart rate monitoring. It's a little on the heavy side, but it offers some of the best running metrics and fitness tools on the market. As for battery life, Garmin says you can expect 19 hours in dual-frequency GPS mode, or an additional extra 10 days in smartwatch mode. A ton of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/early-black-friday-garmin-deals-2024-ditch-your-old-smartwatch-and-save-big-on-forerunner-venu-and-more">Garmin deals</a> are currently available ahead of Black Friday, but this deal on the Forerunner 965 is easily one of the best.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="0ec85033-392a-4148-80a1-0b17d0ff06ae" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$599.99" data-dimension48="$599.99" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/garmin-forerunner-965-gps-smartwatch-47-mm-fiber-reinforced-polymer-carbon-gray-tlc-titanium/6544443.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="x3XC9L6qCL8KL6HswwFq78" name="Garmin Forerunner 965.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/x3XC9L6qCL8KL6HswwFq78.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Garmin Forerunner 965 GPS:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/garmin-forerunner-965-gps-smartwatch-47-mm-fiber-reinforced-polymer-carbon-gray-tlc-titanium/6544443.p?skuId=6544443" target="_blank" data-dimension112="0ec85033-392a-4148-80a1-0b17d0ff06ae" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$599.99" data-dimension48="$599.99" data-dimension25=""><del>$599.99</del> <strong>$499.99 at Best Buy for early Black Friday</strong></a></p><p>This capable smartwatch is $100 off as part of Best Buy's early Black Friday deals, marking a good deal on an otherwise expensive smartwatch. If you're looking for peak accuracy in the GPS department as well as a great smartwatch for running and fitness, this isn't a bad time to pick this one up—even if Garmin does offer a few more affordable options.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/garmin-forerunner-965-gps-smartwatch-47-mm-fiber-reinforced-polymer-carbon-gray-tlc-titanium/6544443.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="0ec85033-392a-4148-80a1-0b17d0ff06ae" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$599.99" data-dimension48="$599.99" data-dimension25="">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title"></div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">- <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare"><strong>Black Friday Google Pixel deals</strong></a><br>- <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more"><strong>Black Friday Motorola deals</strong></a><br>- <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024-early-deals-and-how-to-prepare-for-the-big-sales"><strong>Black Friday Samsung deals</strong></a><br>- <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals"><strong>Black Friday OnePlus deals</strong></a></p></div></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>you're looking for a watch that offers dual-band GPS for optimal accuracy; battery life is a major priority for you when buying a smartwatch; you want something with long lasting battery life.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if:</strong> you're looking for a smartwatch wtih AFib detection; you prefer a lightweight watch; you'd rather go with a Garmin watch with a solar upgrade for a similar MSRP.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-forerunner-965-review">Garmin Forerunner 965</a> is a solid mid-range watch offering dual-band GPS with 12 hours of dual-frequency tracking and automatic route-correction using Apple Maps data. As such, it offers hyper-accurate GPS detection, landing it a notch above Garmin's multiple lower-end watches.</p><p>There are some similarities between the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-forerunner-965-vs-265">Garmin Forerunner 965 and 265</a>, but the inclusion of dual-band GPS and the full-color topographical maps are perhaps the most significant differences—as well as a larger build and a higher price tag.</p><p>This smartwatch is particularly great for iPhone users, but it's also one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-smartwatches-and-fitness-trackers-gps">best fitness smartwatches</a> there is, especially for runners. For those into hiking, backpacking, or other longer excursions, Garmin offers up to nearly 11 days with the Forerunner 965 in smartwatch mode, or up to 19 hours in dual-frequency GPS mode.</p><p>As for downsides, the largest omission is probably the lack of AFib detection, and the fact that it's larger and thicker than some would prefer. Along with that, those who want a watch with a solar upgrade might want to consider the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-forerunner-955-review">Forerunner 955 Solar</a> instead, though it comes at the same MSRP as the 965 without features like dual-band GPS and super-accurate heart rate monitoring.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/ditch-your-old-wearable-this-best-runners-watch-by-garmin-just-got-a-hit-with-a-major-discount-during-best-buys-black-friday-sale</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The pricey Forerunner 965 just got a little more accessible.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">KPH5LceYkb3yhJD5tXywL6</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BHzsZaBRjNgGrAoHRHKkqi.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 17:08:57 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ zacharydvisconti@gmail.com (Zachary Visconti) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BHzsZaBRjNgGrAoHRHKkqi.jpeg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Garmin Forerunner 965 showing data from the CORE Body Temperature Sensor]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Garmin Forerunner 965 showing data from the CORE Body Temperature Sensor]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ First renders leak reveal Motorola’s 2025 budget phone’s familiar design ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Moto G 5G 2025 is the first budget phone from the company that is likely to launch early next year.</li><li>The leaked renders reveal a slightly upgraded design over the Moto G 5G 2024 with a new camera visor, the addition of another camera sensor, and a flat display.</li><li>The device is expected to feature a 6.6-inch display and be powered by Snapdragon 4 Gen 1 SoC.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Motorola offers some great budget phones in the market with simple designs and a great Android UI. Moto G 5G 2024 was one such phone, released early this year, and thanks to a new leak, we now know how the successor looks.</p><p>Tipster Steve Hemmerstoffer, aka OnLeaks, in conjunction with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.91mobiles.com/hub/moto-g-5g-2025-renders-complete-design-exclusive/">91mobiles</a>, has revealed the first renders of the upcoming Moto G 5G 2025. Together, they share the renders of the upcoming <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-android-phones">budget phone</a> shown from all angles. It carries a very familiar design similar to the predecessor model, which includes the notable camera module that swifly blends into the frame and back of the phone.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Hey #FutureSquad! Here comes your very first look at the #Motorola #MotoG5G2025 (360° video + sharp 5K renders + dimensions)!😏On behalf of @91mobiles 👉🏻 https://t.co/rZurqjXqFk pic.twitter.com/u5PlFjAvio<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1860297747535917187">November 23, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>At first glance, the design resembles the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/samsung-galaxy-s21-ultra-review">Galaxy S21 Ultra</a> model released in 2021. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/moto-g-5g-2024-review">Moto G 5G 2024</a> also carried the same design. However, the successor seems to incorporate more than two sensors, as opposed to the previous iteration, which featured dual rear cameras.</p><p>According to the renders, the device appears to have a sizable chin bezel at the bottom on the front, which otherwise is a traditional punch-hole display. The middle frame, on the other hand, features flat edges like most of the popular <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phones</a> currently available this year. It is also one of the few devices that still incorporates the 3.5mm headphone jack.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="fMX2mdvporc9pChFUoacoe" name="moto-g-5g-2025-renders" alt="Moto G 5G 2025 renders" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fMX2mdvporc9pChFUoacoe.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OnLeaks/ 91mobiles)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="bYhaR2bEcihtMLb7Z6Laoe" name="moto-g-5g-2025-renders" alt="Moto G 5G 2025 renders" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bYhaR2bEcihtMLb7Z6Laoe.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OnLeaks/ 91mobiles)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>According to the publication, other expected specifications include a 6.6-inch display housed in the device measuring 167.2 x 76.4 x 8.17mm (9.6mm with rear camera bump). Users can expect a 50MP primary camera, 2MP macro camera, and another sensor, which still needs to be determined. On the front, however, users can expect an 8MP selfie shooter.</p><p>The Moto G 5G 2025 will likely be powered by Snapdragon 4 Gen 1 and a 5000mAh battery underneath with support for 18W fast charging. It will at least feature 4GB of RAM and 128GB of onboard storage, which is believed to be expandable up to 1TB. With MyUX running on top, the device is expected to ship with Android 14 out of the box.</p><p>As for the launch, and going by the predecessor launch, the Moto G 5G 2025 might launch as early as the first quarter of 2025.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u><strong><br></strong></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/moto-g-5g-2025-renders-leak-revealing-its-design-and-possible-specs</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The new Moto G 5G 2025 renders reveal a new camera module that is familiar to the Galaxy S21 Ultra’s camera visor. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">aET2JQN2R8ysuk94CcD5am</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/K6vm6fMdTdUjVctXnAg3pe.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 16:13:11 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/K6vm6fMdTdUjVctXnAg3pe.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[OnLeaks/ 91mobiles]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Moto G 5G 2025 renders]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Moto G 5G 2025 renders]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ How to remove your personal information from results on Google ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Do you know what’s on the Internet about you? Many of us think we do, but do you <em>really</em> know? If you want to do a quick inventory, it’s easy through the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-search-results-about-you" target="_blank">Results about you</a> section in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-app-convenient-share-menu-android" target="_blank">Google app</a>. If you find something you don’t like and want to remove it, you can have this done as well.</p><p>It does require a process that can take up to 24 hours, potentially even longer. But once Google examines your request, if falls in line with policies, Google will remove it. This could be details about you that you want to keep private, like your phone number or address. Here’s how to review what’s out there about you and how to remove your personal information from results on Google if desired.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-remove-your-personal-information-from-results-on-google-2">How to remove your personal information from results on Google</h2>
<p>1. Open the <strong>Google app</strong> and log into your account if you aren’t already logged in.</p><p>2. Select your <strong>profile icon</strong> at the top, right.</p><p>3. Select <strong>Results about you</strong>.</p><p>4. Select <strong>Get started</strong>.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="Qg4sCS6xYNuRwzd6CQrm5W" name="Google Search personal results" alt="Google Search personal results" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Qg4sCS6xYNuRwzd6CQrm5W.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Christine Persaud / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>5. Read the How it works information page and select <strong>Next</strong>.</p><p>6. Read the next information page about What happens next and select <strong>Next</strong>.</p><p>7. Enter your name under <strong>Full name</strong>.</p><p>8. Scroll down and add at least one other Personal bit of contact information, like your <strong>address, phone number, or e-mail address</strong>. Select the <strong>“+” sign</strong> under each if you want to submit more than one entry, like a work and cell number or an old address along with your new one.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="Ee2WDHaNY26GiY22vVAd5W" name="Google Search personal results" alt="Google Search personal results" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Ee2WDHaNY26GiY22vVAd5W.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Christine Persaud / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>9. Add a check to the consent box and select <strong>Continue</strong>.</p><p>10. Choose how you want to be notified if your contact information shows up anywhere. You can select <strong>E-mail, Push notifications</strong>, or both. Select <strong>Save</strong>.</p><p>11. You’ll get a message that reads “We’re taking a look” and will receive a notification when any personal information about you is detected online. Note that this can take up to a few hours, even days. Select <strong>I’m done</strong>.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="yTiyak89sVjQ2tvY3qcQ5W" name="Google Search personal results" alt="Google Search personal results" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yTiyak89sVjQ2tvY3qcQ5W.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Christine Persaud / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>12. Once you receive a notification, look through the list of results. If there’s something you want to remove, you can do so from this same app. With some entries, you may notice that they are listed as not meeting Google’s policy for removal. This could be, for example, if the result leads to a website homepage or is considered to be “valuable to the public.”</p><p>13. For ones that <em>do</em> meet the criteria, tap the <strong>arrow to the right</strong> to open the drop-down menu to learn more.</p><p>14. If you decide you want to remove it, select <strong>Request to remove</strong>. It will then go into a queue for review by Google and you can check the status or wait for an e-mail or push notification once a decision has been made.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="dgpm82sFpCJd5rojiTkP5W" name="Google Search personal results" alt="Google Search personal results" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dgpm82sFpCJd5rojiTkP5W.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Christine Persaud / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<h2 id="how-to-remove-your-personal-results-in-google-search-2">How to remove your personal results in Google Search</h2>
<p>You can also run a Google Search on yourself to see what comes up and apply to have a result removed if it contains personal details you don’t want to disclose.</p>
<p>1. Open a Google Chrome window with <strong>Google.com</strong> and <strong>enter your name</strong>. You can also add details like your phone number or address. Hit <strong>Return</strong>.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="B8tvTV7n9Jn9SpGGyz9w3W" name="Google Search personal results" alt="Google Search personal results" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/B8tvTV7n9Jn9SpGGyz9w3W.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Christine Persaud / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>2. Scan the results. If you see one you don’t wish to come up anymore, select the <strong>More panel</strong> (three vertical dots to the right of the search result).</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="v5d3PsshJPRDCYzyyERj4W" name="Google Search personal results" alt="Google Search personal results" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/v5d3PsshJPRDCYzyyERj4W.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Christine Persaud / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>3. Select <strong>Remove result</strong>.</p><p>4. Select <strong>It shows my personal contact info</strong>.</p><p>5. Follow the steps to submit the request.</p><p>6. Select <strong>I’m done</strong>. You should receive e-mail confirmation within the next few hours and again once the request has been handled. You can see the status of these requests in the same panel of the Google Home app noted above.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="UauWrnUVrtQyDFU4rvbZ5W" name="Google Search personal results" alt="Google Search personal results" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/UauWrnUVrtQyDFU4rvbZ5W.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Christine Persaud / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<h2 id="other-important-things-to-note-2">Other important things to note</h2>
<p>As noted, Google does consider some results valuable to the public. In these instances, your request for approval might be denied. These include information on websites related to the government or education, for example, or online news or business sites. In these cases, the result may not even include the option to remove at all. But there may be instances where even results about you that you request for removal don’t fall in line with Google policies and won’t be done.</p><p>By and large, however, if it’s your private information on a site where you don’t want it to be, you should be successful in requesting removal using the Google app, one of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-apps" target="_blank">the best Android apps</a>. You can check the status of the removal request at any time after filing within the Google app. They are listed as “in progress,” “approved,” “denied,” or “undone.”</p><p>Oddly, while there’s an “undone” option, it doesn’t appear as though there’s any way to undo a removal request once you tap that button. So, make sure you fully understand what the site is and why you’re listed there before making an impulsive decision.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="4cdac39e-bbb4-4703-974e-0b280c82a63b">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tnQGJNQVqF2XVQV4KfMbN8.jpg' alt="google pixel 9 square render"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Get going with Android</strong></em></p><p>The Google app is accessible via desktop and mobile devices, including ones like the new Google Pixel 9. This entry phone in the latest line boasts tons of great features like AI smarts via Gemini, wonderful cameras, and a sleek design.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google/how-to-remove-your-personal-information-from-results-on-google</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ You can easily search for what information is on the internet about you and request to remove any results that show private and personal details. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Drg96e9Q8iEcm3HKTcBvQQ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/h8unttW8b9puUHvhqSAx5W.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 16:00:33 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ christinep2424@gmail.com (Christine Persaud) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/h8unttW8b9puUHvhqSAx5W.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Christine Persaud / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Search personal results]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Search personal results]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung’s next Galaxy Z Flip might have a surprise processor ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung’s next foldables are set for next year, with 2025 possibly bringing an Exynos chip debut in the clamshell model.</li><li>Leaks suggest the Galaxy Z Flip FE will use the Exynos 2400e, found in the Galaxy S24 FE, while the Z Flip 7 might get the Exynos 2500, Samsung’s upcoming in-house chip.</li><li>The Exynos 2500 is rumored to pack three Cortex-X925 cores, five Cortex-A725 cores, and two Cortex-A520 cores, plus an Xclipse 950 GPU.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Samsung’s next foldables are expected to drop next year, but 2025 might shake things up for the lineup with an Exynos chip debut in the clamshell model.</p><p>A leak from @Jukanlosreve on X claims that the Galaxy Z Flip FE will use the Exynos 2400e chip, also found in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-fe-hands-on">Galaxy S24 FE</a>. Interestingly, the premium <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-7">Galaxy Z Flip 7</a> might be powered by Samsung's as-yet unannounced Exynos 2500 SoC (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.gsmarena.com/samsung_galaxy_z_flip_fe_and_z_flip7_chipsets_tipped-news-65467.php" target="_blank">GSMArena</a>).</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Z Flip FE Exynos 2400e (IPoP)Z Flip 7 Exynos 2500There are rumors circulating that the Exynos 2400 might be featured in the Z Flip 7, but I do not agree with this speculation.<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1859857727251796216">November 22, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>If accurate, this is a big shift for the South Korean tech giant, as the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-6-review">Galaxy Z Flip 6</a> draws its power from Qualcomm’s Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 chip. The next model potentially running on Samsung’s in-house processor will be a first for the lineup.</p><p>Samsung's upcoming in-house SoC is rumored to pack three Cortex-X925 cores, five Cortex-A725 cores, and two Cortex-A520 cores, along with an Xclipse 950 GPU.</p><p>Even though Samsung confirmed the Exynos 2500 in a recent earnings call, details about the chip are still scarce. Early reports suggest the company is working on improving its yield rates.</p><p>It’s not out of the question for the Galaxy Z Flip 7 to use the Exynos 2500. Recent leaks suggest the Galaxy S25 will pack the Snapdragon 8 Elite, hinting that Samsung might save its flagship chip for foldables. This theory gains traction with rumors of production issues with the Exynos 2500.</p><p>Meanwhile, it’s no surprise that the Z Flip FE will feature the Exynos 2400e chip, as Samsung looks to keep costs low and stay competitive. Since the Galaxy S24 FE is using the same chip too, it makes sense for the company to choose it for its first budget flip foldable next year.</p><p>Even though it’s a stripped-down version, the Exynos 2400e is still a powerful chip that can handle everyday tasks smoothly, much like the full Exynos 2400.</p><p>We’re still in the dark about the Galaxy Z Flip 7, but we’ll probably get more clues about Samsung’s plans when the next <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-samsung-phones">Galaxy flagship phones</a> drop in the next few months.</p>
<hr>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="aa4c04ac-d34c-4ef4-8c59-97d594de8849">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FSS9nZC9Msg7kxqMaCW32Q.jpg' alt="Render of the mint Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 6"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 6</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>The Galaxy Z Flip 6 is one of the top flip phones right now, packing the best Snapdragon chip of 2024 for solid performance. Plus, it’s loaded with cool AI features like translation, transcription, and more to level up the user experience.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsungs-next-galaxy-z-flip-might-have-a-surprise-processor</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Chip details for the rumored Galaxy Z Flip FE and Z Flip 7 have been leaked. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">T68pqSrsut6AkmkhgAyc99</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/muLAZxgnWdWVKXRtcCm2bH.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 10:23:11 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/muLAZxgnWdWVKXRtcCm2bH.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Galaxy Z Flip 6 Flex Mode Panel with Instagram running]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Galaxy Z Flip 6 Flex Mode Panel with Instagram running]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ OnePlus tipped to drop a compact phone with Snapdragon 8 Elite under the hood ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Like OPPO, OnePlus is reportedly gearing up to launch a small-sized flagship phone powered by the Snapdragon 8 Elite.</li><li>The OnePlus compact phone is rumored to feature a 6.31-inch flat OLED display with 1.5K resolution.</li><li>OPPO’s Find X8 Mini is supposedly targeting early 2025, while OnePlus' compact handset is tipped to follow in Q2.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>While OPPO is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/a-mini-version-of-the-oppo-find-x8-could-be-in-the-works">rumored to be brewing a compact Find X8 model</a>, OnePlus is also tipped to be working on a small flagship for China powered by Qualcomm's Snapdragon 8 Elite.</p><p>A new leak from Digital Chat Station hints that OnePlus is developing a compact flagship (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.gizchina.com/2024/11/22/oneplus-to-launch-a-compact-phone-powered-by-snapdragon-8-elite/" target="_blank">Gizchina</a>). It’ll reportedly sport a 6.31-inch flat OLED screen with a 1.5K resolution. While small in size, this phone is rumored to go head-to-head with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">leading Android phones</a> in performance and features.</p><p>With OPPO allegedly introducing a "Mini" version of the Find X8, OnePlus jumping into the compact phone game feels like a smart move. While there’s rumor about potential competition between the two, leaks hint at enough differences to keep them from stepping on each other’s toes.</p><p>DCS says Oppo and OnePlus are aiming at different crowds with their compact phones. It’s still unclear if OnePlus’s mini flagship will join the numbered series (like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-13">OnePlus 13</a>) or the Ace lineup. Either way, OnePlus is gearing up to drop the Ace 5 and Ace 5 Pro next month, rocking the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 and Snapdragon 8 Elite chips, respectively.</p><p>There’s speculation that the compact phone might join the OnePlus Ace series, possibly debuting as the Ace 5 Pro.</p><p>Even though OPPO and OnePlus share BBK Electronics as their parent company, their compact flagships are expected to stand apart. DCS says they’ll feature unique designs and different chipsets, keeping internal competition at bay.</p><p>Details on the Find X8 Mini’s chipset are still unknown, but rumors point to the Dimensity 9400, just like the Find X8 and X8 Pro. If the OnePlus compact phone packs the Snapdragon 8 Elite, it might back up this theory.</p><p>The Find X8 Mini is rumored to arrive in early 2025, with OnePlus’s compact phone joining the party a bit later in the second half.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-tipped-to-drop-a-compact-phone-with-snapdragon-8-elite-under-the-hood</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ An upcoming OnePlus phone might be small but mighty with Snapdragon 8 Elite. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Nw2Dv74wDvrrzTyfXRmcEC</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TnosrsiAq7pT3yqVwrATZF.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 02:49:58 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TnosrsiAq7pT3yqVwrATZF.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Back of OnePlus 12 Flowy Emerald]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Back of OnePlus 12 Flowy Emerald]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Wait, what? Samsung's Galaxy Tab S9 FE just crashed to its lowest ever price for Black Friday ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>We love Samsung's FE series products, from its phones to tablets. Last year's Galaxy Tab S9 FE came in two sizes and used the same metal design as its more expensive Tab S9 siblings. Samsung has given us a killer <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-tab-s9-fe-10-9-128gb-wi-fi-with-s-pen-gray/6557719.p?skuId=6557719"><strong>Black Friday deal of just $299.99</strong></a> for the 10.9-inch Tab S9 FE's base storage variant. That's a 40% discount and going by our calculations, it's the lowest price yet for this Tab since launch.</p><p>The Galaxy Tab S9 FE boasts of a premium design, comes bundled with the S Pen, and has an IP68 rating just like the more premium <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/samsung-galaxy-tab-s9-hands-on">Galaxy Tab S9 series</a>. We've also ranked the Tab S9 FE as the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-tablets-students">best value tablet for students</a>. Just slap on a keyboard case accessory and you have yourself a portable work machine. It has a large and bright LCD display, good battery life, and a decently powerful processor.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="80bf76ad-1d66-4409-b833-878fc0bde3f8" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 FE (128GB): $449.99" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 FE (128GB): $449.99" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="UjCdiDtSQQUHp5dPF4i8tj" name="Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 FE Plus Book Cover Keyboard.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/UjCdiDtSQQUHp5dPF4i8tj.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1500" height="1500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 FE (128GB): </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-tab-s9-fe-10-9-128gb-wi-fi-with-s-pen-gray/6557719.p?skuId=6557719" data-dimension112="80bf76ad-1d66-4409-b833-878fc0bde3f8" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 FE (128GB): $449.99" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 FE (128GB): $449.99" data-dimension25=""><del>$449.99</del> <strong>$299.99 at Best Buy</strong></a></p><p>The Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 FE offers most of the features of the Tab S9, but at a lower price. Well, the price does not get lower than this Black Friday deal, taking this $449.99 tablet to a whopping $299.99. That's a sweet sweet deal for a tablet with premium looks and an IP68 rating.</p><p><strong>Price comparison: </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Samsung-Galaxy-Tab-S9-FE-10-9-Tablet-128GB-Android-Tablets-Gray/5022271252">Walmart - $304</a> | <a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/tablets/galaxy-tab-s9-fe/buy/galaxy-tab-s9-fe-128gb-gray-wi-fi-sm-x510nzaaxar/">Samsung $449.99</a><a class="view-deal button" href="" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="80bf76ad-1d66-4409-b833-878fc0bde3f8" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 FE (128GB): $449.99" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 FE (128GB): $449.99" data-dimension25="">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Black Friday</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Black Friday Google Pixel deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Black Friday Motorola deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024-early-deals-and-how-to-prepare-for-the-big-sales">Black Friday Samsung deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Black Friday OnePlus deals</a></p></div></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>You want a S Pen-compatible tablet; you need a large display that's also portable; you need IP68 dust and waterproofing.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>You want the high-contrast of an OLED panel; you need a more powerful SoC for gaming; you need an ultrawide camera.</p><p>Our <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/samsung-galaxy-tab-s9-fe-hands-on">hands-on</a> with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/samsung-galaxy-tab-s9-fe">Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 FE</a> left us feeling impressed with this new mid-range tablet. Sure, you don't get all the bells and whistles of the more premium Tab S9 series like the AMOLED panel, more powerful SoC, and so on, but the FE does enough. In fact, it's the only 11-inch tablet in Samsung's current-gen portfolio to offer an LTE option, which we too found to be a bizzare choice.</p><p>This Black Friday deal applies to the Grey and Mint trims of the Galaxy Tab S9 FE with 128GB of storage. The RAM is 6GB, which should be enough for doing basic tasks. The S Pen stylus magnetically attaches to the back of the tablet for stowing away and charging.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/wait-what-samsungs-galaxy-tab-s9-fe-just-crashed-to-its-lowest-ever-price-for-black-friday</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 FE gets you most of the features of the Tab S9, but now at the lowest ever price of just $299.99 with this crazy Black Friday deal. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">ktBEpuFYJ4n7TWFJ5yRCoh</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ctKWckFi7imNB8LD8YkbWA.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 23:08:06 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ roydon.cerejo@gmail.com (Roydon Cerejo) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ctKWckFi7imNB8LD8YkbWA.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 FE in keyboard case with Galaxy S23 FE]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 FE in keyboard case with Galaxy S23 FE]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Kindle that I use every day just got a HUGE discount during Amazon's Black Friday sale — access millions of books for just 85 bucks ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>After a lackluster showing during Prime Day a few months ago, Amazon has finally dropped some Black Friday Kindle deals worth celebrating. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CTMS6KG9"><strong>My daily driver — the lightweight and portable 16GB Amazon Kindle (2024) — just scored a 23% discount</strong></a> during Amazon&apos;s early holiday sale, knocking the price down to its lowest point ever. The deal even comes with three months of Kindle Unlimited at no additional cost, a standalone value of $35.97. </p>
<h2 id="grab-this-apos-cheap-and-cheerful-apos-e-reader-for-only-84-99-during-amazon-apos-s-black-friday-sale-2">Grab this &apos;cheap and cheerful&apos; e-reader for only $84.99 during Amazon&apos;s Black Friday sale</h2>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="812ac165-a206-4bdb-b462-5844831b475b" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Amazon Kindle (2024) 16GB: $109.99" data-dimension48="Amazon Kindle (2024) 16GB: $109.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CTMS6KG9" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1462px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:102.60%;"><img id="ThUg5QjL2rhGkuWVVAjdUD" name="amazon-kindle-2024-official-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ThUg5QjL2rhGkuWVVAjdUD.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1462" height="1500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Amazon Kindle (2024) 16GB: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CTMS6KG9" data-dimension112="812ac165-a206-4bdb-b462-5844831b475b" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Amazon Kindle (2024) 16GB: $109.99" data-dimension48="Amazon Kindle (2024) 16GB: $109.99"><del>$109.99</del> <strong>$84.99, plus three months of Kindle Unlimited at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>Lightweight and versatile, the 11th-gen Amazon Kindle boasts a bright 6-inch display with 16GB of storage for all of your favorite titles, plus a built-in light for anywhere reading, Bluetooth support for audiobooks, and up to six weeks of battery life on a single charge. This version also comes with a free three-month subscription to Kindle Unlimited, so you'll have instant access to millions of e-books at no additional cost. </p>
<p>There are other <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-amazon-kindle">Kindle e-readers</a> to consider if you want a bigger screen or more features, but if you just need something simple to throw into a bag when traveling, this device is pretty perfect. </p>
<p>👀<strong>Alternate Black Friday deal: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CFPJYX7P"><strong>Get 19% off the Kindle Paperwhite (2024) during Amazon's Black Friday sale!</strong></a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CTMS6KG9" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="812ac165-a206-4bdb-b462-5844831b475b" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Amazon Kindle (2024) 16GB: $109.99" data-dimension48="Amazon Kindle (2024) 16GB: $109.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Black Friday deals</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Black Friday Google Pixel deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Black Friday Motorola deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024">Black Friday Samsung deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Black Friday OnePlus deals</a></p></div></div>
<p>Now, to be clear: I&apos;m a big advocate of physical books and I <em>strongly </em>recommend that you spend some money at your local independent bookstore this holiday season — but if you travel a lot like me, it&apos;s hard to beat the convenience of the Amazon Kindle (2024), especially at this price. </p><p>Boot up this e-reader and you&apos;ll get instant access to a vast library of books on a 6-inch, anti-glare display that you can use in any light, thanks to the adjustable built-in screen light. You also get audiobook support via Bluetooth, some incredible battery life, and a durable construction that&apos;s supposed to be waterproof (although I haven&apos;t tested that myself). 16GB of onboard storage also means that you can easily carry thousands of titles with you wherever you go.</p><p>One drawback is that this particular model is ad-supported, which means you&apos;ll have to deal with the occasional banner ad on your lock screen. They won&apos;t show up when you&apos;re reading though, which is good enough for me, but you&apos;ll have to consider if it&apos;s worth paying a bit more to go completely ad-free. </p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/the-kindle-that-i-use-every-day-just-got-a-huge-discount-during-amazons-black-friday-sale-access-millions-of-books-for-just-85-bucks</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Amazon is slashing prices on its entire lineup of Kindle e-readers for Black Friday, including my favorite.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">5TLAZkhPwfZhj9RrfFeGWZ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VGkcGKUtKNEbERvAvE2efK.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 21:00:51 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VGkcGKUtKNEbERvAvE2efK.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Amazon]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Amazon Kindle 2024 lifestyle render]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Amazon Kindle 2024 lifestyle render]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The 'best and most powerful' Android tablet of 2023 just scored a ridiculous discount during Best Buy's Black Friday sale ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Early Black Friday tablet deals have already started making the rounds online, and this next pick is a great option if you want something particularly powerful. Best Buy has launched <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-tab-s9-ultra-14-6-256gb-wi-fi-with-s-pen-graphite/6546675.p?skuId=6546675" target="_blank"><strong>$400 off the price of the 256GB Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 Ultra</strong></a> as part of its Black Friday event, offering a great tablet that'll usually net you well over $1,000.</p><p>Despite recently dropping into last-gen status, the S9 Ultra is a great pick for those who want a tablet with a massive 14.6-inch screen that can easily be used as if it were a laptop. The Galaxy Tab S9 Ultra offers industry-leading performance, backed by 12GB of RAM and a Snapdragon 8 Gen 2 processor, and it also comes with the first-party Samsung S Pen stylus.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="01d76918-3e60-4ce8-9ad0-b4ca5a6d29de" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,199.99" data-dimension48="$1,199.99" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-tab-s9-ultra-14-6-256gb-wi-fi-with-s-pen-graphite/6546675.p?skuId=6546675" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="JMTXKhVNg82E88fw5tk8Cm" name="samsung-galaxy-tab-s9-ultra-render-space.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JMTXKhVNg82E88fw5tk8Cm.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 Ultra (256GB):</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-tab-s9-ultra-14-6-256gb-wi-fi-with-s-pen-graphite/6546675.p?skuId=6546675" target="_blank" data-dimension112="01d76918-3e60-4ce8-9ad0-b4ca5a6d29de" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,199.99" data-dimension48="$1,199.99" data-dimension25=""><del>$1,199.99</del><strong> $799.99 at Best Buy</strong></a></p><p>The Galaxy Tab S9 Ultra is one of the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-tablets">best Android tablets </a>out there, offering performance and speed enough to replace just about any work laptop. This $400 discount at Best Buy might just be a good excuse to add this to your device lineup, especially if you were already eyeing tablets at the premium end of the spectrum.</p><p>This S9 Ultra comes with 256GB of storage, or expandable storage of up to 1TB with a microSD card. It also features the useful Samsung S Pen, and a huge AMOLED display that users love.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-tab-s9-ultra-14-6-256gb-wi-fi-with-s-pen-graphite/6546675.p?skuId=6546675" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="01d76918-3e60-4ce8-9ad0-b4ca5a6d29de" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,199.99" data-dimension48="$1,199.99" data-dimension25="">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Black Friday deals</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">- <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare"><strong>Black Friday Google Pixel deals</strong></a><br>- <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more"><strong>Black Friday Motorola deals</strong></a><br>- <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024-early-deals-and-how-to-prepare-for-the-big-sales"><strong>Black Friday Samsung deals</strong></a><br>- <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals"><strong>Black Friday OnePlus deals</strong></a></p></div></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>you're looking for a tablet with super powerful performance, or for something you can use as a laptop for work; you want a tablet that comes with a stylus; having a massive screen on your tablet is a priority for you.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>you can afford to buy the new Galaxy Tab S10 Ultra; you want a tablet that's lightweight and easy to transport; you're screen-sensitive and need a tablet with solid PWM settings; you need something that can be used with your cell carrier's network.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/samsung-galaxy-tab-s9-ultra-review">Galaxy Tab S9 Ultra</a> is so clearly a premium tablet, boasting some of the best specs available on a modern device. While it's normally priced at $1,200, the extra 25% off from Best Buy makes it a solid competitor with lower-level tablets, but without sacrificing performance.</p><p>This model features 256GB of storage or the ability to increase that up to 1TB using a microSD card. This potential laptop replacement's performance is supported by the crazy-fast Qualcomm Snapdragon 8 Gen 2 processor, 12GB of RAM, offering smooth gaming performance, and ease-of-use for power-intensive work applications. Users also love the 14.6-inch AMOLED display, which features a 120Hz refresh rate.</p><p>Additionally, this tablet has IP68 water and dust resistance, and comes with the S Pen stylus, the latter of which has been a big selling point for some buyers over the years.</p><p>It's worth noting that this may not be a great pick for those who prefer a small or affordable laptop, or for those who need a headphone jack. The display also doesn't have good PWM offerings, nor does the tablet have cellular connectivity—both of which could be a dealbreaker for some.</p><p>In any case, if you're a casual user, you may consider going with a more affordable option from Samsung, while those looking for the best of the best need look no further.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/the-best-and-most-powerful-android-tablet-of-2023-just-scored-a-ridiculous-discount-during-best-buys-black-friday-sale</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Ditch your laptop and grab Samsung's Galaxy Tab S9 Ultra for under $1,000. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">K7ZnQFVtmq6NhxoxQ9SV9R</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3esUEUYz2evESyBvf85Ek6.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 19:14:41 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ zacharydvisconti@gmail.com (Zachary Visconti) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3esUEUYz2evESyBvf85Ek6.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The metal back of the Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 Ultra]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The metal back of the Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 Ultra]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Polar Vantage M3 has premium guts in a mid-range package — with one key flaw ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Sunday Runday</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="rV2GgqHS9nqccNipGMkWqB" name="lloyd-break-dancing.jpg" caption="" alt="Lloyd, the Android Central mascot, break-dancing" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rV2GgqHS9nqccNipGMkWqB.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">In this <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/sunday-runday">weekly column</a>, Android Central Wearables Editor Michael Hicks talks about the world of wearables, apps, and fitness tech related to running and health, in his quest to get faster and more fit.</p></div></div>
<p>The Polar Vantage M3 is the brand's first affordable AMOLED watch, after the $599 Vantage V3 and $749 Grit X2 Pro first shed off the old MIP standard. The $399 M3 shares their 4th-gen Elixir OHR and dual-band GPS, meaning it should offer reliable accuracy on par with Polar's flagships.</p><p>I decided to put this to the test! Despite the rainy weather and coming down with a cold, I took the Polar Vantage M3 on several runs, long walks, and a track run over the past couple of weeks, comparing the results against the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-fenix-8-review">Garmin Fenix 8</a>'s dual-band GPS, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/coros-heart-rate-monitor-review">COROS HRM armband</a>, and the Polar H10 chest strap.</p><p>When I <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/coros-vertix-2s-vs-garmin-forerunner-965-vs-polar-vantage-v3-fitness-test">pitted the Vantage V3 against flagship Garmin and COROS watches</a>, it fell a bit short for GPS accuracy (while still doing better than a GPS-only watch) and was fairly accurate for HR data compared to a chest strap. So I was curious to see how the mid-range Vantage <strong>M3</strong> would do with similar hardware.</p><p>Turns out the Polar Vantage M3 is quite reliable for GPS, but a little less reliable for heart rate accuracy in some cases. Still, the mid-range M3 is already making the flagship V3 look a little overpriced by offering the same experience for less.</p>
<h2 id="polar-vantage-m3-gps-accuracy-2">Polar Vantage M3 GPS accuracy</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="hMJwK564rYFDf9bpcAxKFG" name="Polar-Vantage-M3-Garmin-Fenix-8-distance" alt="The Polar Vantage M3 and Garmin Fenix 8 showing similar run distance summaries" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hMJwK564rYFDf9bpcAxKFG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I used the Fenix 8 as a location accuracy control group because Garmin's dual-band GPS tends to lead the industry for dependable results in my tests. The mid-range <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/coros-pace-pro-gps-and-hr-accuracy-test">COROS PACE Pro</a> did surprisingly well against it in my accuracy test earlier this month, so I had high hopes that the Vantage M3 could do equally well.</p>

<p>I'm sorry that so many of my tests were short jogs — which tend to be too short to reveal discrepancies — or long walks that are usually too slow-paced to challenge the antenna's full abilities. I didn't get to go on a hike for proper elevation testing or accuracy on a tree-obscured route, either.</p><p>From what I was able to test, however, the Vantage M3 did respectably well, always falling closely within the same margins as the Garmin watch for a long run.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 7</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="qZUcVSYMYBYg8B9KmJUf8D" name="Polar-Vantage-M3-vs-Garmin-Fenix-8-GPS-accuracy-test-1" alt="A Google Maps satellite view showing how the Polar Vantage M3 (orange line) and Garmin Fenix 8 (blue line) compared for GPS accuracy during a run." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qZUcVSYMYBYg8B9KmJUf8D.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 7</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="kRvzodqDPANpFABt2d4zCD" name="Polar-Vantage-M3-vs-Garmin-Fenix-8-GPS-accuracy-test-2" alt="A Google Maps satellite view showing how the Polar Vantage M3 (orange line) and Garmin Fenix 8 (blue line) compared for GPS accuracy during a run." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kRvzodqDPANpFABt2d4zCD.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 7</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="GADUVBjddvJmMMA2jxiWCD" name="Polar-Vantage-M3-vs-Garmin-Fenix-8-GPS-accuracy-test-3" alt="A Google Maps satellite view showing how the Polar Vantage M3 (orange line) and Garmin Fenix 8 (blue line) compared for GPS accuracy during a run." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GADUVBjddvJmMMA2jxiWCD.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 4 of 7</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="8mX5i77sLbAXM3VtLg5xFD" name="Polar-Vantage-M3-vs-Garmin-Fenix-8-GPS-accuracy-test-4" alt="A Google Maps satellite view showing how the Polar Vantage M3 (orange line) and Garmin Fenix 8 (blue line) compared for GPS accuracy during a run." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8mX5i77sLbAXM3VtLg5xFD.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 5 of 7</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="Y9MssH7TaUrEFkt26GbQ6D" name="Polar-Vantage-M3-vs-Garmin-Fenix-8-GPS-accuracy-test-5" alt="A Google Maps satellite view showing how the Polar Vantage M3 (orange line) and Garmin Fenix 8 (blue line) compared for GPS accuracy during a run." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Y9MssH7TaUrEFkt26GbQ6D.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 6 of 7</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="jtUSYkTdC58tYg3iC3ZsFD" name="Polar-Vantage-M3-vs-Garmin-Fenix-8-GPS-accuracy-test-6" alt="A Google Maps satellite view showing how the Polar Vantage M3 (orange line) and Garmin Fenix 8 (blue line) compared for GPS accuracy during a run." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jtUSYkTdC58tYg3iC3ZsFD.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 7 of 7</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="oGetWp6k4oSaCxRrNzbJ2D" name="Polar-Vantage-M3-vs-Garmin-Fenix-8-GPS-accuracy-test-7" alt="A Google Maps satellite view showing how the Polar Vantage M3 (orange line) and Garmin Fenix 8 (blue line) compared for GPS accuracy during a run." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oGetWp6k4oSaCxRrNzbJ2D.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>If you look more closely at the GPS map between the Vantage M3 (<em>orange line</em>) and Fenix 8 (<em>blue</em>) for my most recent 10K run above, there are a few instances where the Vantage M3 drifts slightly into the street or buildings, with the same unprompted zig-zagging and hard angles as the dual-frequency <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/suunto-race-review">Suunto Race</a>, as well as some issues with underpasses that the Fenix 8 didn't encounter.</p><p>Thankfully, the Vantage M3 has fewer gaffes than Suunto and does perfectly well in normal conditions, sticking to the correct side of my local trail. And for my track run below, it didn't stick perfectly to the first lane, but that's something every watch I've tested struggles with; Polar's result is actually among the best I've seen among dual-band watches.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="wsEJnPPDbDRcnjtw4k5gDD" name="Polar-Vantage-M3-vs-Garmin-Fenix-8-GPS-accuracy-test-8" alt="A Google Maps satellite view showing how the Polar Vantage M3 (orange line) matched up to a track run completed in lane 1." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wsEJnPPDbDRcnjtw4k5gDD.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While I couldn't do a proper hike, my walk along another nearby trail was illuminating. In the screenshots below, you'll see how the Vantage M3 (now the blue line) does perfectly well on the unimpeded stretches, but under tree cover, you'll see a lot more wavering in short stretches where I was walking straight ahead (and Garmin's orange line is usually more consistent). My total distance was only two-hundredths apart, though, so most people won't mind.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="PwLzgWMrBPY8trNzxfKhBn" name="Polar-Vantage-M3-vs-Garmin-Fenix-8-GPS-accuracy-test-walking-1" alt="A Google Maps satellite view showing how the Polar Vantage M3 (blue line) and Garmin Fenix 8 (orange line) compared for GPS accuracy during a run." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PwLzgWMrBPY8trNzxfKhBn.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="DFqoLpDVuYrdMvm6qgJgHn" name="Polar-Vantage-M3-vs-Garmin-Fenix-8-GPS-accuracy-test-walking-4" alt="A Google Maps satellite view showing how the Polar Vantage M3 (blue line) and Garmin Fenix 8 (orange line) compared for GPS accuracy during a run." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DFqoLpDVuYrdMvm6qgJgHn.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="mSW8w28U5LVtxKgqgqtT8n" name="Polar-Vantage-M3-vs-Garmin-Fenix-8-GPS-accuracy-test-walking-2" alt="A Google Maps satellite view showing how the Polar Vantage M3 (blue line) and Garmin Fenix 8 (orange line) compared for GPS accuracy during a run." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mSW8w28U5LVtxKgqgqtT8n.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 4 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="xEws8aktpXaLeaoZ9ce3Dn" name="Polar-Vantage-M3-vs-Garmin-Fenix-8-GPS-accuracy-test-walking-3" alt="A Google Maps satellite view showing how the Polar Vantage M3 (blue line) and Garmin Fenix 8 (orange line) compared for GPS accuracy during a run." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xEws8aktpXaLeaoZ9ce3Dn.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Overall, I think people will be happy with the Vantage M3's location accuracy, especially for its price. What's perhaps more interesting is how Garmin and Polar consistently track running power, training load, and steps per minute differently.</p><p>I'm inclined to trust Garmin over Polar for steps; Garmin has <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/step-counting-accuracy-test">won several step-counting accuracy tests</a>, and Garmin, Apple, COROS, and Fitbit all closely matched on total steps and cadence across a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/what-i-learned-running-20-mile-race-wearing-four-watches">20-mile, four-watch test</a>.</p><p>But I've noticed in the past how <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-training-load-focus-needs-one-obvious-fix">Garmin training load</a> seems to underestimate walks and overestimate track workouts, while Polar separates cardio and muscle load in a way that feels more sophisticated and accurate to my effort level — aside from the grossly-underestimated track load. And running power has always felt like an arbitrary metric that varies by brand, so I don't put much stock in it.</p>
<h2 id="polar-vantage-m3-hr-accuracy-2">Polar Vantage M3 HR accuracy</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="QGFAkPhHaMb8qznfF6PDFG" name="Polar-Vantage-M3-Garmin-Fenix-8-heart-rate" alt="The Polar Vantage M3 and Garmin Fenix 8 sitting side by side, showing similar heart rate averages" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QGFAkPhHaMb8qznfF6PDFG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>My Polar Vantage M3 heart rate results gave me whiplash. For most normal runs, it delivered consistent HR averages, if all slightly below my external HRMs. But my  track run results were disappointing and my walk data showed the correct averages but was bizarrely wild on the graphs.</p>

<p>For every run except one two-mile jog, the Polar Vantage M3 was 1 bpm short of my optical arm band or my Polar ECG. In the two HR graphs below (hit the magnification button), you can see how the purple Garmin graph sits slightly above the pinker Polar one at most points, aside from when my effort dips and Polar is slower to drop.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2083px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:45.56%;"><img id="LcV6cscwvYVmtbx6AkY2mV" name="Polar-Vantage-M3-HR-test-10K" alt="HR chart showing how the Polar Vantage M3 4th-gen OHR compares against the Polar H10 chest strap" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LcV6cscwvYVmtbx6AkY2mV.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2083" height="949" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2196px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:48.59%;"><img id="8KsxnbEBkgfjFEURY4cWnV" name="Polar-Vantage-M3-HR-test-jog" alt="HR chart showing how the Polar Vantage M3 4th-gen OHR compares against the COROS HRM armband" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8KsxnbEBkgfjFEURY4cWnV.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2196" height="1067" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>There's normally a delay between wrist- and arm-based optical monitors or chest straps, but a solid <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-smartwatches-fitness">fitness watch</a> should still average out to the same result in the end. I'd like to see Polar figure out its algorithm to close the small gap, but 1 bpm isn't a major issue and it's still in the right ballpark.</p><p>What's slightly weirder is looking at my two walking activity charts. Polar really struggled to stay close to my fluctuating heart rate for both activities, with a 5–10 bpm gap above or below my actual HR for sustained stretches.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2196px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:49.04%;"><img id="dGmjKRKLbFHGBA2VMzrUuV" name="Polar-Vantage-M3-HR-test-5-mile-walk" alt="HR chart showing how the Polar Vantage M3 4th-gen OHR compares against the COROS HRM armband" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dGmjKRKLbFHGBA2VMzrUuV.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2196" height="1077" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2026px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:54.69%;"><img id="6H2c5rYa9xAPpqyvRUohoV" name="Polar-Vantage-M3-HR-test-4-mile-walk" alt="HR chart showing how the Polar Vantage M3 4th-gen OHR compares against the COROS HRM armband" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6H2c5rYa9xAPpqyvRUohoV.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2026" height="1108" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>They ended up averaging out to identical or close bpm averages for 6- and 4-mile walks; so again, perhaps you won't care about the difference. But that may have been luck more than everything else; I noticed this <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://the5krunner.com/2024/10/23/polar-vantage-m3-review-pros-cons/" target="_blank">5Krunner HR accuracy test</a> did fine for most runs but had bizarrely inflated HR totals for a calm walk. So I'm hoping this is an area where the Polar algorithm can improve with time.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure pull-right inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1059px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:102.27%;"><img id="ET8ipiebLzPTcQ2r7SSdhV" name="Polar-Vantage-M3-HR-test-track-run" alt="HR chart showing how the Polar Vantage M3 4th-gen OHR compares against the COROS HRM armband" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ET8ipiebLzPTcQ2r7SSdhV.jpg" mos="" align="right" fullscreen="1" width="1059" height="1083" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pull-right expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class="pull-right inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>As for my track workout, I can only show a portion of the graph because it somehow got fully misaligned in-between lap pauses about halfway through, so the results were needlessly confusing. This portion gives you a glimpse of what to expect, though: a few beats short at most points, dipping as low as <em>20 bpm</em> under at one point, and overestimating my max by a few beats. Basically, it's all over the place.</p><p>I'm going to do an unpaused track run for my full Vantage M3 review, to avoid any weird issues with flat, skewed results. But even with this incomplete test, I feel like the Vantage M3 could have done much better in that initial snapshot. If I were a serious athlete trying to track anaerobic effort, I'd probably buy an external monitor to pair with my Vantage M3.</p>
<h2 id="the-polar-vantage-m3-holds-its-own-2">The Polar Vantage M3 holds its own</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="iTYcFRYi9nG36jNEB4uqqF" name="Polar-Vantage-M3-running-power" alt="The Polar Vantage M3 showing a post-run summary of running power and muscle load" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/iTYcFRYi9nG36jNEB4uqqF.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>There's a new category of AMOLED <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-running-watches">running watches</a> that cost about the same as an Apple Watch or Pixel Watch but offer a serious leg up for training metrics, battery life, and accuracy.</p><p>If I had to choose between the COROS PACE Pro ($349), Suunto Race S ($349), Polar Vantage M3 ($399), and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-forerunner-265-review">Garmin Forerunner 265</a> ($449), I'd have a seriously tough decision on my hands — but I'd also feel like I couldn't go wrong with any one choice.</p><p>With the Vantage M3 in particular, I appreciate its lightweight and thin design, Strava route and Komoot directions integration, full suite of sensors like ECG and skin temp, and default topo maps.</p><p>Its 7-day battery life is on the short side for a running watch, and I'm not the biggest fan of Polar Flow as a companion app, but it doesn't feel like a major downgrade from the pricier <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/polar-vantage-v3-review">Vantage V3</a>, with similar perks like its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/why-i-love-polars-manual-vo2-max-and-recovery-tests">useful VO2 Max and orthostatic tests</a> and comparable accuracy. While I've yet to review it fully, the Vantage M3 looks more compelling than the V3 for sheer value.</p><p>I just wish it was a little more accurate for anaerobic runs or low-effort aerobic.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="d5a28e82-6299-46bc-a7ff-f5260c4393b7">
            <a href="https://www.amazon.com/POLAR-Vantage-Dual-Frequency-Turn-Turn/dp/B0DJGS6875?th=1" data-model-name="Vantage M3"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:107.07%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QWau822qJNDFHnGfitEBBi.jpg' alt="Render of the Polar Vantage M3"></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Polar Vantage M3</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Mid-range running excellence</strong></em></p><p>While the Polar Vantage M3 is cheaper than the Vantage V3, it has the same water resistance, health sensors, multi-band GPS, training and recovery software, fitness tests, topographical maps, and limited smart tools for $200 less. It has a shorter battery life, a smaller display, and cheaper materials, but it's otherwise a more compelling option for most runners.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/polar-vantage-m3-gps-hr-accuracy-test</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The new Polar Vantage M3 is an intriguing mid-range running watch; I put its GPS and HR accuracy to the test against Garmin and COROS. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">2sYLQj3bKuBs7u7BT7Vpub</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3xx4EYqgDotrKcGU9kFUoF.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 18:11:11 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3xx4EYqgDotrKcGU9kFUoF.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Polar Vantage M3 sitting atop a benchtop, showing a post-run summary for a 10K.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Polar Vantage M3 sitting atop a benchtop, showing a post-run summary for a 10K.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>