<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 16:59:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ These sustainable tech brands should be on your radar ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Gadget Weekly</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="DZLQ4jKZk9tEF5A3sqU5Jh" name="inspector-lloyd-square.jpg" caption="" alt="Inspector Lloyd" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DZLQ4jKZk9tEF5A3sqU5Jh.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">Join Namerah Saud Fatmi as she explores the cool, quirky, and sometimes downright odd world of smartphone accessories, gadgets, and other nerdy toys <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/gadget-weekly">every week</a>.</p></div></div>
<p>Earth Day is just one day out of 365 each year, but it&apos;s an excellent reminder to adopt permanent changes in our lives that benefit the planet. The tech world is anything but eco-friendly by nature, but many companies have been trying to offset the negative ecological impact of their operations and existence.</p><p>Sustainability in the tech industry has many faces, but it&apos;s important that we&apos;re not just sold marketing gibberish to convince us that a company is going green. There must be actual change and betterment, not just a bunch of PR fluff and mini-projects that do nothing for the environment or anyone else.</p><p>For instance, it doesn&apos;t help the world much if your phone brand of choice uses paper packaging and doesn&apos;t give chargers, but it&apos;s still sourcing finite sources and materials from non-environmentally friendly or unethical sources.</p>
<p>A great way to be a sustainable tech user is by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-refurbished-phones">buying refurbished phones</a> and recycling your used devices. You can also donate your older gadgets and accessories to others. If you absolutely must have a new phone though, try to prioritize buying from brands that make a difference. And while you&apos;re at it, learn <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/amazon/how-to-shop-sustainably-amazon">how to shop sustainably</a> as well.</p><p>It&apos;s very hard to rank or list out all the most sustainable and eco-friendly and recycling your used devices. Fortunately, there are some companies that are very clear and open in the way they are adopting greener practices and decisions. To make things easier for our conscious readers, here are some of the most notable sustainable tech accessories brands that should be on your radar.</p>
<h2 id="fairphone-2">Fairphone</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="8WSNrkRL3BMvriuYCvwYAn" name="Fairphone-4-lifestyle.jpg" alt="Fairphone 4 with its back panel removed" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8WSNrkRL3BMvriuYCvwYAn.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Jerry Hildenbrand / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Fairphone is the most sustainable smartphone brand in the world. Not only does the Dutch phone manufacturer use recycled and eco-friendly materials in the making of its devices, but it also <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.fairphone.com/en/impact/fair-materials/"><u>sources ethically</u></a> and designs its phones to be both self-repairable and upgradeable.</p><p>This means that a Fairphone device, such as the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/fairphone-4-review"><u>Fairphone 4</u></a>, can easily be fixed if broken and bumped up to updated new specs without the need to ditch the entire device if it gets damaged. The prices are reasonable, too, and you get plenty of accessories with the brand&apos;s phones.</p><p>But most impressive is the fact that Fairphone supports its smartphones for a long time, like the Fairphone 2, which received <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/fairphone-2-final-update"><u>software support for roughly seven years</u></a>. This was during a time when phone manufacturers like Samsung and Google had only supported phones for <em>up to</em> five years. </p>
<h2 id="teracube-2">Teracube</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="R7HeDHowZ3GrurDCd6fjCQ" name="teracube-2e-rear-open-2.jpg" alt="Teracube 2e held in one hand with its rear open" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/R7HeDHowZ3GrurDCd6fjCQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Jeramy Johnson / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Teracube takes a leaf out of Fairphone&apos;s book and uses recycled materials as well as discarded e-waste in the production of its devices. On top of that, Teracube promises a four-year guarantee for all of its products. This includes water damage, a cracked display, aging batteries, and more. Before Fairphone arrived in the US, Teracube was the<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-sustainable-repairable-phones"> <u>most sustainable and easily repairable phone</u></a> in the region and is still a good option for anyone looking for an affordable phone. </p>
<h2 id="ifixit-2">iFixit</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3023px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.20%;"><img id="hjLTAjvubj6YzkwJSiY28n" name="Google-Pixel-6-repair-ifitix.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 6 Pro repair" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hjLTAjvubj6YzkwJSiY28n.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3023" height="1699" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: iFitix via Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Repairability is crucial to sustainability because it encourages users to fix their own devices when they break instead of discarding them and buying new products. Android Central&apos;s Jerry Hildenbrand points out how companies often ignore repairability when it&apos;s something they should highlight when talking about sustainability. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-right-to-repair-stance">right-to-repair</a> movement advocates for easier repairability as well as more easily accessible tools and instructions to achieve this.</p><p>iFixit provides a key service in this category, selling comprehensive toolkits and providing how-tos and guides to help the average consumer repair their own gadgets. Holding on to your current electronics as long as you can prevents more e-waste from ending up in landfills or being shipped off to third-world countries, where it eventually ends up polluting the earth anyway.</p><p>iFixit has even teamed up with Google to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/ifixit-begins-selling-official-googles-pixel-8-series-parts-and-tools-for-at-home-repairs">provide official parts</a> for devices like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-review">Pixel 8</a> and more.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-2">Samsung</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1472px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.18%;"><img id="zyPHFrNwQTgp67msjRhxUi" name="s23-series-sustainability-169.JPG" alt="Samsung Galaxy S23 sustainability" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zyPHFrNwQTgp67msjRhxUi.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1472" height="827" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Samsung)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Believe it or not, Samsung has made strides when it comes to the company&apos;s sustainable efforts. It started out with the Korean tech giant reducing and offsetting its carbon footprint. Eventually, the company got more creative and we saw less plastic and more paper packaging, shipping boxes that come with instructions to convert them into things like cat trees, and the disappearance of the power brick inside phone boxes.</p><p>With the launch of the Samsung <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s23-review">Galaxy S23</a> series, Samsung unveiled its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-is-samsungs-galaxy-for-the-planet-initiative">&apos;Galaxy for the Planet&apos;</a> initiative. The S23 lineup was Samsung&apos;s most sustainable lineup to date at the time, built with 22% recycled glass for the screen, 100% recycled paper packaging, 80% recycled PET, and 20% recycled plastic. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/mobile/galaxy-s24-samsungs-first-flagship-phones-with-recycled-cobalt-are-here/">S24 family is even more eco-friendly</a> than its predecessor, using materials such as recycled cobalt.</p><p>On top of all that, you still have Samsung&apos;s commitment to minimize its carbon footprint across the board, from manufacturing and production to distribution and sales. At Galaxy Unpacked 2023, Samsung went as far as pledging to achieve net zero carbon emissions in all consumer product operations by the end of 2030.</p>
<h2 id="casetify-2">CASETiFY</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4133px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="JXSu95WzksYSQKRvCRWoUb" name="casetify-google-pixel-6-4.jpg" alt="CASETiFY Google Pixel 6 cases on a table" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JXSu95WzksYSQKRvCRWoUb.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4133" height="2325" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Once you go down the eco-friendly line, you&apos;ll discover that there are plenty of sustainable tech brands in the accessories sector as well. CASETiFY is an exemplary example. Not only does the famous case maker reuse its own used cases and accessories to create new ones, but it also enables its own users to voluntarily send in their used products for free. This is part of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.casetify.com/sustainability">Re/CASETiFY</a> program, under which the brand aims to eliminate the need to source any new plastic by 2030.</p><p>CASETiFY also employs eco-friendly and sustainable tactics in its operations and donates $1 out of every sale made on Earth Day to plant a tree. To date, CASETiFY has planted over 463,406 trees and prevented more than 84,000 kilos of plastic from being dumped in the ocean or landfills. If you own a case or accessory from the brand, note the inscription on the side that indicates the percentage of recycled materials used to make the product. For phone cases, it&apos;s usually around 65%, which is an impressive number.</p>
<h2 id="pela-2">Pela</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4299px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="WZvNxwBke7iD9qdG9ekQ6Q" name="Pela-cases-lifestyle-1.jpg" alt="Pela case" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WZvNxwBke7iD9qdG9ekQ6Q.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4299" height="2418" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/pela-cases-hands-on-a-love-letter-to-mother-nature">Pela</a> might not be as popular as some of the other names on this list, but don&apos;t let that hold you back. The brand makes completely biodegradable and compostable phone cases for popular brands like Apple, Samsung, and Google. Every single product made by Pela can be buried in your backyard and become one with the soil eventually, including the grips and wallet add-ons. Oh and if you don&apos;t know how to repurpose or compost your phone case, we have a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/how-to-reuse-repurpose-or-recycle-your-old-phone-cases">handy guide</a> for that.</p>
<h2 id="going-green-isn-apos-t-as-hard-as-it-used-to-be-when-it-comes-to-tech-2">Going green isn&apos;t as hard as it used to be when it comes to tech</h2>
<p>Whether you want a sustainable and repairable phone fit for a purist or a more traditional device that&apos;s good for the flowers, it&apos;s a lot easier to find good picks nowadays.</p><p>Fairphone and Teracube are fantastic brands that embrace the green initiative through and through. But it&apos;s even nicer to see big brands like Samsung start to take things seriously. Hopefully, future <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-samsung-phones">Galaxy phones</a> and other electronics will have an even higher percentage of recycled materials.</p><p>Apart from CASETiFY and Pela, there are plenty more <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-environmentally-friendly-phone-accessories">environmentally-friendly phone accessories</a> to consider. These two are the most reputable of the bunch and I have tested their products, which is why I highly recommend them.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/sustainable-tech-brands-to-look-out-for</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ In honor of Earth Day, I have rounded up a set of the most prominent sustainable brands in the tech industry that actually make a difference. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">HYZtRTWMd3iFKGuCowQS8d</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NyUaLQLXBdj7gqd7yCWyqH.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 15:07:44 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NyUaLQLXBdj7gqd7yCWyqH.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Samsung]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung repurposing ocean plastics graphic]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung repurposing ocean plastics graphic]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Razer Kishi Ultra offers everything to turn you into a pro mobile gamer ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Razer has announced the Kishi Ultra and an updated version of the Kishi V2.</li><li>The Kishi Ultra features a USB-C port and can be expanded to fit devices up to the size of the iPad Mini.</li><li>This new controller offers "Pro Grade Ergonomics" along with "Sensa HD Haptics" and can even be used to play games on your PC.</li><li>Pricing starts at $149 for the Ultra and $99 for the updated Kishi V2, with both controllers available now.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>If there&apos;s one thing that we know for sure, it&apos;s that people love to play games on their phones or tablets. There are already a plethora of great controllers out there, but the Razer Kishi Ultra might just top them all.</p><p>This <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.razer.com/mobile-controllers/razer-kishi-ultra">new controller</a> hopes to turn you into a pro with its ergonomic design and a long list of standout features. Getting the mundane stuff out of the way first, the Ultra connects to any of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a> via the USB-C port on the right side. It&apos;s also equipped with pass-through charging and a 3.5mm headphone jack if you prefer the latency of wired earbuds over <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-earbuds">wireless earbuds</a>.</p><p>There are a couple of ways that Razer hopes that the Ultra will stand out in an increasingly crowded market. The first of which is the expanded device support, as the Ultra can now be expanded to connect with the 8.3-inch iPad Mini. This is great news for fans of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">foldable phones</a>, as you don&apos;t have to worry about the Ultra not working with the likes of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-5-review">Galaxy Z Fold 5</a> or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-open-review">OnePlus Open</a>.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="Xzbo8sqMtJi7UFXCaC43N8" name="razer-kishi-ultra-lifestyle-render-3.jpg" alt="Razer Kishi Ultra lifestyle render" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Xzbo8sqMtJi7UFXCaC43N8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Razer)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>With the USB-C connection, you have much more added versatility than you might have thought. Not only will it work with the latest Android phones, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/apple-iphone-15-pro-max-long-term-review">iPhone 15</a> lineup, and the iPad Mini, but the Razer Ultra can also be used as your primary controller from your PC, accomplished by just plugging the USB-C cable into your computer.</p><p>That&apos;s not even the best part about the Ultra. Razer is bringing its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.windowscentral.com/hardware/razer/razer-announces-iskur-v2-gaming-chair-and-an-exciting-world-first-haptic-gaming-cushion-yes-you-read-that-right">Sensa HD Haptics</a> to its top-of-the-line controller, something that is not often seen in this space. At launch, there are a few games and apps that can take advantage of the Ultra&apos;s native haptics. These include many of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-emulators-android">best emulators for Android</a> but also include Xbox Cloud Gaming, Fortnite, and more.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="cTXzT9cMNt882WpeB5dR59" name="razer-kishi-ultra-lifestyle-render-5.jpg" alt="Razer Kishi Ultra lifestyle render" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/cTXzT9cMNt882WpeB5dR59.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Razer)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Even more games are capable of taking advantage of the Kishi Ultra&apos;s "audio-based haptics," and Razer is hoping to see the list grow as developers jump on board. Paired with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.razer.bianca">Razer Nexus</a> app, you&apos;re able to adjust the sensitivity of audio haptics and enable "voice rejection," so a character interaction doesn&apos;t accidentally trigger the haptics.</p><p>Speaking of the Razer Nexus app, this aims to be your one-stop shop for everything when it comes to gaming on your phone. This includes acting as a game launcher, calibrating thumb stick dead zones, remapping buttons, and more. As the Kishi Ultra also comes with RGB, you&apos;ll use the Nexus app to change the colors and Chroma lighting effects.</p><p>With a controller as feature-rich as the Kishi Ultra, you&apos;ll need to get your wallet ready. The Kishi Ultra retails for $149 and is available worldwide starting today.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="808f3287-4030-4402-ace3-89465c6332b1">
            <a href="https://www.razer.com/mobile-controllers/razer-kishi-ultra" data-model-name="Razer Kishi Ultra"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/B5ReuctET95VW8vYqTNZ66.jpg' alt='Razer Kishi Ultra square render'></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Razer Kishi Ultra</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Ultimate mobile gaming</strong></em></p>
<p>The Razer Kishi Ultra might be one of the few good mobile gaming controllers that is worth a higher price tag. It brings an excellent ergonomic experience paired with RGB lighting and works with a wide variety of devices.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/razer-kishi-ultra-launch</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ In a market that continues to expand and grow, the Razer Kishi Ultra attempts to stand out from the crowd. We'll have to see if it manages to follow-through on those promises. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">tdzD4LMoFDRAvo2ojvXqJV</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oua3ERY3cPg8JwqbjiJpJA.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 15:00:41 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ andrew.myrick@futurenet.com (Andrew Myrick) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oua3ERY3cPg8JwqbjiJpJA.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Razer]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Razer Kishi Ultra lifestyle render]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Razer Kishi Ultra lifestyle render]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Samsung Galaxy A35 just landed in the US with a sweet deal on the Galaxy Buds FE ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The Galaxy A35 5G is now available for purchase in the US through various channels, including Samsung's website, retail stores, and major carriers and retailers.</li><li>It comes in two color options: Awesome Navy and Awesome Lilac with a starting price just shy of $400.</li><li>Samsung incentivizes purchases of the Galaxy A35 5G with limited-time offers, including a 30% discount on the Galaxy Buds FE and up to $150 in credit through trade-ins.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Samsung has added another option to its affordable 5G lineup in the US. The Galaxy A35 5G <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-a15-galaxy-a25-launch">joins the A15 and A25</a>, giving you more choices for a phone with next-gen speeds without breaking the bank.</p><p>The Galaxy A35 5G is available to purchase via Samsung&apos;s website, retail stores, and major carriers and retailers. It comes in two colors, Awesome Navy and Awesome Lilac, and starts at just under $400. However, the Galaxy A55, which <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-launches-galaxy-a55-and-a35">debuted with the A35 earlier this year</a>, won&apos;t be hitting the US market.</p><p>The phone sports a 6.6-inch FHD+ Super AMOLED display with a 120Hz refresh rate. And for selfies, there&apos;s a 13MP front camera tucked into a punch hole at the top center.</p><p>Flip it over, and you&apos;ll spot the triple camera setup consisting of a 50MP main camera with image stabilization to keep your photos sharp. Plus, there&apos;s an 8MP ultra-wide camera for fitting more in the shot and a 5MP macro lens.</p><p>The A35 5G runs on Samsung&apos;s own Exynos 1380 processor, which should give you plenty of power for everyday tasks. It comes with 6GB of RAM and 128GB of storage, but you can pop in a microSD card for even more space if you need it. The 5,000mAh battery should last you all day, and it supports up to 25W fast wired charging.</p><p>The A35 5G can take a beating with its IP67 dust and water resistance rating. It also comes with Android 14 out of the box, and Samsung promises to keep it updated with four major Android versions and security updates for five years.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:950px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:66.21%;"><img id="NjqVKYHL4vaHHG2szLh3L8" name="Samsung-Galaxy-A35-lilac.jpg" alt="Galaxy A35 5G in lilac" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NjqVKYHL4vaHHG2szLh3L8.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="950" height="629" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Samsung)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:66.67%;"><img id="d6ED3DRbVtouKD6wVCAm98" name="Samsung-Galaxy-A35-awesome-navy.jpg" alt="Galaxy A35 5G in awesome navy" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/d6ED3DRbVtouKD6wVCAm98.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1500" height="1000" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Samsung)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>You can buy the Galaxy A35 5G starting today, undercutting some of our <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-android-phones">top Android phone picks</a> like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-7a-review">Pixel 7a</a>.</p><p>Samsung is pulling out all the stops to get folks excited about its new phone. For a limited time, if you snag the Galaxy A35, you&apos;ll score a sweet 30% discount on the Galaxy Buds FE. Plus, Samsung is accepting trade-ins for up to $150 credit on your new phone.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-samsung-galaxy-a35-just-landed-in-the-us-with-a-sweet-deal-on-the-galaxy-buds-fe</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Samsung Galaxy A35 5G is now out in the US, priced at $400. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">qva2jzPUwhsR3L6XyQqEbY</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BJWpHDJQSGLNJKgK6hcc9k.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 15:00:22 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BJWpHDJQSGLNJKgK6hcc9k.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Samsung]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung galaxy A35 all colors]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung galaxy A35 all colors]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Maps may soon use satellites even if your phone is offline ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google is gearing up to add support for satellite connectivity in Android, and previous leaks have revealed that texts might be made over satellite. </li><li>Now, code referenced in the Google Maps app reveals that Google might also use satellite connectivity to update a user's location.</li><li>The feature might allow users to update their location every 15 minutes, up to five times per day, using satellite connectivity.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Satellite connectivity has been a hot topic in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android</a> world recently, as all signs point to Google adding the feature to future Android releases and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">new devices</a>. However, most references to satellite connectivity in Android have been related to text messaging while out of range of a cellular tower. Now, new code references hint at a way to use satellite connectivity in future versions of Android that might even be more useful than texting. </p><p>Google Maps will eventually let users update their location using an overhead satellite, according to a report from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://piunikaweb.com/2024/04/17/google-maps-preparing-satellite-connectivity-features/" target="_blank">PiunikaWeb</a>. In a recent Google Maps beta, specifically version v11.125, PiunikaWeb found multiple code snippets describing satellite-enabled location updates. Presumably, users could use this feature to update their location in Google Maps to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-satellite-sos-ui-spotted">share with loved ones or first responders</a> if they are off-grid. </p><p>The code strings preview a new UI that appears in Google Maps when a user does not have cellular connectivity. If the phone loses cellular data connection, users will see a "Connect to satellite" explainer with a button to use satellite connectivity in Google Maps. After pressing it, Google Maps users can update their location via satellite once every 15 minutes, with a limit of five times per day. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="Z4Vs6AfkZhwMcLcT3GjCDa" name="Google-Pixel-8-hazel-01.jpg" alt="Hands-on with the Google Pixel 8" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Z4Vs6AfkZhwMcLcT3GjCDa.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>This limit will mean Android users have to choose wisely before falling back to a satellite for location updates. The five-per-day cap likely has to do with the cost of using satellites for things like messaging and location updates. After being sent to an overhead satellite, the data needs to be returned to a ground satellite and processed, which is a costly endeavor for companies. </p><p>This is precisely the reason why phone companies that offer satellite connectivity, like Apple, caution that the functionality might not be free forever. Apple guarantees two years of free satellite connectivity, and can extend that free period if it chooses to, but the cost beyond that is to be determined. </p><p>While there&apos;s a lot of talk about Google&apos;s upcoming satellite additions in Android, it&apos;s important to remember that there is a hardware component to the functionality. Phones will need to support satellite connectivity in order to take advantage of the software features, and it&apos;s expected that the upcoming <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9">Pixel 9</a> will include that hardware.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-maps-satellite-offline-feature-leak</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google is steadily preparing satellite connectivity support in Android, and the latest implementation of it will make Google Maps location updates more reliable off-grid.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">5n5E38SjyaVpxsvnFk9fr5</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hFR48buiix3bdGhANJNSJ6.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 13:57:40 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hFR48buiix3bdGhANJNSJ6.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Viewing Google Maps on the Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 4&#039;s smaller cover screen]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Viewing Google Maps on the Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 4&#039;s smaller cover screen]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Meta Quest could get airplane travel mode as soon as next month ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>VR enthusiast Luna on X (formerly Twitter) uncovered a potential new airplane travel mode feature in Meta Quest update v65.</li><li>Apple Vision Pro debuted the flight mode feature and this would make Meta Quest headsets also work on airplanes.</li><li>Firmware v65 is expected to launch in May for Meta Quest headsets.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Meta Quest users may soon be able to use their headsets with proper mixed reality tracking while flying on an airplane. A new flight mode has been uncovered in firmware v65 by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/Lunayian/status/1780921198395720129">Luna on X</a> (formerly Twitter). This mode would make it so that the Meta Quest doesn&apos;t constantly lose positioning while the plane is moving at hundreds of miles an hour, a limitation that Quest headsets have always faced up until now.</p><p>If you&apos;ve ever tried to use a Meta Quest headset while flying on an airplane, you&apos;ll know that the UI immediately "falls" backward as if it were left in the clouds by the moving plane you&apos;re on. This is because the Quest, like other VR headsets, uses sensors that rely on gravity and other factors that don&apos;t work in a moving airplane.</p><p>A new flight mode on firmware v65, which should launch in May, would help fix this by disabling some sensors while keeping the headset&apos;s cameras working for mixed reality capture. This is one of the key differences between the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/apple-vision-pro-vs-meta-quest-3">Apple Vision Pro and Meta Quest 3</a>, as Apple&apos;s headset launched with the ability to use it while flying on an airplane. It even landed <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.fastcompany.com/91031178/apple-vision-pro-new-luxury-airline-maldives">Apple some contracts</a> from airlines to offer the headset for customers who want immersive in-flight entertainment.</p><p>While there&apos;s no guarantee that the new mode will launch with v65 when it&apos;s scheduled to go live in May, Luna found the code baked into an early release of the firmware. Based on the code, you&apos;ll be able to enable or disable Travel Mode from the quick settings menu on the Meta Quest. That should help save your neck while working or watching movies on a plane since you can place windows at eye-level instead of having to constantly look down at a phone or laptop.</p><p>Additionally, the code shows that your headset should automatically ask you if you want to enable travel mode when it detects that you&apos;re in a moving plane. The code also notes that users should stay seated while using Travel Mode, so it&apos;s probably best to remove your headset any time you need to get up and walk around the cabin.</p>
<hr>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="00d8d7cc-c001-4c2b-8d04-6aaa71cf1341">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/E75vg2n9urJXwhnVrgFvsQ.jpg' alt='Meta Quest 3 headset and controller render on a white background'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Meta Quest 3</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>Would you like to VR on a train? How about on a plane? No matter where you go, take the Meta Quest 3 with you to get excellent mixed reality experiences.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-flight-mode-v65-leak</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Meta Quest headsets don't work on airplanes right now unless you disable spatial tracking, but a secret new mode uncovered in an upcoming update might fix that. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">ffKorZbxh68evRkPywb3dY</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zB7pApKN3pAjoHvpLMMTSB.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 13:44:53 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nicholas.sutrich@futurenet.com (Nicholas Sutrich) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zB7pApKN3pAjoHvpLMMTSB.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[@Lunayian on X]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A leaked promotional image of the Meta Quest airplane mode feature]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A leaked promotional image of the Meta Quest airplane mode feature]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Nothing Ear and Ear (a) earbuds promise better battery and super clear streaming ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The Nothing Ear is the premium model, while the Ear (a) is the more budget-friendly option, but both offer essential features.</li><li>The Ear boasts the most advanced driver system yet and LHDC 5.0 support for enhanced audio.</li><li>The Ear (a) sacrifices some features for affordability, including less water resistance, a smaller case without wireless charging, and limited sound customization options.</li><li>Both earbuds share common features like 11mm drivers, ANC, a triple-mic setup, and LDAC support.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Nothing has launched two new wireless earbuds: the Ear and Ear (a). The Ear is the top-of-the-line model, while the Ear (a) is a more budget-friendly option with all the essentials.</p><p>Obviously, the company also revamped its earbud names by ditching the numbers. Nothing is aiming to put the spotlight squarely on the product and the user experience with this move.</p><p>To be clear, the Ear is the follow-up to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/nothing-ear-2-review">Nothing Ear (2)</a>, while the Ear (a) is a cheaper option. Both will hit store shelves later this month, and they&apos;re stepping up the game from what was already a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-noise-canceling-true-wireless-earbuds">top-notch earbud</a> series.</p><p>With this latest version, Nothing is making some important upgrades while keeping the brand&apos;s transparent earbud style intact.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="SEybH77ymKogVLorNq8bX8" name="Ear-Product-White-Buds-Case.jpg" alt="Nothing ear buds and case in white" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SEybH77ymKogVLorNq8bX8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="caption-text">Nothing Ear in white </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nothing)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Nothing claims that the Ear rocks its most advanced driver system yet, pumping out richer sound without sacrificing performance. Plus, it&apos;s got LHDC 5.0 support to really amp up your audio experience.</p><p>The Ear (a) is the more wallet-friendly option, but there are a few trade-offs. It&apos;s not quite as water-resistant, the case is smaller and ditches wireless charging, and you can&apos;t fine-tune the sound quite as much.</p><p>They also differ in color options. While both earbuds come in black and white, the Ear (a) spices things up with a pop of yellow.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="etRvBZQ6MNjAZUPxYuAHi7" name="Nothing-Ear-yellow-Buds-Case.jpg" alt="Nothing ear (a) yellow buds plus case" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/etRvBZQ6MNjAZUPxYuAHi7.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nothing)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="9s5FNQ3i696mkDdQngS3H7" name="Nothing-Ear-yellow.jpg" alt="Nothing ear (a) yellow buds" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9s5FNQ3i696mkDdQngS3H7.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nothing)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="jW65woZVhXpRfcRD6PJo98" name="Nothing-Ear-Black-Buds-Case.jpg" alt="Nothing ear buds and case in black" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jW65woZVhXpRfcRD6PJo98.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nothing)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 4 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="ej6kUigGXFzH2KFwsnsps8" name="Nothing-Ear-whte.jpg" alt="Nothing ear buds in white" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ej6kUigGXFzH2KFwsnsps8.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nothing)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Elsewhere, these buds share a bunch of specs and features. They share 11mm drivers, active noise cancellation (ANC), a triple-mic setup, and support for LDAC for high-quality audio streaming.</p><p>Nothing has also upped the ANC game on the new earbuds. The Ear and Ear (a) can block out up to 45dB of noise, which is almost twice as strong as the previous model. And it&apos;s throwing in a "Smart ANC algorithm" to crank that up even more.</p><p>Both the Ear and Ear (a) earbuds last longer on a charge than the previous model. The Ear lasts up to 5.2 hours, while the Ear (a) edges it out with 5.5 hours, even with ANC on. Toggle ANC off, and you&apos;ll get 8.5 hours with the Ear and 9.5 hours with the Ear (a). Plus, the case holds more juice now, offering up to 42.5 hours without ANC for the Ear (a).</p><p>The Nothing Ear keeps the same $149 price tag as its predecessor, while the Ear (a) is a steal at $99. Pre-orders are open now on Nothing.tech, and they&apos;ll be available on April 22.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/the-nothing-ear-and-ear-a-earbuds-promise-better-battery-and-super-clear-streaming</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Nothing's fresh wireless earbuds bring some sneaky but crucial improvements. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">EGvsRYgSBvR54UNXw2U2JT</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YtafWiZnqwfBjEcBDVs7r6.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 13:33:56 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YtafWiZnqwfBjEcBDVs7r6.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nothing]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Nothing ear (a) buds and case in yellow]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Nothing ear (a) buds and case in yellow]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Adobe Express app packs Firefly gen-AI and is now widely available on Android ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Adobe Express, the home of Adobe's Firefly suite of generative AI features, now has a mobile app widely available on iOS and Android. </li><li>Adobe launched the Adobe Express in beta and refined the app for about a month before releasing it publicly. </li><li>The mobile app is a scaled-down version of the desktop Adobe Express app, which was also overhauled to include generative AI features last year.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Adobe is bringing the Adobe Express mobile app starting today, April 17, and that means you can start using generative AI features to edit photos, videos, and more from an iPhone or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android device</a>.</p><p>The app is powered by Adobe Firefly, the company&apos;s suite of gen-AI features. The launch has been in the works since Adobe overhauled the desktop Express app last year and has been beta testing the mobile variant since early March of this year. </p><p>There are a handful of ways to use Firefly in the Adobe Express mobile app, starting with basic image or graphic generation. Like other text-to-image generators, users can enter a prompt in the Express app and return a custom image. Afterward, the newly created image can be further tweaked with generative AI. There&apos;s also a feature called Text Effects that makes headline text pop for things like posters and graphics.</p><p>Adobe Express is positioned as an all-inclusive hub for your <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-photography-apps-android">photo editing</a>, video editing, graphic design, and AI work. Many other apps and sites offer the same separate functionality as the Express app, but few have made them all available in one place. </p><p>That means there are mobile photo and video editing features, including 4K video timelines and layer timing. A time-saving feature lets users in Adobe Express create real-time captions with generative AI and supports more than 100 languages.</p><p>Another neat — but not necessarily new — feature in Adobe Express is Generative Fill. Using custom prompts, the Express app can find and replace people or objects in a photo. </p><p>The transition to a full public release now means that some Adobe Express features will be locked behind a paywall, though. In a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.adobe.com/express/learn/blog/new-mobile-beta" target="_blank">press release</a> from March announcing the beta, Adobe made premium Express features available for free. Now, it will presumably match <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.adobe.com/express/pricing" target="_blank">Adobe Express pricing</a>, with the Adobe Express Premium tier costing $10 per month for individuals. </p><p>However, the Adobe Express app is still free to download from the Google Play Store. There&apos;s also a free tier that offers 25 generative AI credits per month, basic photo editing features, and more.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/adobe-express-app-launch</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Adobe's suite of generative AI features, called Firefly, has a new home in the Adobe Express app on Android. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">4oQG4joi4S97AJYbmpmFjZ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RBFurxmqSsgpcLARRLENde.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 13:00:27 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RBFurxmqSsgpcLARRLENde.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Adobe]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Adobe express app on three phones]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Adobe express app on three phones]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Acer's first Chromebook of 2024 is perfect for students ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-32">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Acer has announced the Chromebook Plus 514 powered by the Intel Core i3-N305.</li><li>It sports a 14-inch FHD display, while offering up to 11 hours of battery life. </li><li>The Chromebook Plus 514 will retail for $399 and is arriving in May.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Things have been pretty quiet on the Chromebook front this year, at least for the most part. However, that might start to change as Acer is introducing its all-new Chromebook Plus 514 (CB514-4H/T). </p><p>As the name suggests, the Chromebook Plus 514 features a 14-inch display, sporting a 16:9 aspect ratio and a Full HD (1920 x 1080) resolution. Under the hood, we have the Intel Core i3-N305 SoC paired with 8GB of RAM and "up to" 512GB of storage. Unsurprisingly, the base model ships with 128GB of storage, but Acer plans to release additional configurations.</p>

<p>Don&apos;t expect much in the way of design changes, but that&apos;s kind of to be expected when it comes to Acer Chromebooks. What&apos;s clear is that this is set to be one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-chromebook-students">best Chromebooks for students</a>, namely, thanks to the 11 hours of battery life. While we miss out on Thunderbolt ports, the Chromebook Plus 514 does feature two USB-C ports with DisplayPort support, along with dual USB-A ports and a microSD card slot.</p><p>With the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/chromebook-plus-models-now-available">Chromebook Plus</a> moniker in tow, this means that you&apos;ll enjoy plenty of great features. These include things like Video Controls, allowing you to automatically apply a background blur and noise cancellation for your microphone. You&apos;ll also find "enhanced editing features" for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-photos-expands-ai-editing-features">Google Photos</a>, such as Magic Eraser and Portrait Blur. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1279px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.22%;"><img id="BYhEPbQFsAtPLZRafDPGJf" name="acer-chromebook-plus-514-16x9-lifestyle-render-1.jpg" alt="Acer Chromebook Plus 514 lifestyle render" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BYhEPbQFsAtPLZRafDPGJf.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1279" height="719" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Acer)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>These are all of the same great features that were announced when Google introduced its Chromebook Plus moniker. And while the additional features are to be expected, it&apos;s still nice to see Acer adding another Chromebook to the mix. </p><p>Acer stopped short of revealing what other configurations will be made available. However, the first models are expected to arrive sometime in May. Pricing for the base model Chromebook Plus 514 will come in at $399, so it will be interesting to see how the other configurations will shake out once they&apos;re released.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/acer-chromebook-plus-514-launch</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Acer has announced its first new Chromebook for 2024 with the Chromebook Plus 514. There's not too much to write home about, other than the fact that it will provide a well-rounded experience. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">CuTHKTDoXX57L9NhbeSkUm</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Fvo9JynTJacVrE7rraA9bf.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 13:00:02 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Chromebooks &amp; Laptops]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ andrew.myrick@futurenet.com (Andrew Myrick) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Fvo9JynTJacVrE7rraA9bf.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Acer]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Acer Chromebook Plus 514 lifestyle render]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Acer Chromebook Plus 514 lifestyle render]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Drive for the web FINALLY gets dark mode, and it's wonderful ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-37">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google Drive now has a dark mode on the web.</li><li>You can toggle between light and dark modes by going into Drive settings. </li><li>The mode doesn't extend to Docs, Sheets, and Slides. </li><li>Gmail and Calendar are yet to make the switch.</li></ul>
<p>It only took Google several years, but the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-google-drive-tips-and-tricks">Google Drive</a> web app now has dark mode. Google announced the change on April 16, and while it usually rolls out features in a phased manner, that isn&apos;t the case this time — dark mode is available to all Google Drive users globally.</p><p>This includes users with personal Google accounts, Google Workspace customers, and Workspace Individual subscribers. If you have a Workspace account, you don&apos;t need admin access to enable the feature — it&apos;s located in the settings, and you can easily toggle between light and dark modes.</p><p>Same goes for everyone else too. When you select the gear icon (located on the top right) and choose Settings, you&apos;ll now notice an Appearance sub-menu with three options: Light, Dark, and Device default. You can manually select light and dark modes, or if you prefer changing it at a system level, use Device default and the mode changes based on your system settings.</p><p>The sidebar has a dark grey tone, with the folder view switching to a fully black color scheme. And while Drive itself has dark mode on the web, that doesn&apos;t extend to Docs, Slides, and Sheets, so if you pull up any documents, they will default to light mode.</p><p>Google took its time to roll out the feature to Drive users — so much so that I resorted to using the Dark Reader extension to get dark mode on all of Google services. While <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-search-web-finally-gets-its-own-dark-mode">Google Search on the web got dark mode back</a> in 2021, several Google services are yet to make the switch, notably Gmail, YouTube, and Calendar. If you don&apos;t want to wait until Google rolls out dark mode across its suite of services, I highly recommend <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://chromewebstore.google.com/detail/dark-reader/eimadpbcbfnmbkopoojfekhnkhdbieeh">Dark Reader</a>.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-drive-for-the-web-finally-gets-dark-mode-and-its-wonderful</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google has decided to roll out dark mode to Drive on the web, and it is now available to all users worldwide.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">qMdvmtSv9erFW6GPMqpE48</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2QiuuNUyS4KYbeiDi5mTJJ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 12:31:09 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2QiuuNUyS4KYbeiDi5mTJJ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Drive web gets dark mode]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Drive web gets dark mode]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Nothing Ear (a) review: Proof you don't need expensive earbuds ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Nothing has made a name for itself by offering great value and daring product designs. That continues with a new addition to their Ear lineup, the Nothing Ear (a). Launched alongside the Ear (Nothing dropped numeric designations this year), Nothing Ear (a) is the successor to the Ear (Stick) and Ear (1). The Ear (2024) is designed for serious audio enthusiasts, while the Ear (a) was built with the everyday listener in mind.</p><p>In addition to the black and white colorways of previous Ear models of the past, 2024 gets a striking new yellow Nothing Ear (a) and matching case. Although, unlike its big sibling Ear, this case is USB-C charging only, although it is smaller than previous-gen designs, with an updated interior layout.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="kWKa3ZpSU54ezBjndu5EZJ" name="Nothing-Ear-a-in-case.jpg" alt="Nothing Ear (a) TWS earbuds in yellow" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kWKa3ZpSU54ezBjndu5EZJ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<h2 id="quot-low-quot-price-hi-res-2">"Low" price, Hi-Res</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="c87oxrSP6MSNr4PUxuqxMB" name="Nothing-Ear-a-buds-in-ear-medium.jpg" alt="Nothing Ear (a) TWS earbuds in yellow" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/c87oxrSP6MSNr4PUxuqxMB.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Let&apos;s get right to it, shall we? Nothing&apos;s Ear (a) has really solid sound reproduction at only $99. I listened to them using the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/bluetooth-audio-terms-codecs-explained">supported LDAC codec</a>, connected to a Pixel 7 Pro, streaming music from Tidal, and playing locally stored FLAC files through VLC media player. I listened to everything from Paul Simon to Art Blakey to Gravediggaz and threw in some EDM and Trap to test that sub-bass. </p><p>Everything I threw at them sounded wonderfully layered and nuanced using the default Balanced equalizer setting. Sub-bass has a resonance that bass heads will revel in, while acoustic music like Diamonds on the Souls of Her Shoes and Art Blakey&apos;s Moanin&apos; were also delightful to listen to. I was surprised by the size of the soundstage in Paul Simon&apos;s Diamonds track for sub-$100 TWS earbuds; any earbuds, actually. Even some premium earbuds can fall short of producing such an airy image.</p><p>My only issue is with the higher-end frequencies in wailing electric guitars. With the default Balanced EQ, tracks from Sylosis and Gojira are shrill. That&apos;s easily fixed with an EQ adjustment if thrash metal is your genre of choice. </p>

<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="auJR7X3FocAi34t2wgNv4F" name="Nothing-Ear-a-on-pixel-7-pro.jpg" alt="Nothing Ear (a) TWS earbuds in yellow" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/auJR7X3FocAi34t2wgNv4F.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Ear (a) has a Low-latency option in the well-designed Nothing X app, but after watching "Saving Private Ryan" and "Blue Eye Samurai," it wasn&apos;t needed. The dialogue was crisp and clear, foley effects were present, and sound design elements like explosions in the D-Day beach scene or the taiko drums in the second "Samurai" episode, "An Unexpected Element," had all the punch and resonance you&apos;d want.</p>
<h2 id="making-something-out-of-nothing-2">Making something out of Nothing</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="R3GFt664Ycg5r88YiaL2GE" name="Nothing-Ear-a-case-dots.jpg" alt="Nothing Ear (a) TWS earbuds case in yellow. Colored dots mark the L and R placement of the buds." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/R3GFt664Ycg5r88YiaL2GE.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I appreciate the attention to detail in so many small choices that Nothing makes with its products. For example, instead of looking for the L or R on your earbuds so you can orient them properly when placing them back in their case, they have a red dot on the right earbud and a white one on the left. In the case, you&apos;ll find corresponding red and white dots. Easy. Then, when listening to music and changing noise canceling modes, instead of figuring out and then remembering which chime means ANC or Transparency mode is activated, there&apos;s the distinctive sound of someone exhaling, signifying that you&apos;re in Transparency mode.</p><p>The Nothing X app is easy to navigate and manages to give you a lot of features without feeling overwhelming. For those who love bass, the Equalizer and Bass Enhance menus offer multiple options for increasing low-frequency response. The latter allows you to adjust lows with five levels of tuning.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="gywJBLhPnX3gx5PqgMGJAV" name="Nothing-X-app-Ear-a.jpg" alt="Nothing X app connected to Nothing Ear (a)" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gywJBLhPnX3gx5PqgMGJAV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Nothing says the Ear (a) suppresses up to 45dB of noise. Your situation may not require that level of noise mitigation, so the Noise Control menu in the Nothing X app gives you high, medium, and low options for ANC. There&apos;s also an Adaptive option that automatically chooses one of those three modes based on your environment&apos;s ambient noise. The ANC isn&apos;t the most robust I&apos;ve experienced on a pair of earbuds, but it quiets enough noise that you don&apos;t have to pump tunes extra loud to drown out the noise you&apos;re trying to cancel.</p><p>Sitting in front of 75dB of airplane cabin noise, the Ear (a) did a good job with low frequencies while allowing more higher-end frequency through. To be fair, the noise canceling is on par with my previous top choice for sub-$100 earbuds, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/earbuds/anker-soundcore-liberty-4-nc-review">Soundcore Liberty 4 NC</a>.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/earbuds/i-tested-7-pairs-of-headphones-for-gym-use-and-this-is-what-id-recommend">If you fancy yourself a "gym rat,"</a> you&apos;ll likely want to add some Comply foam ear tips to the mix so that the Ear (a) feels more locked in. They didn&apos;t fall out when exercising, but sweating makes them shimmy out of your ear canal. No worries about heavy sweating, as the buds are IP54 rated (beach-goers rejoice), while the case is IPX2 rated. Ear (a) is one of the few TWS products on the market with both water resistance and dust ingress ratings and a case that is <em>also</em> water resistance rated at any price point.</p><p>And as a note, I&apos;ll point out that Airpods Pro-style earbuds generally don&apos;t fit my ears well. However, a first for this style, Nothing Ear (a) work well without needing Comply foam ear tips to keep them seated properly.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>Everything I threw at them sounded wonderfully layered and nuanced using the default “Balanced” equalizer setting.</p></blockquote></figure>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="ZyMwnju9AB52TDoJF6t87C" name="Nothing-Ear-a-buds-in-ear-close-up.jpg" alt="Nothing Ear (a) TWS earbuds in yellow" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZyMwnju9AB52TDoJF6t87C.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The transparency mode sounds natural, and wearing the Ear (a) during my 2.5-mile jaunts around the neighborhood, I could hear cars and other sounds easily. Wearing them at work, I can carry on conversations effortlessly while keeping them in my ears.</p><p>Using Transparency mode has an effect on audio frequency response, losing some of the richness of the sound, but that&apos;s what the Nothing X app&apos;s Equalizer and Bass Enhance menus are for. I set up a custom EQ for Transparency listening. You can&apos;t name it and save multiple EQs, but your settings are persistent, so you can move to one of the presets for ANC and then go back to Custom for Transparency mode.</p><p>For those who will buy, my current preferred setup is the EQ set to Balanced with the Bass Enhance set to On, Level 1.</p><p>With regard to call quality, those mics will sound better in quieter environments and a bit muffled out on the streets, where they actively filter out most urban noise. Despite that, their "out here in these streets" sound quality was still quite audible and easy to hear.</p>
<h2 id="missing-one-thing-2">Missing one thing</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="VFz52nZVDWGQZN88pV48UH" name="Nothing-Ear-a-case-only.jpg" alt="Nothing Ear (a) TWS earbuds in yellow" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VFz52nZVDWGQZN88pV48UH.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>For $99, these Bluetooth 5.3 TWS earbuds also include multipoint pairing, in-ear detection, a low latency mode, and an ear tip fit test. The pinch-based controls offer a lot of customization for playback and phone calls. They&apos;re responsive, and for those who like physical controls, you won&apos;t be disappointed in daily use. </p>
<figure><blockquote><p>For those who will buy, my current preferred setup is the EQ set to Balanced with the Bass Enhance set to On, Level 1.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>There&apos;s no wireless charging support in this package. Nothing saved that for the more expensive Ear 2024 model, but the case holds a hefty recharge amount, providing 42.5 hours with ANC off and 24.5 hours with it on. You&apos;ll get rapid charging for the case when you deplete that 500mAh battery, so 10 minutes of case charging will give your earbuds 10 hours of playback (ANC off).</p><p>Rated for 5.5 hours of continuous playback with ANC on, I drained them in five hours with mixed-use. That included 13 minutes on a phone call, 45 minutes of transparency mode during my walk through the neighborhood, and every feature activated that warns you it will deplete the battery faster when you turn it on, including LDAC support and multipoint.</p>
<h2 id="nothing-to-sneeze-at-2">Nothing to sneeze at!</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="fcwfMf5Ys72ZsMb9RADEiD" name="Nothing-Ear-a-buds-only.jpg" alt="Nothing Ear (a) TWS earbuds in yellow" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fcwfMf5Ys72ZsMb9RADEiD.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>One of the greatest compliments I&apos;ve received as a tech journalist is that folks can tell through my videos and articles that I really enjoy technology. That&apos;s the vibe I get from Nothing in its design decisions and attention to the "little things." This is a group of folks who seemingly love what they do, and that shines through in the Nothing Ear (a). </p><p>Sure, these buds won&apos;t win any ANC awards, and wireless charging would be nice. Still, the most important aspect of a pair of Bluetooth TWS earbuds is how they sound, and with Hi-Res Audio LDAC support, coupled with Nothing&apos;s tuning and driver architecture, the Ear (a) delivers a thoroughly enjoyable listening experience and looks rather fetching while doing so.</p><p>In the process, it proves you don&apos;t need to spend hundreds to get great sound, an easy-to-use, feature-rich app, and head-turning looks! I highly recommend checking out Nothing Ear (a) when you&apos;re looking for a new pair of earbuds.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="fc5e3951-4fc6-42a7-bdf5-46a4d98058c7">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/c9cvUbLeKA4yu8hctXVQME.jpg' alt='Nothing Ear (a) TWS earbuds in yellow'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Nothing Ear (a)</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="80" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><strong>Better than the $99 price tag</strong></p>
<p>Hi-res audio support, multipoint pairing, delightful sonics, dozens of fun and functional design choices, and 10 minutes for 10 hours of rapid charging make the Nothing Ear (a) easy to recommend.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/nothing-ear-a-review</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Nothing Ear (a) proves that you don't need to pay hundreds for a great pair of Bluetooth earbuds for everyday use. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">m85d82Ye3xeBmus66ophU5</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PBB5M5HWARscDyd7nXMkrF.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 10:45:37 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Earbuds]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ klpmediallc@gmail.com (Tshaka Armstrong) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PBB5M5HWARscDyd7nXMkrF.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Tshaka Armstrong]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Nothing Ear (a) TWS earbuds in yellow]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Nothing Ear (a) TWS earbuds in yellow]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>