<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 20:07:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Meta Quest Pro 2 is looking even more interesting now ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The LG-made Meta Quest Pro 2 has been delayed until sometime in 2027.</li><li>LG said it's "controlling the pace" of its releases, suggesting that Meta and LG are working to keep from releasing too many Horizon OS-powered headsets at once.</li><li>A new 4K LG Micro OLED display was also recently announced, suggesting that this headset might be using that technology.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Meta&apos;s first enterprise-level headset, the Meta Quest Pro, may not have sold as well as the company originally hoped, but that&apos;s not stopping it from forging ahead with a second-generation model. The only downside is that would-be customers are going to have to wait until 2027 to find out if it&apos;s really better than the original 2022 release.</p><p>The report of the delay comes from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://sedaily.com/NewsView/2D990BASDR">Seoul Economic Daily</a> (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.uploadvr.com/lg-meta-quest-pro-2-delayed-to-2027/">UploadVR</a>) and notes that LG has delayed the headset for roughly two years, as it was originally set for a 2025 release date. That would have made it a nice follow-up to the upcoming <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/samsung-glasses">Samsung XR headset</a>, which is said to be released later this year and is built on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/google-android-xr-meta">Google&apos;s new Android XR platform</a>.</p><p>LG&apos;s headset, by comparison, will be using <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-horizon-os-announced-for-3rd-party-quest-headsets-xbox-asus-lenovo">Meta&apos;s Horizon OS</a>, the same software that runs today&apos;s Meta Quest headsets, albeit likely customized a bit to make it look and feel more like a business-class headset. LG told <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://koreajoongangdaily.joins.com/news/2024-05-20/business/tech/LG-pumps-brakes-on-Meta-partnership-as-headsets-struggle-to-sell/2050663">Korea JoongAng Daily</a> that it&apos;s delaying the release to "control its pace," referring to slow ultra-premium headset sales and likely the fact that several Horizon OS headsets are set to debut over the next year.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.30%;"><img id="oHVzCuKbUU29siZu8hgbMj" name="Meta-Quest-Pro-hands-on-partial-light-blocker-02.jpg" alt="Partial light blockers on the Meta Quest Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oHVzCuKbUU29siZu8hgbMj.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1153" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Regardless of the release date, though, the upcoming LG-built Meta Quest Pro 2 could feature LG&apos;s latest display technology. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.uploadvr.com/lg-next-generation-micro-oled-display-vr/">UploadVR</a> describes it as a proper 4K micro OLED display featuring a resolution of 3840×3840 per eye. By comparison, the Apple Vision Pro&apos;s micro OLED display is 3660×3200 per eye, while the Meta Quest 3 is 2064x2208 per eye.</p><p>The new LG display features 10,000 nits of brightness, which sounds incredibly excessive at first but makes sense when you consider other factors. Pancake lenses like the ones used on Apple Vision Pro or the Meta Quest 3  essentially "eat" light as it&apos;s passed through, meaning the amount of light that eventually reaches your eye is reduced by as much as 90%.</p><p>In addition, VR headsets use a technology called "low persistence" that&apos;s somewhat similar to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-is-pwm-display-flicker-tips-and-tricks">PWM flickering</a>, meaning the pixels turn off several times per second before illuminating again. Low persistence differs from PWM on phone displays because the tech is used to reduce motion blur rather than control brightness.</p><p>Although the technique is similar to PWM, it further reduces the perceived brightness. On Apple Vision Pro, this means the headset&apos;s 5,000 nit display is taken down to a whopping 100 perceived nits once the light reaches your eyes. In other words, you need an "absurdly" bright display behind those lenses to make a display bright enough.</p><p>This, combined with the resolution mean the LG-made Meta Quest Pro 2 could have the best looking VR headset display if nothing better launches between now and then.</p>
<hr>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-pro-2-new-display-delay</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Meta Quest Pro 2 is rumored to have been delayed again, but a related leak points to a more interesting headset. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">AFFY2ZGemeqvmhALK9fFdG</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LwJ4d6BNh8tofNnZKbJ9oE.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 19:49:45 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nicholas.sutrich@futurenet.com (Nicholas Sutrich) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LwJ4d6BNh8tofNnZKbJ9oE.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A Meta Quest Pro with its controller next to the number 2]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A Meta Quest Pro with its controller next to the number 2]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google's Circle to Search tipped to gain a 'listen' feature and more ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The latest version for the Google app's beta contains signs of several new features on tap for Circle to Search.</li><li>A "listen" button was discovered, which could let Google read what they've highlighted aloud, alongside a "select all" option for text.</li><li>The app also showed signs of a "save" button, which would let users take snapshots of whatever they've highlighted and save it in the Google app for later.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google&apos;s beta app displays signs of new features when tapping for its Circle to Search feature on Android.</p><p>Discovered by AssembleDebug in conjunction with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/circle-to-search-three-new-features-teardown-3445102/">Android Authority</a>, Circle to Search is preparing to receive "listen" and "select all" buttons. With these found within the app&apos;s v15.20.36.29 beta code, there wasn&apos;t a way to produce them in real-time. However, there&apos;s speculation that Google could take a page from its Lens feature to make them work.</p><p>The "listen" button could refer to users&apos; soon gaining the ability to let Google read aloud a selection of highlighted text, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-google-lens-search-images-text-simultaneously">like Lens</a>.</p><p>The other function, "select all," is rumored to highlight all relevant text visible through your phone&apos;s camera or a taken image.</p><p>Google&apos;s app beta also points toward a "save" button after circling a section of an image to search. The tipster was able to get this to work, and its demo showed that the save option will appear alongside pre-existing functions like select text, copy, and share.</p><p>These small screenshots are then saved into the "saved" tab of the main Google app, instead of taking up space on your device in Photos or elsewhere. The tipster states screenshots through Circle to Search will be placed in a new "uploaded images" album.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="WMab7m8CVng8rUHffk5bgR" name="Google-Pixel-6a-google-search-bar-home-screen.jpg" alt="Google Search bar on the home screen of the Google Pixel 6a" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WMab7m8CVng8rUHffk5bgR.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It&apos;ll likely take a while longer until these features arrive, considering the "listen" and "select all" functions are still deep in development.</p><p>Meanwhile, Google rolled out Circle to Search <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/pixel-tablet-users-can-finally-use-circle-to-search-on-android-14">on the Pixel Tablet</a>. Users with Android 14 on the device circle or highlight anything on their device to quickly run a query through Search. While the company has remained somewhat consistent in bringing the feature to other Pixels, the feature doesn&apos;t work for the tablet&apos;s split-screen mode.</p><p>Google stated it is looking into implementing support for split-screen mode "in a future update." Such support is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/pixel-phones-may-soon-let-you-use-circle-to-search-in-split-screen-mode">already being tested</a> for Pixel phones as of the Android 15 Beta 1.2 update.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-circle-to-search-listen-save-feature-spotted</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Circle to Search may gain some new tools as a deep dive into the Google app's beta showed signs of what's to come. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">GyM9yJfdwxQMPNkH5WnVuh</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TNn4y4ENeSptPSRPTi9pvi.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 19:36:52 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TNn4y4ENeSptPSRPTi9pvi.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Roydon Cerejo / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Search widget on homescreen]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Search widget on homescreen]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Latest Android 15 Beta brings Repair mode to the OnePlus 12 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>OnePlus found testing a new repair mode on its latest flagship.</li><li>The recent Android 15 beta has introduced the feature on the OnePlus 12.</li><li>The official rollout of the feature is expected with OxygenOS 15 later this year.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Repair mode is an essential feature for phones that will help users hide their data whenever they send their devices to service centers for repair. The latest Android 15 beta has enabled the feature for the flagship OnePlus 12.</p><p>As noted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/oneplus-12-repair-mode-android-15-beta-3444848/">Android Authority</a>, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12-review">OnePlus 12</a>, which received the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/oneplus-brings-android-15-beta-1-to-oneplus-12-and-oneplus-open-users">first Android 15 beta</a> alongside the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-open-review">OnePlus Open</a>, has now gained a new Repair mode feature on the flagship phone. It is similar to the Repair mode on Pixel devices, next to Maintenance Mode on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-samsung-phones">Samsung phones</a>.</p><p>The first Android 15 beta users on the OnePlus 12 can head over to the device’s <strong>Settings> System & updates> Repair mode</strong>, which can be seen right under the Developer Options.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:273px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:219.78%;"><img id="uSF4uzTC54LWkBsmJbYczU" name="OnePlus-12-Repair-Mode.jpg" alt="OnePlus 12 Repair mode" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uSF4uzTC54LWkBsmJbYczU.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="273" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:273px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:219.78%;"><img id="p5bQ67mhh6zoTvdA3tZq6V" name="OnePlus-12-Repair-Mode-01.jpg" alt="OnePlus 12 Repair mode" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/p5bQ67mhh6zoTvdA3tZq6V.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="273" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>According to the publication&apos;s screenshots, the Repair mode can be enabled before users take their flagship for repair, and they can hide their personal information, including photos, videos, contacts, SMS messages, and chats.</p><p>However, repair personnel can use essential functions required for troubleshooting, including Bluetooth, Wi-Fi, mobile data, and phone calls. OnePlus 12 users are still advised to back up their phones before entering repair mode. </p><p>Strong Lock screen password is another parameter that the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">flagship phone</a> owners should be aware of before submitting their device to the personnel via repair mode. Overall, the functionality certainly adds privacy when submitting devices to repair personnel.</p>
<p>As mentioned, the instructions are similar to those on Pixel and Galaxy phones. While the former opts for Dynamic System Updates, the latter allows users to create a new profile. Samsung was one of the first OEM makers to introduce a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-galaxy-one-ui-5-maintenance-mode">Maintenance mode</a> in OneUI 5.0 (Android 13-based). Google picked up the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/repair-mode-for-google-pixel-phones">Repair mode</a> in Android 14 back in December 2023.</p><p>While it is encouraging to see OnePlus opting for Repair mode in the latest Android 15 beta, Android Authority notes that there’s a catch with the approach on the OnePlus 12. In Galaxy and Pixel phones, the respective repair mode takes the device to the home screen.</p>
<p>In the OnePlus 12’s case, the repair mode brings the device to a phone setup stage wherein users have to follow a process similar to setting up a new device. While users can still skip these steps, it still takes some time compared to the aforementioned process.</p><p>Since it is the first time that OnePlus is bringing a Repair mode in the first Android 15 beta, it is still likely in the testing phase, and it presumably would be hassle-free when the rollout happens officially with the OxygenOS 15 later this year.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12-gets-repair-mode-in-android-15-beta</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ OnePlus added a Repair mode for its flagship in the recent beta. Previously, Samsung and Google developed versions of similar repair modes. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">qiYGBAs5Jvi3G5Xcm5c4k8</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2WyfCGhDf6xUMQs2TVo8AH.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 19:29:43 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2WyfCGhDf6xUMQs2TVo8AH.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus 12 about page]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus 12 about page]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google’s AI overviews in search might kill publishing, and it’s going to backfire eventually ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google is rolling out AI overviews in Google Search, also known as Search Generative Experience, to all U.S. users.</li><li>AI overviews replace "featured snippets" in many cases, summarizing web pages, sometimes without linking to the sites they summarize. </li><li>Google's plan to cut publishers out of Search is a shortsighted one, as there will be less incentive to publish the new content that AI models depend on. </li><li>The company earns most of its revenue through digital ads, and it's unclear how Google will monetize SGE instead. </li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google unveiled its plan to inject artificial intelligence into Search, the company&apos;s main business, at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-io-2024-biggest-announcements">Google I/O 2024</a>. AI overviews are rolling out at the very top of search results pages for all users in the U.S. as of last week. These overviews first appeared as tests for a limited number of users, and is also known as the Search Generative Experience. Now that Google is going all-in on generative AI in Google Search, it is under immense pressure to get it right. </p><p>Google <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gen-ai-search-upgrades-io-2024">putting AI overviews at the top of all search results</a> pages brings up a few key questions, like whether these summaries are outright plagiarism, how publishers will be compensated, and why users would even click webpages anymore. The stakes are high because, as Google&apos;s own AI overview explains, Google is the biggest referrer of web traffic on the internet — and it really isn&apos;t close.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:5443px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="Junb4VSDL3zmmUMuxggTjX" name="Google-Web-Traffic-AI-Overview.jpg" alt="An AI overview explaining web traffic data." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Junb4VSDL3zmmUMuxggTjX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="5443" height="3061" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google / Future)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It&apos;s easy to see why people in the online media and publishing industry are worried. If Google is summarizing content and giving people the answers they need right in an AI overview, there&apos;s little reason for users to click through to the original source. </p><p>To the company, this is by design. Google wants to be the only site you need, explaining that soon, "Google will do the searching, simplifying, researching, planning, brainstorming and so much more."</p><p>The problem is that if Google completely cuts out publishers and disincentivizes people from creating original content, it will end up cannibalizing its own business model. There won&apos;t be new content to train AI models, which will make the overall quality and effectiveness of features like Search Generative Experience worse. </p><p>Digital ad revenue will drop alongside the cratering web traffic caused by reliance on AI overviews in Search and fewer webpage clicks. Both of these things could be disastrous for Google, yet it&apos;s the company that might be causing them to happen. </p>
<h2 id="google-makes-money-off-ads-so-how-does-it-earn-from-ai-overviews-2">Google makes money off ads, so how does it earn from AI overviews?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3200px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.28%;"><img id="z6tvCEtF9C5BiHta3vMEoh" name="google-io-google-logo.jpeg" alt="Google's "G" logo" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/z6tvCEtF9C5BiHta3vMEoh.jpeg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3200" height="1801" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google has dipped its toe in just about every part of the tech industry, from hardware, to software, to services. But none of its businesses are more lucrative than Search, and by extension, advertising. Last year alone, Google earned $237.86 billion from digital advertising, according to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/266249/advertising-revenue-of-google/" target="_blank">Statista</a>. Many online publishers use Google Ads, so the ads you see on the sites you visit may be supplied by Google. </p><p>The conundrum here is obvious. If the primary way Google earns revenue is through advertisements on websites, how will the company continue to make money if people stop clicking on webpages? </p><p>AI overviews aim to give users the answer to their query straight from Google using generative AI. There are surely benefits to this for Google, such as cutting out the person in the middle. Any revenue Google might earn from AI in Search would go directly to the company instead of being split with publishers. </p><p>The question of how Google makes money from AI overviews is still unanswered. I&apos;m inclined to think that Google cares about collecting user data more than anything else. While it won&apos;t directly earn ad revenue from AI overviews in Google Search, it will still collect data. The tricky part is that the main purpose of Google&apos;s data collection is to serve personalized ads to users. If people aren&apos;t clicking on actual websites and seeing personalized ads, it doesn&apos;t matter how much data Google collects — there won&apos;t be any advertisements to serve.</p><p>There are other ways Google could increase revenue from SGE, and e-commerce looks to be a big one. </p><p>At I/O 2024, the company announced that Google Shopping is getting AI-based features, and that could be a growth opportunity. There were also rumors that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-is-reportedly-weighing-making-search-generative-experience-a-paid-feature">Google could charge for SGE</a>, though it denied that possibility, at least for now. </p><p>Regardless, there are a lot of unknowns about what might happen to the internet if AI summaries take over. Google, with a rich advertising business clearing over $200 billion annually, seems to have more to lose than it does to gain if things are disrupted. </p>
<h2 id="ai-models-constantly-need-to-source-new-information-2">AI models constantly need to source new information</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3394px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.28%;"><img id="QUuejB6p5fokJUFyse3swb" name="Google-Gemini-app-home-page.JPG" alt="The Google Gemini app" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QUuejB6p5fokJUFyse3swb.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3394" height="1910" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While the large language models (LLMs) that power AI chatbots and features may have large context windows, they are outdated as soon as they are released. For example, the knowledge cutoff date for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini</a> is early 2023. By comparison, OpenAI&apos;s knowledge cutoff date for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/openai-gpt-4o-launch-demo">GPT-4</a> is April 2023. If you ask any AI model what happened last week, last month, or even this time last year — it&apos;ll be clueless. </p><p>The knowledge and effectiveness of AI depends on the new information that it is trained on and that it can tap into. For example, some AI chatbots are able to answer questions about recent events using web results on the internet. Someday, GPT-5 or a future Gemini model will be trained on a newer data set, extending its knowledge cutoff date. It&apos;ll know more about recent events, because human authors, researchers, and publishers have given it data to learn from. </p><p>There&apos;s one key component to the success of AI, and that&apos;s new content. Without new content being created, artificial intelligence models will completely stagnate and won&apos;t be able to answer questions regarding new information. The end goal for AI development is what is known as artificial general intelligence, or AGI. When or if AGI is reached, AI models will function more like human intelligence. Until then, AI is just an incredibly good pattern-matcher that is only as knowledgable as the information it is trained with. </p><p>Again, the problem here is quite obvious. If Google&apos;s plan for Search involves AI overviews that eliminate the need for users to visit websites, there will be little financial incentive for new content to be created. Without new content, AI models will become less and less informed, and they will fail. That&apos;s why Google&apos;s strategy of effectively replacing online publishers is a shortsighted one. Unless companies find a way to compensate publishers for the content that is being used to train AI models, they&apos;ll just stop making that content. </p><p>For what it&apos;s worth, Google would reject the idea that SGE is out to replace online publishing, as CEO Sundar Pichai explained to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.theverge.com/24158374/google-ceo-sundar-pichai-ai-search-gemini-future-of-the-internet-web-openai-decoder-interview" target="_blank">The Verge</a>. "People are responding very positively to AI Overviews. It’s one of the most positive changes I’ve seen in Search based on metrics," Pichai explained. "But people do jump off on it. And when you give context around it, they actually jump off it." </p><p>"It actually helps them understand, and so they engage with content underneath, too," he added. "In fact, if you put content and links within AI Overviews, they get higher clickthrough rates than if you put it outside of AI Overviews."</p><p>We&apos;ll have to wait and see whether Pichai&apos;s opinion of AI overviews turns out to be correct. For now, we can only look at the unexpected drops of organic traffic from Google Search that have hit publishers hard in recent months. Many sites, especially independent ones, have downsized or shuttered altogether due to changes in Google Search rankings. If web traffic continues to drop thanks to AI overviews, it could doom more sites. </p>
<h2 id="cutting-out-publishers-hurts-google-and-ai-xa0-development-in-the-long-run-2">Cutting out publishers hurts Google and AI  development in the long run</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="qnqkKh8GSNWaffJHXJDSr7" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Tab-S9-Ultra-display-01.jpg" alt="Reading Android Central on the Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 Ultra" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qnqkKh8GSNWaffJHXJDSr7.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>At one point, it seemed like Google and online website hosts wanted the same thing and had the same goals. When website owners saw traffic, both Google and the sites earned money from advertisements. Somewhere along the way, the goals of Google and publishers drifted apart from each other. Now, the rollout of AI overviews is the latest example of Google focusing on its own strategies with little regard for the websites it depends on. </p><p>Generative AI might make it seem like Google is less reliant on publishers and creatives than ever, but the opposite is true. If the company goes all-in on AI overviews and SGE, it&apos;ll need publishers to keep churning out content to advance AI models and provide new information to summarize. Without incentivizing people to keep creating on the web, Google could be left without ad revenue <em>and</em> knowledgable AI models. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google/googles-ai-overviews-in-search-might-kill-publishing-and-its-going-to-backfire-eventually</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Now that Google is rolling out AI overviews widely in Search, online media and publishing faces its most fervent threat yet. But if digital publishing falls, so will AI.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">6opNSjeLEVvPsMZ5bkkvVE</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/H668jKUNrYyRWCJvQL4z3D.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 18:43:33 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/H668jKUNrYyRWCJvQL4z3D.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google generative AI in Search]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google generative AI in Search]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Honor 'V Flip' might outdo the competition with a 'super-large' cover display ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Rumors are swirling about Honor's upcoming clamshell foldable and its potential advantage over the competition.</li><li>The "Magic V Flip" could feature a "super-large" cover display that consumes the entire outer panel as its rumored case only frames the device's edges.</li><li>The device is also rumored to feature a 4,500mAh battery setup and a Qualcomm Snapdragon SoC.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Rumors are surfacing about Honor&apos;s upcoming clamshell foldable, and there are a lot of eyes on its cover display.</p><p>Chinese Weibo leaker <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://weibo.com/6048569942/Ofha70XWL">Digital Chat Station</a> (DCS) posted the rumors, stating the Magic V Flip&apos;s cover display will span the entire outer panel (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.thetechoutlook.com/new-release/gadgets-release/mobile/honor-magic-v-flips-case-image-hints-a-massive-cover-display/">TheTechOutlook</a>). The screen is touted as a "super-large" display that could rival others in the clamshell foldable industry, like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-review">Razr Plus 2023</a> and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-5-review">Galaxy Z Flip 5</a>.</p><p>Additionally, DCS posted an alleged early render of the case for the Magic V Flip. With it, the tipster states the "outer screen&apos;s shell only borders" the device, pointing toward its all-encompassing design.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:566px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:76.15%;"><img id="9DoLS8cw4UPqZuUk96ctcR" name="honor-magic-v-flip-rumored-case-frame.jpg" alt="A rumored look at the Honor Magic V Flip case frame around its cover display." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9DoLS8cw4UPqZuUk96ctcR.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="566" height="431" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Digital Chat Station / Weibo)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The rumors don&apos;t end there as <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.thetechoutlook.com/new-release/gadgets-release/mobile/honors-magic-flip-tipped-to-feature-largest-battery-on-a-flip-phone-4500-mah-battery-backup/">the publication reiterates</a> that Honor&apos;s clamshell could arrive with a 4,500mAh battery. DCS led those rumors, with the proposed battery setup purported as 2,420mAh and 1,980mAh.</p><p>Moreover, there&apos;s speculation that Honor could power the V Flip with a Qualcomm Snapdragon SoC, but we&apos;ll have to wait and see. Rumors added that the device could be the "thinnest and lightest" among its industry competitors.</p><p>We&apos;re still left theorizing about when Honor could debut the device. The publication notes that the company is preparing to debut its 200 phone series on May 27 in China. It could follow this with a "Magic V Flip" launch in June.</p><p>For context, Motorola&apos;s 2023 clamshell offers a 3.6-inch cover display, while Samsung&apos;s features a 3.4-inch screen. Rumors haven&apos;t gotten specific regarding Honor&apos;s version, though they&apos;re pointing us in the direction of "super-large." However, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/major-motorola-razr-plus-2024-specs-leak">recent leaks</a> for Moto&apos;s upcoming Razr Plus 2024 suggest its display could reach 3.9 inches.</p><p>Elsewhere, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/honor-developing-a-smart-ring">during MWC 2024</a>, Honor appeared and teased that it was getting into the Flip foldable game. The company&apos;s CEO George Zhao stated, "this year we are preparing for the flip phone launch—now that we are internally in the final stage."</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-v-flip-cover-display-battery-case-rumors</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A new leak suggested Honor's upcoming clamshell could have a cover display to beat its competition. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">uzzfqPEQ7a7f7R3UcLZwj</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2WSHnQTAk6zbgwTguDRwCg.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 18:24:27 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2WSHnQTAk6zbgwTguDRwCg.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Honor Magic 6 Pro review]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Honor Magic 6 Pro review]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google rolls out Android 15 Beta 2.1 in haste following user woes ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>After users spotted issues with the new Private Space feature, Google rolled out the new Android 15 Beta 2.1 update.</li><li>The update is only rolling out to Pixel devices 6 and over, with a file size of 12 MB.</li><li>Android Beta 2.1 will be automatically available OTA for eligible devices enrolled in the Beta program on the System Updates tab.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>After showing off the new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-beta-2-just-landed-for-google-pixels-and-non-pixel-devices-too">Android 15 Beta 2 </a>at I/O last week, Google had to follow it up with another update as those who downloaded the Beta were experiencing major issues with the Private Space feature. </p><p>The feature allows you to lock sensitive apps in a separate section that is password protected. Once locked, these apps don&apos;t appear in the app drawer or the overview menu; they&apos;re hidden inside a new user profile.</p><p>However, when some <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/android_beta/comments/1cwm0ra/android_15_beta_21_patch_now_available/">users tried</a> this for the first time, they saw it deleted app icons from the Home screen.<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://issuetracker.google.com/issues/340868295"> Google&apos;s Issue Tracker</a> website also details that this has been brought to their attention and that Beta 2.1, a "minor update," began rolling out to all eligible Pixels on Monday (May 20).</p><p>The build number for this update is <strong>AP31.240426.023</strong>, and it comes with Play Services version 24.15.18</p>
<p>According to Android Police,  the new version initially <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidpolice.com/android-15-beta-21-b/">came out </a>with a 2.57GB file size on one of their devices before downloading. However, users who installed this update stated in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/android_beta/comments/1cwm0ra/android_15_beta_21_patch_now_available/">Reddit thread</a> that the file size was anywhere between<br>
11.30 MB to 12.12 MB when they restarted their device. </p><p>Google says that only Pixel devices that are enrolled in the beta program will automatically get offered an over-the-air (OTA) update, i.e., <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a"> Pixel 8a</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8">Pixel 8</a>, Pixel 8 Pro, Pixel 7a, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-7-pro-review">Pixel 7 Pro</a>, Pixel 7, Pixel 6a, Pixel 6 Pro, Pixel 6, Pixel Fold, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/google-pixel-tablet-eyntk">Pixel Tablet</a>. </p><p>However, any<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15"> other new devices</a> set to receive the expanded Android 15 Beta might get their own updates based on the device. These include Honor, Nothing, OnePlus, Vivo, and more phones. </p><p>Per the update notes, the OTA update may take up to 24 hours to arrive on your device. You can check for updates by visiting <strong>Settings > System > System updates.</strong></p><p>However, one user took to Reddit to share that the new Beta 2.1 update was throwing an error on the Android Beta Feedback App, while most users saw that it fixed the Private space issue for them.</p>
<blockquote class="reddit-card"  ><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/android_beta/comments/1cwm0ra/comment/l4wyjfx">Comment</a> from <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/android_beta">r/android_beta</a></blockquote><script async src="//embed.redditmedia.com/widgets/platform.js" charset="UTF-8"></script>
<p>While new Beta updates bring several exciting features to your phones, users should <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/dont-install-android-15-dev-preview">be wary of downloading</a> as they may come with a new set of issues. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-rolls-out-android-15-beta-21-in-haste-following-user-woes</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ After several users spotted an issue with Private space, Google had to roll out Android 15 Beta 2.1.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Ge9exq4DSypJWzdttm9JQk</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AxWTrfRYJAJ7DLJEZoxu5g.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 17:42:30 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nandika.iyerravi@futurenet.com (Nandika Ravi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AxWTrfRYJAJ7DLJEZoxu5g.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android 15 home screen]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android 15 home screen]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ RedMagic takes on SHARGE with this cool 150W transparent GaN charger ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Gadget Weekly</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="DZLQ4jKZk9tEF5A3sqU5Jh" name="inspector-lloyd-square.jpg" caption="" alt="Inspector Lloyd" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DZLQ4jKZk9tEF5A3sqU5Jh.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">Join Namerah Saud Fatmi as she explores the cool, quirky, and sometimes downright odd world of smartphone accessories, gadgets, and other nerdy toys <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/gadget-weekly">every week</a>.</p></div></div>
<p>Brands like Nothing and SHARGE are living, breathing proof that transparent tech is more than just a fad. From earbuds and portable power banks to Android phones, we&apos;ve seen more and more enthusiast-centric products come out with see-through designs and they&apos;re the most creative kind of gadgets imaginable.</p><p>RedMagic is anything but new to the game and has become famous for incorporating see-through elements into its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-phone-gamers">gaming phones</a> and other accessories. The RedMagic 9 Pro is the brand&apos;s current top-of-the-line offering, and it comes in both opaque and stunningly transparent iterations. If you <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/redmagic-9-pro-review">read my review</a>, you must&apos;ve gotten a good look at the icy Snowfall variant of the phone in all of its see-through glory.</p><p>If you&apos;re obsessed with transparent tech and its futuristic vibe, SHARGE&apos;s — or Shargeek&apos;s — lineup of high-wattage power banks and chargers must be on your wishlist. If you&apos;re looking for proper alternatives, RedMagic has launched its own overpowered, transparent charger to spice things up.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4032px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="Nu7bYLuAAFebNP4B5zdoMC" name="RedMagic-DAO-150W-GaN-Charger-1.jpg" alt="RedMagic DAO 150W GaN Charger" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Nu7bYLuAAFebNP4B5zdoMC.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4032" height="2268" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4032px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="FmbJt5qfaGCyvwi6Asit8B" name="RedMagic-DAO-150W-GaN-Charger-3.jpg" alt="RedMagic DAO 150W GaN Charger" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FmbJt5qfaGCyvwi6Asit8B.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4032" height="2268" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4032px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="jQtQx5tGscQFQud3c5CXiE" name="RedMagic-DAO-150W-GaN-Charger-5.jpg" alt="RedMagic DAO 150W GaN Charger" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jQtQx5tGscQFQud3c5CXiE.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4032" height="2268" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Officially released in March 2024, the RedMagic DAO 150W GaN Charger is now globally available for about $199 or €199, depending on the region. Considering its insanely cool look and charging capabilities, that isn&apos;t too steep a price. After all, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/sharge-shargeek-170-power-bank-review">SHARGE Shargeek 170 Power Bank</a> retails at $199. Of course, the main difference there is that the Shargeek 170 Power Bank is a portable battery pack as well as a charger.</p><p>Let&apos;s look at what the DAO 150W GaN Charger has to offer in terms of ports, compatibility, and accessories. Here&apos;s a quick summary:</p>
<ul><li><strong>USB-C (Port 1): </strong>140W</li><li><strong>USB-C (Port 2): </strong>140W</li><li><strong>USB-A: </strong>30W</li><li><strong>DC: </strong>150W</li><li><strong>Compatibility: </strong>QC3.0/QC4.0, PD2.0/PD3.0/PD3.1, PPS</li><li><strong>Accessories:</strong> AC extension cord, DC-to-DC cable,  6A 150W USB-C-to-USB-C data cable, velvet pouch</li></ul>
<p>Apart from four ports, you get a colorful LCD display that indicates the voltage of each port in use. The screen is touch-activated. RedMagic also added foldable prongs to the DAO 150W GaN Charger and an interesting extension cord that extends the charger via a cable that plugs into a mains socket.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4032px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="VZw2eq3YWwgcs8KoqBa2dD" name="RedMagic-DAO-150W-GaN-Charger-4.jpg" alt="RedMagic DAO 150W GaN Charger" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VZw2eq3YWwgcs8KoqBa2dD.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4032" height="2268" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>To make this extravagant charger even more over the top, RedMagic also added Bluetooth connectivity to the 150W GaN Charger. Why would you possibly want Bluetooth in a charger? To control the RGB, of course!</p><p>That&apos;s right, RedMagic went to town on this thing and added its boisterous flavor of gaming core to the DAO 150W GaN Charger.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3394px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="3jYz6c4XZCoaDJ8XPixwt9" name="RedMagic-DAO-150W-GaN-Charger-8.jpg" alt="RedMagic DAO 150W GaN Charger" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3jYz6c4XZCoaDJ8XPixwt9.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="3394" height="1909" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3561px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="mPf8nsFYxrX95AGb75dCFF" name="RedMagic-DAO-150W-GaN-Charger-7.jpg" alt="RedMagic DAO 150W GaN Charger" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mPf8nsFYxrX95AGb75dCFF.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="3561" height="2003" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Thanks to the Chinese gaming brand&apos;s Goper app, you can view the current power output of the ports on your <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phone</a>. What&apos;s more fun is that you can customize the RGB lights extensively, from the colors and shifts in shades to the speed and style. And if you&apos;re about to go to sleep, you can turn the lights off altogether.</p><p>And if you want to go all in, you can set a custom screensaver for your transparent RGB charger through the app. How insane is that? It&apos;s not like these practical additions change anything from a functional perspective. But it&apos;s the creativity and fun that drive it home for me.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3866px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.26%;"><img id="QFkHkXNEzk3bvYahe4gtG9" name="RedMagic-DAO-150W-GaN-Charger-6.jpg" alt="RedMagic DAO 150W GaN Charger" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QFkHkXNEzk3bvYahe4gtG9.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3866" height="2175" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Should the occasion call for it, you can whip out the included DC-to-DC cable to power something off of it or use the AC extension cord in the box to lengthen the 150W charger. RedMagic kindly included a USB-A port, too, so if you&apos;ve got cables other than Type-C, you&apos;ll be good to go.</p><p>The combination of ports and cords in the box makes this a versatile buy. Just like SHARGE&apos;s iconic yellow custom cables, RedMagic&apos;s wires are bright yellow and come with customized heads. Plus, the RedMagic DAO has the latest PD 3.1 charging protocol, so you get wider compatibility.</p><p>The RedMagic DAO 150W GaN Charger might not be a very portable charging solution, but it&apos;s an excellent charger that makes the basic task of topping up devices a whole lot more fun. Is it worth paying $200 to attain one? That&apos;s subjective, but if you have the money and the nerdy passion for it, I say yes.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="53c9aeb9-2d76-415e-a541-b0318600e688">
            <a href="https://na.redmagic.gg/products/redmagic-dao-150w-gan-charger" data-model-name="null"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yLS9WWEwRuwbeZtusdp7MM.jpg' alt='RedMagic DAO 150W GaN Charger'></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">RedMagic DAO 150W GaN Charger</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="80" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>For heavy-duty gamers</strong></em></p>
<p>RedMagic has expanded its mobile accessories lineup to include the fantastic DAO 150W GaN Charger. This transparent, RGB-laden 150W charger has lots of ports and lots more to love.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/redmagic-dao-150w-gan-charger-hands-on</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ RedMagic drew inspiration from SHARGE with its beefed-up new GaN charger and we're all for it. Here's a hands-on look at the see-through charging accessory. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">uLMjttPbcmcsKQCqbDEQr3</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rXXPJXPsfeBrMDRUaSQ6B8.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 17:26:12 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rXXPJXPsfeBrMDRUaSQ6B8.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[RedMagic DAO 150W GaN Charger]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[RedMagic DAO 150W GaN Charger]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Our favorite headphones for battery life are 24% off during Amazon's Memorial Day sale ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Wireless headphone deals for name brands like Sennheiser only come around every so often, and they&apos;re often well worth your consideration. Right now, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0B6GHW1SX"><strong>Amazon is offering the Sennheiser Momentum 4 headphones for 24% off</strong></a>, This is our favorite over-ear headphone model for battery life, offering as much as 60 hours per charge — that&apos;s an increase of 17 hours compared to Sennheiser&apos;s previous generation. </p><p>The Momentum 4 headphones also have great ANC settings, really comfortable ear cups, and the high-tier audio quality that&apos;s become synonymous with Sennheiser.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="8b496a3b-e47b-4e12-8394-58a5a3dc7d1e" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$379.95" data-dimension48="$379.95" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0B6GHW1SX" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:480px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.21%;"><img id="VFKzYrQaDLuqVNKSZohoDG" name="Sennheiser-Momentum-4-render-bg.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VFKzYrQaDLuqVNKSZohoDG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="480" height="601" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Sennheiser Momentum 4 Wireless Headphones:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0B6GHW1SX" data-dimension112="8b496a3b-e47b-4e12-8394-58a5a3dc7d1e" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$379.95" data-dimension48="$379.95"><del>$379.95</del> <strong>$290.10 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>You can get 24% off the Sennheiser Momentum 4 wireless headphones for a limited time! The <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/headphones/sennheiser-momentum-4-wireless">Momentum 4</a> wireless headphones offer impressive specs across the board, but where they really shine is in the battery life department. With around 60 hours of wireless battery life per charge, these headphones pretty easily top other headphones, making it so most users rarely ever need to charge them up.</p>
<p><strong>Price comparison:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/sennheiser-momentum-4-wireless-adaptive-noise-canceling-over-the-ear-headphones-denim/6557562.p">Best Buy - $399.99</a> | <a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Sennheiser-Momentum-4-Wireless-Headphones-Bluetooth-Headset-Crystal-Clear-Calls-Adaptive-Noise-Cancellation-60h-Battery-Life-Customizable-Sound-Black/1870220056">Walmart - $299.95</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0B6GHW1SX" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="8b496a3b-e47b-4e12-8394-58a5a3dc7d1e" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$379.95" data-dimension48="$379.95">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>you&apos;re looking for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones">best wireless headphones</a> for industry-leading battery life; you have liked other Sennheiser products you&apos;ve owned in the past.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>you prefer headphones with a seriously eye-catching design language; you need something with highly customizable EQ settings.</p><p>The Sennheiser Momentum 4s may not have the most aesthetically pleasing design overall, but they do have some of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones#section-best-battery-life">best battery life</a> in the headphone industry, and it&apos;s hard to argue with their audio quality. The ANC settings let you visualize and see how much sound the headphones are canceling. This alongside EQ and other audio options are available to edit from the easy-to-use Sennheiser app, offering presets, sound check mode, individualized sound zones, and more.</p><p>It&apos;s worth noting that the EQ offerings could be better since they only offer three-band customization options. But frankly, it&apos;s tough to make these headphones sound <em>bad</em>, and most users are content with the audio they&apos;re able to achieve with them. Plus, with this discount, you&apos;ll find these headphones to be a better pick than most around this price point.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/headphones/our-favorite-headphones-for-battery-life-are-24-off-during-amazons-memorial-day-sale</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Sennheiser Momentum 4 wireless headphones are 24% off at Amazon, marking a solid deal on our favorite headphones for battery life. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">rziDBeD9nGjn5cUyhPEJtK</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SRiLsqEg5pnqej8NLsMc8n.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 17:00:35 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Headphones]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SRiLsqEg5pnqej8NLsMc8n.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Sennheiser]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Sennheiser Momentum 4 headphones with stylized background]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Sennheiser Momentum 4 headphones with stylized background]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ New listing teases Vivo X Fold 3 Pro debut in India ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-32">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Vivo X Fold 3 Pro is the latest flagship foldable phone launched in China.</li><li>New Flipkart listing hints at the Pro model coming to the Indian market for the first time.</li><li>It is unclear whether the standard Vivo X Fold 3 is also debuting into the country.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>A new e-commerce listing confirms that Vivo is likely expanding its foldable market, which was earlier confined to China. The upcoming Vivo X Fold 3 Pro has been teased for the Indian market.</p><p>Flipkart, which exclusively sells phones like the recent <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/nothing-phone-2a-review">Phone 2a</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-review">Pixel 8a</a>, will also sell the latest foldable Vivo X Fold 3 Pro soon. It is unclear whether the regular Vivo X Fold 3 will also be released alongside the Pro variant. For now, the<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.flipkart.com/vivo-x-fold3-pro-coming-soon-hd38k-store?"> listing</a> hints that the foldable phone will be coming soon and will feature ZEISS-powered cameras.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="syu7oMHmv5Nmc2bdvEy6cc" name="vivo-x-fold-3-pro-02.jpg" alt="Vivo X Fold 3 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/syu7oMHmv5Nmc2bdvEy6cc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Vivo)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The previous Vivo X Fold 2 models were confined to the Chinese market, and the successor series, including the Vivo X Fold 3 and the Pro model, was <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.vivo.com.cn/vivo/xfold3pro/">launched</a> in China in March. The Vivo X Fold 3 Pro is one of the thinner, good-looking foldable smartphones, measuring 5.2mm in thickness (unfolded) and 11.2mm when folded. </p><p>The Chinese variant has sported a large 8.03-inch foldable screen and a 6.53-inch outer screen. Both have AMOLED displays with refresh rates of up to 120Hz. A large circular module at the back comprises a triple camera setup featuring a 50MP primary camera, a 50MP ultra-wide angle lens, and a 64MP ZEISS-powered telephoto lens. The cover and foldable screen equip a 32MP selfie shooter for selfies and video conferencing.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="PZyLCpuLAgASvPkuRpqAhc" name="vivo-x-fold-3-pro-03.jpg" alt="Vivo X Fold 3 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PZyLCpuLAgASvPkuRpqAhc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Vivo)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Vivo X Fold 3 Pro is powered by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-3-launch">Snapdragon 8 Gen 3</a> and features up to 16GB of RAM and 512GB of onboard storage. Keeping the lights on is a large 5700mAh battery capacity aided by 100W fast charge support. Out of the box, the device ships with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review">Android 14</a>-based OriginOS 4.</p><p>It is encouraging to see Vivo expanding its folding technology prowess to other markets, otherwise dominated by Samsung, OnePlus, and Oppo with their <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-5-review">Galaxy Z Fold 5</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-open-review">OnePlus Open</a>, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oppo-find-n3-and-n3-flip-global-launch">OPPO Find N3</a> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">foldable phones</a>. Venturing through India’s diverse smartphone market is a promising move for the upcoming Vivo foldable phone.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/vivo-x-fold-3-pro-is-expanding-to-indian-market</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Vivo recently launched X Fold 3 and X Fold 3 Pro phones in China, and the latter is venturing into the Indian market this year. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">9JAQ9bXvLLLDdKaawgmKT3</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NEqiJxpyJqbEfFcEsojJXc.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 14:52:48 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NEqiJxpyJqbEfFcEsojJXc.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Vivo]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Vivo X Fold 3 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Vivo X Fold 3 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Sonos Ace are the brand's first pair of over-ear headphones ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-37">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Sonos is launching its first-ever pair of headphones with Ace, Bluetooth wireless over-ear headphones designed to fit in its wider ecosystem.</li><li>The Sonos Ace has active noise cancelation (ANC), supports hi-res audio, and features a battery life of up to 30 hours.</li><li>They are compatible with Dolby Atmos, include head tracking, and can integrate with select Sonos soundbars to listen to TV audio through the Ace.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>It only took two decades, but Sonos has finally branched out from making speakers. The Sonos Ace is the brand&apos;s first-ever pair of headphones, engineered in-house with its trademark penchant for resonant sound. Now, you&apos;ll be able to bring that sound into any room.</p><p>The Sonos Ace will ship in black or soft white, mirroring Sonos&apos; more recent color choices with its Era speakers. In a unique design trait, the ear cups are removable, making them easier to clean or swap out for new colors or replacements.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="GSSZBZ22aH7mU2Zy6NtoZW" name="Sonos-Ace-ear-cups.jpg" alt="Sonos Ace ear cups are removable." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GSSZBZ22aH7mU2Zy6NtoZW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ted Kritsonis / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>These are Bluetooth wireless headphones but also offer wired playback through the lone USB-C port. Two cables — one a USB-C-to-USB-C, the other a USB-C-to-3.5mm — will come in the box to accommodate a wide range of playback devices when you want to go wired or prefer to listen to hi-res tunes at the highest quality.</p><p>Sonos is also throwing a bone at those wanting wireless hi-res playback by supporting Qualcomm&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/qualcomm-snapdragon-sound">Snapdragon Sound</a> through its aptX Lossless Bluetooth codec. With the right device and content source (think Tidal, Qobuz, Amazon Music, or Apple Music), you can get higher bit rates. It marks the first time Sonos is supporting any hi-res Bluetooth codec, as previous <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-sonos-speakers">Sonos speakers</a> like the Move, Move 2, and Roam haven&apos;t done the same.</p><p>There are 40mm dynamic drivers and four microphones arrayed on each cup, the latter to help deliver effective active noise cancelation (ANC) and a clearer Aware mode. Sonos says they&apos;re beamforming mics that will muffle background noise and ensure voices are clearer during phone calls as well. Built-in wear sensors will detect if you remove the headphones and auto-pause playback until you put the headset back on.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="83jk6kohg9iYALUTU6qCvV" name="Sonos-Ace-wearing-hands-on.jpg" alt="Trying on the Sonos Ace headphones." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/83jk6kohg9iYALUTU6qCvV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ted Kritsonis / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Swappable cups also explain why the Ace doesn&apos;t have any touch-based controls. A button on the right cup toggles between ANC and Aware mode. Holding it down awakens your phone&apos;s voice assistant. The Content Key slider button controls volume, playback, and phone calls.</p><p>The Sonos app isn&apos;t required to set up the Ace, though you will need it if you want to adjust the basic EQ (bass, treble, loudness) and connect to compatible Sonos speakers. </p><p>At launch, the Ace will integrate with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/sonos-arc-review">Sonos Arc</a> first, so you can swap TV audio from the soundbar to your headphones for more private listening. After setting it up in the app, you can hold down the Content Key to switch between them. This ad hoc connection happens over Wi-Fi without having to manually connect the Ace to a Wi-Fi network because the headphones piggyback onto the Arc&apos;s existing connection. </p><p>Sonos says it will soon expand compatibility to its other current soundbars, like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/sonos-beam-review">Beam</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/sonos-beam-gen-2-review">Beam 2</a>, and Ray.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="zX7NLohYdhCNapzeoVaFqU" name="Sonos-Ace-app-home-theater.jpg" alt="Sonos app showing Ace headphones swap with Sonos Arc." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zX7NLohYdhCNapzeoVaFqU.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ted Kritsonis / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Sonos Ace comes with Dolby Atmos support and can stream spatial audio content from supported services, including head tracking, wherever available. Later in 2024, it&apos;ll add "TrueCinema," new tech that will map the space around you and create a virtual surround sound system meant to emulate the room you&apos;re in. This is slightly different from how Sonos&apos; Trueplay adjusts sound by measuring a room&apos;s acoustics. It uses Ace&apos;s microphones to complete the virtual map and is specifically aimed at spatial audio.</p><p>Sonos will include a felt case made of 75% recycled plastic water bottles to fit the Ace (and all cables) inside snugly. Battery life is rated at 30 hours per charge with ANC on for audio playback, though Sonos didn&apos;t quantify how much it drops when using it in a home theater setting connected to a soundbar. A quick three-minute charge with the USB-C cable delivers up to three hours of playback.</p><p>They&apos;ll come at a premium for $449 and will be available for pre-order from Sonos starting May 21, with general availability on June 5.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/audio/sonos-launch-ace-headphones</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Sonos Ace are wireless Bluetooth headphones built to expand the company's pedigree in sound quality. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">mgtWTGXhHuMQJd4w4F2mC6</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CtSeGHd6fNuwVrUPRa86TV.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 13:00:52 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Headphones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ ted@byteddyk.com (Ted Kritsonis) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CtSeGHd6fNuwVrUPRa86TV.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Ted Kritsonis / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Sonos Ace headphones in soft white resting on holder.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Sonos Ace headphones in soft white resting on holder.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>