<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 16:34:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Android 15 might finally make your Pixel's webcam a little less frustrating ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Last year's rollout of the webcam feature for Pixel phones with Android 14 QPR1 fell short in image quality, but Google seems to be addressing this shortcoming for the next Android version.</li><li>The latest Android 15 Developer Preview introduces a High-Quality mode for the webcam.</li><li>While the HQ mode may impact battery life, the noticeable improvement in video quality could make it worthwhile for tasks like video streaming.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google seems to be working on beefing up Android&apos;s built-in webcam feature to match Apple&apos;s <em>Continuity Camera</em> quality.</p><p>Last year, Google <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-qpr-beta-webcam-feature-video-quality">rolled out a webcam feature for Pixel phones</a>, kicking off with Android 14 QPR1. Though it sounded promising, the actual image quality when using it on an Android device often fell short. However, Google appears to have listened to user feedback and is working on improving it for the next Android version.</p><p>In the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-second-developer-preview">latest Android 15 Developer Preview release</a>, Google has thrown in a fresh HQ button for the webcam, as spotted by Mishaal Rahman over at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/android-webcam-high-quality-mode-3427591/" target="_blank">Android Authority</a>. It&apos;s located in the top-left corner of the viewfinder, and tapping that button brings up <em>High Quality</em> mode, ramping up the video quality big time.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:332px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:222.89%;"><img id="DapMMSiJBDvaaQA944ztqm" name="Android-webcam-HQ-mode.jpg" alt="HQ button in Android's built-in webcam interface" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DapMMSiJBDvaaQA944ztqm.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="332" height="740" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The feature does that by flicking off Google&apos;s power optimizations behind the scenes. According to Rahman&apos;s experiments, the Pixel phone seems to be pumping out video streams in Full HD at 30 frames per second.</p><p>Based on his testing, the video quality doesn&apos;t seem to be munching away at the phone&apos;s battery life. Plus, even after a solid 2.5-hour grind, Rahman didn&apos;t notice his <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-pro-review">Pixel 8 Pro</a> breaking a sweat and overheating.</p><p>Of course, diving into HQ Mode is bound to nibble on your battery life, so if you&apos;re planning a marathon video session, it might be wise to leave it off to save juice. But Rahman suggests that for specific tasks like streaming video, it could be worth flipping the switch because the boost in video quality is pretty darn noticeable.</p><p>This could be a game changer for users keen on capturing higher-quality video content without breaking the bank. Instead of shelling out for a pricey webcam, you can tap into your phone&apos;s potential and save yourself some cash.</p><p>It&apos;s nice to see Google fixing a big issue with Pixel phone webcams. But remember, this feature is only in the latest <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a> developer preview. While we&apos;re hopeful it&apos;ll stick around for the final build, there&apos;s always a chance it could pull a disappearing act, as we&apos;ve seen happen before with Android beta features.</p><p>Once Android 15 hits the stable channel, we&apos;ll have to wait and see if this stays for the long haul.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-could-offer-high-quality-mode-for-webcam</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Android 15 might let you crank up the quality of your phone's webcam. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">gxxuhyHmou4gJxxNncfzxW</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/g9Bi4RbHqqdWBpSRdhqiWg.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 16:30:44 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/g9Bi4RbHqqdWBpSRdhqiWg.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android 15 logo]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android 15 logo]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Shopping gets seamless as Google rolls out new tools ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Users in the U.S. can now have a personalized shopping experience — thanks to Google.</li><li>The search giant is bringing nifty new features to Google Search on mobile, desktop, and the app.</li><li>It will include style recommendations, an AI-powered image generation tool, and a virtual try-on option.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google wants to make your shopping experience more personalized by introducing new tools, the search giant announced today (Mar.27).</p><p>Users in the U.S. who usually use mobile browsers or the Google app to shop for apparel or accessories will now see a new section dubbed "style recommendations."</p><p>It will have various options to choose from and rate with a thumbs up or thumbs down button. Users can further swipe right or left to see their personalized results. Google says more options will be provided when users don&apos;t find what they are looking for, and they can keep on the search.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:292px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:205.48%;"><img id="XSZ84GHToJkfBhiXaMhRZR" name="Google-Shopping-Style-Picking-Tool.gif" alt="Google Shopping Style Pick tool" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XSZ84GHToJkfBhiXaMhRZR.gif" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="292" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google will remember these preferences, and the next time users search for the same set of accessories/apparel, they will get personalized results based on the saved preferences. If  any accidental taps occur, users can tap on three dots next to the Search result and "look for personalization options in the "About this result" panel."</p><p>Additionally, Google allows U.S. shoppers to specify brands they like when choosing apparel, shoes, or accessories on mobile, desktop, and the Google app. Once they choose their brands, the subsequent search results will showcase products from those brands first. As mentioned, they can still change their preferences in the aforementioned process.</p><p>Users in the U.S. who <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.google/products/shopping/google-search-generative-ai-holiday-gifts/#:~:text=Shop%20what%E2%80%99s%20(literally)%20on%20your%20mind">opted for</a> Search Generative Experience (SGE) via Search Labs will have access to a new experimental feature on the Google app and mobile browsers. It is an AI-powered image generation for shopping tool that allows users to find their favorite products based on their search query. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1227px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:48.90%;"><img id="jUko56SQrmahFNLgchXXMT" name="google-shopping-ai-tool.jpg" alt="Google Shopping AI tool" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jUko56SQrmahFNLgchXXMT.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1227" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google cites examples like the "colorful quilted spring jacket" search query, which showcases photorealistic images that match users&apos; ideas. Once the images are generated, they can select and view suitable options by scrolling through them. </p><p>After finding the right one, the search giant is offering shoppers a virtual try-on (VTO) tool. The tool was first <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-ai-clothes-virtual-try-on">introduced</a> last year for U.S. users shopping on desktop, mobile, or the Google app. The tool provides a diverse set of models, including sizes ranging from XXS to 4XL. Users can look for the "try-on" icon in shopping results to check out the men&apos;s or women&apos;s tops.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-rolls-out-new-shopping-tools</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google is bringing many new tools to enhance the shopping experience, including options like AI-generated photorealist images for a search query. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">KG6XXatLFiSRhd3gQn2TsZ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ytdSPYoHBv4V5TYinvRNRU.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ytdSPYoHBv4V5TYinvRNRU.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[null]]></media:credit>
                                                                                </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Three Google Map updates to help you prep for your next vacation ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google has announced three updates to Google Maps that promise to make planning your next trip easier than ever.</li><li>These introduce three major new features – curated recommendations, customized lists, and AI that can help you on the go.</li><li>The updates will start rolling out over the next few weeks.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>When you’re planning a vacation, deciding where to stay, what to eat, and which sites to see can be hard work. And while guidebooks can be incredibly helpful, they aren’t always up to date with the latest information. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-maps-popularity-united-states-study">Google Maps is already the most popular navigation app</a> that helps people find their way. Today, Google has announced three updates to Maps that promise to make planning where to go a lot easier.</p><p>When visiting a new destination, it’s normal to look for recommendations from other travelers or locals to help decide what to do. The first Maps update promises to make this easier by providing curated lists of recommendations “from people who know the city well.” In addition, Maps will give you lists from well-respected expert sites, such as Lonely Planet and OpenTable. </p>
<p>This update will roll out in the US and Canada this week, providing lists for more than 40 cities in these two countries. If you’re visiting any of those cities, you can search for it in Maps and swipe up to see the list of recommendations.</p><p>There are also three types of curated restaurant lists being prepped: The “Trending” list, which includes “places that have recently seen a spike in popularity on Maps.” The &apos;top&apos; list identifies places that are consistently popular with the Maps community. Finally, the &apos;gems&apos; list helps you find great restaurants that perhaps aren’t as well known. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="hyUdeUHaQVABZe6dzNcqGG" name="Google-Maps-recommendations-and-customized-lists.jpg" alt="Screenshots of recommendations, customised lists and AI updates" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hyUdeUHaQVABZe6dzNcqGG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Another Maps update allows users to create lists by tapping the<em><strong> new list</strong></em> button under the <em><strong>saved</strong></em> tab. This will allow users to compile a list of places they want to go and places they’ve been. </p><p>Users can then move destinations up and down on their list to rank them. According to Google, “you can choose the order places to appear in your lists to make them even more useful. So if you’re planning a trip and compiling recommendations, you can organize them chronologically — like an itinerary.” You’ll also be able to link your lists to content from your social media. This update is due to roll out globally later this month on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android</a> and iOS.</p>
<p>Finally, Google is bringing AI to Maps to help users with real-time decision-making. This appears to be an advancement on an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-details-gen-ai-search-maps">update from February</a>, which introduced generative AI to select Local Guides. </p><p>According to Google: “When you’re checking out a restaurant and scrolling through photos of the food, we’ll use AI to help you identify what a dish is called (perfect if you’re in a new city and not familiar with the cuisine), and show you helpful information based on the menu — like what it costs, if it’s popular, and even if it’s vegetarian or vegan.” You’ll also receive reviews to help you decide if it’s the right place for you. This builds on Maps’ ability to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-maps-now-identifies-the-menu-items-in-restaurant-food-photos">identify menu items based on restaurant food photos</a>, which was spotted in January.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-maps">Google Maps</a> is also planning a design refresh over the coming months. This includes reducing the number of home screen tabs and new pin colors that help you find places on the map more easily. Having recently rolled out a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-maps-directions-ui-redesign-rollout">redesign for the Maps UI</a>, Google is working hard to make Maps as helpful and user-friendly as possible.  </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-maps-gets-three-new-updates</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google Maps is introducing three tweaks to help users access relevant information about their destination. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">UXAf6fvfbFxyVyrvXkpCec</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yuBWmaqBPBVsNYRK3uPqHm.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ stevenshaw444@gmail.com (Steven Shaw) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yuBWmaqBPBVsNYRK3uPqHm.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A view of Chicago on Google Maps running on a ThinkPhone by Motorola]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A view of Chicago on Google Maps running on a ThinkPhone by Motorola]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Circle to Search will roll out to more Android devices this week, including Pixel Fold and Tablet ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google released Circle to Search earlier this year, but it was limited to current-generation Google and Samsung phones.</li><li>After expanding Circle to Search to the Pixel 7 and Pixel 7 Pro, Google announced today the feature will come to the Pixel 6 series, Pixel 7a, Pixel Fold, and Pixel Tablet this week.</li><li>Samsung Galaxy devices released in 2023 will also get Circle to Search this week, including the Galaxy Z Fold 5, Galaxy Z Flip 5, Galaxy S23 series, and Galaxy Tab S9 series. </li><li>Separately, Google is optimizing Circle to Search and Search Generative Experience to help with your summer activities. </li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google released <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-circle-to-search">Circle to Search</a> alongside the Samsung Galaxy S24 series in January, and it quickly became one of the best software features shipped this year. While it was initially limited to Google and Samsung&apos;s most recent <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">flagship phones</a>, Google today announced Circle to Search will start rolling out to more Android phones, foldables, and tablets beginning this week. Additionally, Circle to Search will soon gain the ability to translate the contents of your screen in an instant. </p><p>The availability of the Circle to Search feature was a point of contention for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-fold-review">Pixel Fold</a> owners. The Pixel 8 series was the first Google phone to receive the feature, but Circle to Search later expanded to the Pixel 7 and Pixel 7 Pro. For weeks, owners of Google&apos;s $1,800 foldable were left in the dark as to whether their smartphone would eventually get Circle to Search. Starting today (Mar. 27), Google confirms that Circle to Search is "coming soon" to both the Pixel Fold and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/google-pixel-tablet-review">Pixel Tablet</a>. </p><p>The last three years of Google phones will support Circle to Search, as will the 2023 lineup of Samsung Galaxy devices. You can view the full list of newly supported devices below, which will gain Circle to Search as early as this week. </p>
<ul><li>Google Pixel 6</li><li>Google Pixel 6 Pro</li><li>Google Pixel 6a</li><li>Google Pixel 7a</li><li>Samsung Galaxy S23 series</li><li>Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5</li><li>Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 5</li><li>Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 series</li><li>Google Pixel Fold (coming soon)</li><li>Google Pixel Tablet (coming soon)</li></ul>
<p>In the coming weeks, Circle to Search will get more powerful with new translation features. To start using it, users can activate Circle to Search by either long pressing the home button or the navigation bar. Besides the Google Search bar, there will be a new translate icon. Tapping it will translate your screen&apos;s contents in an instant. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:50.00%;"><img id="cW2wdcdU5qY2mGXWxivHG9" name="Circle-to-Search-Translate.jpg" alt="Google Translate in Circle to Search" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/cW2wdcdU5qY2mGXWxivHG9.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1000" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google expects this feature to be great for traveling when people navigate content in foreign languages on their smartphones. Users can also translate things in their real-world environment with Google Lens in the Google Search app. </p>
<h2 id="google-wants-you-to-plan-your-summer-trip-with-sge-2">Google wants you to plan your summer trip with SGE</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:50.00%;"><img id="M7FggtTeFEk9emnE6vGiiF" name="Google-SGE-Trip-Planning.jpg" alt="An example search with SGE." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/M7FggtTeFEk9emnE6vGiiF.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1000" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>As people start to plan their summer vacations, Google wants to help beyond translation in Circle to Search. Users who opt in to Search Generative Experience via Search Labs can create a custom travel itinerary using generative AI. Simply entering something like "plan a four-day trip to Washington, D.C." in Google Search can result in a unique travel plan for your summer trip.</p><p>This new functionality comes just in time for travel season and as Google expands its Search Generative Experience. Starting this week, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-search-ai-overviews-test-expansion">SGE began appearing to users</a> who were not enrolled in the Search Labs test. </p><p>To recap, Circle to Search will be available on more devices starting this week. Translate functionality will debut in the coming weeks, and custom travel plans using Search Generative Experience will be available in Search Labs starting today (Mar. 27). </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/circle-to-search-will-roll-out-to-more-devices</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Circle to Search, the new feature that lets users search areas of their screen by circling them, is confirmed to be coming to more Android devices this week.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">zXnDJ4J2k5J2d4GspUvhVg</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qjoT7qHMLGmweQtVLSLssJ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qjoT7qHMLGmweQtVLSLssJ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Comparing the outer display size between the Google Pixel Fold and Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Comparing the outer display size between the Google Pixel Fold and Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Onyx Boox Note Air 3 review: A large e-reader that's terrific at taking notes ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Onyx has managed to carving out a niche in the e-reader category on the back of exciting launches, with devices like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/onyx-boox-palma-review">Boox Palma</a> serving a unique use case. It&apos;s aiming to do something similar with the Boox Note Air 3, a large e-reader that has several differentiating features.</p><p>The Boox Note Air 3 is designed to take notes, and it does a great job in that area. But you also get a full-fledged version of Android, and that lets you install apps from the Play Store and use it as a tablet. While I&apos;m testing the monochrome version of the device, Onyx sells the Boox Note Air 3 with a color screen as well.</p><p>Clearly, there&apos;s a lot on offer with the Boox Note Air 3, and after using it for two months, I&apos;m convinced that this is one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-e-ink-tablet">best e-readers</a> if you want a large screen.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-onyx-boox-note-air-3-pricing-and-release-date"><span>Onyx Boox Note Air 3: Pricing and release date</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="CnnJdNnghULsmwcGZUM8UY" name="onyx-boox-note-air-3-2.jpg" alt="Onyx Boox Note Air 3 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CnnJdNnghULsmwcGZUM8UY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Onyx unveiled the Boox Note Air 3 in October 2023, and the e-reader is now available in all global markets where the brand has an official presence. The standard variant of the Boox Note Air 3 comes with a stylus and magnetic case (which is really good), and it costs $399. There&apos;s a stylus bundle that includes a better-quality stylus in addition to the standard one, and this variant is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://shop.boox.com/products/noteair3">available for $447 at Boox&apos;s website</a>.</p><p>Onyx makes a variant of the Boox Note Air 3 with a color screen, and this is called the Boox Note Air 3C. This costs $499 for the standard model that includes the stylus and magnetic case, and the stylus model is $547.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-onyx-boox-note-air-3-design"><span>Onyx Boox Note Air 3: Design</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="cPLiKmsZWhGm9Qkd2dCETc" name="onyx-boox-note-air-3-20.jpg" alt="Onyx Boox Note Air 3 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/cPLiKmsZWhGm9Qkd2dCETc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Boox Note Air 3 looks every bit as premium as its price tag suggests, with the e-reader featuring an aluminum chassis that&apos;s great to hold and use. The brushed metal design is elegant, the rounded edges make it comfortable to hold the e-reader, and while it is quite heavy at 450g, the weight is balanced well.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="wXLmJmFmPozLKq6RmzhPHZ" name="onyx-boox-note-air-3-6.jpg" alt="Onyx Boox Note Air 3 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wXLmJmFmPozLKq6RmzhPHZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I like the orange accents at the back and around the USB-C charging port, and this adds some vibrancy. The Boox Note Air 3 has an asymmetrical design — similar to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/kindle-oasis-2019-long-term-review">Kindle Oasis</a> — and this makes a big difference in daily use. That said, there are no physical page turn buttons, and that lack of tactility when turning pages makes reading books on the e-reader a little less fun.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="jgHjzzLd8YSH6jiNdT64tY" name="onyx-boox-note-air-3-4.jpg" alt="Onyx Boox Note Air 3 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jgHjzzLd8YSH6jiNdT64tY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Another feature that&apos;s missing is ingress protection; the Boox Note Air 3 isn&apos;t resistant to dust or water, and that limits its versatility to a great extent. That said, the sheer size of the e-reader means it isn&apos;t exactly practical to carry it to the pool — like you would a Kindle — but it is still a letdown.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="hDec28qZu7wcD49NfXCFta" name="onyx-boox-note-air-3-13.jpg" alt="Onyx Boox Note Air 3 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hDec28qZu7wcD49NfXCFta.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>You get sizeable bezels around the 10.3-inch screen, and while it is more than double the weight of the Kindle Oasis, you get a considerably larger screen. The USB-C port is mounted on the left, along with two speakers. While they have large drivers, the sound quality isn&apos;t particularly detailed, and they don&apos;t get loud. They&apos;re serviceable for podcasts, but if you want to listen to music, you should really use earbuds.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="73KKTPVYHNvDwi4k6yWKhZ" name="onyx-boox-note-air-3-8.jpg" alt="Onyx Boox Note Air 3 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/73KKTPVYHNvDwi4k6yWKhZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>What I particularly like is that there&apos;s a case bundled in the package, and it is of a good quality. It attaches magnetically to the e-reader, folds into two different configurations, and offers adequate protection when the Boox Note Air 3 isn&apos;t in use.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-onyx-boox-note-air-3-display-and-hardware"><span>Onyx Boox Note Air 3: Display and hardware</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="DxnhjzJKJaQV3jERJZaiZb" name="onyx-boox-note-air-3-16.jpg" alt="Onyx Boox Note Air 3 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DxnhjzJKJaQV3jERJZaiZb.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I used over a dozen e-readers up to this point, but they&apos;ve all had medium-sized screens. The Boox Note Air 3, on the other hand, has a 10.3-inch panel, and the difference was absolutely evident from the moment I started using the e-reader.</p><p>The panel itself is an E Ink Carta 1200, and with a resolution of 1872 x 1404, you get an effective pixel density of 227PPI. That&apos;s more than adequate for an e-reader, and in the two months I used the Boox Note Air 3, I didn&apos;t notice any issues with the panel.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="uEbxcPHdnuXXcPb4dmai4b" name="onyx-boox-note-air-3-14.jpg" alt="Onyx Boox Note Air 3 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uEbxcPHdnuXXcPb4dmai4b.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Switching over to the hardware, the Boox Note Air 3 is powered by Qualcomm&apos;s Snapdragon 680, and while you won&apos;t find it on any phone, it does a good job on the e-reader. You also get 4GB of RAM and 64GB of storage, Wi-Fi ac, and Bluetooth 5.0. There&apos;s an accelerometer that switches the orientation of the screen based on what hand you&apos;re holding the e-reader, but it isn&apos;t as smooth as the Kindle Oasis. You also get a MicroSD slot if you want to extend the storage.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="fVgPnBwW9bB99avqwf88YZ" name="onyx-boox-note-air-3-7.jpg" alt="Onyx Boox Note Air 3 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fVgPnBwW9bB99avqwf88YZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Boox Note Air 3 has a 3,700mAh battery, and the e-reader lasts a week between charges even with heavy use. I read two books over the course of a week and took notes daily, and the battery was still a very reasonable 30%. The e-reader charges at 15W, and it takes well over 90 minutes to charge the battery.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-onyx-boox-note-air-3-performance"><span>Onyx Boox Note Air 3: Performance</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="W8WuZkxAuXmLwhpv7vVj6a" name="onyx-boox-note-air-3-10.jpg" alt="Onyx Boox Note Air 3 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/W8WuZkxAuXmLwhpv7vVj6a.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Reading on the Boox Note Air 3 is an absolute joy; the large 10.3-inch screen is terrific in this regard. It doesn&apos;t have the same pixel density as the Kindle Oasis, but that doesn&apos;t really make a huge difference in daily use, and text is clear. There is some ghosting at times, but it isn&apos;t noticeable, and this is an issue with all e-readers that use E Ink panels anyway.</p><p>The e-reader has a built-in NeoReader utility that works with all major formats — including EPUB, MOBI, PDF, AZW3, CBR, and so on — and you can change the font size, choose from a selection of fonts or install your own, and so much more.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="Utfs6TFQKDSkJZrxA7u77c" name="onyx-boox-note-air-3-18.jpg" alt="Onyx Boox Note Air 3 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Utfs6TFQKDSkJZrxA7u77c.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>NeoReader has a tabbed interface that&apos;s ideal if you&apos;re switching between documents, and you can easily annotate via the bundled stylus. On that note, the stylus has 4,096 level of pressure sensitivity, and it is outstanding at taking notes. I normally use a Lamy Safari and Leuchtturm1917 notebooks to journal and take notes, and while the e-reader doesn&apos;t quite match the feeling of a fountain pen, it comes mighty close.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="kBoRcKFEQmVvsTppAWgFaa" name="onyx-boox-note-air-3-12.jpg" alt="Onyx Boox Note Air 3 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kBoRcKFEQmVvsTppAWgFaa.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It&apos;s also particularly good at sketching. My wife is an artist, and she uses an iPad Air along with an Apple Pencil to paint digitally. She mentioned that the Boox Note Air 3&apos;s stylus has a slight delay when creating strokes, and that there&apos;s no way to duplicate a layer of copy large drawings.</p><p>On the whole, the Boox Note Air 3 is a great choice if you&apos;re looking for a large e-reader that doubles as a note-taking device.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-onyx-boox-note-air-3-software"><span>Onyx Boox Note Air 3: Software</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="eMumLKkMW2mpEcX4SBbVrZ" name="onyx-boox-note-air-3-9.jpg" alt="Onyx Boox Note Air 3 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/eMumLKkMW2mpEcX4SBbVrZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Onyx offers a custom version of Android on the Boox Note Air 3, and while Android 12 is outdated at this point, the device will get three platform updates. While it&apos;s great that the e-reader runs Android, you can&apos;t do much with it outside of reading, note-taking, and sketching. The E Ink tech just doesn&apos;t play well with video content, and even scrolling through web pages, you can make out distinct afterimages.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="WwncriQNrKaaDVWfcHksGa" name="onyx-boox-note-air-3-11.jpg" alt="Onyx Boox Note Air 3 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WwncriQNrKaaDVWfcHksGa.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>You get 10GB of cloud storage as standard with an Onyx account, giving you plenty of storage for all of your books and notes. Onyx has a lot of pre-installed utilities — including a clock, recorder, calculator, and so on — but the fact that you get the Play Store means you can install just about anything you want.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-onyx-boox-note-air-3-the-competition"><span>Onyx Boox Note Air 3: The competition</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="rsJyo4f5DAchnZmTpVmFib" name="onyx-boox-note-air-3-17.jpg" alt="Onyx Boox Note Air 3 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rsJyo4f5DAchnZmTpVmFib.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/amazon-kindle-scribe-review">Kindle Scribe</a> is a great alternative if you need a large e-reader to take notes. It gives you easy access to Amazon&apos;s ecosystem, comes with plenty of useful features, and at $255, it is affordable.</p><p>Then there&apos;s the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/remarkable-2-review">reMarkable 2</a>. It is the definitive note-taking device, and while it is costlier, it is lighter, has a sleeker design, and does an even better job at taking notes.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-onyx-boox-note-air-3-should-you-buy-it"><span>Onyx Boox Note Air 3: Should you buy it?</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="dRSqRDByHAjL6DRBhWF2Lb" name="onyx-boox-note-air-3-15.jpg" alt="Onyx Boox Note Air 3 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dRSqRDByHAjL6DRBhWF2Lb.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>You should buy this if:</strong></p>
<ul><li>You want a large e-reader that's great for reading and taking notes</li><li>You need the extensibility of Android</li><li>You want an e-reader that lasts a week between charges</li><li>You need a bundled stylus</li></ul>
<p><strong>You shouldn&apos;t buy this if:</strong></p>
<ul><li>You want physical page turn buttons</li><li>You need ingress protection</li></ul>
<p>Other than the lack of ingress protection and physical page turn buttons, I can&apos;t really find any faults. Onyx clearly knows what it&apos;s doing, and the Boox Note Air 3 is one of the best e-readers currently available. The large 10.3-inch screen is great for reading e-books and browsing, and it doubles as a fantastic digital note-taking device— all thanks to that bundled stylus.</p><p>The fact that you have full access to the Play Store is an added bonus; you just don&apos;t get that versatility with many other e-readers. Battery life is outstanding, the metallic chassis is durable, and there&apos;s plenty of customizability — much more so than what you get with other e-readers.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="73e30894-3348-474a-b481-0300e32e9421">
            <a href="https://www.amazon.com/BOOX-Tablet-Note-Air-ePaper/dp/B0CHF423CP" data-model-name="Onyx Boox Note Air 3"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:93.10%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/C6dJmCMXHqxDqiyBNWDczM.jpg' alt='Onyx Boox Note Air 3'></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Onyx Boox Note Air 3</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>The Boox Note Air 3 is a great choice if you want a large e-reader that's great for going through e-books and documents as well as taking notes. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/onyx-boox-note-air-3-review</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Boox Note Air 3 is a 10.3-inch e-reader that comes with a bundled stylus, giving you the ability to take notes. The result is a two-in-one device that's outstanding.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">BqRyGrJWxfojPBpitPm6Rf</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Vcv2CAjEP3hENxDjvM4RDY.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 13:20:40 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Vcv2CAjEP3hENxDjvM4RDY.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Onyx Boox Note Air 3 review]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Onyx Boox Note Air 3 review]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google says 97 zero-day vulnerabilities were exploited in 2023 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>In 2023, there were 97 zero-day vulnerabilities exploited, a significant rise of over 50% compared to 2022 (62 vulnerabilities).</li><li>Analysis by Google's Threat Analysis Group (TAG) and Mandiant revealed that espionage was the primary motive behind 48 out of 58 zero-day vulnerabilities analyzed.</li><li>Criminals focused on end-user platforms like smartphones, operating systems, web browsers, and applications, with a total of 61 zero-days affecting these targets.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google has found that there were 97 zero-day vulnerabilities that were exploited in 2023, over 50% higher than the number from 2022 (62 vulnerabilities).</p><p>Google&apos;s Threat Analysis Group (TAG) and Mandiant teamed up to analyze the zero-day flaws revealed last year. Their analysis revealed that out of the 58 zero-days for which they could attribute the threat actor’s motivations, espionage was the main motive for 48 of those vulnerabilities.</p><p>Zero-days are essentially flaws that haven&apos;t been found by security experts yet. This means IT teams have zero time to fix them before hackers exploit them. That&apos;s why hackers love them, because using them doesn&apos;t set off any alarms.</p><p>Out of all the potential targets, criminals had their <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/project-zero-exynos-modem-vulnerability">sights set on end-user platforms and products like smartphones</a>, operating systems, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-updates-chrome-browser-sixth-zero-day-vulnerability-of-2023">web browsers</a>, and various applications. Google found that a total of 61 zero-days impacted these targets.</p><p>In 2023, Android saw nine <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-fixes-critical-android-zero-click-flaw">vulnerabilities being exploited</a>, up from just three in 2022. On the other hand, iOS faced nine zero-days out in the wild, compared to four in the previous year.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:817px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:91.80%;"><img id="NeDwiiUXHdZKk7W49v3utV" name="zero-days-2023.png" alt="Zero-day vulnerabilities discovered in 2023" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NeDwiiUXHdZKk7W49v3utV.png" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="817" height="750" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Additionally, there were eight zero-days hitting Chrome and 11 targeting Safari in the wild. Windows takes the lead among the top five, with 17 zero-day vulnerabilities exploited, up from 13 the previous year.</p><p>Looking at the findings by region, Google reports that 12 of the zero-days were exploited by Chinese state-sponsored threat actors, with Russia, North Korea, and Belarus following suit. In total, state-sponsored espionage made up 41.4% of the exploited zero-days in 2023.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1067px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:58.76%;"><img id="sJYfhvnUxAtHEZ853b2G4W" name="zero-day-vulnerabilities-2023.png" alt="Zero-day vulnerabilities discovered in 2023" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sJYfhvnUxAtHEZ853b2G4W.png" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1067" height="627" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>"In 2023, we attributed to commercial surveillance vendors (CSVs) and government espionage actors a combined 48 of 58 zero-days for which we could attribute motivation and only 10 vulnerabilities to financially motivated actors," Google says. "The proportion (roughly 17%) in 2023 of financially motivated exploitation is slightly lower than our observations from 2022, and both of these years were down from the nearly one-third of vulnerabilities we attributed to financially motivated actors in 2021."</p><p>That said, investments in exploit mitigations across browsers and operating systems are making it harder for attackers to achieve their goals using certain types of vulnerabilities.</p><p>Google&apos;s researchers point out that companies like Apple, Google, and Microsoft, who are responsible for end-user platforms, have made significant investments. These investments are clearly affecting the types and quantity of zero-days that attackers can exploit.</p><p>Anyway, 2023 saw fewer disclosed zero-day flaws than 2021, which had 106 vulnerabilities. While this might sound like a good thing, researchers think that the rate of zero-day discovery and exploitation will probably stay high compared to the numbers before 2021.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-report-zero-days-exploited-in-2023</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google and Mandiant looked into the zero-day bugs revealed in 2023 and found that dozens were connected to cyberespionage groups. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">VigcbjQ9GpduEjq9huVism</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WvhWaELsXDFdqwaQk36qTP.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 13:00:26 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WvhWaELsXDFdqwaQk36qTP.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android malware code]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android malware code]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Gemini could soon make an appearance on the Pixel Tablet ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Since Google released the Gemini app for Android, it has only been available on smartphones, with tablets notably excluded. </li><li>The latest version of the Google Search app includes multiple new references to Gemini working on tablets.</li><li>While an exact launch date is unknown, it's possible that Gemini will appear on the Pixel Tablet first, with the potential for third-party support coming later.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>After Google revamped Gemini with a new mobile app, everyone started wondering where the artificial intelligence assistant would appear next. There have been past reports and inklings that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/the-gemini-app-will-come-to-headphones-that-support-google-assistant">Gemini will appear on Google Assistant earbuds</a>, tablets, or smart displays. However, new references to Gemini on tablets in the latest version of the Google Search app suggest a release could be near.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/03/26/gemini-tablet-launch-nears/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a> found strings in version 15.12 of the Google Search app that directly outline how Gemini will work on tablets. "When Gemini is the digital assistant on this tablet, hosted by the Google app, it can access certain system permissions and data,"  a prompt explains, "like dialer, call and message logs, and contacts (to help you keep in touch), installed apps like Clock (to control alarms and timers), and screen content (to help you act on it)."</p><p>As is the case for Gemini on other platforms, there&apos;s a disclaimer that Gemini is still learning. Google also says that Google Assistant may be used in situations where Gemini isn&apos;t capable of helping and that some Assistant features won&apos;t be available. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3394px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.28%;"><img id="QUuejB6p5fokJUFyse3swb" name="Google-Gemini-app-home-page.JPG" alt="The Google Gemini app" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QUuejB6p5fokJUFyse3swb.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3394" height="1910" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>9to5Google managed to get Gemini up and running on a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/google-pixel-tablet-review">Pixel Tablet</a> using the latest version of the Google Search app. Overall, the experience using Gemini on tablets is unexpectedly similar to using it on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">big-screen foldables</a>, such as the Pixel Fold. Notably, Google Assistant remains the default voice assistant even when Gemini is installed on a Pixel Tablet. This falls in line with Google&apos;s earlier guidance that smart devices will still use Google Assistant. </p><p>"Gemini will not replace Google Assistant on your other devices, even if you opt-in to use it as your mobile assistant," Google explains in a support document. "On other non-mobile devices, including Smart Displays, smart speakers, TVs, cars, smart watches, headphones, and earbuds with Google Assistant built-in, and Pixel Tablets, Google Assistant will continue to respond to &apos;Hey Google.&apos;"</p><p>The Pixel Tablet is an interesting device because it is a standalone tablet and a smart home hub. Due to Gemini&apos;s current limitations with assistant-based features, it makes sense that Google isn&apos;t ready to completely swap out Assistant for Gemini on the Pixel Tablet.</p><p>While an official launch date is unknown, it looks like Google is gearing up for a Gemini launch on tablets. The Pixel Tablet will almost certainly be one of the first tablets to support Gemini, but it&apos;s possible third-party devices could be supported as well.  </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/gemini-could-soon-make-an-appearance-on-the-pixel-tablet</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ An unreleased version of the Google Search app for tablets contains references to Gemini, and the Pixel Tablet will probably be the first device to receive the AI assistant.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">GX98BV8ijgUSzkD2RxuX5m</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uJDp3PYcTYEc2ruefbfFLJ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 12:37:17 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uJDp3PYcTYEc2ruefbfFLJ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Pixel Tablet in vertical mode]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Pixel Tablet in vertical mode]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The 3-2-1 backup rule is broken — here's how I safeguard my data ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The 3-2-1 backup rule has been around for over two decades, and it states that you need to store three copies of your data across two different kinds of media, and one at an offsite location. While this strategy made a lot of sense when it was introduced, data usage has changed considerably over the last two decades; these days, it&apos;s incredibly easy to put your data on a public cloud service and have it accessible from anywhere.</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Hardwired</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="5u6gVPowTCuSQ8NJeoktj7" name="lloyd-hardwired.png" caption="" alt="Android Central's LLoyd with a bionic eye" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5u6gVPowTCuSQ8NJeoktj7.png" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">In <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/hardwired">Hardwired</a>, AC Senior Editor Harish Jonnalagadda delves into all things hardware, including phones, storage servers, and routers.</p></div></div>
<p>The downside to relying on public cloud providers is privacy — you don&apos;t have much say where your data is stored. So when I was strategizing on how to back up my data, I came up with a modified version of the 3-2-1 rule that made the most amount of sense for my particular use case. I&apos;ll start by saying that I have outsized storage requirements that are definitely not the norm — I currently use over 300TB of storage.</p><p>Out of that 300TB, just over 100TB is the actual data; it consists of all the photos and videos that my wife and I have taken over the past decade, a sizeable music library, and our media collection. The primary storehouse of the data is a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/i-set-up-the-ultimate-home-nas-with-over-100tb-of-storage">DiskStation DS1823xs+ with seven NAS HDDs</a>, totaling 128TB of storage. I then back up the NAS to a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/synology-diskstation-ds3622xs-review">DiskStation DS3622xs+</a>, which has a dozen 12TB drives.</p><p>The third copy of this data is on an older <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/synology-diskstation-ds1019-plus-review">DiskStation DS1019+</a>; this was my primary home NAS until a few months ago, until I decided to switch to the DS1823xs+. As I was using brand-new HDDs in the DS1823xs+, I just left the DS1019+ and its data intact; I intend to move it to my parents house in a few weeks, and it will serve as the default offsite backup.</p><p>The missing piece of the puzzle is a cloud backup solution; I used Google Workspace until the end of last year to back up all the data from the DS1019+ to the cloud, which was encrypted with Hyper Backup. This was possible as Google didn&apos;t enforce any data limits with Workspace accounts — making the $20 monthly fee the best deal in the world of backups — but that isn&apos;t the case now.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="wFfV2S93G9cnKhm4nsqB5Y" name="diskstation-ds1823xs-plus-26.jpg" alt="DiskStation DS1823xs+" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wFfV2S93G9cnKhm4nsqB5Y.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I still use Google Photos to back up photos taken from phones, but other than that and storing documents in Drive, I don&apos;t have much need of cloud storage. Even if I decided to back up all that data, it would be absurdly costly to do so. </p><p>Utilities like Tailscale make it extremely easy to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/how-to-securely-access-your-synology-nas-from-anywhere">access a NAS from anywhere</a>, and with the sheer amount of data I have, it just doesn&apos;t make sense to back up to a cloud provider. Also, every time I consider storing data on a remote server, I&apos;m reminded of this quote from Dune: "The power to destroy a thing is the absolute control over it."</p><p>Technically, the 3-2-1 rule mentions you need to store data in two different media types, but that&apos;s unnecessary for my own needs, so I use mechanical hard drives throughout. Flash storage is still too costly, but I am considering picking up a quartet of 4TB WD Red NVMe drives and seeing how they hold up.</p><p>I know it&apos;s not feasible for everyone to store data in three different locations, but it makes sense to at least back up data to an external medium. This is one of the biggest selling points of a NAS, and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-nas-home">best home NAS servers</a> make it easier than ever to store your data and media collection in a centralized location. </p><p>But if you don&apos;t want to go that route, I recommend an external SSD; the Crucial X9 Pro is the one I use the most, and the 4TB variant is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Crucial-Pro-4TB-Portable-CT4000X9PROSSD902/dp/B0C9WGQY8G">going for as low as $259</a>. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/the-3-2-1-backup-rule-is-broken-heres-how-i-safeguard-my-data</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The 3-2-1 backup rule doesn't really make sense now that we have NAS HDDs that can store up to 24TB of data on a single drive.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">nWZtrb9F5zjAsmoap9SS3b</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VwqcNN8CKfGbJPpGqghbqX.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 09:09:56 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Smart Home]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VwqcNN8CKfGbJPpGqghbqX.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[DiskStation DS1823xs+]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[DiskStation DS1823xs+]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Moto G 5G 2024 review: A slice of luxury for less ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Buying a smartphone on a tight budget normally isn&apos;t a fun time. Most phones at this price tag look nearly identical on paper, and may even be made by companies you&apos;ve never heard of.</p><p>That&apos;s where the Moto G 5G 2024 comes in. Motorola is a household name with a great Android UI and a better update record than the company has ever had. This year&apos;s model has been upgraded with a vegan leather back, faster charging, faster 5G speeds, and NFC. Motorola certainly seems to be listening.</p><p>Some decisions are bizarre — a 2MP macro camera is useless and RAM boost does more harm than good — but the overall experience is one of the better ones you&apos;ll find at this price. The processor is fast enough to do most things, and while 4GB of RAM is anemic even with a 720p display, a little bit of patience will go a long way. If you&apos;ve only got <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones-under-200">$200 to spend on a new phone</a>, this is a good choice.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-moto-g-5g-2024-price-availability"><span>Moto G 5G 2024: Price & availability</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.30%;"><img id="MRWkqLJB3sVLnMnjiRNxFW" name="Moto-G-5G-2024-back-close-03.jpg" alt="The vegan leather back of the Moto G 5G 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MRWkqLJB3sVLnMnjiRNxFW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1153" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Motorola offers the Moto G 5G 2024 unlocked in the U.S. starting on March 21 at Amazon, Best Buy, and Motorola.com for $199.99 — that&apos;s $50 less than last year. The Moto G 5G 2024 will be available in Canada on May 2 at motorola.ca and at select Canadian carriers in the coming months.</p><p>Alternatively, you can find it at your carrier of choice, including AT&T, Boost Infinite, Boost Mobile, Cox Mobile, Consumer Cellular, Google Fi Wireless, Metro by T-Mobile, Optimum Mobile, Simple Mobile, Straight Talk, T-Mobile, Total by Verizon, Tracfone, UScellular, Verizon, Visible, Walmart Family Mobile, Xfinity Mobile. Prices vary by carrier.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-moto-g-5g-2024-what-i-like"><span>Moto G 5G 2024: What I like</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="uTof3cXM2BePqoMycbjnxW" name="Moto-G-5G-2024-hero.jpg" alt="The vegan leather back of the Moto G 5G 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uTof3cXM2BePqoMycbjnxW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It&apos;s hard to believe, but design is the biggest differentiator between the Moto G 5G 2024 and basically every other <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones-under-200">Android phone under $200</a>. The back isn&apos;t some nasty, shiny plastic that&apos;s going to attract fingerprints and dust every time you take it out of your pocket. Instead, it&apos;s clad in a lovely vegan leather finish that looks as good as it feels.</p><p>Ironically, vegan leather is just another strange form of plastic that&apos;s built in a way to resemble actual animal leather without using animal products. It doesn&apos;t have <em>exactly</em> the same feel as <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/dbrand-leather-skin-review">DBrand leather phone skins</a>, but it feels substantially better than plastic or glass, in my opinion.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="x2yEgwoi34zRt67NHSXTzg" name="Corning-Gorilla-Glass-victus-2-scratch-demo.jpg" alt="Motorola's MWC display of how scratch resistant Gorilla Glass Victus 2 is versus the previous generation glass" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/x2yEgwoi34zRt67NHSXTzg.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="bBGTbKxfiT9RD7LXhEQvzV" name="Moto-G-5G-2024-back-camera-island-02.jpg" alt="The vegan leather back of the Moto G 5G 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bBGTbKxfiT9RD7LXhEQvzV.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="pVKeCWdtfh5JrPDjcftcYW" name="Moto-G-5G-2024-bottom.jpg" alt="The ports on the bottom of the Moto G 5G 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pVKeCWdtfh5JrPDjcftcYW.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 4 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="UmgMNEUT3QfeTdUqpAxKDX" name="Moto-G-5G-2024-right-side.jpg" alt="The right side and buttons of the Moto G 5G 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/UmgMNEUT3QfeTdUqpAxKDX.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 5 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="9bQrWKAGBnKNya6MYfY66X" name="Moto-G-5G-2024-left-side.jpg" alt="The left side of the Moto G 5G 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9bQrWKAGBnKNya6MYfY66X.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<figure><blockquote><p>Vegan leather is so much better than plastic back.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>That puts the Moto G 5G 2024 in a strange middle ground of design aesthetics and build that other $200 phones can&apos;t compete with. I love it, and it goes well with the new, stronger Gorilla Glass 3 on the front of the phone, which is more resistant to scratches and breaks than any previous generation of budget-minded Motorola phones.</p><p>The side rails of the phone are still slightly slippery plastic, but I don&apos;t expect metal or a finer finish at this price tag. At least the fingerprint scanner is included inside of the power button, a favorite design of mine that I&apos;d love to see extended to <strong>all</strong> Android phones, not just a select few models.</p><p>It&apos;s faster, more accurate, and more comfortable to use than the awkward in-screen fingerprint scanners found in more expensive phones.</p>

<figure><blockquote><p>Motorola listened to feedback and included important features like NFC in this year's model.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>It&apos;s also well worth noting that Motorola listened to feedback and included NFC on the Moto G 5G 2024, an omission that bit Motorola with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/moto-g-5g-2023-review#section-moto-g-5g-2023-price-availability">Moto G 5G 2023</a> and its other budget-priced 2023 phone models. This means you can make contactless payments with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet">Google Wallet</a>.</p><p>Motorola launched the Moto G 5G 2024 with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review">Android 14</a> aboard and guarantees the phone will get Android 15 along with three years of security updates. That&apos;s great since the performance of this phone is lacking and likely will feel painfully sluggish in four years when support ends.</p><p>I also love Motorola&apos;s gestures, such as double-chopping the phone to toggle the flashlight feature. These gestures have been on Motorola phones for a decade now and are still some of the best defining features of the Motorola experience.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pul3o6sWcp0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>Lastly, I&apos;d like to commend Motorola for including an LCD with no noticeable <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-is-pwm-display-flicker-tips-and-tricks">PWM dimming</a> flicker. While phones like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-a15-5g-review">Samsung Galaxy A15</a> offer better-looking AMOLED panels, Samsung&apos;s displays flicker like no other displays on the market. Most people aren&apos;t negatively affected by this, but if you&apos;re like me, just a few minutes of looking at a flickering display like that could give you hours of headaches or eye aches.</p><p>The Moto G 5G 2024&apos;s LCD has no perceivable PWM flicker, and my Opple Light Master IV tells me it has a frequency between 28,000Hz and 40,000Hz with extremely low modulation. This is the most friendly kind of display you&apos;ll find on any modern phone, full stop.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-moto-g-5g-2024-what-isn-t-great"><span>Moto G 5G 2024: What isn't great</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="9tbAVUcAbLFw6jKvQxdSZZ" name="Moto-G-5G-2024-back-holding-01.jpg" alt="The back of the vegan leather Moto G 5G 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9tbAVUcAbLFw6jKvQxdSZZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>First thing&apos;s first. If you end up buying a Moto G 5G 2024, turn off the RAM boost feature. Motorola included this to "virtually" expand the phone&apos;s RAM beyond the anemic 4GB included, but it ends up creating a worse overall experience. In my time with the phone, I found that RAM boost made switching between apps unreliable and, at worst, unstable.</p><p>Once I turned RAM boost off, the phone was notably more usable even if it&apos;s not the fastest device I&apos;ve ever used. You&apos;re not going to be playing Fortnite on the Moto G 5G 2024, but it&apos;ll do all your other daily tasks like web browsing, messaging, and phone calling just fine.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>RAM boost makes things worse, not better. Turn it off right away.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>Beyond that, it&apos;s clear that Motorola had to skimp a bit on the camera quality to include a processor that could actually <em>do</em> something without needing the patience of a saint. Motorola <strong>highly</strong> oversells the camera in its marketing, saying you can "snap a flawless shot day or night" with the Moto G 5G 2024&apos;s main camera.</p><p>That&apos;s not true, although the camera isn&apos;t entirely useless, either. Every photo I took with the phone was quite soft, even during broad daylight.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3072px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:132.81%;"><img id="SmvHyU2Q5RRg6AyRim3y4P" name="Moto-g-5g-2024-camera-sample-main-04.jpg" alt="A camera sample from the Moto G 5G 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SmvHyU2Q5RRg6AyRim3y4P.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="3072" height="4080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.29%;"><img id="5nx8rqYoppR4qzYtajh9Xj" name="Moto-g-5g-2024-camera-sample-main-02.jpg" alt="Camera samples from the Moto G 5G 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5nx8rqYoppR4qzYtajh9Xj.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4080" height="3072" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.29%;"><img id="KfKru9Rpi2RWvjj5wzL2Ek" name="Moto-g-5g-2024-camera-sample-main-03.jpg" alt="Camera samples from the Moto G 5G 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KfKru9Rpi2RWvjj5wzL2Ek.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4080" height="3072" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 4 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.29%;"><img id="R4JSpnZXcj5fyxe3FMXR6n" name="Moto-g-5g-2024-camera-sample-main-01.jpg" alt="Camera samples from the Moto G 5G 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/R4JSpnZXcj5fyxe3FMXR6n.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4080" height="3072" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 5 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3264px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="nD2dK6z9RTmwCZ9qwUANwk" name="Moto-g-5g-2024-camera-sample-front-01.jpg" alt="Camera samples from the Moto G 5G 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nD2dK6z9RTmwCZ9qwUANwk.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="3264" height="2448" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>I don&apos;t expect a $200 phone to take pictures I&apos;d be proud to print and hang on a wall, but this one doesn&apos;t quite live up to the hype Motorola tries to sell it with. The flower picture above is by far the best picture I took with the phone. Most others didn&apos;t even come close.</p><p>Additionally, the 2MP macro camera is <em>entirely</em> useless. I wish companies like Motorola would just get rid of these silly gimmicks and put the extra savings into a better main camera.</p><p>Likewise, the selfie camera is quite weak, delivering soft images at all times of the day or night. I thought this was just because the low-resolution 720P made captured images appear soft after taking them, but closer inspection on a monitor shows that this is just the way it is. It&apos;s fine, but don&apos;t expect much from this phone&apos;s camera.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-moto-g-5g-2024-competition"><span>Moto G 5G 2024: Competition</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4535px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="yU7ozaB4MqKhxNfHGBWVbn" name="Samsung-Galaxy-A15-5.jpg" alt="A Samsung Galaxy A15 5G on a table." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yU7ozaB4MqKhxNfHGBWVbn.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4535" height="2551" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Brady Snyder / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I&apos;d pick this phone over Samsung&apos;s similarly-priced model for two main reasons: display, and performance. While AMOLED "looks" better, it flickers and hurts my head.</p><p>Samsung&apos;s choice of a lower-performance processor also means day-to-day use is pretty miserable on the Galaxy A15, while the Snapdragon 4 Gen 1 in the Moto G 5G 2024 is a far more usable choice. Aside from that, Motorola&apos;s phone build is superior, even if it&apos;s not getting as many software updates.</p><p>If you can wait to buy a phone, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-nord-n30-5g-review">OnePlus Nord N30</a> often goes on sale for $229 and is well worth the extra $30 over the Moto G 5G 2024. It&apos;s got a <em>much</em> faster processor, better cameras, and faster charging. I hate the shiny plastic back, but at least the screen is also PWM-free and is easy to look at.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-moto-g-5g-2024-should-you-buy-it"><span>Moto G 5G 2024: Should you buy it?</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="CvqPXMRFKhjf7ht7pHM3kW" name="Moto-G-5G-2024-display.jpg" alt="The display of the Moto G 5G 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CvqPXMRFKhjf7ht7pHM3kW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>You should buy this if...</strong></p>
<ul><li>You need a good phone for $200.</li><li>You like Motorola gestures and MyUX features.</li><li>You're tired of phones with nasty slippery plastic backs.</li><li>You need a display that's PWM-free.</li></ul>
<p><strong>You shouldn&apos;t buy this if...</strong></p>
<ul><li>You need great camera quality.</li><li>You like graphics-intense mobile games.</li><li>You need a waterproof phone.</li></ul>
<p>Building a quality phone for $200 is difficult, as companies have to balance components that don&apos;t cost much but still offer a "good enough" experience to feel worth the purchase. For the most part, the Moto G 5G 2024 fits the bill but it has a few shortcomings to be aware of.</p><p>Performance requires some patience, but it&apos;s nowhere near the disastrous level that we saw from budget Moto phones in 2022. Unfortunately, the faster performance meant Motorola had to make concessions on the camera quality. It&apos;s not awful, but it&apos;s (ironically) not as good as we saw from Moto in 2022.</p><p>Thankfully, though, daily use is just fine so long as you turn off the silly RAM boost feature. The inclusion of NFC means this can be used for mobile payments and other important modern features, plus a 3.5mm headset jack, all-day battery life, and fast 18W charging means you won&apos;t get annoyed by the little things that some other phones skimp on. All in all, it&apos;s a solid $200 buy if that&apos;s the top of your budget for a new phone.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="28de9f59-11ef-431c-8064-6d99f1cff669">
            <a href="https://www.motorola.com/us/smartphones-moto-g-5g-gen-3/p" data-model-name="Moto G 5G 2024"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ca6CvQJAircpckuKsUQvFB.jpg' alt='The Sage Green Moto G 5G 2024'></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Moto G 5G 2024</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="70" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Premium looks, budget price</strong></em></p>
<p>Motorola redesigned its budget-friendly lineup with vegan leather backs to give you a touch of luxury without the added price. Plus, important capabilities like NFC, fast charging, and Motorola's helpful gestures mean this is a great everyday phone for the price.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/moto-g-5g-2024-review</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Moto G 5G 2024 is a surprisingly decent phone for the price, and the new vegan leather back is a slice of luxury we didn't expect. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">fd6CK7CBsG79bn4UgsbqkL</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zThXs799Zzyon4PWZA3ETX.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 07:00:40 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nicholas.sutrich@futurenet.com (Nicholas Sutrich) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zThXs799Zzyon4PWZA3ETX.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The vegan leather back of the Moto G 5G 2024]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The vegan leather back of the Moto G 5G 2024]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Android 15: Eligible devices, release date, and all the new features in DP2 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Google rolled out the stable build of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review">Android 14</a> back in October, but it doesn&apos;t wait around to start work on the next version of Android. The brand likes to roll out preview builds as soon as possible to give developers a chance to test out the new features well in advance, and these releases also serve as a way to deliver feedback to the brand over the latest additions heading to Android.</p><p>Google introduced the first preview build of Android 15 at the end of February, and followed it up with DP2 on March 21. These builds are targeted at devs, and aren&apos;t meant for public use — those will come a bit later. The preview builds give us an early look into the features Google is building into Android, and while there wasn&apos;t a lot of excitement around Android 14, there&apos;s plenty of new stuff in Android 15.</p><p>I installed Android 15 Developer Preview 2 on my <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-review">Pixel 8</a> as soon as it became available, and I&apos;ve been testing it a few days now. Before we get to the new features, a word of caution: the build is very unstable, and it isn&apos;t remotely close to being ready as a daily driver. While the Play Store doesn&apos;t crash on launch — which was the case in Developer Preview 1 — there are plenty of issues with the build. With that out of the day, here&apos;s what&apos;s new in Android 15.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-android-15-release-timeline"><span>Android 15 release timeline</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="Gor37rkx9LtEEZRJASiyog" name="android-15-schedule.jpg" alt="Android 15 release schedule" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Gor37rkx9LtEEZRJASiyog.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google has a clearly defined timeline with its Android releases, and that&apos;s no different with Android 15. The preview builds will run until March, and we&apos;ll get a public beta build of Android 15 sometime in April, with Google planning four beta builds at this moment, running through July.</p><p>The stable build follows soon after, and while <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/android-12">Android 12</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-13-review">Android 13</a> debuted in the month of August, Android 14 was delayed until October last year. That said, it is likely that Google will go back to its usual cadence this year, so a stable build should be available in August — I&apos;ll have more to share as we get more details.</p><p>While Google doesn&apos;t use codenames in public-facing documentation, all Android releases still have internal dessert codenames, and Android 15 is designated Vanilla Ice Cream. Like previous years, the Android beta program is limited to the Pixels, and this time, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-pixel-5-review">Pixel 5</a> series isn&apos;t eligible — only the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-pixel-6">Pixel 6</a> and upwards will pick up the update. Here&apos;s the list of devices:</p>
<ul><li>Pixel 6</li><li>Pixel 6 Pro</li><li>Pixel 6a</li><li>Pixel 7</li><li>Pixel 7 Pro</li><li>Pixel 7a</li><li>Pixel 8</li><li>Pixel 8 Pro</li><li>Pixel Fold</li><li>Pixel Tablet</li></ul>
<p>Android beta builds usually make their way to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a> by other brands as well, but this doesn&apos;t kick off until much later in the year. I&apos;ll share additional details as and when they&apos;re available.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-notification-cooldown-turns-down-the-noise"><span>Notification cooldown turns down the noise</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="kiuynbZRkJSBsn6cyAv9zg" name="android-15-notifications.jpg" alt="Android 15 notification cooldown" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kiuynbZRkJSBsn6cyAv9zg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Notification cooldown is a great new feature that lowers the volume of incoming notifications when you get successive notifications from the same app. So if you&apos;re in a group chat and start getting constant notifications, Android 15 automatically lowers the volume of subsequent notifications. What&apos;s great is that you can select this setting for just conversations, or all apps. As someone who doesn&apos;t like getting many notification alerts (I use DND most of the day), this is a great new addition, and one that I will use to good effect.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-keyboard-vibration-gets-its-own-toggle"><span>Keyboard vibration gets its own toggle</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="gYViU9VahDfiu4YX38UNof" name="android-15-keyboard.jpg" alt="Android 15 keyboard vibration toggle" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gYViU9VahDfiu4YX38UNof.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Android 15 is adding a system-wide toggle to enable or disable keyboard vibration. You could do this previously by going into a keyboard&apos;s settings and toggle the feature individually, but the option to do so at a system-wide level that works across keyboards is a good addition. Google is also integrating a slider that lets you adjust the intensity of haptic feedback, similar to what OPPO and other brands already do.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-the-brightness-slider-vibrates-now"><span>The brightness slider vibrates now</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="HzD3qv9czFhiUjhPJyYnff" name="android-15-brightness.jpg" alt="Android 15 brightness slider in action" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HzD3qv9czFhiUjhPJyYnff.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In a bid to bring better feedback across the system, Google is adding haptic feedback to the brightness slider in Android 15. The effect is very subtle — it&apos;s not on the same level as the nav gesture intensity, but it is still great that you get some amount of feedback when adjusting the brightness.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-partial-screen-recording-lets-you-share-only-what-s-needed"><span>Partial screen recording lets you share only what's needed</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="9AqLjyR8TTy32ofebF9P9h" name="android-15-record.jpg" alt="Android 15 screen record" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9AqLjyR8TTy32ofebF9P9h.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google took its sweet time integrating a screen recorder into Android, and by the time it added it, all other brands had their own take on the feature, which was usually better. Anyway, Android 15 is getting an update that lets you take partial screen recording. Instead of recording the entire screen by default, you can now select to record an individual app, and it won&apos;t show the rest of the screen and notifications.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-bluetooth-tile-is-actually-useful"><span>Bluetooth tile is actually useful</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="qQ3JfHpNrxcsMWgr33tNQf" name="android-15-bluetooth.jpg" alt="Android 15 Bluetooth tile" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qQ3JfHpNrxcsMWgr33tNQf.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google moved the Wi-Fi and cellular connection tiles to a single tile called Internet, and it is a constant source of frustration as it adds another step if I just want to toggle my home internet on or off. By contrast, the Bluetooth tile — which could have actually benefitted with this functionality — was a standard toggle that turned the Bluetooth radio or on off.</p><p>Thankfully, Google is addressing this issue in Android 15, and a short press on the Bluetooth tile now pulls up a dialog box similar to the Internet one — you get to see your paired devices, and you have the ability to easily switch between devices, and there&apos;s the option to toggle Bluetooth connectivity. If you want to pair a new device, hitting the + icon at the bottom of the dialog box to pull up the Bluetooth settings page and connect a new device.</p><p>Samsung&apos;s One UI and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/nothing-os-2-review">Nothing OS</a> already use this system, and it&apos;s good to see Google baking it into Android.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-better-continuity-on-foldables"><span>Better continuity on foldables</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="otdGLT6rYiTxVh5oAktd2H" name="oneplus-open-25.jpg" alt="OnePlus Open review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/otdGLT6rYiTxVh5oAktd2H.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google is lifting a feature that debuted on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-open-review">OnePlus Open</a> that switches whatever action you&apos;re doing on the inner screen to the cover screen when you fold a device. This is a very useful feature, and other foldables like the Honor Magic V2 also have it. With it being integrated into Android 15, we should see it heading to even more foldables in the future.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-android-15-should-have-better-optimization"><span>Android 15 should have better optimization</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="AxWTrfRYJAJ7DLJEZoxu5g" name="android-15-home.jpg" alt="Android 15 home screen" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AxWTrfRYJAJ7DLJEZoxu5g.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google is making it easier for game and app makers to directly access the hardware, and the Android Dynamic Performance Framework consists of a set of APIs that allow better optimization, and in Android 15, Google is introducing a power-efficiency mode that&apos;s designed for "long-running background workloads." This is to ensure any background apps don&apos;t utilize more system resources than necessary.</p><p>In a similar vein, Google is rolling out new thermal thresholds that should make a difference with throttling. Even the latest phones with powerful hardware struggle with throttling issues in demanding titles, and I&apos;m excited to see if this change makes a difference in real-world use.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-android-15-rolls-out-an-hq-webcam-mode"><span>Android 15 rolls out an HQ webcam mode</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="AriHAnbWjHYfa6q4QWWvVG" name="Google-Pixel-8-Pro-camera-bar-01.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 8 Pro camera bar in the porcelain colorway" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AriHAnbWjHYfa6q4QWWvVG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>You can <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-use-your-android-phone-webcam-your-pc">use your phone as a webcam</a>, and with Android 15, Google is rolling out an HQ mode that makes a difference to video quality. There&apos;s now a toggle that lets you enable HQ mode, and it offers better detail resolution. The only issue is that your device will get noticeably warm, but it is a nice addition nevertheless</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-android-15-has-an-always-active-taskbar"><span>Android 15 has an always-active taskbar</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2043px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:42.88%;"><img id="QtA2nUGNH7HEavU6yCjZ3R" name="Google-Pixel-Fold-display-unfolded-home-21x9.jpg" alt="The home screen on the large inner display of the Google Pixel Fold" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QtA2nUGNH7HEavU6yCjZ3R.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2043" height="876" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Android 15 DP2 brings a new feature to the Pixel Fold and Android tablets that enables a persistent taskbar at the bottom of the screen. Other brands offer this feature as standard on their foldables, so it is good to see Google adding it natively in Android 15. </p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-android-15-lets-you-share-audio-like-its-the-90s"><span>Android 15 lets you share audio like its the '90s</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="oUS42RqQJZhbPVtv5JKjTW" name="nothing-ear-2-26.jpg" alt="Nothing Ear (2) earbuds review on red background" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oUS42RqQJZhbPVtv5JKjTW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Another new feature in Android 15 DP2 is the ability to pay the same audio across multiple headphones — no need to share earbuds. The Audio sharing sub-menu is located within the Connected devices page, and it lets you cast music to more than one Bluetooth device at a time. I wasn&apos;t able to get this feature to work just yet, but it should be usable in later builds. </p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-android-15-features-i-want-to-see"><span>Android 15 features I want to see</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="skASRE5PwdHQGoTTr98rLg" name="android-15-logo-hand.jpg" alt="Android 15 logo in hand" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/skASRE5PwdHQGoTTr98rLg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The best part of Android is its sheer diversity; different brands have their own take on what Android should look like, and they roll out custom features that go above and beyond what Google offers on the Pixels. As I get to use all the flavors of Android, these are the features I want to see in Android 15 — that said, it&apos;s unlikely Google will include any of these in upcoming builds.</p>
<h2 id="floating-windows-2">Floating windows</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="WK9cZrrNyLyNAnDaRtoBe8" name="android-15-list-6.jpg" alt="Android 15 wishlist" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WK9cZrrNyLyNAnDaRtoBe8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>ColorOS and MIUI rolled out floating windows three years ago, and it is a useful utility that lets you maximize screen real estate. Floating windows essentially lets you resize any app so that it fits on the display without taking up its entire width, and it can be overlaid onto another app, making it quite convenient to use. My best use case is launching the calculator in a floating window whenever I need to add up a few things, and it works exceedingly well in this situation.</p><p>If Google is looking to add floating windows to Android 15, it should consider looking at ColorOS&apos; implementation and not MIUI. In all its wisdom, Xiaomi thought it best to have floating windows enabled as default, with no way to turn off the feature. This means that whenever you pull down on a notification, it opens in a floating window, and I&apos;ve had several instances over the years where I inadvertently launched floating windows without meaning to.</p>
<h2 id="better-icon-customization-2">Better icon customization</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="tkpuueaEzKaJHRbs8HtCp7" name="android-15-list-2.jpg" alt="Android 15 wishlist" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tkpuueaEzKaJHRbs8HtCp7.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google introduced themed icons in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/android-12">Android 12</a> (albeit in beta), and two years after launch, the feature is still half-baked at best. The problem isn&apos;t down to Google, but devs — as this feature isn&apos;t mandated, most app makers still choose to ignore it, and it makes the home screen look less cohesive. Even well-known services like Evernote don&apos;t offer the feature, and while that&apos;s more to do with the state of Evernote, it&apos;s annoying to not have all icons utilize the feature.</p><p>While Google&apos;s at it, if it can roll out the ability to change icon shape and size, that would be fantastic. I&apos;m still annoyed at how little customization is available on a Pixel phone in this particular regard, and really needs to do better.</p>
<h2 id="screen-distance-2">Screen Distance</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="S5AwoYS6gMPUzzuiquYjy7" name="android-15-list-3.jpg" alt="Android 15 wishlist" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/S5AwoYS6gMPUzzuiquYjy7.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Screen Distance is a clever new feature in iOS 17 that utilizes the front camera to determine if you&apos;re holding your phone too close to your eyes. The goal here is to reduce eye strain, and if the camera detects that you&apos;re using your device closer than 12 inches from your face, it triggers a full-screen alert asking you to move your phone or tablet further away.</p><p>This feature proved to be quite useful on the iPhone 15 Pro Max, and I found that I had a tendency to hold the phone a little closer at night. Screen Distance is designed to reduce risk of myopia in children, but if you tend to use your phone in bed a lot, it can be quite a handy tool. Google needs to bring a similar utility to Android, and given that it uses the camera to gauge distance, it shouldn&apos;t be hard to implement.</p>
<h2 id="better-always-on-display-2">Better Always On Display</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="yaCWQ5vnHxH9LsGU9iJTD8" name="android-15-list-4.jpg" alt="Android 15 wishlist" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yaCWQ5vnHxH9LsGU9iJTD8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google&apos;s take on an Always On Display has always been lackluster, and Android 14 doesn&apos;t do much to change that. You only get the option to show time and date when choosing an always-on screen, and while you get notification icons at the bottom, there isn&apos;t any customization possible.</p><p>Other interfaces, meanwhile, offer extensive customizability in this area. I like the range of styles available in ColorOS and the fact that I can design my own pattern that shows up on the lock screen, and while One UI doesn&apos;t offer much out of the box, you can always install Good Lock and unlock a slate of customization options.</p>
<h2 id="app-cloning-2">App cloning</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="6cGejBsBers5RfFCh9TKS8" name="android-15-list-5.jpg" alt="Android 15 wishlist" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6cGejBsBers5RfFCh9TKS8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Most Android brands give you the option to clone an app so you can run two instances of it. This is handy if you&apos;ve got two SIM cards and want to fully utilize messaging services like WhatsApp or Telegram, but you don&apos;t have the ability to do so on a Pixel phone. As it usually does, Google teased this feature in earlier Android 14 beta builds, but it was nowhere to be found in subsequent betas, and is missing on the stable version.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-android-15-much-more-to-come"><span>Android 15: Much more to come</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="a7NZY6fiEXh9Dfx4A7Xwkg" name="android-15-logo-wide.jpg" alt="Android 15 logo on Pixel 8" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/a7NZY6fiEXh9Dfx4A7Xwkg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>We&apos;re just getting started with Android 15, and the public-facing beta builds are still a month away. That&apos;s when we usually see the big interface changes, and by that time, the builds are usually stable enough to be used on a daily basis. I&apos;ll regularly update this post as new builds show up, but even the little we&apos;ve seen of Android 15 suggests it will be an exciting release.  </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ It feels like Google just rolled out Android 14, but Android 15 is making its debut already, with the preview builds starting to become available. Here's what's new in Android 15.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">iU3jbtKzdGYbaWzYQtJSa5</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LmDEBeSE5Yia7z5BCvWuDg.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 06:15:46 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LmDEBeSE5Yia7z5BCvWuDg.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android 15 logo on Pixel 8 next to Pixel 7a and 7 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android 15 logo on Pixel 8 next to Pixel 7a and 7 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>