<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 12:25:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Moto Buds Plus are official with Bose-powered ANC and EQ tuning ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Motorola introduced its latest earbuds lineup, including the Moto Buds and Moto Buds Plus, with Hi-Res Audio and advanced noise control features.</li><li>Partnering with Bose, Motorola integrated Sound by Bose into the Moto Buds Plus for enhanced active noise cancellation and EQ tuning.</li><li>CrystalTalk AI technology promises clear voice transmission, even in noisy environments, while dual dynamic drivers promise studio-quality sound.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Motorola is big on smartphones, but it also offers a bunch of accessories like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-earbuds">wireless earbuds</a>, and the company announced today (April 16), its latest earbuds lineup.</p><p>A few days ago, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1778277983582634255" target="_blank">rumors were buzzing</a> about the Moto Buds and Moto Buds Plus. Now, they&apos;re official with Hi-Res Audio, top-notch noise control, and a triple-mic setup. Plus, they&apos;re rocking a water-repellent design, although Motorola is keeping us in the dark about the official IP rating.</p><p>The Plus model is coming in Forest Grey and Beach Sand. Meanwhile, the regular version is dropping in four colors: Starlight Blue, Glacier Blue, Coral Peach, and Kiwi Green.</p><p>Motorola teamed up with Bose to tweak the Moto Buds Plus. That means you&apos;re getting some serious active noise cancellation and EQ tuning, thanks to the integration of <em>Sound by Bose</em>.</p><p>Another standout feature is Motorola&apos;s CrystalTalk AI, which features an anti-wind noise algorithm so that even in noisy places, your voice comes through crystal clear.</p><p>Under the hood, the Moto Buds Plus include dual dynamic drivers and promising studio-quality music thanks to Hi-Res Audio. It captures sound in a wider range with three times more detail, especially on Hi-Res Audio streaming apps.</p><p>The Moto Buds Plus also works with <em>Dolby Head Tracking</em> when hooked up to the latest Motorola Edge smartphones rocking Dolby Atmos tech, like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-edge-50-ultra-launch">Motorola Edge 50 Ultra</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-edge-50-pro-announced-in-india">Edge 50 Pro</a>. With Dolby Head Tracking, your sound adjusts as you move your head, giving you a natural listening experience.</p><p>In terms of battery life, the Moto Buds Plus promises up to eight hours of playtime on just one charge. And if you&apos;re in a rush, just 10 minutes of charging gives you an extra three hours of listening time. Plus, with their charging case, these buds can last up to 38 hours.</p><p>Meanwhile, the regular Moto Buds come with a 12.4mm dynamic driver, guaranteeing you some sharp, clean audio.</p><p>Just like its higher-end siblings, the regular Moto Buds also come equipped with CrystalTalk AI. But these buds outlast the Moto Buds Plus. With up to nine hours of playtime on one charge and an extra two hours squeezed out of just 10 minutes of charging, they&apos;re ready for the long haul.</p><p>The Moto Buds models have a dedicated app to control them. You can use it to adjust how much noise cancellation you want or turn it off completely. Even better, the app can automatically adjust the noise cancellation depending on how noisy things are around you. And if you need to hear what&apos;s happening around you, you can turn on Transparency Mode so you don&apos;t miss anything.</p><p>Motorola hasn&apos;t disclosed the pricing details yet, as they vary by region. We&apos;ll update this article when we have more information.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/the-moto-buds-plus-are-official-with-bose-powered-anc-and-eq-tuning</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Motorola's new earbuds come in two versions: a regular one and a top-tier version with Bose noise-canceling and more options to tweak the sound. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">veUqSUJGpjBQcRp6oounF5</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TPGMhRWUb9DeZQvtM4Sj7c.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 12:19:55 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TPGMhRWUb9DeZQvtM4Sj7c.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Motorola]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Moto Buds series in black]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Moto Buds series in black]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ How to transfer a Wear OS smartwatch from one phone to another ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Transferring your Wear OS watch to a new phone is much easier than before, when you had to reset your smartwatch first. You can now preserve your settings and data after the transfer, in most cases.</p><p>Only <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/wear-os-4">Wear OS 4</a> watches like the Pixel Watch 2 or Galaxy Watch 6 have access to this feature, however, and they both handle the transfer using their respective watch apps and unique steps (which we&apos;ll explain below).</p><p>As for other Wear OS watches stuck at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/wear-os-3">Wear OS 3</a>, you&apos;ll have to factory reset your watch before setting it up on the new phone like you would with a brand-new watch. </p><p>Below, we&apos;ll break down the specific steps for transferring a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-6-review">Galaxy Watch 6</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-2-review">Pixel Watch 2</a>, or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oneplus-watch-2-review">OnePlus Watch 2</a> to a new Android smartphone without losing your data.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-transfer-galaxy-watch-6-to-a-new-phone-2">How to transfer Galaxy Watch 6 to a new phone</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="A2YEywXZVp9aDXogXA6Gtg" name="galaxy-watch-6-transfer-screenshots.jpg" alt="Four Samsung Wearable app screenshots showing the steps for transferring a Galaxy Watch to a new Android phone." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/A2YEywXZVp9aDXogXA6Gtg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>1. Set up your new Android phone, <strong>enable Bluetooth</strong> if it isn&apos;t on already, and <strong>log into the same Google account</strong> as your old phone. You&apos;ll <strong>have to reset the watch</strong> if they don&apos;t match.</p><p>2. On your old phone, open the <strong>Wearable app</strong>. Make sure your smartwatch is synced with that phone.</p><p>3. Tap <strong>Watch Settings</strong>.</p><p>4. Tap <strong>General</strong>.</p><p>5. Tap <strong>Transfer watch to new phone</strong>, located near the bottom. Then tap that text again on the next screen.</p><p>6. You&apos;ll be taken to a <strong>Ready to transfer</strong> screen. If your new phone is a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-samsung-phones">Samsung phone</a>, you should see an automatic prompt showing your watch, where you&apos;ll tap <strong>Connect</strong>.</p><p>6a. If the prompt doesn&apos;t appear on your new phone, you may need to either <strong>download </strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.samsung.android.app.watchmanager&hl=en_US&gl=US" target="_blank"><strong>Galaxy Wearable</strong></a> from the Play Store or find the watch in your Bluetooth menu in <strong>Settings</strong>.</p><p>At this point, you&apos;ll simply go through the steps in the Galaxy Wearable app, confirming your settings, before you&apos;ll have access to your smartwatch again!</p>
<h2 id="how-to-transfer-pixel-watch-2-to-new-phone-2">How to transfer Pixel Watch 2 to new phone</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="ZXuNABK9Q7pZckprnmFZEE" name="pixel-watch-2-transfer-watch-screenshots-fixed.jpg" alt="Screenshots showing how to transfer the Pixel Watch 2 to a new Android phone." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZXuNABK9Q7pZckprnmFZEE.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>1. On your new phone, make sure you&apos;re <strong>logged into the same Google account</strong> as your old phone, and download the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.wear.companion&hl=en_US&gl=US" target="_blank"><strong>Google Pixel Watch app</strong></a>.</p><p>2. On your Pixel Watch 2, <strong>open Settings</strong> by swiping a finger down from the top of the display to find the Cog icon.</p><p>3. Scroll down to <strong>System</strong>, then down to <strong>Transfer Watch</strong> (both are the final options).</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="EhHZXH9YDLXPoj6uXDQAeg" name="pixel-watch-2-transfer-watch-screenshots-2.jpg" alt="Screenshots showing a Pixel Watch 2 transfer to a new phone." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/EhHZXH9YDLXPoj6uXDQAeg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>4. On the <strong>Transfer watch</strong> screen, tap the <strong>Checkmark</strong>. </p><p>5. Open the Pixel Watch app on your new phone and follow the steps, confirming the <strong>pairing code</strong> is the same on both devices.</p><p>Having tested this system ourselves, transferring the Pixel Watch 2 to a new phone only takes a couple of minutes at most, so you&apos;ll be all set quickly!</p>
<h2 id="how-to-transfer-the-oneplus-watch-2-to-a-new-phone-2">How to transfer the OnePlus Watch 2 to a new phone</h2>
<p>Unfortunately, the OnePlus Watch 2 doesn&apos;t transfer over as easily, despite running Wear OS 4. We&apos;ve confirmed with OnePlus that you need to "disconnect and reset" your smartwatch before pairing with a new phone:</p><p>1. In the OHealth app, tap the <strong>Device</strong> tab, then scroll down to select <strong>More</strong>.</p><p>2. Tap <strong>Unpair</strong>, then tap <strong>Unpair</strong> again. Your OnePlus Watch 2 will automatically factory reset itself, so you can sync it to your new phone.</p><p>That said, you <em>can</em> transfer over your health data before the reset, by installing the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.heytap.health.international&hl=en_US&gl=US" target="_blank"><strong>OHealth app</strong></a> on your new phone:</p><p>1. Sign into the same OHealth account on both phones.</p><p>2. Make sure both phones are on the <strong>same Wi-Fi network</strong>.</p><p>3. On both phones, tap the <strong>profile icon</strong> in the app&apos;s top-right, then tap <strong>Migrate</strong>.</p><p>4. Tap either <strong>new phone</strong> or <strong>old phone</strong> on each phone, then <strong>scan the QR code</strong>.</p><p>5. Select which data you want to migrate. All data is selected by default.</p>
<h2 id="figuring-out-wear-os-and-propriety-skins-2">Figuring out Wear OS and propriety skins</h2>
<p>We didn&apos;t cover every <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wear-os-watch">Wear OS watch</a> here, because most of the older Wear OS 3 watches use their own proprietary systems and require you to reset the watch first. We&apos;re happy that Google finally prioritized simple transfers, for people who frequently swap between <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-android-phones">cheap Android phones</a> but want to make their smartwatch last across devices.</p><p>It&apos;s no coincidence, though, that the two <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch">best Android watches</a> are the two that made this transfer system work. Google and Samsung frequently develop the latest smartwatch tech for themselves, leaving other brands playing catch-up. So if you&apos;re looking for a smartwatch built to last, you&apos;ll probably want to consider a Galaxy or Pixel Watch first.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="986d37c0-76f7-4066-a06d-0f3f53dcc732">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/THaadG2dg24wXev2QcdJvR.jpg' alt='Official render of the Samsung Galaxy Watch 6'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy Watch 6</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Built to last</strong></em></p>
<p>The Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 came out in mid-2023, but because it'll receive four years of software support, it's meant to last through 2027 (at least). That means it'll be ready to transfer from one Android phone to the next, offering long battery life and a bright, thin-edged AMOLED display.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/how-to-transfer-wear-os-watch-to-new-phone</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ We show the steps and screenshots for transferring your Galaxy Watch 6, Pixel Watch 2, or OnePlus Watch 2 to your new Android phone. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Yy8fubYzvmELNkL2Mzn7gJ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/i5R5GaDyvJAtD7JhffhgEh.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 12:04:26 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wear Os]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/i5R5GaDyvJAtD7JhffhgEh.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nick Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The OnePlus Watch 2 sitting in-between two Android phones for an OHealth data transfer, for showing how to transfer Wear OS watch to new phone.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The OnePlus Watch 2 sitting in-between two Android phones for an OHealth data transfer, for showing how to transfer Wear OS watch to new phone.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Motorola announces the new Edge 50 Ultra with the latest Qualcomm AI chip ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>After debuting the Motorola Edge 50 Pro in India earlier this month, Motorola has revealed the entire 50-series, including the Motorola Edge 50 Fusion and Motorola Edge 50 Ultra. </li><li>The flagship Motorola Edge 50 Ultra features the Snapdragon 8s Gen 3 chip, a triple-camera system, and includes "Moto AI" software tools.</li><li>For now, the smartphones have limited global availability in Europe, Latin America, Asia, and Oceania. North America isn't getting the phones yet, but that could change later on. </li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Following the company&apos;s launch of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-edge-50-pro-announced-in-india">Motorola Edge 50 Pro</a> in India earlier this month, Motorola revealed the complete Edge 50 series today. That includes the flagship Motorola Edge 50 Ultra, the mid-range Motorola Edge 50 Pro, and the budget Motorola Edge 50 Fusion. The company&apos;s latest smartphones are launching in a few global markets soon, including parts of Europe, Latin America, Asia, and Oceania — but not North America, for now. </p><p>Leaks around the high-end Edge 50 Ultra intensified over the last few weeks, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-edge-50-ultra-launch-date-teasers">with Motorola itself teasing the official announcement</a> last Friday. At the time, Motorola confirmed that the Edge 50 Ultra would support 125W TurboPower charging. Now, we know that the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">flagship phone</a> also supports 50W wireless charging and has a 4,500 mAh battery capacity. Those are the exact same specs as the Edge 50 Pro, for reference. </p><p>However, the Edge 50 Ultra separates itself from the rest of the lineup through the phone&apos;s display, camera system, and chipset. It features a 6.7-inch pOLED with a higher resolution than the last generation model, as well as Qualcomm&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-snapdragon-8s-gen-3-announced">Snapdragon 8s Gen 3</a> Mobile Platform for processing power. That&apos;s a half-step below the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 platform we see on Samsung and OnePlus flagships, but it&apos;s still a notable inclusion, offering up to 16GB of memory and up to 1TB of storage.</p><p>For the cameras, Motorola equipped the Edge 50 Ultra with a triple-camera system highlighted by a 50MP main sensor. There&apos;s also a 64MP telephoto lens capable of 3x optical zoom and a 50MP ultrawide lens. On the front, you&apos;ll find another 50MP selfie camera. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="qUE3wimHb4H4VubfnAdn9T" name="Motorola-Edge-50-Ultra-Cameras.jpg" alt="The camera on the Motorola Edge 50 Ultra." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qUE3wimHb4H4VubfnAdn9T.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1600" height="900" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central / Motorola)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Motorola&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-edge-50-pro-launching-on-april-3-2024">Edge 50 Pro</a> is the same phone here as the one that debuted on April 3 in India. It&apos;s a solid mid-ranger but comes with a few compromises. There&apos;s still a triple-camera system on the Edge 50 Pro, but the telephoto and ultrawide sensors are smaller than the ones found on the Edge 50 Ultra. The chipset is a step-down, too, since this phone uses the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phone/snapdragon-7-gen-3-launch">Snapdragon 7 Gen 3</a> Mobile Platform. However, it includes a quality 6.7-inch pOLED display with support for 144Hz refresh rates.</p><p>The budget option in this lineup is the Motorola Edge 50 Fusion. It sports a 6.7-inch display capable of a 120Hz refresh rate but has a lower resolution than the other 50 series phones. While Motorola did not disclose the chip powering the Edge 50 Fusion in its press release, it may possibly be the Qualcomm <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/snapdragon-6-gen-1-snapdragon-4-gen-1-launch">Snapdragon 6 Gen 1</a> processor. The Edge 50 Fusion has a dual-camera system with a 50MP main camera and a 13MP ultrawide camera as well.</p><p>All the phones come with Moto AI, Motorola&apos;s new suite of AI-based features. The company says this functionality includes generative theming, AI-based search and navigation, and camera features. Since Motorola&apos;s My UX Android skin uses Google Photos as the native gallery app, these phones will support AI features like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-use-magic-editor-on-the-pixel-8">Magic Editor</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-use-magic-eraser-non-pixel-phones">Magic Eraser</a>, and Photo Unblur in the coming weeks.</p><p>The Motorola Edge 50 Ultra will retail for €999, the Edge 50 Pro will be priced at €699, and the Edge 50 Fusion will cost €399. All three phones will be available in selected markets in Europe, Latin America, Asia, and Oceania. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-edge-50-ultra-launch</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Motorola's new Edge 50 series lineup includes the Edge 50 Pro, Edge 50 Fusion, and Edge 50 Ultra — but they're not available in North America just yet.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">AYybqiocATbzQgjxYjJGUb</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/egUqEWpkv9kUTanE4CEYKT.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 12:00:51 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/egUqEWpkv9kUTanE4CEYKT.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central / Motorola]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The three phones in the Motorola Edge 50 series.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The three phones in the Motorola Edge 50 series.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Fiio K19 review: The ultimate DAC upgrade ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Quick Menu</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="ytn53A4xZSm7hUkoEzhfPk" name="fiio-k19-18.jpg" caption="" alt="Fiio K19 DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ytn53A4xZSm7hUkoEzhfPk.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">1. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="#section-fiio-k19-pricing-and-release-date">Pricing and release date</a><br>
2. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="#section-fiio-k19-design">Design</a><br>
3. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="#section-fiio-k19-connectivity-and-features">Connectivity and features</a><br>
4. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="#section-fiio-k19-sound-quality">Sound quality</a><br>
5. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="#section-fiio-k19-the-competition">The competition</a><br>
6. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="#section-fiio-k19-should-you-buy-it">Should you buy it?</a></p></div></div>
<p>Fiio started focusing on high-end gear two years ago, and that resulted in products like the K9 Pro. The K9 Pro has just about every feature you need in a desktop DAC, and with the ability to deliver up to 2.1W of power, it drives just about any headset available today.</p><p>As I said in my <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-k9-pro-ess-review">K9 Pro review</a>, there isn&apos;t anything missing in the DAC, and although it is two years old at this point, it continues to be outstanding. I used it daily for the better part of a year and a half, and having tested it with several dozen headsets and IEMs, I can confidently say that I haven&apos;t used a better DAC.</p><p>Until now. Fiio launched the K19 at the start of 2024, and the flagship DAC is designed to take over from the K9 Pro. There are so many differences between the two that it&apos;s unfair to call the K19 an upgrade — think of it as an overhaul. Fiio went with an all-new design, somehow crammed even more ports into the DAC, and increased the power to 8W — four times that of the K9 Pro.</p><p>That obviously comes with an increase in the asking price, and the K19 retails for $1,349. Having used the K19 alongside the K9 Pro, it&apos;s easy to see that Fiio is onto something special with its 2024 flagship.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-fiio-k19-pricing-and-release-date"><span>Fiio K19: Pricing and release date</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="miv2YS9dUQKeiCtT2dWZHe" name="fiio-k19-2.jpg" alt="Fiio K19 DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/miv2YS9dUQKeiCtT2dWZHe.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Fiio unveiled the K19 at the end of February 2024, and the DAC is now available in China and is slowly making its way to global markets. The K19 retails for $1,349 — $500 more than that of the K9 Pro. Unlike earlier models in the series, the K19 is available in black and white color options.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-fiio-k19-design"><span>Fiio K19: Design</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="i5LCj43fjfkDQw8eVVMnKg" name="fiio-k19-34.jpg" alt="Fiio K19 DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/i5LCj43fjfkDQw8eVVMnKg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Fiio tends to use a consistent design aesthetic, but it&apos;s switching things up with the K19. The DAC has an all-new design language that looks downright gorgeous, and you won&apos;t find any similarities to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-k9-review">K9</a> or any of its predecessors. The key difference is that the K19 is noticeably thinner and wider than the K9 Pro, with the DAC designed to be used in a vertical orientation.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="5BBTnxi3RGiQvWzDHnz7Ve" name="fiio-k19-22.jpg" alt="Fiio K19 DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5BBTnxi3RGiQvWzDHnz7Ve.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="d6yZas8guQmrUM8gTvDDjf" name="fiio-k19-8.jpg" alt="Fiio K19 DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/d6yZas8guQmrUM8gTvDDjf.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="yGmeAd9HRepkmLDjNpyvXh" name="fiio-k19-7.jpg" alt="Fiio K19 DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yGmeAd9HRepkmLDjNpyvXh.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>That&apos;s why the labels around the two rotary dials are located to the side; there are metal mounting brackets that can be screwed into the left side if you&apos;re interested in using the K19 vertically. But if you want to use the DAC horizontally, you get rubber feet in the box that can be attached to the underside.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="dUj7Uwym7YGEdxPRTjy3Fo" name="fiio-k19-3.jpg" alt="Fiio K19 DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dUj7Uwym7YGEdxPRTjy3Fo.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The standout design feature is the honeycomb structure that covers the top and bottom halves of the DAC; this creates a much more elegant design while increasing passive airflow to the DAC at the same time. There&apos;s a steel mesh underneath the honeycomb pattern that does a good job preventing dust ingress, and there are vents on either side that deliver airflow into the DAC.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="UAS3NKp5YtkAe4DhGahRsg" name="fiio-k19-10.jpg" alt="Fiio K19 DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/UAS3NKp5YtkAe4DhGahRsg.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="SMV3AAxNH8uuyV7amcNT2e" name="fiio-k19-23.jpg" alt="Fiio K19 DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SMV3AAxNH8uuyV7amcNT2e.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="jCYBUgnbqHMetZ8t9YXzAg" name="fiio-k19-9.jpg" alt="Fiio K19 DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jCYBUgnbqHMetZ8t9YXzAg.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Like the K9 Pro, the K19 is cooled passively, but the increased vents means the DAC doesn&apos;t get hot after extended use. The chassis itself is made out of aluminum, and it has a reassuring heft to it; I didn&apos;t see any issues whatsoever with the build quality, and it&apos;s clear that the K19 is designed to last decades.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="YHGpN3V8rxTC23J2rYNFLf" name="fiio-k19-5.jpg" alt="Fiio K19 DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YHGpN3V8rxTC23J2rYNFLf.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>An interesting change this time is the availability of a silver color variant. It makes the K19 look that much more elegant, and gives it a presence that you just don&apos;t get with the black version. That said, the silver model is designed to grab attention, so if you want a DAC that you can tuck away unobtrusively, you should get the black model.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="KLmGhTuzFXNQgostSkd8D" name="fiio-k19-16.jpg" alt="Fiio K19 DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KLmGhTuzFXNQgostSkd8D.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The model name, THX branding, and Hi-Res logo are all located on the underside, leading to a cleaner look — you just get the Fiio logo at the top. Fiio also changed the navigation, so instead of buttons, you get two rotary knobs, and a built-in 1.3-inch screen that lets you change between various modes and sources.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="keG4tUjgY77vP5cswWiaGh" name="fiio-k19-36.jpg" alt="Fiio K19 DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/keG4tUjgY77vP5cswWiaGh.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The screen has a TFT panel and gets bright enough, but I would have preferred a larger panel. One rotary knob is used to control the volume, with the other used to change the menu options. Both knobs have a knurled texture that makes using them incredibly easy, and they an LED ring light that changes color based on quality of playback source.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="VNo6Svc636VwzixpnffGpj" name="fiio-k19-29.jpg" alt="Fiio K19 DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VNo6Svc636VwzixpnffGpj.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Talking about a clean design, the screen sits in an island along the front that includes all the connectivity options, and this is decked out in black, serving up a good contrast against the white chassis. As is the case with all of its products, Fiio bundles a generous amount of accessories with the K19, and the one I like the most is an acrylic cone that&apos;s designed to wedge into the side — this allows the DAC to double as a headset stand, and that&apos;s just plain cool.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="ZzeGes9DxbBMgfYbnnsEkd" name="fiio-k19-6.jpg" alt="Fiio K19 DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZzeGes9DxbBMgfYbnnsEkd.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Overall, Fiio did an outstanding job with the design of the K19; the DAC looks stunning, and the changes to the passive cooling means it gets much better ventilation.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-fiio-k19-connectivity-and-features"><span>Fiio K19: Connectivity and features</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="EPQQPG3jkqPUphzY8t4w7i" name="fiio-k19-15.jpg" alt="Fiio K19 DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/EPQQPG3jkqPUphzY8t4w7i.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Similar to the design, Fiio paid close attention to detail when it comes to the K19&apos;s feature-set, and as a result, you get what is possibly the best connectivity of any DAC. Let&apos;s start with the front: the K19 has a single-ended 6.35mm port in addition to the balanced 4.4mm port, and the 4-pin XLR port is hidden behind a dust cover. There&apos;s even a USB-C port, giving you easy access to connect to other devices.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="4RbK7wtqZzDCZkMHR4NHSi" name="fiio-k19-14.jpg" alt="Fiio K19 DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4RbK7wtqZzDCZkMHR4NHSi.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It&apos;s at the back where things get interesting. The K19 can be powered by both AC and DC sources, and there&apos;s a toggle to switch between the two. Fiio bundles an AC power cord in the box, but if you have a DC barrel plug and want to use it that way, you can do so (it uses 15V/3A).</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="kfFXcxTRZ53PYL2ZPEgGEj" name="fiio-k19-13.jpg" alt="Fiio K19 DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kfFXcxTRZ53PYL2ZPEgGEj.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>When it comes to analog connectors, you get balanced 3-pin XLR in addition to RCA, with the latter featuring dust covers. Digital connectivity is handled by optical in/out, coaxial in/out, and USB in. What&apos;s interesting with the K19 is that Fiio is no longer using the USB-B connector, instead switching over to USB-C, making it extremely easy to connect the DAC to a source device. I had no issues connecting the DAC to my Windows machine via the bundled USB-C to USB-A cable.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="zHwdBcDBMobCb4NjtXrsZj" name="fiio-k19-12.jpg" alt="Fiio K19 DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zHwdBcDBMobCb4NjtXrsZj.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Fiio is using an integrated Bluetooth antenna on the K19 — just like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-r7-review">R7</a> — and it adds to the cleaner look of the DAC. The biggest change to the DAC is the inclusion of HDMI ports; you get HDMI in and HDMI ARC out, and this allows the K19 to be used with TVs and gaming consoles.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="b6DDnR8Um45djxW7pwPLge" name="fiio-k19-27.jpg" alt="Fiio K19 DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/b6DDnR8Um45djxW7pwPLge.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>To that effect, Fiio bundles an infrared remote in the box. You can use it to change the volume, switch the K19 on or off, adjust the EQ, and change connection modes. It doesn&apos;t have backlit keys, but it offers an easy way to control the K19. Of course, if you want to use your phone, Fiio Control gives you access to all the K19&apos;s settings.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-fiio-k19-sound-quality"><span>Fiio K19: Sound quality</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="MEBsUh4LQjjbZwaL9QygWm" name="fiio-k19-33.jpg" alt="Fiio K19 DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MEBsUh4LQjjbZwaL9QygWm.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Fiio uses dual ESS&apos;s latest ES9039S Pro DAC hardware, and it goes up to 768kHz/32-bit over PCM and DSD512 via USB. It has an XMOS XU316 USB controller, and the Bluetooth side of things is handled by Qualcomm&apos;s QCC5125 — the same as the K9. Similar to the K9 Pro, amplification is by way of THX&apos;s outstanding 8-channel 788+ modules.</p>
<p>What makes the K19 stand out is the sheer power on offer; it is able to deliver up to an insane 8000mW at 32Ω via the balanced ports, and that&apos;s significantly higher than what you get with any other DAC. Interestingly, the K19 has a built-in DSP engine that enables parametric EQ — accessible via Fiio&apos;s custom DSP software on Android, Windows, and macOS — that gives you granular control over the sound.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="3Y5cGYJxezNKJbUN2jnQVf" name="fiio-k19-26.jpg" alt="Fiio K19 DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3Y5cGYJxezNKJbUN2jnQVf.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I tested the K19 with a wide range of IEMs, including <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-fx15-review">Fiio&apos;s own FX15</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/letshuoer-cadenza-12-review">Letshuoer Cadenza 12</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/audeze-euclid-review">Audeze Euclid</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/thieaudio-prestige-ltd-review">Thieaudio Prestige LTD</a>, and a half-dozen budget models. The K19 has no problems driving sensitive IEMs, and it did a fantastic job in this regard — as you&apos;d imagine.</p>
<p>I didn&apos;t run into any issues at all with headsets, and I used the likes of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/audeze-mm-500-review">Audeze MM-500</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/audeze-lcd-x-review">LCD-X</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-ft5-review">Fiio FT5</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/moondrop-venus-review">Moondrop Venus</a>, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/massdrop-x-focal-elex-review">Focal Elex</a>. There&apos;s just no scenario where the K19 doesn&apos;t deliver more than enough power, and that&apos;s just not a problem with this DAC.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="2AKfdxX2ZMVWY6h7tLLevi" name="fiio-k19-32.jpg" alt="Fiio K19 DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2AKfdxX2ZMVWY6h7tLLevi.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Coming to the sound, the K19 has Fiio&apos;s characteristic signature, but with added vibrancy. When using the FT5 and MM-500, bass notes have good vigor and impact, with a subtle sub-bass extension that&apos;s terrific. There&apos;s better definition than the K9 Pro, and that&apos;s immediately evident when switching between the two.</p>
<p>The mid-range is clean and natural, and vocals have no problem shining through the mix. Instrument separation is excellent, and you can hear intricate details with ease, like the pluck of a guitar. The treble has good extension, and you get a sense of airiness that adds dynamism.</p><p>On the whole, the biggest difference over the K9 Pro is that the K19 sounds more engaging and dynamic, and you get a wider soundstage that&apos;s just enjoyable.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-fiio-k19-the-competition"><span>Fiio K19: The competition</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:42.87%;"><img id="fEbCG6bPAwHNqAZHHMLXdh" name="fiio-k9-pro-hero.jpg" alt="Fiio K9 Pro ESS" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fEbCG6bPAwHNqAZHHMLXdh.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="878" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The K9 Pro is still a stellar choice in 2024. It has a terrific sound, the design looks cool thanks to the gold accents, and you get extensive connectivity. It doesn&apos;t have any issues driving demanding planar headsets, and the sound is engaging and wide. The K9 Pro <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/FiiO-Amplifier-Headphone-Bluetooth-Resolution/dp/B09PDM588T">costs $849 as of writing</a>, but it is likely to go on sale as the K19 becomes available globally. Fiio has mentioned that it will sell the K9 Pro alongside the K19, so if you don&apos;t need the extra power or some of the additional features, the K9 Pro would be the way to go.</p><p>If you want the best value, you should consider the regular K9. It has the same design as the K9 Pro, and while it doesn&apos;t feature the best ESS DACs, the tonality is remarkably close to the K9 Pro. Best of all, the K9 <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/FiiO-K9-Headphone-Amplifier-Bluetooth/dp/B0C13XK1WC">costs just $499</a>.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-fiio-k19-should-you-buy-it"><span>Fiio K19: Should you buy it?</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="dDfJts9HtnSiyeAPwnay4h" name="fiio-k19-35.jpg" alt="Fiio K19 DAC review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dDfJts9HtnSiyeAPwnay4h.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>You should buy this if:</strong></p>
<ul><li>You want a high-end DAC</li><li>You need extensive analog and digital connectivity</li><li>You want a DAC with an elegant design that's built to last</li><li>You need an engaging sound with good dynamics</li></ul>
<p><strong>You shouldn&apos;t buy this if:</strong></p>
<ul><li>You need a value-focused DAC</li></ul>
<p>The naming convention with the K19 suggests it is an upgrade over the K9 Pro, but it is so much more than that — this is a truly outstanding product that immediately stands out in the brand&apos;s portfolio. The design is unmistakably premium, and the white version in particular looks stunning. The ability to use it in vertical or horizontal orientation makes it that much more versatile, and the sleeker build along with all-metal chassis means the K19 is designed to last decades.</p><p>But it&apos;s the feature-set that makes the K19 so alluring; you get every single port you&apos;ll ever need, and the exhaustive connectivity combined with Bluetooth 5.1 and lossless audio codecs make this a fantastic choice when paired with just about any audio device.</p><p>Ultimately, the K19 is a halo device that solidifies Fiio&apos;s position as one of the leaders in the enthusiast audio category. Yes, it costs a lot of money, but you&apos;re getting a ton of features, and if you&apos;re after an endgame DAC that can do it all, you&apos;ve just found it.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-k19-review</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Fiio makes some of the best DACs you can buy, and with the K19, it is delivering a halo product that is absolutely incredible.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">MZ5iLE8cjHQXsegK9UyFrS</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6sVWgM8azJ4LY7KQRrx5eg.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 10:47:31 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6sVWgM8azJ4LY7KQRrx5eg.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Fiio K19 DAC review]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Fiio K19 DAC review]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung shipped more phones than anyone else in Q1 2024 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>IDC's latest data reveals that fewer iPhones were sold last quarter, while Samsung's strategy of releasing its new Galaxy S24 series earlier proved successful.</li><li>Samsung shipped 60.1 million units in Q1 2024, capturing a 20.8% market share, while Apple shipped 50.1 million units, representing 17.3% of the market.</li><li>While Samsung and Apple are expected to maintain dominance, other brands like Xiaomi, Transsion, Oppo, and Vivo are gaining traction, especially outside the US.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Samsung <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-no-longer-biggest-smartphone-maker">lost the top spot to Apple in 2023</a>, but now it is back in the driver&apos;s seat after shipping the most smartphones worldwide in the first quarter of 2024.</p><p>The South Korean electronics giant outdid Apple to reclaim the top spot as the No. 1 smartphone company worldwide, according to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.idc.com/getdoc.jsp?containerId=prUS52032524" target="_blank">International Data Corporation</a>.</p><p>IDC&apos;s early data reveals two things: not as many iPhones flew off the shelves last quarter, and Samsung&apos;s gamble of releasing its new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24">Galaxy S24</a> series a bit earlier really worked out.</p><p>According to the preliminary data from IDC&apos;s Mobile Phone Tracker for Q1 2024, Samsung shipped 60.1 million units worldwide, grabbing a 20.8 percent market share. Meanwhile, Apple shipped 50.1 million units, accounting for 17.3 percent of the market. Both companies experienced a decline compared to the first quarter of 2023, with Apple&apos;s drop (-9.6 percent) being much larger than Samsung&apos;s (-0.7 percent).</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:586px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:82.94%;"><img id="exUHuvBUSoViPCvP3cjQjU" name="IDC-Q1-2024-smartphone-shipments.jpg" alt="IDC graph showing the top smartphone brands in Q1 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/exUHuvBUSoViPCvP3cjQjU.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="586" height="486" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: IDC)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While IDC says Samsung and Apple will probably remain at the top, there&apos;s a growing trend of other brands gaining traction, especially outside the United States. Brands like Xiaomi, Transsion, Oppo, and Vivo are becoming increasingly popular.</p><p>In Q1 2024, Xiaomi secured its spot with 40.8 million units shipped, while Transsion (owner of brands like TECNO, Infinix, and Itel) moved up to fourth place with 28.5 million units, surpassing OPPO, which shipped 25.2 million units.</p><p>Overall, the smartphone market is on the rise, according to IDC. There was a 7.8% increase in smartphone shipments in Q1 2024 compared to Q1 2023. In the last quarter, there were 289.4 million smartphone shipments, compared to 268.5 million in the same period of 2023. This suggests that the industry is recovering nicely after any slowdowns it might have faced earlier.</p><p>Even though IDC doesn&apos;t give us a breakdown of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best-selling specific phones</a>, the high shipment numbers for certain brands are a strong indicator of what&apos;s popular. Unfortunately, phone makers keep their actual sales figures under wraps.</p><p>Looking into the future, it seems the smartphone market isn&apos;t slowing down anytime soon. Nabila Popal, research director with IDC&apos;s Worldwide Tracker team, pointed out that average selling prices are rising as consumers opt for pricier models.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-shipped-more-phones-than-anyone-else-in-q1-2024</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung is back on top, beating Apple in smartphone sales this quarter. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">7aFnoYWEDPPzmZ2cvCfmVi</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HssvJK6hy6FGRuF6cvyiAF.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 06:09:26 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HssvJK6hy6FGRuF6cvyiAF.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung logo]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung logo]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ New Realme P1 Pro brings a flagship design to a midrange phone ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Realme announces two new affordable Android phones to India under the “P Series.”</li><li>Dubbed Realme P1 and P1 Pro, they equip 120Hz displays, and the Pro model features a curved screen.</li><li>The Realme P1 Pro is powered by the Snapdragon 6 Gen 1, and the standard model equips a MediaTek Dimensity 7050 SoC.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Curved displays on smartphones have been a luxury for consumers as most are generally seen on flagship phones. However, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.realme.com/in/realme-p1-pro-5g">Realme P1 Pro</a>, priced under Rs 22,000 ($265), includes a curved display at a more affordable price. </p><p>The company has announced the new P1 series with Realme P1 and the P1 Pro models in India. The latter sports a 6.7-inch curved screen that further has Full HD+ resolution and a higher 120Hz refresh rate. The Pro model is powered by a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/snapdragon-6-gen-1-snapdragon-4-gen-1-launch">Snapdragon 6 Gen 1</a> octa-core CPU and Adreno 710 GPU.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1200px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:50.00%;"><img id="cWfZsdHCHwMFJjYQgyryke" name="realme-p1-pro-01.jpg" alt="Realme P1 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/cWfZsdHCHwMFJjYQgyryke.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1200" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Realme)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1200px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:50.00%;"><img id="Q6fjGqhfK5P9Kbefckiiee" name="realme-p1-pro-02.jpg" alt="Realme P1 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Q6fjGqhfK5P9Kbefckiiee.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1200" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Realme)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>The device looks stunning, especially for the segment it is catered to; it has a giant circular camera module on the rear, and accompanying it are striking new Phoenix Red and Parrot Blue colorways. Although the camera visor looks rather large, it only features two sensors: a primary 50MP camera accompanied by an 8MP ultra-wide angle lens. The device relies on a 16MP lens for selfies.</p><p>The Realme P1 Pro ships <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review">Android 14</a> with Realme UI 5.0 running on top of it. Keeping the lights on is a 5,000mAh battery capacity with support for 45W SuperVOOC charging.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1200px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:50.00%;"><img id="dDQec2zoLdBc4RFt4iMx3f" name="realme-p1.jpg" alt="Realme P1" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dDQec2zoLdBc4RFt4iMx3f.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1200" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Realme)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Meanwhile, the standard <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.realme.com/in/realme-p1-5g">Realme P1</a> is powered by a MediaTek Dimensity 7050 chipset equipped with a 120Hz refresh panel and priced under Rs 16,000 (~$200), falling under the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-android-phones">cheaper Android phone</a> segment. It also has a 50MP primary camera and a 16MP selfie camera.</p><p>The device&apos;s color options look toned down compared to those of its sibling; however, the colors look attractive. There is a 5,000mAh battery capacity powering the device, and it supports 45W super fast charging. Additionally, it supports reverse charging.</p><p>The Realme P1 Pro is priced at Rs 21,999 for the 8GB+128GB variant and Rs 22,999 for the larger 256GB variant. The standard Realme P1 costs Rs 15,999 for the 6GB+128GB variant and Rs 18,999 for the 8GB+256GB model. It also sports the Phoenix Red color alongside Peacock Green.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/realme-p1-pro-launch</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Curved displays tailored to flagship Android phones are now a thing of the past. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">3NgRTphXpZfcdo6exLKGEN</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4skJxavvMeLGBScNjLQJwe.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 05:57:34 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4skJxavvMeLGBScNjLQJwe.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Realme]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Realme P1 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Realme P1 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ YouTube eliminates a workaround to block ads on videos ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>YouTube started cracking down on users watching videos with ad blockers in October 2023, preventing video playback if an ad blocker is in use. </li><li>Now, the platform is also taking steps to block third-party apps from circumventing ads, and videos might not play properly while using apps that attempt to avoid ads. </li><li>As YouTube has consistently done, it is urging people to subscribe to YouTube Premium if they don't want to watch ads.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>YouTube&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-global-efforts-clock-ad-blockers">attempt to thwart ad blockers</a> on the platform now covers third-party apps, as explained in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/youtube/thread/269521462/enforcement-on-third-party-apps?hl=en" target="_blank">community announcement</a> on Monday, April 15. The video streaming site first started to crack down on users employing ad blockers to avoid watching ads in October 2023 in browsers. If you tried to watch a video on YouTube while using an ad blocker, playback would be paused until YouTube was whitelisted or the ad blocker was disabled. However, for months, a few apps could get around ads using YouTube&apos;s API. </p><p>That appears to be over, as YouTube says it is "strengthening our enforcement on third-party apps that violate YouTube&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://developers.google.com/youtube/terms/api-services-terms-of-service" target="_blank">Terms of Service</a>, specifically ad-blocking apps." A popular app that served as an alternative to watching YouTube ads was AdGuard, and some browsers include ad-blocking functionality as well. YouTube Vanced was another as well, before it shut down in 2022 due to legal reasons. </p><p>While YouTube&apos;s ad blocker crackdown on the web featured a pop-up that clearly instructed users to disable their ad-blocking software, the platform&apos;s approach to third-party apps with ad blockers is more subtle. Users who try to watch a YouTube video on one of these apps might notice buffering problems that prevent playback. Alternatively, the YouTube API might show "the following content is not available on this app" as an error message.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="6pvjASLAuGSMQzSoFxqBqG" name="YouTube-Premium-lifestyle.jpg" alt="YouTube Premium homepage on Android" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6pvjASLAuGSMQzSoFxqBqG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Jay Bonggolto / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>"We want to emphasize that our terms don&apos;t allow third-party apps to turn off ads because that prevents the creator from being rewarded for viewership," YouTube explains, "and Ads on YouTube help support creators and let billions of people around the world use the streaming service."</p><p>YouTube is once again pushing users who want an ad-free experience to subscribe to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/youtube-premium">YouTube Premium</a>. It costs <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-raising-price-of-youtube-premium">$14 per month</a> and, among other things, removes all ads on the platform. YouTube Premium subscribers can watch videos uninterrupted, but a portion of their subscription fee is still shared with creators in the YouTube Partner Program.</p><p>"When we find an app that violates these terms, we will take appropriate action to protect our platform, creators, and viewers," YouTube said. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-blocks-third-party-ad-blockers</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google's quest to take down ad blockers circumventing YouTube ads is now affecting third-party apps.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">JH8Aj3yhaauXSNv2Ai5BLC</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Fm9BFBYs92bPuYnziBKnnk.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 04:35:49 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Fm9BFBYs92bPuYnziBKnnk.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The YouTube app listing on the Google Play Store, running on a Google Pixel 8 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The YouTube app listing on the Google Play Store, running on a Google Pixel 8 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Telegram launches a new editor to create custom stickers ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Telegram launches a Sticker Editor — a new way to create personal stickers</li><li>The created stickers can be combined into a sticker set, which can be shared with other users.</li><li>Telegram also has plans to bring 16 new features to the platform later this month. </li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Telegram is introducing a new ability to the popular messaging platform that lets anyone quickly create stickers and entire sticker sets — thanks to a new editor.</p><p>In the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://telegram.org/blog/sticker-maker">announcement blog post</a>, Telegram explains how the feature works and shows it in action. Users easily choose any photo from their device&apos;s gallery and "add text, drawings — or countless animated stickers, emojis and GIFs that exist on the platform." For instance, a simple cat photo can be turned into visual art without much user effort.</p>
<div class="looped-video"><video class="lazyload-in-view lazyloading" data-src="https://telegram.org/file/400780400575/1/RiTI5hhBHxs.5364408.mp4/fc4535d49ea0d8c0ec" autoplay loop muted playsinline src="https://telegram.org/file/400780400575/1/RiTI5hhBHxs.5364408.mp4/fc4535d49ea0d8c0ec"></video></div>
<p>Users can further pick a photo, and with a single tap, they can "cut out objects and remove background." They can also manually erase parts in a photo or restore them and even add an outline to get the "classic sticker look," notes Telegram.</p><p>Users can head over to the app&apos;s keyboard, open the stickers pane, and click the "+" button, which eventually opens up the new sticker tool. Once a sticker is created, they can send it or add all similar stickers to a separate sticker set, which can be pulled up whenever required, just like emojis.</p><p>The feature works similarly to the WhatsApp photo editor, allowing users to generate stickers from their device&apos;s albums. Google Messages has a similar feature called <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-photomoji-google-messages">Photomoji</a> that lets users react to messages using photos or send them as stickers.</p><p>The sticker set can be created, and Telegram will utilize the app&apos;s AI to suggest different emoji that correspond to the image, which can then be selected in a chat the next time you use a particular emoji.</p>
<div class="looped-video"><video class="lazyload-in-view lazyloading" data-src="https://telegram.org/file/400780400593/8/DvM7H4axK64.4832881.mp4/9f58afe487f6d2f42f" autoplay loop muted playsinline src="https://telegram.org/file/400780400593/8/DvM7H4axK64.4832881.mp4/9f58afe487f6d2f42f"></video></div>
<p>"On Telegram, emojis act as shortcuts for stickers. When you type an emoji in a chat, Telegram automatically offers matching stickers you can send."</p><p>Telegram is one of the most <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-messaging-apps">popular messaging platforms</a> and has featured stickers for a little less than a decade now. However, this new ability to create your versions is a refreshing change to add more personality to conversations. Users can combine the existing and new ones into a single pack under themed collections.</p>
<div class="looped-video"><video class="lazyload-in-view lazyloading" data-src="https://telegram.org/file/400780400204/3/f5g3L4wA-as.3545233.mp4/d9349564763781c847" autoplay loop muted playsinline src="https://telegram.org/file/400780400204/3/f5g3L4wA-as.3545233.mp4/d9349564763781c847"></video></div>
<p>Moreover, once a user creates stickers and puts them in a sticker set, they can further share them with other users through a "<em>t.me</em>" link, which lets other Telegram users add them to their accounts. The new update also adds "neat link previews for all sticker and emoji sets."</p><p>In addition to stickers, Telegram says it further has plans to announce at least 16 new features to the messaging platform later this month.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/telegram-introduces-sticker-creator-tool</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ With the new editor tool, users can create stickers from their device's albums without much effort. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">MdSfz6LUnRv5vQUvqojSEc</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/eMmANDLJ85Pwu59t2PeX7f.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 04:18:39 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/eMmANDLJ85Pwu59t2PeX7f.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Telegram]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Telegram Sticker editor]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Telegram Sticker editor]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ OnePlus runs into a setback in its biggest market ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-32">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>OnePlus phones will not be sold at 4,500 retail chains across six states in the southern and western parts of India.</li><li>The retailers association noted encountering 'significant obstacles' with OnePlus, including delays in processing warranties, and slender profit margins.</li><li>The sales ban will go live on May 1.</li></ul>
<p>OnePlus has always counted India as its biggest market; at one point in its ten-year journey, the manufacturer noted that a full 50% of its global sales came from the country. And that&apos;s particularly true in 2024 considering the manufacturer sells a lot of budget models under the Nord series — including the latest <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-nord-ce4-review">Nord CE4</a> — which sell incredibly well in India.</p><p>But OnePlus&apos;s momentum may come tumbling down in a key part of the country. According to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/technology/mobile-retail-chains-to-discontinue-sale-of-oneplus-devices-from-may-1-due-to-unresolved-issues-12616181.html"><em>Money Control</em></a>, select Indian retailers in the southern and western regions are set to enforce a sales ban on OnePlus in the coming weeks, following issues with profit margins, delays with warranty processing, and needless bundling of products.</p><p>If the ban goes through, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-oneplus-phones">best OnePlus phones</a>, tablets, and accessories will be taken off shelves of over 4,500 retail outlets in six states: Andhra Pradesh, Telangana, Tamil Nadu, Karnataka, Maharashtra, and Gujarat. These aren&apos;t small retailers either; the likes of Poorvika, Sangeetha, Big C, and Pooja will no longer carry OnePlus from May 1.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="idULYP7YsgEfrRmJhvUaGK" name="oneplus-12-31.jpg" alt="OnePlus 12 next to OnePlus 9, OnePlus 10, and OnePlus 11" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/idULYP7YsgEfrRmJhvUaGK.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The South Indian Organised Retailers Association is a body that oversees issues facing major retail chains in the south, and its president, Sridhar TS, sent a letter to OnePlus India informing the company of its decision:</p><p>"Throughout the past year, we have encountered significant obstacles associated with selling OnePlus products, which remain unresolved. As esteemed partners, we had hoped for a more fruitful collaboration with OnePlus. Regrettably, the ongoing issues have left us with no alternative but to discontinue the sale of your products in our stores. ORA painfully wishes to inform our collective decision to halt the retail of OnePlus products in our establishments from 1st May, 2024."</p><p>These grievances include delays with warranty and service claims, along with slim profit margins, and bundling of accessories with products: "We have experienced instances where we are compelled to bundle products or services with OnePlus devices, limiting our flexibility and hindering our ability to cater to diverse customer needs. Consequently, this has resulted in stagnant inventory and loss of sales. Despite our persistent efforts to address these concerns with your company, little progress or resolution has been achieved. Promises made have not been fulfilled, leaving us with no recourse but to take this drastic measure."</p><p>Obviously, the move affects the company&apos;s ability to make its products available to mainstream consumers, but the impact may not be severe. While OnePlus sells its phones and accessories at offline stores these days, a sizeable majority of the company&apos;s sales are still via online channels — like its own website, and Amazon India — and those are unaffected.</p><p>There&apos;s also the fact that retailers are unable to match the enticing offers that are exclusive to online sales, and this has been a point of contention for nearly a decade. I remember retailers blocking sales of Xiaomi products back when the manufacturer was starting out in India, so this particular tactic isn&apos;t new.</p><p>OnePlus, for its part, says that it "values all the support" it has garnished from its retail partners over the last seven years, and that it is working with the retailers to address highlighted issues. </p><p>In a statement to Android Central, OnePlus said: "At present, we are working with our partners to address the areas highlighted, ensuring our continued commitment to a strong relationship going forward."</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-sales-ban-india-2024</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Over 4,500 retail outlets in key parts of India will discontinue sales of OnePlus phones, tablets, and accessories from May 1.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">cKHRTeHntq4S6QcPYpwXkR</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/V2UZcanyFQqZVSzA2Rz48K.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 04:03:12 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/V2UZcanyFQqZVSzA2Rz48K.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus 12 camera island next to OnePlus 11]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus 12 camera island next to OnePlus 11]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Epic wants a judge to open up the Google Play Store for good ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-37">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>After suing Google years ago for its alleged monopolistic practices regarding Android and the Google Play Store, Epic won in a surprise jury verdict last year.</li><li>As part of the decision, Epic has been tasked with submitting a proposed injunction to the court for consideration. In simpler terms, the court wants to know what changes Epic wants to see on the Google Play Store and Android.</li><li>The court filing comes a few weeks after Epic announced that it will bring the Epic Games Store to iOS and Android as an alternative app marketplace "later this year."</li></ul>
<hr>
<p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/google-loses-antitrust-court-battle-against-epic">Epic won an antitrust case against Google</a> last year concerning the company&apos;s practices managing the Google Play Store and Android. But even when the verdict was reached, we weren&apos;t quite sure what Epic had won. Now, we know exactly what Epic wants an open Google Play Store to look like, as the company laid out its wishes in a proposed injunction and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.epicgames.com/site/en-US/news/epics-remedy-following-google-case-jury-verdict" target="_blank">press release</a>.</p><p>Put simply, Epic wants complete parity between the experience of downloading apps and making payments on the Google Play Store, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/epic-games-store-arriving-on-android-later-this-year">third-party app stores</a>, or via sideloading. There are a lot of specifics related to that principle outlined in the proposed injunction, which is 16 pages long. Asking the company to remove screens warning users about the consequences of downloading apps from unknown sources and eliminating deals with carriers and OEMs that elevate the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-play">Google Play Store&apos;s</a> standing are just a few examples. </p><p>Epic is also asking for an open in-app purchase market, where developers can link to wherever they choose for digital payments. It called out Google&apos;s User Choice Billing, which is a "sham compliance program," according to Epic. </p><p>Basically, Epic doesn&apos;t want Google to be able to offer anything that other competing app marketplaces can&apos;t. That includes exclusive apps, integration with Android APIs, and requiring use of the Google Play Store to connect with other Google products and services. Of course, Epic also wants to specifically bar Google from retaliating at developers for going around the Google Play Store. </p>
<p>However, this proposed injunction is far from being enacted. Google has a chance to respond with a filing of its own by May 2, and a May 23 hearing will see the two sides explain their position with their own economic experts. The judge&apos;s final decision will likely look different than what Epic is currently asking for. Amidst all this, Google says that it still plans to appeal the original verdict. </p><p>"Epic&apos;s filing to the US Federal Court shows again that it simply wants the benefits of Google Play without having to pay for it," a Google spokesperson told Android Central. "We&apos;ll continue to challenge the verdict, as Android is an open mobile platform that faces fierce competition from the Apple App Store, as well as app stores on Android devices, PCs and gaming consoles."</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/epic-wants-google-play-store-open</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ After a surprise victory in Epic v. Google last year, Epic Games' proposed injunction asks the presiding judge to change a few big things about how the Google Play Store operates.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Y6ocX5CjVqi8TA5N94whzN</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AhaX4oiMTLreQSzTcsAWn7.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 03:56:54 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AhaX4oiMTLreQSzTcsAWn7.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Play Store home page on Android and Chrome OS]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Play Store home page on Android and Chrome OS]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>