<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 17:29:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google gifts Pixels a December feature drop with Gemini and dual-screen updates ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google detailed the rollout of its major Pixel December feature drop.</li><li>Its AI Gemini is picking up several updates like a Spotify extension, calling/texting abilities, and "Saved info with Gemini."</li><li>The Pixel 9 series receives help from Gemini Nano for screened calls, updates to Pixel Screenshots, and the Fold series grabs a "Dual-Screen" update.</li><li>These updates are hitting Pixel devices today (Dec 5).</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google's latest Pixel feature drop might help stymie the lingering chill of December with loads of new features.</p><p>Today (Dec 5), Google detailed the rollout of its major December 2024 Pixel feature drop that will start hitting devices. Starting the update train are a few updates for Gemini. According to a press release, Google is spreading Gemini across even more of its ecosystem. The AI model's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini-spotify-extension-rollout-detailed">new Spotify extension</a> is rolling out to more Pixels alongside the AI's ability to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/gemini-on-lock-screen-call-messages--rollout">call or text your contacts</a>, per your instruction.</p><p>The company highlights the added ability for Gemini to alter your timers and alarms, and even open your camera app. These updates are hitting Pixel 6 devices and newer.</p><p>Elsewhere, Google rolls out "saved info with Gemini." This feature is said to let users instruct Gemini to remember specific details about them or their preferences. The idea is to help users gain more "relevant and helpful" responses from the AI, as they won't have to repeat the details. Google states this is rolling out to all Android phones and Gemini on desktop.</p><p>Gemini Live picks up support for even more languages in the places where it's available.</p>
<h2 id="pixel-9-series-updates-2">Pixel 9 series updates</h2>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:325px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:184.62%;"><img id="KMZPN4fpP2X3g2zHxK8ck8" name="google-pixel-9-gemini-nano-call-screen-example" alt="The Call Screen on the Pixel 9 series leverages Gemini Nano for added assistance like suggested replies." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KMZPN4fpP2X3g2zHxK8ck8.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="325" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:325px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:184.62%;"><img id="8QZSAd5MZL9VQDvXSKvyAC" name="google-pixel-screenshots-app-gboard-example" alt="Pixel Screenshots is now usable in Google Wallet and snapshots can be saved from Circle to Search." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8QZSAd5MZL9VQDvXSKvyAC.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="325" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Google adds that its phones will soon grab specific updates, beginning with the Pixel 9 series' new Call Screen. The post states Gemini Nano is entering to suggest "easy-to-tap" replies on the call screen. Of course, this will affect those screening a call as you can use the AI as a buffer between you and them or to reply to a delivery's request.</p><p>What's more, Google says users can now peek at the conversation between a caller and the AI on their device during "automatic call screening."</p><p>The Gemini Nano-powered update is rolling out for the entire Pixel 9 series (including <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-fold-hands-on">the 9 Pro Fold</a>) in the U.S. while the automatic call screening hits Pixel 6 and newer phones.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-use-the-pixel-screenshots-app-on-the-google-pixel-9">Pixel Screenshots app</a> is receiving the December gift of Circle to Search compatibility. Google states users circling or highlighting an object for Search can now save a snapshot of that to its Screenshots app. Moreover, the app will now automatically organize your screenshots based on information like calendar dates and more.</p><p>This is rolling out to the Pixel 9 series for English language users.</p><p>Updates for screenshots continue as Google details its new functionality with the Wallet app. The Pixel 9 series users can soon take screenshots of cards or tickets can add them into Google Wallet. Support includes driver's licenses, boarding passes, "and more." Additionally, Gboard will display recommendations like movies, music, and more based on your screenshots.</p><p>These suggestions will appear in "relevant" apps. However, Google states that users can turn this function off (or on) under the "Show suggestions from your screenshots in other apps" option in the Screenshots app settings.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:325px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:184.62%;"><img id="fpdrhaYwCuFqafbnVjene4" name="google-pixel-recorder-app-clear-voice-example" alt="The Recorder app picks up "Clear Voice" to reduce background noises." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fpdrhaYwCuFqafbnVjene4.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="325" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Other updates for the Pixel 9 series includes the ability to "capture and share" Ultra HDR photos on Instagram. This is rolling out to Pixel 9 devices globally.</p><p>Pixel Studio stickers have expanded to be useable in Gboard. Also, the Pixel Recorder app is picking up a "clear voice" feature. Clear Voice is said to "reduce noise and distractions automatically." Pixel 9 series users must enable this feature in the app's settings.</p><p>Google's foldables are receiving a few updates such as "Dual Screen in Portrait mode." Available on the original Fold and the 9 Pro Fold, users on both sides of the camera can see what a photo will look like before it's snapped. Also, it might be hard to get your little one to look at the camera, but that's where "Made you look" comes into play.</p><p>Google is bringing this feature to the first Pixel Fold, meaning parents can place a cute and funny animation on their phone to set up the perfect photo. On the other hand, the Pixel 9 Pro Fold is grabbing a new character: Joy, from Disney's Inside Out.</p>
<h2 id="more-pixel-joy-2">More Pixel joy</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:342px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:175.44%;"><img id="AfcjWBdaEcSbvJyS5WNGFh" name="google-pixel-expressive-captions-example" alt="Google rolls out "Expressive Captions" to the Pixel 6 and newer series." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AfcjWBdaEcSbvJyS5WNGFh.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="342" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>"Expressive captions" is a feature that Pixels ranging from the 6 series to the latest 9 series can use. Google states its AI will "automatically capture the intensity and emotion" of a person speaking on a live stream or phone call. The AI will suggest what your reaction could be, like gasping at a shocking moment or cheering for a score.</p><p>These captions are also "compatible with other Android devices."</p><p>Snapchat is receiving a dedicated Photo Picker for users. Google states this should help users find what they're looking for in their folders, favorites, and images stored in the Cloud.</p><p>The company detailed a security feature entering beta called "Identity Check." Google states that when users enter a "new location," their Pixel 6 or newer device will ask for facial recognition or your fingerprint before they can alter any "sensitive information."</p><p>Smaller updates include "Simple View," which produces a larger system-wide font and increases your Pixel's touch sensitivity. Quick Share is faster and "Now Playing" will show the album art when viewing its history.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="ab5f818f-56c5-4fa9-a47c-8e3e53624bfe">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:131.12%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8traMGgrwAvoqr8vUr6kdH.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL render"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 Pro XL</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>The Pixel 9 Pro XL is the larger of the two Pro models for Google's 2024 flagship series. The device features a 6.8-inch display with 120Hz refresh rate and a larger 5,060mAh battery.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-december-2024-feature-drop-announced</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google detailed its major December 2024 Pixel feature drop. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">AyVPvQAneSagMQijUPYrNP</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HLjRCX2zMkWQ4UnoGFHREQ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HLjRCX2zMkWQ4UnoGFHREQ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Pixel 9 Pro XL back view against colorful background]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Pixel 9 Pro XL back view against colorful background]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google's December feature drop for Pixel Watch lets you peek at Nest cameras from your wrist ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google today announced the December 2024 Pixel Feature Drop, and the Pixel Watch is getting a few key upgrades.</li><li>Notably, the Pixel Watch 2 and Pixel Watch 3 can now be used to peek into Nest doorbells and cameras with Live View.</li><li>Loss of Pulse detection and Cardio/Target Load are coming to more devices and region for select Pixel Watch and Fitbit models.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>If you own a Pixel Watch or Fitbit wearable, the holiday season's gifts just came early. Google today announced the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-december-2024-feature-drop-announced">December 2024 Pixel Feature Drop</a>, which includes a few key upgrades for the company's wearables. Notably, Pixel Watch users in the Google smart home ecosystem are gaining a convenient Live View feature that will let them peek at their Nest cameras.</p><p>Android and Nest cameras are highly integrated, and that means you can view live previews of smart doorbells and cameras from your <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">flagship Android phone</a>. Now, similar functionality is coming to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-2-review">Pixel Watch 2</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-3-review">Pixel Watch 3</a>. When users get a notification from a Nest Cam or Nest Doorbell, they can now see a live view from their wrist. Additionally, Pixel Watch wearers can talk with the person at their door directly in the Live View.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4480px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="CtiHisF9tgXRcLfFW4g52L" name="Live-View-Pixel-Watch" alt="Live View on the Pixel Watch 2 and 3." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CtiHisF9tgXRcLfFW4g52L.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4480" height="2520" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central / Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>This functionality should make it easier to catch who's out your door before they walk away. If your hands are full, viewing the notification and opening up your Android phone can take too much time — that's where the Pixel Watch comes in handy with Live View. However, it's unfortunate that the original Pixel Watch does not support this new feature.</p><p>Live View is the only new feature coming to Google wearables as part of this month's feature drop. With that being said, a few crucial health and fitness tools are coming to more devices and regions. For example, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/pixel-watch-3-loss-of-pulse-detection-explained">Loss of Pulse detection</a> — which can detect a cardiac event, such as a heart attack — is now available for the first time on Pixel Watch 3 in Germany and Portugal.</p><p>Cardio Load and Target Load, initially launched as Pixel Watch 3 exclusives, are now coming to most Google wearables. The feature is now available for Pixel Watch 1, Pixel Watch 2, Pixel Watch 3, Sense, Sense 2, Versa 2, Versa 3, Versa 4, Charge 5, Charge 6, Inspire 2, Inspire 3, and Luxe. Google says these tools will "help you know your body better and balance activity with recovery so you can optimize your workouts and rest to prevent overtraining."</p><p>While the December 2024 Pixel Feature Drop only brought one new feature, it's still a significant update. Fitbit and Pixel Watch owners will appreciate getting two former Pixel Watch 3 exclusives, and Live View will be a life-changer for people deep into the Google ecosystem.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/googles-december-feature-drop-for-pixel-watch-lets-you-peek-at-nest-cameras-from-your-wrist</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Live View is coming to Pixel Watch, and Loss of Pulse detection and Cardio/Target Load are coming to more devices and regions. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">ppLuFcgCyAABknVW954reC</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/V4LxpJjZ88vsDoXPQrbNrg.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/V4LxpJjZ88vsDoXPQrbNrg.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A close up of an info-packed watch face on the Google Pixel Watch 3, held above a pond]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A close up of an info-packed watch face on the Google Pixel Watch 3, held above a pond]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google spruces up Android with 6 new features improving Gemini, accessibility, and sharing ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google is adding a few new features to Android starting today, including Expressive Captions and spoken image descriptions, which will improve accessibility.</li><li>Sharing is also getting a boost, with new sticker combos and keyboard, plus QR code sharing.</li><li>Finally, document scans will now be in higher quality with auto enhancements in Google Drive, and new Gemini Extensions are here.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google is adding a slew of new features to Android starting today, it announced in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.google/products/android/new-android-features-december-2024" target="_blank">blog post</a>. The changes range from accessibility features designed to make Android better for people with hearing impairments to quality-of-life improvements to Gemini and sharing. These new features will be available on various Android devices, meanwhile, the improvements coincide with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-december-2024-feature-drop-announced">December 2024 Pixel Feature Drop</a>, which also released today.</p><p>Artificial intelligence is a core part of many of Google's announcements for Android, including Expressive Captions. With Expressive Captions, the company hopes to make the experience of reading audio captions more immersive. The feature uses things like uppercase and lowercase text, as well as phonetic transcriptions, to convey key aspects of sound. The idea is to help people enjoy the emotion and intensity of audio content through captions.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2096px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.39%;"><img id="KWCPKtFcpSyumoehMCWYpG" name="1. Expressive Captions ON_OFF-4 2-min" alt="Expressive Captions in Android." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KWCPKtFcpSyumoehMCWYpG.gif" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2096" height="1182" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Expressive Captions are coming to Android system-wide, meaning that you can use them in any app of your choice.</p><p>In a similar move, Google is improving Gemini's image description capabilities. Image Q&A in Lookout lets users get written description of images, and it now uses the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini 1.5 Pro model</a> for more helpful descriptions, according to Google. More importantly, these descriptions can be spoken aloud with the help of Gemini, and supports follow-up questions.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4480px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="rEocALNeyzY82dMGuNXLc6" name="Android-December-2024-updates-1" alt="Screenshots of new features coming to Android 15." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rEocALNeyzY82dMGuNXLc6.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4480" height="2520" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central / Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google also wants to make it easier to communicate with others using emoji on Android, specifically in situations when the default emoji options just don't cut it. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/emoji-kitchen-web-google-search">Emoji Kitchen</a> will let you make a new emoji from a combination of two default ones, like the pizza and heart emojis in the sample screen shot above. This is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-gboard-emoji-mashups-and-how-create-your-own">available in Gboard</a>, where there's also a new <strong>Clearflow</strong> glide typing keyboard option.</p><p>While we're on the topic of sharing, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-quick-share-upgraded-arm-windows-rollout">Quick Share</a> is making it simpler to share photos, files, and more with people who aren't in your context. After the latest update, you can now create a QR code to Quick Share content with others. If that content happens to be a document scanned in Drive, you're in luck, because Google is now auto-enhancing the quality of these scans.</p><p>Finally, the company is officially announcing new Gemini Extensions for Spotify and Home. Some of these capabilities <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini-spotify-extension-rollout-detailed">already began to roll out last month</a>, but will presumably be available more widely now. These features are all rolling out starting today, so you can start trying them immediately.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-spruces-up-android-with-6-new-features-improving-gemini-accessibility-and-sharing</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Expressive Captions are coming to Android to help you feel the emotion and expression of sound through text. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">f5W8zDqN5bqKx5UC3kTioC</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2aMJ5AjP9QkTWyLEboKPwb.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2aMJ5AjP9QkTWyLEboKPwb.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The expressive captions coming to Android 15.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The expressive captions coming to Android 15.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ One of our favorite running watch brands is adding Strava Live Segments ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>COROS has added Strava Live Segments to the PACE 3/ Pro, APEX 2/ 2 Pro, VERTIX 2/ 2S, and DURA.</li><li>30 starred segments from your Strava Premium account will sync to your watch or bike computer.</li><li>You can choose whether to race yourself, the fastest athlete, or people near your time.</li><li>During a segment, your COROS watch shows your progress relative to your rival or goal time.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Strava Live Segments are a great way to spice up training runs by challenging you to beat past times or race people you've never met. COROS, one of our favorite running watch brands, is incorporating this feature into all its latest watches, catching up to rivals like Garmin and Polar.</p><p>COROS' <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://coros.com/stravalivesegments">Strava feature page</a> runs through how to enable these Live Segments. You need a Strava Premium membership and any of the most recent PACE, APEX, and VERTIX watches (or the DURA bike computer). Your first 30 starred segments on Strava will automatically sync to the COROS app, sharing the list with your device.</p><p>Once enabled, your COROS watch will alert you and signal when you're getting close to a segment's starting point. When the segment starts, you'll see a graphic showing how your current GPS position compares to your target time, with data fields for the time ahead/behind your goal time and distance remaining to the end of the segment.</p><p>Plus, in case you're not sure of the segment's path, there'll be a second map view with an orange line to guide you.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="s7BKqQqGqWsGQCiskDtNpH" name="coros-strava-live-segments" alt="COROS' official renders showing its new Strava Live Segments tool: (left) starred live segments in the COROS mobile app; (center): A Select Competitor view on a COROS watch; (right) the Strava Live Segment view showing the runners current position relative to the target pace." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/s7BKqQqGqWsGQCiskDtNpH.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1500" height="844" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: COROS)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>As for what time you'll be racing against, it'll default to your "Carrot" time, aka the segment pace of the person directly above you on the segment leaderboard. But you can change it to be your "Wolf" — the person directly below you — your segment PR time, or the King/ Queen of the Mountain with the best leaderboard time.</p><p>Once you finish the segment, a pop-up notification will show your time and progress against your rival; you'll also have the option to see this data in the post-run summary.</p><p>Garmin first started supporting Strava Live Segments in 2015 with its Edge 520 bike computer, as well as many of its high-end Fenixes and Forerunners going back years — most recently the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-fenix-8-review">Fenix 8</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-forerunner-965-review">Forerunner 965</a>. But it's always been reserved as a "premium" feature, while COROS is making it available on budget models like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/coros-pace-3-review">PACE 3</a>.</p><p>COROS has made a lot of progress catching up to rivals like Garmin on software features in recent months. Its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/coros-september-update-adds-gear-tracking-sleep-analysis-dura-fixes">September 2024 update</a> added familiar features like gear tracking and nap detection, while other 2024 updates included daily stress, safety alerts, a wellness check, and a virtual pacer.</p><p>Equally important, COROS launched the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/coros-pace-pro-gps-and-hr-accuracy-test">PACE Pro</a>, its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/coros-announces-pace-pro-first-amoled-running-watch">first AMOLED running watch</a> after years of MIP watches. Its rivals had begun to switch en masse to AMOLED over the last couple of years, making this switch long overdue. I suspect these Strava Live Segments will look especially good on the PACE Pro, and I'm excited to test it for myself.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="481422a9-ad20-48e6-b883-f3b67d2d3d00">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dXddejbHgnziEVGQrkgdum.jpg' alt="The COROS Pace Pro"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">COROS PACE Pro</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Pace yourself against your PRs</strong></em></p><p>The PACE Pro has a 20-day battery life, accurate dual-band GPS, and its full COROS training suite paired with a bright 1.3-inch AMOLED display. It has a new twice-as-fast CPU and 3X the RAM of the PACE 3, so it's built to handle Strava Live Segments and other future training features years down the line. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/one-of-our-favorite-running-watch-brands-is-adding-strava-live-segments</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Strava Live Segments let you check if you're on pace to beat your PR or neighborhood rivals on a particular stretch, and this brand is finally getting them. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">6AjQDSRavmFzaPWkGKfvqP</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uuJ9kJsekN5V5ufV2bbCSL.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uuJ9kJsekN5V5ufV2bbCSL.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A 5-mile run summary on the COROS PACE Pro AMOLED display]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A 5-mile run summary on the COROS PACE Pro AMOLED display]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Oura's Symptom Radar is an early warning system for signs of sickness ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Oura highlighted its new Symptom Radar, which will encourage you to take rest days based on your biometric changes.</li><li>Symptom Radar features three levels of potential signs of strain with the highest being "Major Risk," meaning users should take a rest day.</li><li>Oura states this feature could help users get ahead of potential signs of sickness and take time to rest their bodies.</li><li>This is rolling out to Oura Ring 4 and Gen 3 members in its app on December 9.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Oura is detailing a new feature for two of its smart rings that could help you get ahead of those sick days.</p><p>The company highlighted the coming arrival of "Symptom Radar" for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oura-ring-4-review">Oura Ring 4</a> and Gen 3 members. The post states that the feature works by monitoring "changes in your data." According to Oura, the data it sifts through <em>could </em>indicate that something is "straining" your body, like sickness. Wearing your Oura ring will give the app the information it needs to function, such as your skin temperature, average temperature "trends," respiratory rate, resting heart rate, heart rate variability, and inactive time.</p><p>The post states users will find their Symptom Radar in the Oura app by navigating to the Today tab. Tapping its highlight card will produce its full page. Moreover, the radar can be accessed more regularly through the hamburger menu in the top left of the Today tab.</p><p>Symptom Radar displays signs of strain in three levels, with the first being "No Signs." Oura says this means that your ring has not detected an "obvious sign" in your biometrics that points toward bodily stress. "Minor Signs" means that there is something there or "small signs" that could indicate approaching sickness.</p><p>Lastly, "Major Signs" means that in your biometrics, your ring has detected "stronger signs" that something is working against your body. Oura says that "Biometrics under strain" section will explain which parts of your data show the most signs of stress. If there is a significant change in your trends, this could indicate sickness/stress.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:287px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:209.06%;"><img id="SA8pkcbvQMe2YLUk3aqHU7" name="oura-ring-symptom-radar-sign-ratings" alt="Oura's Symptom Radar delivers three levels of risk level for potential sickness/stress." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SA8pkcbvQMe2YLUk3aqHU7.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="287" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Oura)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:289px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:207.61%;"><img id="z7yEJhrKxrsjrJwBiouP3A" name="oura-ring-symptom-radar-highlight-card" alt="Oura's Symptom Radar will have a spotlight card on the Today tab." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/z7yEJhrKxrsjrJwBiouP3A.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="289" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Oura)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Oura adds that it looks at multiple pieces of data to see if there's a "deviation in combination" of everything it's collected. If there are major signs or, perhaps, minimal ones, Oura will suggest taking a rest day.</p><p>The press release states that users enabling Rest Mode will see their activity scores paused alongside any goals and activity contributors. However, Symptom Radar will continue to work in the background whilst Rest Mode is active.</p><p>Oura offered a few advisories, stating Symptom Radar may not work with "pre-existing medical conditions." Additionally, pregnancy may impact "biometric baselines" and affect the accuracy of the feature. Oura adds that this radar can be turned off if you are pregnant. What's more, the company reiterates that its rings are not a "medical device." It seems wise to take what Symptom Radar is telling you and see a medical professional if <em>you </em>feel concerned.</p><p>Oura states Symptom Radar is rolling out to all members with a Ring 4 or Gen 3 on December 9 in the app.</p><p>In a separate post, Oura detailed the long development history of its Symptom Radar. The science and process of it stretches back to March 2020. However, Oura's April launch of its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oura-labs-members-test-experience-announced">Labs experience</a> helped further its progress. During its early testing, the company stated users found it difficult to know if Symptom Radar's information had been updated. As a result, Oura states it provides a historical graph so users can see the different updates the feature has made.</p><p>More importantly, the post says testers reported increased interest in seeing which biometric changes "indicated risk." Oura states users will now see markers for a changed piece of data and "why the risk increased."</p><p>Seeing as the colder months are here, Symptom Radar may help users as we enter flu season.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oura-symptom-radar-early-stress-signs-announced</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Oura announced its new Symptom Radar for the Ring 4 and Gen 3. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">fP84eF4nSAX6WAh7ETKujP</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rGQs7nag3abwkJeuSmT4VD.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rGQs7nag3abwkJeuSmT4VD.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Oura]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Oura introduced its Symptom Radar for the Ring 4 and Gen 3.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Oura introduced its Symptom Radar for the Ring 4 and Gen 3.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung's first One UI 7 beta is available now, public release set for early 2025 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung's upcoming One UI 7 update, based on Android 15, has experienced numerous delays, but a beta is available now.</li><li>The update is expected to debut near or alongside the release of the Samsung Galaxy S25 series in January.</li><li>One UI 7 adds new features like the <strong>Now Bar</strong>, new <strong>camera toggles</strong>, and persistent <strong>Writing Tools</strong>.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Samsung today announced that, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-one-ui-7-beta-pushed-back-again">after numerous delays</a>, the first One UI 7 beta is now available for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24">Samsung Galaxy S24 series</a>. The company says that Samsung Members can apply for access to the One UI 7 beta starting today to gain early access to the Android 15-based update. Otherwise, the upgrade is expected to launch early next year alongside the upcoming <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25">Samsung Galaxy S25 series</a>, as the company confirms One UI 7 will release publicly in the first quarter of 2025.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/extra-one-ui-7-features-samsung-early-post-leak">One UI 7</a> is set to launch with "upcoming Galaxy S series devices," but will arrive on other Galaxy devices as part of a gradual rollout. For now, the Samsung Galaxy S24, Galaxy S24 Plus, and Galaxy S24 Ultra are the only three models known for certain to be eligible for the One UI 7 beta immediately. It's possible that the beta could be expanded to include the Galaxy S24 FE, Galaxy Z Fold 6, and Galaxy Z Flip 6.</p><p>As was expected, Samsung is doubling down on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-galaxy-ai">Galaxy AI</a> with One UI 7. It's specifically trying to compete with Apple Intelligence with more system-wide software tools. For example, Writing Tools — a set of generative AI-based grammar and writing options — are now able to be used anywhere without needing to switch apps.</p><p>Additionally, Samsung touts that One UI 7 will bring "more intuitive interaction and greater personalization," with AI at the heart of it.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="H7pxJnSUSSLBy3dNadjs7M" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-display-lockscreen-03.jpg" alt="The Amber Yellow Samsung Galaxy S24 colorway and its vibrant display" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/H7pxJnSUSSLBy3dNadjs7M.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Samsung also shared a few details about the new features One UI 7 will bring. A <strong>Now Bar</strong> will become a new part of the One UI lock screen, making it possible for users to see important notifications dynamically without needing to open their phone. Additionally, the Camera app in One UI 7 is getting a boost, as the viewfinder now includes new buttons, controls, and modes. In another Apple Intelligence-inspired feature, <strong>Call Transcript</strong> will automatically transcribe recorded calls in 20 supported languages.</p><p>A few security improvements add a <strong>Knox Matrix dashboard</strong> that lets users view their connected devices in one place, <strong>Credential Syncs</strong>, and a new recovery method for data transfers.</p><p>You can apply to gain access to the One UI 7 beta and test these features for yourself by becoming a Samsung Member if you have a Galaxy S24 series device.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsungs-first-one-ui-7-beta-is-available-now-public-release-set-for-early-2025</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ One UI 7 has faced delay after delay, but the beta is finally available — with tons of AI features set to rival Apple Intelligence. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">t73NEqPMz5KXAWMksedRJQ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SduTUL5Je8xoVoFriPCNBh.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SduTUL5Je8xoVoFriPCNBh.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Using Air Commands with the S Pen on the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Using Air Commands with the S Pen on the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ When will my phone get Android 16? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Android 16 is coming sooner than ever before, and the initial preview build is now available on select Pixels. While Google usually releases these builds in Q1, the brand is changing its strategy this time around, and is making the release available earlier. There's a good reason for this: with the debut of the Pixels pushed up, Google wants to have the latest Android version ready before it announces hardware, and as a result, we're getting Android 16 just a month after the stable <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-review">Android 15</a> release. <br><br>That's a good thing, as it means more devices will come with the latest version of Android installed out of the box. While brands do a decent job rolling out the stable Android update to their high-end phones, most mid-range phones take several months to make the switch, and this won't be as big an issue if the update itself is available sooner. While details are scant at the moment, here's what you need to know about when <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16">Android 16</a> might be available on your device.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-google"><span>Google</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="wpYGZEdqh2jnAK5kX8Wq8L" name="google-pixel-9-pro-pixel-9-pro-xl-4.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro and Pixel 9 Pro XL angled view" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wpYGZEdqh2jnAK5kX8Wq8L.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>If you have a Pixel 6 and above, you can <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-install-android-beta">install the Android 16 beta</a> right now. That said, I wouldn't recommend installing the build right now; there are no visible user-facing changes, and most of the under-the-hood tweaks aren't aimed at end users anyway. <br><br>That will change over the coming months as Google starts adding features to Android 16, and when the time comes, I will share additional details on what's new, and whether it makes sense to install Android 16 on your Pixel. Until then though, Android 15 is still the best choice.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-samsung"><span>Samsung</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="SduTUL5Je8xoVoFriPCNBh" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-Ultra-s-pen-air-command.jpg" alt="Using Air Commands with the S Pen on the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SduTUL5Je8xoVoFriPCNBh.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Samsung is yet to introduce its Android 15-based One UI 7, and the focus for the brand is to get that out the door. We should see the One UI 7 beta sometime later this month, but as of now, Samsung hasn't detailed plans around Android 16. With the Galaxy S25 series launching in January, we should know more early next year.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-oppo"><span>OPPO</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="qMypyPS3qjq6ed3kcFTF8b" name="oppo-find-x8-pro-23.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qMypyPS3qjq6ed3kcFTF8b.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>OPPO just introduced the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oppo-find-x8-pro-review">Find X8 Pro</a> and Find X8 in global markets, and both devices run Android 15 out of the box. While there's no details on Android 16 just yet, we should have additional details once the public beta goes live sometime in Q1 2025. <br><br>Although ColorOS 15 just went live, OPPO is internally testing ColorOS 16, and will launch the version alongside Android 16 sometime in Q2 2025. At this point, there's no details on new features coming to the interface.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-vivo"><span>Vivo</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="hyet8kTDnvDvroVXqHRHoQ" name="vivo-x100-ultra-26.jpg" alt="Vivo X100 Ultra review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hyet8kTDnvDvroVXqHRHoQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Vivo's X200 and X200 Pro are going global later this month, and they also run Android 15 out of the box. Similar to ColorOS 15, there's no telling when Vivo will start rolling out Android 16-based Funtouch OS, but with the manufacturer doing a much better job in this area, it shouldn't take too long once the stable build becomes available in Q2 2025.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-oneplus"><span>OnePlus</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="kersukxmGC4L8iY6McykXa" name="oxygenos-15-8.jpg" alt="OnePlus 12 with OxygenOS 15" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kersukxmGC4L8iY6McykXa.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/three-reasons-you-should-wait-for-the-oneplus-13-and-two-reasons-not-to">OnePlus 13</a> is launching globally in January, and it will run OxygenOS 15 based on Android 15. OnePlus is usually good with beta software releases, and it tends to roll out public betas to its devices once they become available. It's a good bet that the OnePlus 13 will get the public beta sometime in Q1 2025, but there's no confirmation about that as yet — I talked to the manufacturer about the same, and will update once I know more.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-honor"><span>Honor</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="RFtqLEdfQwv9Q8aAWximqe" name="honor-magic-6-pro-4.jpg" alt="Honor Magic 6 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RFtqLEdfQwv9Q8aAWximqe.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Honor's had a busy year, and its Magic 7 series is all set to make its global debut in the coming weeks. The phone comes with MagicOS 9.0 based on Android 15. Honor is leaning heavily into AI, and that is continuing with MagicOS 9.0, with the brand partnering with Google to deliver a suite of AI utilities. At this moment, there's no details of when Honor will kickstart its Android 16 beta, but it should be sometime after the initial public build becomes available.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-xiaomi"><span>Xiaomi</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="rVsa5tGkkr9zRBkfVzgVoH" name="xiaomi14-ultra-27.jpg" alt="Xiaomi 14 Ultra review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rVsa5tGkkr9zRBkfVzgVoH.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>As is always the case with Xiaomi, the manufacturer has several devices launching in December and January. The Xiaomi 15 should make its global debut sometime this month, but ahead of that, the Redmi Note 14 is launching in India, and that device is coming with Android 14. <br><br>Xiaomi has been leveraging this strategy over the last three years to get out of delivering long-term software updates, and this is the main reason why I don't recommend Redmi Note devices any longer. If every other brand is able to launch phones with Android 15 out of the box, there's no reason why Xiaomi can't do the same.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-coming-soon"><span>Coming soon</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4480px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="MLCKfeSHeDZWCUwT9QjhHA" name="Android-16-Pixel9PF" alt="The logo for Android 16 on a Pixel 9 Pro Fold." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MLCKfeSHeDZWCUwT9QjhHA.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4480" height="2520" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Brady Snyder / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>There isn't much in the way of information regarding Android 16 at the moment, that will change over the coming weeks. Given the accelerated timeline, it will be interesting to see if the update will make its way to additional devices. If you're on an eligible Pixel, I wouldn't suggest installing Android 16 right now — there's no incentive to do so. Again, that should change once we get user-facing changes, and I'll update this post as soon as new builds go live.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/when-will-my-phone-get-android-16</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The initial preview build of Android 16 is now available, but there's no reason to install it. But with Google rolling out the update sooner than ever before, here's when your phone might get Android 16.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">uzxECcTjVqoqLdkh7fRLMb</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/StDoGZtqBGmdMzhzYsE66Z.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 04:42:48 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/StDoGZtqBGmdMzhzYsE66Z.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Pixel 9 Pro XL next to Pixel 9 Pro, Pixel 8 Pro, Pixel 8a, OnePlus Open, OnePlus 12, and OnePlus 12R]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Pixel 9 Pro XL next to Pixel 9 Pro, Pixel 8 Pro, Pixel 8a, OnePlus Open, OnePlus 12, and OnePlus 12R]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Forget traditional lights! These Nanoleaf Canvas smart LED wall panels are 44% OFF at Amazon right now ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The holiday season is coming up fast, and what better time to upgrade your decorative lighting rig than with this smart lighting deal from Nanoleaf. Just days after Cyber Monday, Amazon has slashed <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Nanoleaf-Canvas-Smarter-Kit/dp/B07LC23SVM/" target="_blank"><strong>44% off the Nanoleaf Canvas Smart Wall Panel Lights</strong></a>, marking $80 off and giving you tons of customization options.</p><p>This starter kit comes with nine panels total, as well as mounting tape that's more than sufficient for adhering them to your wall. If you want to do anything large or elaborate, you'll likely need more than one set, but even just nine panels will be plenty to add a little color to your gaming rig, living room, bedroom, or other space.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="5a979d6c-45d1-4f5b-92c2-dc3677e5f330" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$179.99" data-dimension48="$179.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/Nanoleaf-Canvas-Smarter-Kit/dp/B07LC23SVM/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1248px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:114.26%;"><img id="GWAmSohUiKdzf3yMBumNoE" name="nanoleaf-canvas-wifi-wall-panel-lights.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GWAmSohUiKdzf3yMBumNoE.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1248" height="1426" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Nanoleaf Canvas WiFi Smart RGB Smart Lights:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Nanoleaf-Canvas-Smarter-Kit/dp/B07LC23SVM/" target="_blank" data-dimension112="5a979d6c-45d1-4f5b-92c2-dc3677e5f330" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$179.99" data-dimension48="$179.99" data-dimension25=""><del>$179.99</del> <strong>$99.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p><p>Amazon has cut 44% off the price of the Nanoleaf Canvas starter wall panels set, knocking $80 off the normal purchase price for nine RGB smart wall panel lights to get you started. From their easy installation to the simplicity of creating colorful designs, these wall lights are a great way to take your space up a notch, whether you're decorating the area around your gaming PC or your dining room.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/Nanoleaf-Canvas-Smarter-Kit/dp/B07LC23SVM/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="5a979d6c-45d1-4f5b-92c2-dc3677e5f330" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$179.99" data-dimension48="$179.99" data-dimension25="">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>you're looking for an easy way to make elaborate images, colorful and bright designs, or other simple wall patterns based on squares; you'd prefer lighting that can be easily controlled from a mobile app; you want a lighting setup that's non-traditional and can be customized to your liking.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if:</strong> you prefer more traditional string lights or other lighting fixtures and don't want to spend the extra money on something like this; you don't have a lot of wall space or flat surfaces on which to adhere these; you'd prefer a different shape than a square, like the commonly found triangular or hexagonal wall panels.</p><p>If you're interested in intelligent lighting, Nanoleaf's offerings are definitely up there among the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/best-smart-home-devices">best smart home devices</a> available, giving you customizable colored LED lighting that's super easy to install and even easier to customize. If you don't mind going with the square shape, this discount might be a good chance to pick some up, though it's worth noting that Nanoleaf and other companies do make a wide array of shapes, including triangles, hexagons, straight lines, and even more traditional light bulbs.</p><p>The Nanoleaf Canvas kit comes with nine square wall panels that are easy to combine into the shapes of your choosing, and the mobile app lets users customize colors into over 16 million different RGB options, according to the company. These lights also come with useful features like the Highlight Motion to create a rippling design, or choose from the preset scenes to jump right into a pre-programmed aesthetic.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/forget-traditional-lights-these-nanoleaf-canvas-smart-led-wall-panels-are-44-percent-off-at-amazon-right-now</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Bright, square lighting panels at $80 off. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">aUKR3zv6gfMi5jc3Bg9iXM</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/EoSUEjhmQqa84oE3Rt5TAD.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Smart Home]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ zacharydvisconti@gmail.com (Zachary Visconti) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/EoSUEjhmQqa84oE3Rt5TAD.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nanoleaf]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Nanoleaf Canvas smart lights next to desktop and gaming chair]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Nanoleaf Canvas smart lights next to desktop and gaming chair]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 is STILL 53% off after Cyber Monday — don't tell Amazon ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The Black Friday/Cyber Monday festivities have officially come to a close, but you might be surprised at the number of great smartwatch deals still hanging around. For example, I was shocked to see that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Bluetooth-Smartwatch-Personalized-Advanced/dp/B0C792QRW6"><strong>Amazon is </strong><em><strong>still </strong></em><strong>carving 53% off the Galaxy Watch 6 following the major sale event,</strong></a> a leftover deal that drops the beloved Samsung watch to its lowest price EVER. As of writing, the retailer is claiming to have only 20 of these watches left in stock, so I would act fast if you're interested. </p>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/"><em><strong>Samsung's Cyber Week sale is LIVE — see the official list of deals</strong></em></a></li></ul>
<p>Despite being a last-gen wearable, the Galaxy Watch 6 continues to impress as one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch">best Android watches</a> around, thanks to its sophisticated blend of sleek design choices, snappy Exynos performance, and loads of RAM. It even has a lot of the same hardware and display tech as the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-7-review">Galaxy Watch 7</a>, Samsung's latest smartwatch.</p><p>If we were talking about full price here, I'd say go with the newer model — but pair the Galaxy Watch 6 with a $139.99 price tag? That's an amazing deal, just in time for the holidays.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="bbd6d024-87c1-4053-8e7f-27613af32eb9" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 40mm (BT): $299.99" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 40mm (BT): $299.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Bluetooth-Smartwatch-Personalized-Advanced/dp/B0C792QRW6" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="ZFk8tX7bD9dZBwf8oaBae8" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Watch-6-square-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZFk8tX7bD9dZBwf8oaBae8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="800" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 40mm (BT): </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Bluetooth-Smartwatch-Personalized-Advanced/dp/B0C792QRW6" data-dimension112="bbd6d024-87c1-4053-8e7f-27613af32eb9" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 40mm (BT): $299.99" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 40mm (BT): $299.99" data-dimension25=""><del>$299.99</del><strong> $139.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p><p>Amazon has extended a Cyber Monday deal that carves an incredible 53% off the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-6-review">Samsung Galaxy Watch 6</a>, one of the best smartwatches that the OEM has ever produced. This discount is only available for the Black variety of the watch. </p><p>👀 <strong>Did this deal sell out? Here's the next best thing: </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/watches/galaxy-watch6/buy/galaxy-watch6-40mm-gold-bt-sm-r930nzeaxaa/"><strong>get 50% off the Galaxy Watch 6 at Samsung during Cyber Week</strong></a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Bluetooth-Smartwatch-Personalized-Advanced/dp/B0C792QRW6" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="bbd6d024-87c1-4053-8e7f-27613af32eb9" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 40mm (BT): $299.99" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 40mm (BT): $299.99" data-dimension25="">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>Full disclosure: this deal is being slightly overshadowed by another Amazon discount that's carving <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D3216K2G"><strong>37% off the Galaxy Watch FE</strong></a>, but don't be fooled: that watch may be newer, but the Galaxy Watch 6 surpasses that Fan Edition watch in just about every way imaginable. </p><p>The last-gen watch has a better display, faster hardware, and more comprehensive sleep tracking technology, and the only way I'd choose the FE over it is if getting that extra year of software support is particularly important to you. Check out our <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-fe-vs-galaxy-watch-6">Galaxy Watch 6 vs. Galaxy Watch FE</a> guide if you're still unsure, but otherwise, the answer is clear. </p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/the-samsung-galaxy-watch-6-is-still-53-percent-off-after-cyber-monday-dont-tell-amazon</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Amazon is still carving 53% off the Galaxy Watch 6 following Cyber Monday. How long will it last? ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">deeX7FjbeeRqzq2TVt6aYR</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ng7EwTzTP7RFHNdYehnDVE.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 21:42:52 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ng7EwTzTP7RFHNdYehnDVE.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Watch 6]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Watch 6]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Pixel owners can now check their device temperature with the latest app update ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-32">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google Pixel Troubleshooting update gets new Device Temperature check feature.</li><li>It allows Pixel 6, Pixel 7, Pixel 8, and Pixel 9 users to check their device temperatures whenever their devices seem warm to touch.</li><li>The temperature check feature involves relevant color schemes to accurately represent the device's condition.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Some Pixel phones might have a nifty new feature that lets users identify how hot their devices are running directly from their handsets' battery settings.</p><p>Google has apparently released a Pixel Troubleshooting app update for its devices, ranging from Pixel 6 to the latest <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-series-hands-on">Pixel 9 series</a>, notes <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/12/02/pixel-9-temperature-troubleshooting/">9to5Google</a>. The latest update brings a new "Device temperature" feature, which can be seen in the Battery section of the device Settings.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:269px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:223.05%;"><img id="mXRQoZnPyFJskUdLNWjYgi" name="Pixel-9-device-temperature-feature-1" alt="Pixel Device temperature feature" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mXRQoZnPyFJskUdLNWjYgi.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="269" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: 9to5Google)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:269px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:223.05%;"><img id="3Si4Jt7ToqjdRQJVZgKMhi" name="Pixel-9-device-temperature-feature" alt="Pixel Device temperature feature" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3Si4Jt7ToqjdRQJVZgKMhi.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="269" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: 9to5Google)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>It sits under the battery diagnostics' "Phone is very warm" section, which earlier showcased settings that keep the device battery optimized. Another way to access the new page is to directly search for "Device temperature" through the Settings app.</p><p>Under the Device temperature, users can now find four relevant colors, evidently dubbed Cold, Normal, Warm, and Elevated, indicating the current temperature state of the device.</p>
<p>The new page further indicates that the projected device temperature is according to various internal sensors that the aforementioned Pixel phones already ship with. 9to5 further notes that users can also witness other tips like "To cool down your phone, provide airflow to your phone if possible" and "Use only cases or covers made for your specific phone," among others.</p><p>The live device temperature is being rolled out via the Pixel Troubleshooting app bearing the <strong>1.0.693922709</strong> version. Pixel phones include the Pixel 6, Pixel 7, Pixel 8, and the Pixel 9 series. It has not yet been rolled out to Pixel Tablet. As 9to5 notes, the update was seen running on the devices mentioned above, running on stable <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-review">Android 15</a>, which was <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/android-15-just-made-2024s-best-phone-even-better">recently rolled out</a> to all compatible Pixel phones.</p><p>For the uninitiated, the Pixel Troubleshooting app was introduced last year, and the Pixel 8 was one of the first handsets to receive the feature. It helps users diagnose their battery and network issues, and the new temperature feature is indeed a valuable addition as it eliminates the need for installing third-party apps or devices to measure the device's temperature.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-pixel-phones-gain-device-temperature-feature</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ If Pixel phone users feel their devices are warmer, they might now know how warm they are precisely. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">r7XmJqmcjzdQEsryMQfdHG</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/A4wRsPwjhJssSQAt24Uq6P.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 20:45:52 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/A4wRsPwjhJssSQAt24Uq6P.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Top-down view of Google Pixel 9 Pro and 9 Pro XL]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Top-down view of Google Pixel 9 Pro and 9 Pro XL]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>