<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 20:26:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Vivo X100 Ultra and X100s series confirmed for May as prices leak ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Vivo confirmed on Weibo that its upcoming X100 Ultra and X100s flagship series phones will arrive on May 13.</li><li>The Ultra model is rumored to feature a 200MP telephoto sensor, a 50MP primary lens, and a periscope lens.</li><li>The X100s series devices will supposedly feature MediaTek's latest Dimensity 9300 Plus SoC and a 6.7-inch display.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Vivo has confirmed that its upcoming X100 Ultra and the X100s series will arrive on May 13.</p><p>The company highlighted as much <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://weibo.com/1809745371/OcZJNAQ6u">on Weibo</a>, while also giving consumers a decent look at what the devices will look like (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.fonearena.com/blog/423138/vivo-x100-ultra-launch-date-x100s-x100s-pro.html">fonearena</a>). The X100 Ultra continues Vivo&apos;s trend of a large circular triple-camera housing array in the center of its back panel. However, the lenses are in a square formation rather than a diamond, like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/vivo-x100-pro-review">X100 Pro</a>.</p><p>Vivo&apos;s confirmation video shows that Zeiss still powers the device&apos;s camera system. Moreover, the back paneling has been upgraded with a glossier finish, rather than the matte look the Pro model delivers. The upcoming X100 Ultra also appears to have a slightly curved display along its edges, as well.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:335px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:179.10%;"><img id="Tzf9NpTbgKwDnMxLXvvZRY" name="vivo-x100-ultra-teaser-image.jpg" alt="A look at the upcoming Vivo X100 Ultra." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Tzf9NpTbgKwDnMxLXvvZRY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="335" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Vivo / Weibo)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The publication mentioned rumors which suggest the Ultra variant will be powered by Qualcomm&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-3">Snapdragon 8 Gen 3</a> SoC. The camera housing is speculated to hold a 50MP LYT-900 primary lens, a periscope lens, and a 200MP telephoto lens with an f/2.67 aperture.</p><p>Known Weibo leaker <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://weibo.com/6048569942/OcZyzbRzx">Digital Chat Station</a> chimed in, suggesting the Ultra will arrive in Black, Titanium, and White colorways. Additionally, the device could arrive for consumers with the following RAM/internal storage setups: 12/256GB, 16/512GB, and 16/1TB.</p><p>For its 1TB option, a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://weibo.com/3108827753/Od07R1kAT">pricing leak</a> suggested consumers could see an 8,499 yuan ($1,180) price tag (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://playfuldroid.com/vivo-x100-ultra-x100s-x100s-pro-are-launching-on-may-13-prices-leaked/">PlayfulDroid</a>). Additionally, this option could hold satellite connectivity capabilities for those who purchase it.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:335px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:179.10%;"><img id="UhLCxSfdtiEqGCJEeYxRcf" name="vivo-x100s-teaser-image-blue.jpg" alt="A teaser image for the Vivo X100s in a blue hue." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/UhLCxSfdtiEqGCJEeYxRcf.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="335" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Vivo / Weibo)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:337px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:178.04%;"><img id="SHyuLakRyPqV28HiNHz8Tj" name="vivo-x100s-pro-three-colorways-teaser.jpg" alt="A teaser image depicting the three colorways for the upcoming X100s Pro by Vivo." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SHyuLakRyPqV28HiNHz8Tj.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="337" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Vivo / Weibo)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>The X100s and X100s Pro are rumored to feature a 6.7-inch display, similar to the Pro variant from 2023. Unlike the upcoming Ultra model, Vivo&apos;s teaser shows that the X100s series will sport flat edges and sides. Internally, the devices are expected to arrive powered by MediaTek&apos;s recently debuted <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/mediateks-new-dimensity-9300-chip-brings-higher-clock-speeds-and-better-ai-processing">Dimensity 9300 Plus</a> chipset. The chip launched today (May 7), featuring higher clock speeds and better AI processing over the base 9300.</p><p>Vivo is keeping the design theme consistent across these two new additions with the centered circular camera array.</p><p>The company is suggested to offer the base X100s model with the following RAM/internal storage options: 12/256GB, 16/256GB, 16/512GB, and 16/1TB. The device should be available in black, blue, titanium, and white colorways. The X100s Pro is expected to have the same RAM/storage options; however, its colorways will drop the blue option.</p><p>Similarly, the pricing leak states the 1TB option for the X100s and X100s Pro could pick up a 5,199 yuan ($720) and 6,199 yuan ($855) tag, respectively.</p><p>We&apos;re one week away from Vivo&apos;s debut event on May 13. At that event, we&apos;ll learn more concrete details about these upcoming flagship phones.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/vivo-x100-ultra-x100s-series-launch-confirmed</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Vivo confirmed that its upcoming flagship models will launch in May while some supposed prices surface. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">KyJio3nRGgHtELJLNtsBNJ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/aaSCTVr5cBrjMMvP9QtARE.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 20:15:32 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/aaSCTVr5cBrjMMvP9QtARE.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Vivo / Weibo]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A teaser video highlighting the upcoming Vivo X100 Ultra.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A teaser video highlighting the upcoming Vivo X100 Ultra.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Meta launches new business tools backed by generative AI for Advantage Plus ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Today (May 7), Meta announced new generative AI tools, such as image and text generation, arriving for businesses and advertisers.</li><li>The former leverages AI to alter an original photo with varying backgrounds and creative input, while the latter assists with titles and descriptions.</li><li>Meta Verified for Business is also expanding its test to more countries and the company is preparing to bring the program to WhatsApp "soon."</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Businesses and advertisers are receiving some new AI-powered capabilities on Meta&apos;s platform.</p><p>Meta states in a press release that its generative AI software is arriving for advertisers in the form of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.facebook.com/business/help/297506218282224?id=649869995454285">image generation</a>. Those getting involved can now create "full image variations" alongside text overlaying capabilities for their ads. Meta says users can use its AI software to create several variations of the original advertisement.</p><p>Not only is the AI said to alter the background of the photo, but it can even change the subject of the image to give users "more creative options."</p><p>Meta&apos;s full image variations and text overlay have already started rolling out and the company plans to introduce "text prompts" so users can receive more personalized AI creations. The post then teases that "image expansion" is on the horizon for advertisers looking to place their content in Reels and Feed for Facebook and Instagram.</p><p>The company states that the feature will let such users alter the aspect ratio across multiple mediums so that the image is shown appropriately.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1081px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:55.50%;"><img id="gemSRvRvcHdHBdgUhL7Q4n" name="meta-image-generation-ai-capabilities-businesses.jpg" alt="Meta is bringing a few generative AI tools to businesses and advertisers backed by generative AI." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gemSRvRvcHdHBdgUhL7Q4n.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1081" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Meta)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The generative AI additions continue with "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.facebook.com/business/help/180641596861873">text generation</a>." The feature is said to help advertisers create a catchy headline while helping with a primary text. The ability of the AI to properly replicate your brand&apos;s voice is still being tested. Meta teases that it plans for the AI to make callbacks to previous ad campaigns once testing is complete.</p><p>When everything is done, Meta plans to provide such voice and tone capabilities through its Llama 3 next-gen large language model (LLM).</p><p>Image generation and text generation are rolling out today (May 7). Meta plans to make them available globally by the "end of the year." However, Meta highlights that text generation and overlay will begin for English before arriving for others.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="zGi9bmXX83DkDhaFhV2EAH" name="Meta-logo-facebook-page-on-laptop.jpg" alt="Meta's company page on Facebook" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zGi9bmXX83DkDhaFhV2EAH.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>To make things easier, Meta said it is housing all of its new generative AI efforts under <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.facebook.com/business/help/297506218282224?id=649869995454285">Advantage Plus Creative</a> for businesses looking to start their journey. This manager is picking up some notable updates alongside the previously mentioned gen AI features.</p><p>Businesses will soon find better optimization options for video ads in Reels and for the Facebook and Instagram mobile apps. For "catalog ads," which are the recommendations users see, Meta is rolling out the ability to use videos or demonstration videos instead of static photos.</p><p>Moreover, Advantage Plus Creative&apos;s influence in catalog ads brings the capabilities of Meta&apos;s AI to the table. The post states businesses can now display a "hero" image on their video. Meta adds that its AI software will take this image and "dynamically show" a company&apos;s "best product" to help drive interaction.</p><p>The post concludes by stating that Meta Verified for Business is expanding its test on Facebook and Instagram. The company adds that the program is available today (May 7) in Australia and New Zealand and will soon arrive in Argentina, Mexico, Chile, Peru, France, and Italy. Additionally, Meta is preparing to bring the verified badge service to WhatsApp "soon."</p><p>This expansion will bring its subscription plan to four, enabling Meta to support a "wider range of business needs."</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/meta-generative-ai-business-tools-launch</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Meta discussed several new generative AI tools that are starting to arrive for businesses. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">prLFsGya5kdATzH2DJq9QE</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PmNVwScjKJoNPHxsC8pzUi.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PmNVwScjKJoNPHxsC8pzUi.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Alex Dobie / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Meta Logo.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Meta Logo.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Best Google Pixel 8a cases 2024 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The latest A series Pixel is here and it is a doozy. This value-packed device makes you question whether you really need a thousand-dollar flagship at all. Naturally, this means that should you buy one, you&apos;ll need the best Google Pixel 8a cases to keep it in good shape.</p><p>Some folks don&apos;t like cases, but I don&apos;t recommend that. A good phone cover with raised edges can prevent large cracks. It also improves the resale value of your device by keeping the body free of scratches and nicks. On top of that, the best <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-google-pixel-8a-packs-just-as-much-ai-punch-as-the-standard-pixel-8">Pixel 8a</a> cases also bring added functionality like a kickstand or MagSafe support.</p>
<h2 id="these-pixel-8a-cases-are-slim-trim-and-full-of-vigor-2">These Pixel 8a cases are slim, trim, and full of vigor</h2>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="05266ef8-8586-49d7-ae37-cfd476aa5d2f">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2KwhPGRN7N7d3DFhbA7nmj.jpg' alt='Spigen Liquid Air for Pixel 8a'><span class='featured__label hero__label'>Staff pick</span></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Spigen Liquid Air for Pixel 8a</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best overall</strong></em></p>
<p>Time and time again, Spigen has proven that its Liquid Air series is the ultimate choice for any device. This slim, lightweight case is perfect for the Pixel 8a. You get grip, style, and protection in a featherweight and affordable package.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="8eb3135c-8c2a-43e4-a351-d1a698207b2c">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/L7Lwk8poum2ZpYyRa2ZUmQ.jpg' alt='Caseology Capella for Pixel 8a'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Caseology Capella for Pixel 8a</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best clear case</strong></em></p>
<p>Caseology promises military-grade drop-proofing with this Google Pixel 8a case. On top of that, it incorporates anti-yellowing technology and a handy little kickstand on the rear.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="613ce837-9e6d-4a30-a444-f4e0330a282f">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SJ7R4KuPEtZkn64oBbY4Gi.jpg' alt='Poetic Guardian MagPro Case for Google Pixel 8a'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Poetic Guardian MagPro Case for Google Pixel 8a</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best bumper cover</strong></em></p>
<p>Poetic pulled out all the stops with the Guardian MagPro Case for the Google Pixel 8a. This rugged bumper cover has built-in screen protection, grippy sides, and a MagSafe ring on the rear.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="e0bf14d0-9734-4d00-b6e5-3588f3fca87c">
            <a href="https://www.otterbox.com/en-us/emoji-pixel-8a-case-clear/75-00093.html" data-model-name="null"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7aYM6gERHbTwSGFRK5a7se.jpg' alt='OtterBox React Series for Pixel 8a'></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">OtterBox React Series for Pixel 8a</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best print</strong></em></p>
<p>OtterBox used to be the top rugged case maker, but the brand's new React Series for the Pixel 8a is more intriguing this time. If you like fun clear covers, you'll enjoy this emoji-ridden see-through case.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="dfd33d94-986f-4ffa-9930-81478bf70a3a">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/euSD53Jjpt8FcfRjFy8RqB.jpg' alt='Ringke Onyx for Google Pixel 8a'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Ringke Onyx for Google Pixel 8a</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best value</strong></em></p>
<p>The Ringke Onyx case comes with a tempered glass unit for the Pixel 8a's camera bar, increasing its value overall. This sleek case has a non-slip sandpapery texture and has lanyard holes bored into the side.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="3e81d9c6-6bc6-43d5-a8de-3c88cb3c49c3">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FEvERbG8iYipcShkV6MHVV.jpg' alt='Poetic Neon Case for Pixel 8a'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Poetic Neon Case for Pixel 8a</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best rugged</strong></em></p>
<p>If you're worried about your Pixel's safety, the rugged Poetic Neon Case is an ideal choice. This robust Pixel 8a ensemble is shockproof and packs military-grade drop-proofing. There's a clever MagSafe kickstand on the rear too.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<ul><li><a href="#main"><strong>Back to the top ^</strong></a></li></ul>
<h2 id="get-the-best-gear-for-your-google-pixel-8a-2">Get the best gear for your Google Pixel 8a</h2>
<p>Boasting a tiny 6.1-inch display, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a">Google Pixel 8a</a> is a small device. As such, you don&apos;t want to destroy the beauty of a small and lightweight phone by bulking it up with a fat cover. This doesn&apos;t mean you need to forgo protection because luckily, the best Pixel 8a cases come in sleek sizes.</p><p>Our favorite case for the new Pixel is — unsurprisingly — the Spigen Liquid Air. This wonderful thin case for the Pixel 8a is drop-proof, affordable, extremely lightweight, and stylish all at once. Raised edges thwart direct contact with surfaces in the event of a fall and Spigen&apos;s Air Cushion technology improves shock absorption while minimizing damage. I just wish there were more than two dark colors to choose from.</p><p>If you want something flashier, try the Poetic Guardian MagPro Case for the Google Pixel 8a. This bumper cover touts military-grade drop-proofing, which is incredible. This is achieved by adding a built-in screen protector and raising the edges by a good amount. What&apos;s fun about this Pixel 8a case is that it is see-through, so you can admire your phone&apos;s paint job, and it has a MagSafe ring on the back. This enables you to use any of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-magsafe-accessories-for-android-phones">best MagSafe accessories for Android phones</a> with your Pixel 8a.</p><p>Haven&apos;t placed your order yet? Here&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/best-google-pixel-8a-deals-how-to-buy">how you can buy the Google Pixel 8a</a>. We&apos;ve also rounded up early deals and what you need to know about the Pixel 8a for your ease.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/best-google-pixel-8a-cases</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A case is the first accessory you should get for your phone. If you're a Pixel 8a owner, here are the best ones you should purchase. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">KpgAj8iPYswyzX3bmNfbUj</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Cr28zQoTeiqetwc6M9JeQ4.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 19:28:45 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Cr28zQoTeiqetwc6M9JeQ4.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nick Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Pixel 8a cases]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Pixel 8a cases]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ YouTube's 'jump ahead' experimental AI feature is here in wider test ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>One of YouTube's experimental AI features, called "jump ahead," is now being tested with many YouTube Premium subscribers.</li><li>The feature uses AI to figure out the best parts of a YouTube video and automatically skip to them to save users' time.</li><li>It's like the standard skip tool for YouTube videos but powered by AI. </li></ul>
<hr>
<p>YouTube is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-jump-ahead-ai-experimental-feature">testing "jump ahead,"</a> an AI-assisted feature that will automatically skip to the best or most important parts of YouTube videos, in a wider experiment for YouTube Premium subscribers. It takes watch data from real users and analyzes them with artificial intelligence and machine learning algorithms to find the most-watched sections. Essentially, it&apos;s like skimming the summary of a book online instead of reading the whole thing. </p><p>YouTube&apos;s algorithm will pick these key points in a video, and you can skip through them. Or, if you&apos;re in the middle of watching a video, you can "jump ahead" to the closest key point in a YouTube video. </p><p>However, this won&apos;t work for every YouTube video during this growing test. We don&apos;t know the exact qualifications needed for "jump ahead" to be an option for a video. It could be based on how many views a video gets, because perhaps YouTube needs a big enough viewer sample size to identify those key points. This is all speculation for now, and we&apos;ll likely learn more about this feature if it progresses in development. </p><p>Our knowledge of the feature now comes from YouTube&apos;s Creator Insider channel, which detailed the "jump ahead" feature in a March 2024 video:</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4OX-OthHWAA?start=8" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>Jump Ahead works in tandem with the regular skip video on YouTube. If you&apos;re a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/youtube-premium">Premium user</a> on an eligible video, you may see the jump ahead option when you try to do a regular 10-second skip. If you tap the option that appears, YouTube will move you to the next key point in a given YouTube video. </p><p>This functionality is exclusive to the YouTube for Android app, at least at the moment. In a sidebar, YouTube explains that jump ahead "is a Premium-only feature that combines watch data and AI to help identify the next best point a viewer typically skips ahead to."</p><p>You can try jump ahead through <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/new" target="_blank">YouTube&apos;s new experiments page</a>, and it is opt-in. For now, YouTube has set an end date for the test early next month, but it&apos;s possible the platform could keep it going for longer.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtubes-jump-ahead-experimental-ai-feature-is-here-in-wider-test</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ After previewing an AI-assisted feature for YouTube called "jump ahead" in March, it's now showing up in a wider test for Premium susbcribers. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">fo2bJBeMG2X45qMLRFQwJG</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fbeSpBwcSYx94g4taJRYTQ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 19:21:24 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fbeSpBwcSYx94g4taJRYTQ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[YouTube Premium Galaxy Z Fold 3.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[YouTube Premium Galaxy Z Fold 3.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 just leaked again ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Motorola's upcoming Razr 50 Ultra/Razr Plus 2024 was just spotted in live images.</li><li>It reveals the device design next to both the cover and foldable screens.</li><li>The leak also reveals the device's possible launch in new Blue, Orange, and Green color options.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>The launch of the new Razr phones might be a couple of months away, but the Razr 50 Ultra, aka the Razr Plus 2024, may be on its way soon, as a possible live image of the latter has now surfaced online.</p><p>The live image of the Razr 50 Ultra is shared by tipster <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://twitter.com/Sudhanshu1414/status/1787389107171152062">Sudhanshu Ambhore</a> on X in conjunction with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.91mobiles.com/hub/exclusive-motorola-razr-50-ultra-live-image-imminent-launch/">91mobiles</a>, wherein we also get to know about the colorways of the upcoming foldable phone next to its storage options.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:431px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:139.21%;"><img id="yJ6wEFHPeLkJNGEcdMxRy9" name="motorola-razr-50-ultra-live-image-leak.jpg" alt="Razr 50 Ultra/Plus 2024 live image leak" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yJ6wEFHPeLkJNGEcdMxRy9.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="431" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: 91mobiles)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Per the published live image, the Razr 50 Ultra doesn&apos;t look radically different from the predecessor Razr 40 Ultra/<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-review">Razr Plus 2023</a>. It carries the same aesthetic as the predecessor, including a wider cover screen with horizontal dual cameras and the Razr logo at the chin. The folding screen with punch hole cut out can also be seen in the shared live image, which will likely have thinner bezels.</p><p>As for the button placements, the volume rocker and power button are on the right pane of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">foldable phone</a>. The publication further shares the possible colorways of the Razr 50 Ultra, likely to be Blue, Orange, and Green variants. The predecessor came in Black, Blue, Magenta, and Peach color options. The foldable handset will be bearing the <strong>XT-24510-3</strong> model number and is expected to be shipped in a 12GB RAM variant with 512GB of onboard storage.</p>
<p>The new render from 91mobiles follows the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2024-alleged-leaked-render">first supposed render</a> that came in January 2024 and included an identical design. Over the last couple of months, the Motorola Razr 50 Ultra/Razr Plus 2024 has also been spotted in various certification sites like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.91mobiles.com/hub/motorola-razr-50-ultra-bis-india-launch-expected-soon/">BIS</a>, EEC, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2024-reaches-radio-certification">Radio Certification</a> in China. </p><p>These certifications don&apos;t reveal significant specs of the foldable but only point to the fact that the launch is sooner rather than later. Going by the launch timeframe of the previous models, we should likely see the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2024">Razr Plus 2024</a> hitting the stores sometime next month.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-50-ultra-aka-razr-plus-2024-live-image</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Razr 50 Ultra, also known as Razr Plus 2024, just leaked again, alongside possible color and storage variant information. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">X2Lc3DPTcAqWYcgzyUopMJ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oS6rwDfVxRuNQn8RJq678E.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 18:58:30 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oS6rwDfVxRuNQn8RJq678E.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Maps on the Motorola Razr Plus cover screen]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Maps on the Motorola Razr Plus cover screen]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ An RFID blocker could be a lifesaver — here's why ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Ever heard of an RFID blocker? If you&apos;re interested in wallet cases for your phone or even wallets in general, you might have heard the term. A lot of wallets and wallet accessories, such as MagSafe wallet add-ons, boast RFID-blocking as a feature. What is this feature, and why is it important anyway? I&apos;m here to shed some light on this matter.</p><p>Contactless payments weren&apos;t as widespread a couple of years ago, but they&apos;re all the rage right now. NFC-based services like "Tap to Pay" and the marriage of Google Wallet with Google Pay have ushered in a new era where we feel comfortable storing our credit cards, debit cards, IDs, and even <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet-to-expand-digital-drivers-license-support">driving licenses digitally</a>. Our overall trust in such payment methods has increased. Even modern debit and credit cards that use "Tap to Pay" rely on NFC to work.</p><p>Unbeknownst to most people, however, this system has a glaring security flaw. Although many security mechanisms protect personal and financial details when you depend on contactless payment mechanisms, these NFC-based systems are still unable to prevent certain activities.</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Gadget Weekly</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="DZLQ4jKZk9tEF5A3sqU5Jh" name="inspector-lloyd-square.jpg" caption="" alt="Inspector Lloyd" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DZLQ4jKZk9tEF5A3sqU5Jh.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">Join Namerah Saud Fatmi as she explores the cool, quirky, and sometimes downright odd world of smartphone accessories, gadgets, and other nerdy toys <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/gadget-weekly">every week</a>.</p></div></div>
<p>Don&apos;t worry; I&apos;m not going to bore you with technical details that you don&apos;t understand anyway. The problem is extremely simple, to the point that it&apos;s ridiculous.</p>
<h2 id="understanding-contactless-payments-2">Understanding contactless payments</h2>
<p>Let&apos;s start by breaking down how NFC-based payments are made. You use your phone&apos;s or smartwatch&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet">Google Wallet</a> or e-wallet by enabling NFC and adding your supported credit or debit cards to it. Most banks in the world require you to set up limits for contactless digital transactions. Select transactions over a certain limit may require additional authentication, such as a PIN, a one-time password (OTP), or biometric verification.</p><p>However, for contactless digital transactions within the bank&apos;s specified limits, your device does not usually need additional authentication after initial setup and verification. After all, this is what makes it a convenient payment method on the go. You tap your device or "Tap to Pay"-enabled card to make a payment, and then you&apos;re off on your way.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4032px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="nrqkh5HfztKp2zRgfifXcS" name="TicWatch-Pro-3-Wear-OS-Google-Pay-lifestyle-16x9-1.jpeg" alt="Google Wallet on Wear OS device, TicWatch Pro 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nrqkh5HfztKp2zRgfifXcS.jpeg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4032" height="2268" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Chris Wedel/Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The problem with relying on NFC is that it activates as soon as it detects a compatible payment device nearby. Your <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phone</a>, wearable, or card automatically makes a payment when it detects a compatible machine nearby, usually if the phone has been unlocked within a few minutes of the purchase. As long as your device&apos;s NFC is enabled, this will happen automatically. It gets worse with your cards because those don&apos;t have the option to disable NFC.</p><p>You could place your wallet or phone near a contactless payment card machine, and it could automatically make a payment, even if you didn&apos;t intend to use it. Now, this might sound silly, but there are actual reports of people facing this issue.</p><p>For example, a user called <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/wallet/thread/197094676/automatically-paid-without-consent">Aram Dermenjian 2298 took to the Google Wallet support page</a> to address this issue in January 2023. The user complained that their Google Wallet made a payment without their consent because of the unlocked phone&apos;s close proximity to the payment machine.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1882px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="7qCwyttCFPnGUDqWYKoWfB" name="google-wallet-automatic-payment-complain.jpg" alt="Google Wallet support page complaint about non-consensual payment" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7qCwyttCFPnGUDqWYKoWfB.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1882" height="1059" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Aram Dermenjian 2298 had no intention of paying for their purchase with their Google Wallet&apos;s primary card as it was a business expense. However, because of the nature of NFC payments, the payment automatically went out because their phone detected the payment machine and initiated the transaction.</p><p>I am not a fintech professional by any means, but this non-consensual transaction sent alarm bells ringing through my head. There are so many unfortunate scenarios where this flaw could be taken advantage of. The worst part is that the only real solution to this is to disable your NFC when your wallet isn&apos;t in use or to add more passwords and locks for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/wallet/answer/12059519">additional verification</a>, which kills the convenience of the system itself.</p>
<h2 id="this-is-where-rfid-blockers-come-in-2">This is where RFID blockers come in</h2>
<p>While you can add a ton of extra preventive measures to your phone or wearable to stop this from happening, things aren&apos;t as easy with your credit or debit cards. This is where RFID and NFC-blocking wallets come into play.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>The best way to block NFC or RFID signals is by using an aluminum plate.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>The best way to block NFC or RFID signals is by placing an aluminum plate on top of your cards or on the back of your phone. This can be done with the help of an RFID-blocking wallet or wallet case for your phone. Fortunately, these can be found a dime a dozen. It is a pretty simple and easy idea that reduces the number of things you need to carry. Most importantly, however, this solution prevents unfavorable scenarios from happening, such as unintentional payouts from your e-wallet or bank cards.</p><p>You can find an RFID-blocking wallet or wallet case at affordable pricing from most retailers. If you&apos;re using a flagship phone like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review">Galaxy S24 Ultra</a>, recommend the Scooch Wingmate as it&apos;s a wallet case with an RFID-blocking metal plate baked in.</p><p>If you don&apos;t want to buy an accessory, even some aluminum foil will do the trick. Now that you&apos;re aware of this situation, be sure to take the necessary precautions.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="f35a3bab-da32-417e-b9a5-42ea9013830f">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WygAuWNgWSJGWmJkwpS3n7.jpg' alt='Scooch Wingmate for Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Scooch Wingmate for Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>RFID-blocking wallet case</strong></em></p>
<p>Scooch keeps practicality at the center with the Wingmate wallet <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-galaxy-s24-ultra-cases">case for the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra</a>. You can buy this RFID-blocking case for plenty of other Android and iOS phones as well.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/the-importance-of-an-rfid-blocker</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Do you rely on contactless payments via your phone, wearable, or cards? There's something you need to know. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">w2nsNFsHH2TYtuRPbXrztJ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/iSNZtYCjj8zGf6UCJZgbrC.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 18:13:18 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/iSNZtYCjj8zGf6UCJZgbrC.jpeg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Menu to add a payment card, transit pass, loyalty card, or gift card to Google Wallet]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Menu to add a payment card, transit pass, loyalty card, or gift card to Google Wallet]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Google Pixel 8a isn't even out yet and Verizon is already giving them away for free ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Google&apos;s latest midrange masterpiece was finally announced this morning, and Verizon has wasted no time in dropping one of the best Google Pixel 8a deals we&apos;ve seen yet. Preorder the Pixel 8a ahead of its May 14th release date and you&apos;ll <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/google-pixel-8a/"><strong>get the phone for free</strong></a> when you add a line with an eligible unlimited plan. No trade-in is required, and I&apos;m not just talking about Verizon&apos;s most expensive plan options here either: the Unlimited Welcome, Unlimited Plus, AND Unlimited Ultra plans are all eligible for the promotion. </p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="252d91f7-f34e-4644-8043-3859b5bcced5" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 8a 128GB: $499" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 8a 128GB: $499" href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/google-pixel-8a/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2365px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:136.24%;"><img id="iQ8LKCZQ6bKz5aPN7ECzjR" name="google-pixel-8a-render-front-and-back-porcelain.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/iQ8LKCZQ6bKz5aPN7ECzjR.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2365" height="3222" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Google Pixel 8a 128GB: </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/google-pixel-8a/" data-dimension112="252d91f7-f34e-4644-8043-3859b5bcced5" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 8a 128GB: $499" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 8a 128GB: $499"><del>$499</del> <strong>FREE with eligible Unlimited plan at Verizon</strong></a></p>
<p>Add a line to your Verizon service with the Unlimited Welcome, Unlimited Plus, or Unlimited Ultimate plan and the carrier will hook you up with enough promo credits to make the new <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a">Google Pixel 8a</a> totally free. No trade-in required! Sure, you're still paying for the wireless plan, but this is a pretty impressive promotion for a smartphone that isn't even out yet. </p>
<p>The Unlimited Welcome plan would be the most affordable option here, starting at $65 per month for a single line (although the plan can drop as low as $30 per month when you add additional lines).<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/google-pixel-8a/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="252d91f7-f34e-4644-8043-3859b5bcced5" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 8a 128GB: $499" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 8a 128GB: $499">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>This <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/best-verizon-phone-deals-plans">Verizon deal</a> makes the most sense if you&apos;re already a customer or you&apos;re interested in making the switch. If you prefer to buy your phones unlocked, however, there are already several other <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/best-google-pixel-8a-deals-how-to-buy">Google Pixel 8a preorder deals</a> that might be worth checking out (with plenty more on the way). </p><p>Either way, you&apos;ll be getting one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-android-phones">best cheap Android phones</a> expected to hit store shelves in 2024, coming complete with a gorgeous 120Hz display, some flagship-quality camera tech, and the same Tensor G3 processor that&apos;s behind the flagship Pixel 8 and Pixel 8 Pro. The Google Pixel 8a also features a bigger battery than its predecessor, and you&apos;ll be guaranteed to receive seven years of OS upgrades.</p><p>Like we mentioned above, the Google Pixel 8a is slated for release on May 14th, the same day as Google I/O 2024. The 128GB version will retail for $499 in the United States, while the larger 256GB storage configuration will set you back $599. </p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-google-pixel-8a-isnt-even-out-yet-and-verizon-is-already-giving-them-away-for-free</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Sign up for an eligible data plan and Verizon will give you enough promo credits over 36 months to make the new Google Pixel 8a completely free.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">j3nceKQK8SQmGedxMMzpeU</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DwGUL6HR9yAXoAVt3xJnf.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 17:15:07 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DwGUL6HR9yAXoAVt3xJnf.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A montage of all the Google Pixel 8a colorways]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A montage of all the Google Pixel 8a colorways]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Pixel 8a vs. Pixel 8 Pro ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[         <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="4349cabe-c8dd-4810-aa38-19cd380535ab">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XjXDP3u2nLmLvarrAGcGeZ.jpg' alt='Google Pixel 8a'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 8a</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>A cheaper alternative </strong></em></p>
<p>For those who have been waiting for a cheaper alternative to the Google Pixel 8 Pro and Google Pixel 8, the Google Pixel 8a is the answer. Like the Google Pixel 7a, it’s a step down but still a feature-rich phone that provides a solid experience for a value price. Rather than downgrade to the Google Pixel 7 to save money, you can get the latest in the line for a similar price point.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Cheaper</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Great battery life</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>7 years of OS and security updates</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Has AI features</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Not as durable</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Screen isn't as bright</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Doesn't have as much RAM</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Taps out at 256GB storage</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="4e13032f-cf6d-431b-840f-7236596657ba">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rDsWwogtufZ6wpYuRqE8XY.jpg' alt='Pixel 8 Pro in Bay front and back square render'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 8 Pro</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Still the top of the line </strong></em></p>
<p>If you have the extra dollars to spare, the Google Pixel 8 Pro is still the top-line device in the Pixel line-up. It has all the bells and whistles, including tons of great AI integration feature. The screen is beautiful and bright, the finish and materials elegant and stylish, and it has plenty of RAM and up to 1TB storage to keep up with your daily needs. But you’ll pay more for it.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Fantastic and bright screen</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Powerful cameras and AI editing features</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Powerful processor, RAM</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Seven years of OS and security updates</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Expensive</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No expandable storage</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>G3 processor isn't yet ideal for gaming</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<p>Now that you know the Google Pixel 8a exists, the decision comes down to the Google Pixel 8a vs. Google Pixel 8 Pro. On the one hand, you save money and still get a new device with the Google Pixel 8a. On the other, you aren’t getting the most premium experience. Which way should you go? We’re here to help with this detailed comparison of the two Pixel phones.</p>
<h2 id="google-pixel-8a-vs-google-pixel-8-pro-the-look-and-basics-2">Google Pixel 8a vs. Google Pixel 8 Pro: The look and basics</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="8vk8nBQLetvaiFmUpZZBPG" name="google-pixel-8a-official-lifestyle-aloe-01.jpg" alt="A person holding an Aloe Google Pixel 8a" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8vk8nBQLetvaiFmUpZZBPG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Google Pixel 8a is Google’s “budget” entry option in the latest 8 line. Prior to its launch, if you wanted a step down from the Google Pixel 8, your best option would be the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-7-review">Google Pixel 7</a> or even the Google Pixel 7a. This device offers upgraded specs compared to those phones while still keeping the price down for a current device. </p><p>The Google Pixel 8a has a 6.1-inch Actua OLED display that boasts 1,080 x 2,400 resolution and up to 120Hz refresh rate. You get a decent up to 1,400 nits brightness in HDR or up to 2,000 nits peak brightness, which is great for viewing outdoors. It isn’t quite as bright and beautiful as the screen on the Google Pixel 8 Pro, but Google says it’s 40 percent brighter than the Pixel 7a screen. </p><p>The always-on screen is covered with Corning Gorilla Glass 3 with a fingerprint-resistant coating, and it’s made from a matte composite with a matte aluminum frame. So, it isn’t as durable, but considering you’ll be using a protective case, this might not matter much for regular everyday use. It comes in Obsidian and Porcelain and, for the first time with an A-series device, Bay, along with a brand-new limited edition Aloe finish. The Google Pixel 8a is also IP67 water- and dust-resistant, so slightly less rugged in this respect than the Pixel 8 Pro. </p><p>For the first time with an A-series model, you can choose from 128 GB or 256GB storage. This isn’t expandable, though, as with the Google Pixel 8 Pro. The Pixel 8a runs Android 14 and promises seven years of OS and security updates as well as frequent Feature Drops. So, like with other new Pixel devices, you can be assured that this phone will last you a long time. </p><p>Speaking of lasting, it has a 4,492mAh battery that Google says lasts for more than a day and can extend to up to 72 hours using the Extreme Battery Saver mode. It also supports both fast and wireless charging, the latter with Qi-certified chargers. </p><p>The Google Pixel 8a includes face and fingerprint unlock just like its bigger sisters along with stereo speakers with two mics and noise suppression, though you won’t get support for Spatial Audio. There’s no headphone jack, as is typical with most phones nowadays.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="47po7vPbimkNg6taSyW5KC" name="Google-Pixel-8-Pro-back-porcelain-01.jpg" alt="The matte glass on the back of the Google Pixel 8 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/47po7vPbimkNg6taSyW5KC.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>How does this compare to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-pro-review">Google Pixel 8 Pro</a>? The flagship has a larger 6.7-inch Super Actua LTPO OLED display that boasts a higher resolution at 1,344 x 2992. It’s also brighter at 1,600 nits with a peak brightness up to 2,400 nits, so if you use your phone a lot outdoors in bright sunlight, this might matter to you. The refresh rate is adaptive as well at 1-120Hz, so it can keep up with demanding tasks. </p><p>The screen employs <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/cornings-new-gorilla-glass-victus-can-survive-drop-2-meters">Corning Gorilla Glass Victus</a>, which is more durable and resistant against scratches and fingerprints. But again, with a protective case, which is recommended for any phone, as well as a screen protector, this might not be a dealbreaker. This phone also has a higher IP68 water- and dust-resistant rating. </p><p>The Google Pixel 8 Pro comes in three finishes, Porcelain, Bay, and Obsidian, and you get the option for 512GB and 1TB capacities as well as 128GB and 256GB. If you plan to download a lot of apps and store tons of photos and other content and don’t want to rely on cloud storage, this phone is the better option since you can get tons more onboard storage. Of course, you’re also paying more for it. Keep in mind that the Google Pixel 8 Pro comes with a six-month trial compared to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-one">Google One</a> Premium, which includes 2TB cloud storage. </p><p>The Google Pixel 8 Pro runs on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review">Android 14</a> as well, with the same promise of seven years of OS and security updates. It has a larger 5,500mAh battery that can also last for up to 24 hours or longer, up to 72 hours, with the Extreme Battery Saver mode. This phone also supports fast charging and fast wireless charging, along with Battery Share for recharging compatible devices like Pixel Buds with the phone.   </p><p>Along with the same fingerprint and face unlock, you get stereo speakers, three mics with noise suppression, and support for Spatial Audio. So, you’ll enjoy a better audio experience with this phone. This device also does not have a headphone jack.</p>
<h2 id="google-pixel-8-pro-vs-google-pixel-fold-the-specifications-2">Google Pixel 8 Pro vs. Google Pixel Fold: The specifications</h2>
<p>Let’s break things down by specs to paint a clearer picture of how these two Google Pixel phones compare and contrast with one another.</p>

<p>It’s obvious from these specs that the Google Pixel 8a is a step down from the Google Pixel 8 Pro in several ways. But it’s all a matter of price and what you need and value the most.</p>
<h2 id="google-pixel-8a-vs-google-pixel-8-pro-power-and-processing-2">Google Pixel 8a vs. Google Pixel 8 Pro: Power and processing</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="mGEzzuDVBtLfDKfoZVBdQZ" name="pixel 8a parts.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 8a" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mGEzzuDVBtLfDKfoZVBdQZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Not surprisingly, the Google Pixel 8a is a less powerful device than the Google Pixel 8 Pro. As noted, they both come loaded with Android 14, and both also include the Google Tensor G3 chip. You get less RAM with the Google Pixel 8a at just 8GB, but this is still respectable: you can expect the phone to meet your daily needs. </p><p>From a security perspective, you get VPN by Google One included with a purchase of the phone along with Google’s standard end-to-end security, which comes with every Pixel device. There’s also the Tensor security core, Titan M2 security chip, and anti-malware and phishing protection, all of which are par for the course with Pixel devices. Using Family Link, you can manage privacy settings, establish screen time limits, and share location, useful for parents getting this device for kids. </p><p>Interestingly, the Google Pixel 8a has all the same AI goodies as its bigger sister, like Circle to Search for easily searching for a subject or object by circling or scribbling over it, and Google’s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini</a>. With the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-gemini-app-android">Gemini</a> built-in AI assistant, once you enable extensions, just hold the power button to ask Gemini to do things like summarize an e-mail, help you brainstorm ideas, write a thank you note, or even plan a vacation. </p><p>There’s also Pixel Call Assist, Call Screen, Direct My Call, Hold for Me, Clear Calling, and other features. A fun new feature, presumably that will also be accessible in the Google Pixel 8 Pro, is called <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-phone-audio-emoji-update-spotted">Audio Emoji</a>. Effectively, you can create your own soundtrack on a call, playing audio “emoji” like applause or laughing as part of the conversation.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="LmWknuwaArYGhwNhZ6FWzB" name="Google-Pixel-8-Pro-display-01.jpg" alt="The bright display on the Google Pixel 8 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LmWknuwaArYGhwNhZ6FWzB.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Google Pixel 8 Pro has all that and more. Along with the Google Tensor G3 chip and Google AI, it has more RAM at 12GB. Note, however, that Android Central’s Nicholas Sutrich says he didn’t notice much of a difference when gaming with the Pixel 8 Pro over previous generation devices with the Google Tensor G2 chip. So, keep this in mind if you plan to do a lot of mobile gaming. The Google Pixel 8 Pro is still the better option between the two in this respect, though. It will be snappier and better for gaming, multi-tasking, and other high-resource apps. </p><p>Along with features like Call Screen to automatically screen and filter out spam calls, you can enjoy AI functions like Live Translate and an improved Google Assistant experience that can summarize web pages, even translate them, help you compose messages, and more. </p><p>It has the same security features, including VPN by Google One and the Titan M2 chip, and adds others like crisis alerts and car crash detection. While the built-in temperature sensor in the Google Pixel 8 Pro is a nice-to-have feature, there’s still some work to do with it, so it isn’t a deal-breaking feature. </p><p>For fitness folks, the Google Pixel 8 Pro comes with a six-month Fitbit Premium trial as well as three months of YouTube Premium if you love to watch videos on the device. This is a nice incentive that could sway you in the direction of this phone, too, especially if you own a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-2">Google Pixel Watch 2</a> or another compatible Fitbit device.</p>
<h2 id="google-pixel-8a-vs-google-pixel-8-pro-the-cameras-2">Google Pixel 8a vs. Google Pixel 8 Pro: The cameras</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="DwGUL6HR9yAXoAVt3xJnf" name="google-pixel-8a-colorway-montage.jpg" alt="A montage of all the Google Pixel 8a colorways" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DwGUL6HR9yAXoAVt3xJnf.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Taking photos from your mobile device is important. For some, in fact, the cameras could be the deciding factor between two phones. </p><p>The Google Pixel 8a comes out of the gate with a main camera that has a larger 64MP quad PD wide camera with Super Res Zoom up to 8x. It has a 13MP ultra-wide camera, ideal for getting group of panoramic scenic shots. This is complemented by the decent 13MP front camera, which has an ultra-wide field-of-view so you can get everyone in the photo and is actually higher resolution than the front camera in the Google Pixel 8 Pro. </p><p>You can enjoy all the typical Google Pixel photo editing and capture features like Magic Editor for repositioning and resizing objects and using preset backgrounds, Best Take for adjusting facial expressions for each person in a photo to get the best one (Sutrich says it works flawlessly), Magic Eraser, Photo Unblur, Real Tone, Face Unblur, Night Sight, Portrait Mode, and more. There’s also Audio Magic Eraser for videos, which removes distracting background noises. So, you’re getting all the same great features, but the cameras themselves aren’t the same. </p><p>With that said, we haven’t yet put the cameras in this phone through their paces, so we can’t compare head-to-head. But based on specs alone, and the expectation that the Google Pixel 8 Pro provides a superior experience, keep this in mind. Also consider that the Google Pixel 8 and even the Google Pixel 7a take wonderful photos, so you likely won’t be disappointed with the cameras in the Google Pixel 8a. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="AriHAnbWjHYfa6q4QWWvVG" name="Google-Pixel-8-Pro-camera-bar-01.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 8 Pro camera bar in the porcelain colorway" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AriHAnbWjHYfa6q4QWWvVG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In terms of specs, the Google Pixel 8 Pro has a 50MP main camera, 48MP telephoto camera, 48MP ultra-wide camera with improved Macro focus, and 10.5MP front camera, so its front camera is actually lower resolution than the Google Pixel 8a. The Super Res Zoom is superior, however, going up to 30x. You get those same photo editing features like Photo Unblur, Magic Eraser, Face Unblur, Real Tone, Night Sight, and Best Take, as well as <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-astrophotography-mode-google-pixel">Astrophotography</a> and, of course, Portrait mode. </p><p>There are some professional-level camera controls worth mentioning with the Google Pixel 8 Pro, including advanced camera settings for shutter speed, ISO, and more. There’s also <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-audio-magic-eraser">Audio Magic Eraser</a> for videos, which, as mentioned, you get in the Google Pixel 8a as well. Sutrich says it works “unbelievably well.”</p>
<h2 id="google-pixel-8a-vs-google-pixel-8-pro-which-should-you-buy-2">Google Pixel 8a vs. Google Pixel 8 Pro: Which should you buy?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="LmBSLmMxrfGrwJyWv9Li75" name="google-pixel-8-pro-display-outside.jpg" alt="The Google Pixel 8 Pro's vibrant display outside" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LmBSLmMxrfGrwJyWv9Li75.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Now, it’s decision time. Which should you buy between the Google Pixel 8a vs. Google Pixel 8 Pro? It really comes down to budget and needs. If you just want a simple device for an affordable price, go with the Google Pixel 8a, which will easily rank among the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-android-phones">best cheap Android phones</a>. You’ll save a ton while also still coming out with premium features that are typically only reserved for higher-end models like the Google Pixel 8 Pro and Google Pixel 8. These range from photo editing tools to a wonderful primary and even selfie camera, fast processor, and lots of AI goodies. </p><p>If you want the best of the best, go with the Google Pixel 8 Pro. It is more powerful overall, has a more elegant and durable build, more RAM, larger storage options, and additional cameras. All the Google AI goodies will come in handy, and you may use them more than you think you will. </p><p>The nice Goldilocks option, if you can’t decide, is the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-review">Google Pixel 8</a>, which sits neatly between these two devices. It has many of the same features with a few step-ups in design, build, and specs compared to the Pixel 8a, but with a smaller screen and some concessions compared to the Google Pixel 8 Pro. See our comparison between the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-vs-google-pixel-8-pro">Google Pixel 8 Pro vs. Google Pixel 8</a> to decide which one would suit you better if you think the Google Pixel 8a is too entry-level for you. </p><p>But as a fabulous first phone, secondary phone, or even a device for a teen or tween, the Google Pixel 8a is offered at a great price with tons of features to rival even some higher-end phones. If you prefer the smaller screen size, that might be enough to sway you towards this phone. For average, everyday use, good photos, and even the option to play around with AI features, the Google Pixel 8a is worth considering. </p><p>The bottom line: no matter which of the Pixel 8 devices you choose, you can rest assured that it will keep up with demanding tasks, take great photos, and provide an intuitive and pleasurable experience. The best part is that with seven years of updates promised for all three, you can easily sell or trade-in one and upgrade if needed, and the phone will retain its value for years to come.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="df8278f0-9174-49c1-b303-22170f3175d6">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XjXDP3u2nLmLvarrAGcGeZ.jpg' alt='Google Pixel 8a'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 8a</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Save some dough </strong></em></p>
<p>If you’re looking for a premium Android device that’s new and will last a long time, the Google Pixel 8a offers a great solution at an affordable price. While it doesn’t have all the bells and whistles of the Google Pixel 8 Pro, it’s also more compact and might suit some users just fine.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="59be32c1-dc45-48be-a015-f2fd42562dba">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/u3naKehRAxgCXQWDcR854X.jpg' alt='Pixel 8 Pro in Porcelain front and back square render'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 8 Pro</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Still among the best</strong></em> </p>
<p>For the best of the best not only Google has to offer, but among Android phones of all brands in general, save up and go with the Google Pixel 8 Pro. It’s a solid phone that excels in virtual every department, from the look and feel to the cameras, processing power, battery life, and AI.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-vs-pixel-8-pro</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Google Pixel 8a is a new entry-level option in the 8 series line, and compared to the Google Pixel 8 Pro, it isn't a massive step down. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">b2GoaUNoXxwQiGCXco8NDA</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RaL37TDWMzmbSNVTtztGci.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 17:00:50 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ christinep2424@gmail.com (Christine Persaud) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RaL37TDWMzmbSNVTtztGci.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The green Pixel 8a next to the blue Pixel 8 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The green Pixel 8a next to the blue Pixel 8 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Pixel 8a vs. Pixel 8: Every key difference ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[         <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="7db0320d-803a-428a-8175-fa7e93b33355">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XjXDP3u2nLmLvarrAGcGeZ.jpg' alt='Google Pixel 8a'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 8a</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Barely a compromise</strong></em></p>
<p>The Google Pixel 8a has shed most of the downsides of past Pixel "A" phones like poorer display quality and less RAM, making it a great mid-range option with very few downsides. Google does block a few mainline features from its cheaper model to upsell you, but almost nothing feels like an insurmountable issue. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Spend $200 less</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Tensor G3 chip with 8GB RAM</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>FHD 120Hz display w/ 2,000 nits</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Comparable battery life</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>7 years of OS updates</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Cameras lack autofocus, capture less light</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Slower charging speed</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Lower Gorilla Glass and IP protection</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="7e8dac06-1ac5-41e5-8b2b-2539d20840f9">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NVAviLLwEx5w5e8isxEjna.jpg' alt='Hazel Google Pixel 8'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 8</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Niche upgrades</strong></em></p>
<p>The Pixel 8 has better cameras than the Pixel 8a for photography buffs who can't afford the Pixel 8 Pro. If you want to use a Pixel for its 7-year software lifespan, the Pixel 8's stronger Victus protection could make it more likely to withstand the wear and tear of life. It'll also charge faster, especially wirelessly. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Better, brighter AF cameras with Macro Focus</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Smaller display bezels</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>IP68/ GG Victus protection</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Wi-Fi 7 support</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Faster charging</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>More expensive</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No major upgrades to performance, display</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Missing some 8 Pro camera tricks</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<p>Comparing the Pixel 8a vs. Pixel 8 requires diving deep into Google&apos;s tech specs for both phones. Intentionally designed to be quite similar to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-review">Pixel 8</a>, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a">Google Pixel 8a</a> shares common traits like its Tensor G3 chip, 120Hz FHD display, and seven years of OS updates. </p><p>Launching at $499, the Pixel 8a is similar enough to the Pixel 8 ($699) that you&apos;re probably wondering where the price difference comes in. Many of the differences are minor, but you might decide that you can&apos;t live without specific Pixel 8 upgrades like its auto-focusing cameras</p>
<h2 id="google-pixel-8a-vs-pixel-8-design-2">Google Pixel 8a vs. Pixel 8: Design</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:716px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.28%;"><img id="v4xcb6kXnVfxKPm8EQL9c7" name="google-pixel-8a-colors-169.jpg" alt="All of the official color options for the Google Pixel 8a" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/v4xcb6kXnVfxKPm8EQL9c7.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="716" height="403" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="caption-text">The four Pixel 8a color options </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Despite its slightly smaller display, the 6.1-inch Pixel 8a is one gram heavier and about 1.5mm taller and wider than the 6.2-inch Pixel 8. You&apos;ll notice aluminum bezels along the 8a&apos;s front, while the Pixel 8 is thinner along the edge. That being said, you won&apos;t notice a difference holding them, especially once you add a case. </p><p>Both Pixels use recycled aluminum for the camera bar and side frame, but the Pixel 8a has a matte composite back, while the Pixel 8 has a glossy glass back with Gorilla Glass Victus protection. It&apos;s a judgment call whether you prefer a matte or gloss look, but most of the AC staff prefer the Pixel 8a&apos;s matte look since it&apos;s less likely to accentuate fingerprints.</p><p>They share that classic Pixel camera bar aesthetic, with the dual camera sensors aligned to the left cutout and the LED on the right. It gives the Pixel 8a a unique look compared to most <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-android-phones">budget Android phones</a>.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="owRGtn4hGbgqgRqWoroKZH" name="pixel-8-7.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 8 camera bar close-up" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/owRGtn4hGbgqgRqWoroKZH.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Pixel 8 ships in Obsidian, Hazel, Mint, and Rose, while the Pixel 8a has Obsidian, Porcelain, Bay, and Aloe.</p><p>One non-aesthetic design difference to note: the Pixel 8a only hits IP67 protection, slightly below the Pixel 8&apos;s IP68 protection. Technically, both phones can be submerged in one meter of water for 30 minutes, but the Pixel 8 is more likely to survive at slightly greater depths or longer durations. Don&apos;t go swimming with either phone, though.</p><p>While both phones have stereo speakers, the Pixel 8 has one extra microphone (3) than the Pixel 8a (2), which could make your voice clearer for phone calls. </p>
<h2 id="google-pixel-8a-vs-pixel-8-display-2">Google Pixel 8a vs. Pixel 8: Display</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="GryJcEWXbjLvqtupDhaqvL" name="pixel-8-23.jpg" alt="The Google Pixel 8 display" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GryJcEWXbjLvqtupDhaqvL.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Spec-wise, the 6.2-inch Pixel 8 and 6.1-inch Pixel 8a displays are extremely similar, aside from the slight size difference. </p><p>They share AMOLED displays with 2400 x 1080 resolution and 120Hz refresh rates (a step up from the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-7a-review">Pixel 7a</a>&apos;s 90Hz display). They each hit 1,400 nits for HDR or 2,000 nits for peak brightness. Visually, they have the same 1-million-to-1 contrast ratio and 16 million colors. Technically, the Pixel 8a beats the Pixel 8 by two pixels per inch (430 vs. 428), but you won&apos;t notice. </p><p>Both phones have a flat-edged design — none of the curving you get with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-pro-review">Pixel 8 Pro</a> or other flagships — and an in-display optical fingerprint sensor.</p><p>As mentioned before, the Pixel 8 has slightly smaller bezels than the Pixel 8a, which looks more visually appealing. Plus, the Pixel 8a only has Gorilla Glass 3, which is much less durable against cracks and scratches than the Victus on the mainline Pixel 8.</p>
<h2 id="google-pixel-8a-vs-pixel-8-hardware-and-cameras-2">Google Pixel 8a vs. Pixel 8: Hardware and cameras</h2>

<p>Google gave the Pixel 8a the same Tensor G3 chip, 8GB of RAM, and UFS 3.1 storage as the Pixel 8, presumably making their performance identical. Be warned, though: we learned that the Pixel 7a had a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/pixel-7a-tensor-g2-alleged-packaging">slightly worse version of the Tensor G2</a> a month after launch, so we can&apos;t be certain of the 8a&apos;s performance until we test it for ourselves. </p><p>Google&apos;s spec sheets list both phones as lasting 24 hours in normal conditions or 72 hours in Extreme Battery Saver mode. Specifically, the Pixel 8 has a typical 4,575mAh capacity or 4,485mAh minimum; the Pixel 8a hits 4,492mAh (typical) or 4,404mAh (minimum). </p><p>While the Pixel 8 does "win" here, the extra capacity will go straight to the extra display space, so it should be a wash. The Pixel 8 averaged about six hours of active screen time in our review testing, so expect the Pixel 8a to last about the same amount of time. </p><p>Google lists both phones as having "Fast Charging," but only the Pixel 8 has a guaranteed 50% charge in 30 minutes with 27W speeds. The Pixel 8a is only rated to hit 18W charging. While the Pixel 8 took about 75 minutes to recharge fully, we expect the Pixel 8a will take slightly longer. </p><p>As for wireless charging, the Pixel 8a will likely use the same (painfully slow) 5W charging as the Pixel 7a, giving the Pixel 8 the advantage for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-charging-pads">wireless charging pad</a> owners.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="XJrBJTbAnK5LULvLJybsBG" name="google-pixel-8a-official-lifestyle-obsidian-01.jpg" alt="A person holding an Obsidian Google Pixel 8a" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XJrBJTbAnK5LULvLJybsBG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Most of the key Pixel 8a vs. Pixel 8 differences pertain to camera specs and features. </p><p>While the Pixel 8a main camera has 64 megapixels to the Pixel 8&apos;s 50, the latter has an "Octa PD" system that enables autofocus shots, while the Pixel 8a has fixed focus. For point-and-shoot photography, the Pixel 8 is the simpler user option. You also have a lower aperture for better light capture. Both main sensors have 8X Super Res Zoom and optical image stabilization. </p><p>Only the Pixel 8 ultrawide camera has autofocus, and it gives you about six extra degrees of width on its shots. Both have the same aperture, but the Pixel 8a has a smaller pixel size. </p><p>For the front camera, both phones use a fixed-focus lens. Once again, the Pixel 8a selfie has a higher resolution (13MP)  and the same aperture, while the Pixel 8 has a 10.5MP dual PD camera with a larger pixel size. Of the two, only the Pixel 8 can film 4K 60FPS selfie videos, while the Pixel 8a maxes at 30FPS. </p><p>Thanks to its Tensor G3 chip, the Pixel 8a has most of its more expensive sibling&apos;s epic Google AI tricks, including <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-use-magic-editor-on-the-pixel-8">Magic Editor</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/how-to-use-best-take-on-the-pixel-8">Best Take</a>, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-audio-magic-eraser">Audio Magic Eraser</a>. However, Google reserves a couple of tricks for the Pixel 8, like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/how-to-use-macro-focus-on-pixel-7-pro">Macro Focus</a>, Macro Focus Video, and Cinematic Blur. </p>
<h2 id="google-pixel-8a-vs-pixel-8-software-and-connectivity-2">Google Pixel 8a vs. Pixel 8: Software and connectivity</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="hyrPidBKr4fAi7NHfCnQyD" name="Google-Pixel-8-best-shot-before.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 8 hands on with AI features" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hyrPidBKr4fAi7NHfCnQyD.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Whether you buy the Pixel 8 or Pixel 8a, you&apos;ll get seven years of software updates and security updates. Both launched with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review">Android 14</a>, which means they&apos;ll receive <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/what-does-android-21-look-like-on-pixel-8">Android 21 in seven years</a>. </p><p>It&apos;s fair to ask whether the Tensor G3 will hold up for that long, and you can rest assured that neither phone will get whatever new camera tricks come to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9">Pixel 9</a>. Nevertheless, this longevity is appreciated since it could increase both phones&apos; eventual trade-in value. </p><p>Google has also promised to bring <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini</a> to the Pixel 8a, in addition to popular AI tricks on the mainline Pixels like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-circle-to-search">Circle to Search</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-is-pixel-call-assist">Pixel Call Assist</a>.</p><p>Both phones support most 5G bands, including mmWave, in the United States. If you have a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/wi-fi-7-explained">Wi-Fi 7</a> router, the Pixel 8 is better equipped to take advantage of the extra speed; the Pixel 8a will get the benefits of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wi-fi-6e-router">Wi-Fi 6E routers</a>, at least. Also, the Pixel 8 has dual-band GPS support for better accuracy while using Google Maps, while the Pixel 8a might be more prone to signal blockage.</p>
<h2 id="google-pixel-8a-vs-pixel-8-which-should-you-buy-2">Google Pixel 8a vs. Pixel 8: Which should you buy?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="zHAkdeQq3P5TrA2YK9FedL" name="Google-Pixel-8-mint-colorway-holding-back-01.jpg" alt="The mint colorway of the Google Pixel 8" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zHAkdeQq3P5TrA2YK9FedL.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>As of publication, the Pixel 7a sits on our list of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a>, though the Pixel 8a is likely to supplant it once we&apos;ve reviewed it. It has the same perks — a mainline Tensor chip, Google AI processing behind solid cameras, and a cool design — while fixing many of its drawbacks, like the glossy back, dim brightness, lower refresh rate, and lack of 256B storage option. </p><p>The Pixel 8 still has the 8a beat in a couple of areas. Maybe you like to go caseless and need extra protection, have a Wi-Fi 7 router, like macro photography, or are really passionate about wireless charging. Otherwise, I think you can happily buy the Pixel 8a without the fear of missing out on anything drastic, especially since you&apos;ve gone this long without buying the Pixel 8. </p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="107bc669-d873-4ae5-8ca6-c774a387109c">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XjXDP3u2nLmLvarrAGcGeZ.jpg' alt='Google Pixel 8a'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 8a</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Barely a compromise</strong></em></p>
<p>Choose the Pixel 8a for a reasonable price, respectable performance, fun camera AI trickery, and more security updates than any other mid-range phone is likely to get. Skip it if you can't do without the best possible camera sensors offered by the mainline Pixel 8s. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="e344f1da-0226-4621-8b38-0176587609c2">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NVAviLLwEx5w5e8isxEjna.jpg' alt='Hazel Google Pixel 8'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 8</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Niche upgrades</strong></em></p>
<p>Choose the Pixel 8 for the best protection, connectivity and charging speeds, and a slightly larger display. Skip it if you want something more affordable, or you'd prefer the Pro for the best possible speed and photography. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-vs-pixel-8</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Pixel 8a is barely a compromise compared to last year's Pixel 8, but there are a few downgrades in exchange for the $200 off the price tag.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">enr5jK3y2qdWUjwRLoVx8F</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XqB69iVTHGU5aMR7PxjE2b.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 17:00:46 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XqB69iVTHGU5aMR7PxjE2b.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Renders of the Google Pixel 8a and Pixel 8]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Renders of the Google Pixel 8a and Pixel 8]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Pixel 8a vs. Pixel 7a: There's a definitive winner ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[         <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="92cd6177-3349-4c91-8727-a2800eab5fbb">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:136.23%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NuXNsh3rPHBW7h8dnBvdvQ.jpg' alt='An official product render of the front and back of the Aloe Google Pixel 8a'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 8a</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The obvious choice</strong></em></p>
<p>The biggest difference with the Pixel 8a is that the phone finally gets a 120Hz panel, bringing it on par with other mid-range devices. Google is also rolling out the same seven-year software update guarantee as the regular Pixel 8 series, and that gives the Pixel 8a a distinct edge in this category — no other mid-range phone will get as many updates. The cameras haven't changed, but you get all the latest AI features that debuted on the Pixel 8, and there's a 256GB model this time. The phone is costlier than last year, but the upgrades combined with long-term software updates means the Pixel 8a is an easy recommendation.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>120Hz OLED panel</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Seven years of software updates</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Terrific cameras</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Clean software with no bloatware</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>256GB model </li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Costlier than last year</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Charges at 18W</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Still not available in most global markets</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="762c91ee-34ac-4144-adc9-6c8c4595a799">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:150%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sEEPUMrnak3AUKjb64XLXc.jpg' alt='Official render of the Google Pixel 7a'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 7a</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Still great</strong></em></p>
<p>The Pixel 7a still has a lot to offer in 2024, and there isn't any area where the phone falls short. That said, it has a tendency to overheat during extended gaming sessions, so if playing games is a priority, you should look at the Pixel 8a instead. The cameras are the best in this segment, you get clean software, and the battery lasts a day. However, the Pixel 8a offers much better upgrades, and unless you're getting a great deal on the Pixel 7a, I'd suggest going with the 8a.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Better value</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Reliable in daily use</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Standout cameras at the back</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Clean software without any bloat</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>90Hz panel</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Limited to 128GB of storage</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Overheats while gaming</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Only three platform updates</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<h2 id="google-pixel-8a-vs-pixel-7a-design-2">Google Pixel 8a vs. Pixel 7a: Design</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="8vk8nBQLetvaiFmUpZZBPG" name="google-pixel-8a-official-lifestyle-aloe-01.jpg" alt="A person holding an Aloe Google Pixel 8a" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8vk8nBQLetvaiFmUpZZBPG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google has a distinct design aesthetic, and it hasn&apos;t deviated too much from that path with the Pixel 8a. The phone is nearly identical to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-7a-review">Pixel 7a</a>, so you get the same camera bar at the back that runs along the width, with the camera modules housed inside.</p><p>The key difference this time is that the phone has rounded corners, and that makes it a look a little more elegant while being easier to hold and use. Google is also rolling out exciting color options, with the Pixel 8a available in Aloe, Bay, Obsidian, and Porcelain. Aloe has a green hue that is quite striking, and Bay is the same great blue variant that debuted with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-pro-review">Pixel 8 Pro</a>, but it looks a little more vibrant.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="49AVQgVxLWzNimwEovQZeL" name="Google-Pixel-7a-back-02.jpg" alt="The back of the Charcoal Google Pixel 7a" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/49AVQgVxLWzNimwEovQZeL.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google is still using a polycarbonate back and an aluminum mid-frame, but the brand is using more recycled materials this time around. Interestingly, the Pixel 8a is touted to be more durable, but I don&apos;t know what that translates to in terms of real-world use — I&apos;ll share more after I&apos;ve used the phone for a while.</p><p>The Pixel 8a has roughly the same dimensions as the 7a, and coming in at 188g, it is a smidgen lighter. I like the Aloe and Bay color options, and while Google had issues with launching its more interesting colorways outside the U.S., it is doing a better job on that front — all four colors should be coming to all regions.</p>
<p>Given the similarities between the two devices, there isn&apos;t much to talk about the Pixel 7a. The phone has muted color choices, has a great in-hand feel, and I didn&apos;t see any issues on the design side of things after several months of usage. Both phones have IP67 ingress protection, giving them added resilience against the elements. On the whole, there really isn&apos;t much to distinguish the two devices in this area, but the rounded edges along with vibrant colors give the Pixel 8a a slender edge.</p>
<h2 id="google-pixel-8a-vs-pixel-7a-display-2">Google Pixel 8a vs. Pixel 7a: Display</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="Kdn7pHjPhJBkcTujnXXvP3" name="Google-pixel-7a-gaming-polytopia.jpg" alt="Playing the game Polytopia on a Google Pixel 7a" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Kdn7pHjPhJBkcTujnXXvP3.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google has been stingy with refresh rate on its mid-range phones; the Pixel 6a had a 60Hz panel, and the Pixel 7a came with a 90Hz panel. That&apos;s thankfully changing with the Pixel 8a — the phone has a 120Hz OLED panel, and it uses the same Actua tech that the brand debuted with the Pixel 8.</p><p>The screen gets noticeably brighter, going up to as high as 2,000 nits in HDR mode. Google hasn&apos;t changed the screen size, so you still get a 6.1-inch panel with a resolution of 2400 x 1080, and it has a layer of Gorilla Glass 3, just like the Pixel 7a. The always-on mode and At A Glance and Now Playing features are intact as well.</p><p>The switch to 120Hz is the biggest talking point, and it gives the Pixel 8a a sizeable advantage over the 7a. The 90Hz panel on the Pixel 7a is decent enough in its own right, but you can make out a difference when using the device alongside a 120Hz phone. So I&apos;m glad Google finally decided to roll out 120Hz refresh to the Pixel 8a, and it makes the device that much more enticing.</p>
<h2 id="google-pixel-8a-vs-pixel-7a-hardware-2">Google Pixel 8a vs. Pixel 7a: Hardware</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="W7ny4Hfq5wDz5NcBTChgsd" name="google-pixel-8a-official-parts.jpg" alt="The Aloe Google Pixel 8a alongside recycled materials" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/W7ny4Hfq5wDz5NcBTChgsd.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Not much has changed on the hardware side of things; the Pixel 8a gets the usual silicon upgrade, with the phone rocking Google&apos;s latest Tensor G3 platform. It has newer cores and much better performance, but thermal management is an unknown at this point. The Pixel 7a was severely constrained in this area, and even the Pixel 8 struggles with demanding workloads at times.</p><p>In that context, it will be interesting to see how the Pixel 8a holds up. The phone has the same 8GB of RAM as last year, and this time, Google is rolling out a 256GB model in addition to the base 128GB version. Limiting the Pixel 7a to 128GB was an oversight on Google&apos;s part last year, and I&apos;m glad to see the brand addressing that issue this time.</p>

<p>That said, the Pixel 8a has UFS 3.1 storage modules, and it misses out on the fastest UFS 4.0 storage. This doesn&apos;t make a difference in real-world use (at least not right now), but with the device slated to last the better part of a decade, UFS 4.0 would have been the better choice.</p><p>Coming to the battery, the Pixel 8a has a larger 4492mAh battery — versus the 4385mAh unit on the 7a — and it should last a little longer. It has the same 18W charging and 7.5W wireless charging as the Pixel 7a, and you don&apos;t get a charger in the box.</p><p>Google needs to do better with its charging tech, and with the Pixel 8 series going up to 27W now, that should have been the case with the Pixel 8a as well — 18W charging just isn&apos;t enough in 2024.</p>
<h2 id="google-pixel-8a-vs-pixel-7a-cameras-2">Google Pixel 8a vs. Pixel 7a: Cameras</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="imgvxRR8FUb2cmw5XGDHNL" name="Google-Pixel-7a-back-08.jpg" alt="The back of the Charcoal Google Pixel 7a" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/imgvxRR8FUb2cmw5XGDHNL.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div></figure>
<p>Google isn&apos;t making too many modifications to the cameras; the Pixel 8a has the same 64MP main camera at the back alongside a 13MP wide-angle lens, and there&apos;s a 13MP camera at the front. If that sounds familiar, it&apos;s because it is the same set of sensors as the Pixel 7a.</p><p>While the camera modules haven&apos;t changed, Google continually optimizes its algorithms, and the Pixel 8a should deliver noticeable gains in this area. Cameras have always been a strong selling point for Google — particularly the Pixel A series — and the Pixel 7a is still the best phone in this regard, but with the new imaging processor in the Pixel 8a, the phone is likely to take the crown. I&apos;ll share images and side-by-side shots of both devices shortly.</p>
<h2 id="google-pixel-8a-vs-pixel-7a-software-2">Google Pixel 8a vs. Pixel 7a: Software</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="rHqTnwm9mbE55iEUKUgEdB" name="Google-Pixel-7a-display-02.jpg" alt="The Google Pixel 7a's vibrant, bright display showcasing the home screen with the default coral feathers wallpaper" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rHqTnwm9mbE55iEUKUgEdB.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div></figure>
<p>Google guarantees seven years of software updates to the Pixel 8 and 8 Pro, and it is extending that to the Pixel 8a. The phone comes with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review">Android 14</a> out of the box and will get seven Android OS updates, and there&apos;s no other device that comes close to it in this segment. While Samsung also has the same guarantee, it&apos;s limited to the Galaxy S23 series, and the Galaxy A35 and A55 will get four updates.</p><p>The Pixel 7a, meanwhile, will get three platform updates along with five years of security updates. I didn&apos;t think Google would extend the same guarantee as its high-end phones to the Pixel 8a, but it is absolutely the right move.</p><p>What&apos;s also interesting is that the Pixel 8a is getting all the AI-focused features that debuted on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-review">Pixel 8</a> series. That includes Best Take, Audio Magic Eraser, and Magic Editor. The phone gets all the camera-focused additions as well, and that again gives it a big advantage over just about every other mid-range phone.</p><p>The software itself is clean and doesn&apos;t have any bloatware, and Google has a ton of useful features that make using its devices an absolute joy.</p>
<h2 id="google-pixel-8a-vs-pixel-7a-which-should-you-buy-2">Google Pixel 8a vs. Pixel 7a: Which should you buy?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="XJrBJTbAnK5LULvLJybsBG" name="google-pixel-8a-official-lifestyle-obsidian-01.jpg" alt="Holding an Obsidian Google Pixel 8a" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XJrBJTbAnK5LULvLJybsBG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Global availability is still a bit of an issue with Pixel phones, and while that is getting better, Google just doesn&apos;t have a presence in anywhere as many markets as its rivals. The Pixel 8a is launching in 17 countries, and there isn&apos;t a lengthy wait to get your hands on the device — it&apos;s going on sale globally starting May 14.</p><p>As much as I like the Pixel 7a, the 90Hz panel and lack of a 256GB model ultimately limit the device. The Pixel 8a doesn&apos;t have these problems, and just the fact that it has a 120Hz panel makes it worthy of consideration. Yes, it has minor upgrades in all areas, but it&apos;s the screen and the seven-year update guarantee that makes the phone stand out. It is the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-android-phones">best mid-range phone</a> you can get today. </p><p>If you need a new phone that can last the better part of a decade and takes fantastic photos and videos, the Pixel 8a is the obvious choice. Coming in at $499, it is $50 more than the Pixel 7a, but you&apos;re also getting better hardware. If you want to maximize value, I&apos;d suggest waiting until there&apos;s a good deal on the Pixel 7a. Anything in the vicinity to $300 is a terrific price for the device, and you&apos;re still getting feature-rich software and outstanding cameras.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="91018eb8-43be-4153-8ed7-f80f8df3b0e1">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:136.23%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NuXNsh3rPHBW7h8dnBvdvQ.jpg' alt='An official product render of the front and back of the Aloe Google Pixel 8a'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 8a</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The best mid-ranger</strong></em></p>
<p>Thanks to a 120Hz panel and seven years of software updates, the Pixel 8a is the best mid-range phone you can get in 2024. There really isn't another device that offers the same combination of cameras, clean software, and long-term updates.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="d0af22cd-dfbd-4154-8504-aeab3ce7a5ac">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:150%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sEEPUMrnak3AUKjb64XLXc.jpg' alt='Official render of the Google Pixel 7a'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 7a</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Still great</strong></em></p>
<p>I think the Pixel 7a is still a great choice, and the cameras are the main reason to pick up the phone. However, the Pixel 8a is a better all-round choice, and you should only consider the Pixel 7a if you can get it at a good deal.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-vs-pixel-7a</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Pixel 8a is now available, and it has exciting upgrades over the Pixel 7a that make it a magnificent choice.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">4o62QTJdocRrKcsDcmyvue</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8vk8nBQLetvaiFmUpZZBPG.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 16:30:37 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8vk8nBQLetvaiFmUpZZBPG.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A person holding an Aloe Google Pixel 8a]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A person holding an Aloe Google Pixel 8a]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>