<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 02:14:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung Galaxy S25 vs. Galaxy S23: Finally time for an upgrade? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[         <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="94b70110-8aa0-4a9d-bfeb-6baf6190df5c">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JyBHooJcxaVXhoASHXQEuc.jpg' alt="Leaked render of the Galaxy S25"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S25</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The next base-model Galaxy flagship</strong></em></p><p>It's true that we don't know exactly what the Samsung Galaxy S25 will bring; however, reliable leaks paint a pretty good picture. We're expecting a new phone with a similar design, a Qualcomm Snapdragon 8 Elite chipset, and One UI 7. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Qualcomm Snapdragon 8 Elite processor with custom Oryon cores (rumored)</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>One UI 7 (Android 15) available at launch with seven years of OS upgrades</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>New Galaxy AI features (assumed)</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>A bigger screen and slightly larger form factor (rumored)</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Higher price point due to Snapdragon 8 Elite chipset (rumored)</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Not available currently with expected launch window of mid-January 2025</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Snapdragon 8 Elite could pose thermal and battery life problems</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="1a5b7d14-5745-441d-b88b-b9322b667d60">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TS4sHKwoTVLEJNMGjugfFi.jpg' alt="Official render of the Galaxy S23 in green"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S23</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Still going strong in 2024</strong></em></p><p>So far, it's been a fantastic year for the Samsung Galaxy S23. It's very similar to the newer Galaxy S24, and it received a few significant software updates. That includes the bump to One UI 6 and a bunch of top Galaxy AI features. This phone has a lot of life left in it, but the Galaxy S25 could entice some users to upgrade early.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Snapdragon 8 Gen 2 chipset is still capable in 2024</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>This phone will still get a couple of OS upgrades</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Great battery life</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Much cheaper than the newer Galaxy S24, and expectedly the Galaxy S25</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Slow wired charging</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Aging camera hardware</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Retail availability will be hard to come by</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<p>Samsung needs a win with the upcoming Galaxy S25 series. The company is facing major issues and delays with its One UI 7 update, based on Android 15. It's also <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/is-samsung-sorry-for-failing-to-innovate-or-just-sorry-sales-are-down">apologizing for failing to innovate</a>. While we don't know exactly what the Samsung Galaxy S25 will look like, we do know a whole lot based on leaks and rumors ahead of the phone's expected mid-January launch.</p><p>With a Qualcomm Snapdragon 8 Elite chipset, a bigger display, slight design tweaks, and a software overhaul, the Galaxy S25 could indeed be a massive victory. The question is, will the upgrades be tempting enough to make people still rocking a Samsung Galaxy S23 want to upgrade? That's what we'll help you start to figure out in this early comparison.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-s25-vs-galaxy-s23-design-2">Samsung Galaxy S25 vs. Galaxy S23: Design</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3699px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.26%;"><img id="DzgsjUdUBJbMPWDkgoyaKP" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S23-review-rear-outdoors.jpg" alt="The Galaxy S23 in hand" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DzgsjUdUBJbMPWDkgoyaKP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3699" height="2081" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>If you've been keeping a close eye on new Samsung phones recently, you probably have a good idea of where the Samsung Galaxy S25's design is headed. With the Galaxy Z Fold 6, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-6-review">Galaxy Z Flip 6</a>, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-fe-hands-on">Galaxy S24 FE</a>, the company moved to a flat and more rectangular design language. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-leaked-renders-reveal-flat-design">Based on the latest renders</a>, we expect the Galaxy S25 to follow a similar pattern. It'll likely be a boxy phone with matte aluminum rails and a new lens covering around the rear camera system, closely resembling the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Galaxy Z Fold 6</a>.</p><p>The exact dimensions of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25">Galaxy S25</a> are up in the air, but rumors suggest the phone could have a chassis measuring 146.94 x 70.46 x 7.25mm. That would be slightly smaller than the current Galaxy S24 and the older Galaxy S23. The phone's weight could be around the 168-gram mark. As far as durability is concerned, an IP68 water and dust-resistance rating and Gorilla Glass coverings are near locks.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1408px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="GSTZrT4GF3toZ8EVFwdWhh" name="samsung-galaxy-s25-angled-side-early-alleged-rendering.jpeg" alt="Another alleged angled rendering of the Galaxy S25." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GSTZrT4GF3toZ8EVFwdWhh.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1408" height="792" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The biggest change to the Galaxy S25 could be the display size. The older <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s23-i-just-cant">Samsung Galaxy S23</a> features a 6.1-inch AMOLED display, but the Galaxy S25 could receive a bump to a 6.3-inch panel. That would follow industry trends, which are consistently shifting to favor larger displays. For example, Apple made the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/apple-iphone-16-pro-max-review">iPhone 16 Pro and Pro Max</a> larger this year.</p><p>Although the Galaxy S23 will have a smaller screen, it'll likely keep up with the newer model in terms of display specs. We expect both phones to have a 120Hz AMOLED panel with variable refresh rates and high brightness capabilities.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="dKDSMyFkuHBoPJcHRZAFY8" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S23-review-display-outdoors-1.jpg" alt="The Galaxy S23 outdoors next to a pillar" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dKDSMyFkuHBoPJcHRZAFY8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4080" height="2295" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In terms of colors, the latest leaks reveal <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-series-color-options-tipped">the Galaxy S25 should come in at least four colors</a>: Moon Night Blue, Silver Shadow, Sparkling Blue, and Sparkling Green. Meanwhile, the Galaxy S23 came in many more colors: Cobalt Violet, Amber Yellow, Onyx Black, Marble Grey (Samsung exclusive Jade Green, Sapphire Blue, Sandstone Orange). In all likelihood, Samsung still has a few online exclusives up its sleeve for the Galaxy S25 series.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-s25-vs-galaxy-s23-hardware-and-specs-2">Samsung Galaxy S25 vs. Galaxy S23: Hardware and specs</h2>
<p>Those looking for a major camera upgrade on the Samsung Galaxy S25 series may end up once again disappointed. Top rumors indicate that the Galaxy S25 will have the same camera hardware as the Galaxy S24, which, unfortunately, would also be the same as the Galaxy S23. However, there are also leaks that predict Samsung could make a major camera hardware switch to Sony sensors, but this is something that leakers can't agree on yet.</p><p>If the Galaxy S25 indeed sticks with the same camera hardware, both phones in this comparison would feature a 50MP main shooter, a 12MP ultrawide lens, and a 10MP telephoto lens supporting 3x optical zoom. There could be some quality improvements, even with the same hardware, based on improved image-signal processing and computational photography features.</p>

<p>The exact memory and storage configurations are unknown, as are the connectivity options. However, we're looking for the Galaxy S25 to get 5G support, Wi-Fi 7, and Bluetooth 5.3, which would make it competitive with recent flagship releases.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-s25-vs-galaxy-s23-performance-and-software-2">Samsung Galaxy S25 vs. Galaxy S23: Performance and software</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3573px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="N3j7ApGKMWFvn5gPUaKQu8" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S23-review-battery-life.jpg" alt="Galaxy S23 estimated battery life" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/N3j7ApGKMWFvn5gPUaKQu8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3573" height="2009" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The key things to watch on the Samsung Galaxy S25 are the phone's performance and software. It's tabbed to get the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/snapdragon-8-elite">Qualcomm Snapdragon 8 Elite</a> chip, which you can think of as a Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 successor. It's called 'Elite' because it now uses the same custom Oryon cores that power Qualcomm's Snapdragon X Elite laptop chips. In other words, the Snapdragon 8 Elite will be the most performant chip ever in a Galaxy phone.</p><p>However, we don't know what effect that will have on thermals, performance, or battery life. Some rumors suggest the Galaxy S25 will get a 5,000mAh battery to help make the phone longer-lasting. Additionally, reports indicate that the Snapdragon 8 Elite is an expensive chip, and its inclusion could drive the price upward.</p><p>On the flip side, the Galaxy S23 still sports the Snapdragon 8 Gen 2 for Galaxy processor. It's going to be two years old when the Galaxy S25 debuts, but it's still plenty capable. It'll eventually get the jump to One UI 7 and currently supports a wide variety of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-galaxy-ai">Galaxy AI</a> features. Plus, there are still a few years of software upgrades left.</p><p>One UI 7 is expected to launch on the Galaxy S25, but it's a bit of a wild card. There have been <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-one-ui-7-beta-pushed-back-again">extensive delays to One UI 7's development and release</a>, partly because it's an ambitious update. If Samsung pulls it off, it'll be a key reason why the Galaxy S25 sets itself apart. However, if its struggles continue, the phone could be a buggy mess at launch.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-s25-vs-galaxy-s23-should-you-upgrade-2">Samsung Galaxy S25 vs. Galaxy S23: Should you upgrade?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3593px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="FjUR3TmWXa7WQyYkknxcYP" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S23-review-lavender.jpg" alt="The Lavender Galaxy S23 in hand" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FjUR3TmWXa7WQyYkknxcYP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3593" height="2021" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>As we look toward the Samsung Galaxy S25's expected mid-January launch, it's time to start thinking about whether Galaxy S23 owners should upgrade. Buying the Galaxy S25 two years after purchasing the Galaxy S23 could be a tough sell. That's especially true if the design is lackluster and the cameras are unchanged. But the Snapdragon 8 Elite chipset, a bigger screen, and new software features might be tempting.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="2c165276-9b43-42e1-9400-5255c4a093ab">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JyBHooJcxaVXhoASHXQEuc.jpg' alt="Leaked render of the Galaxy S25"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S25</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>It'll soon be the latest and greatest</strong></em></p><p>Samsung is known for fairly small year-over-year upgrades, but the Galaxy S25 might offer enough improvements over the Galaxy S23 to make users consider a switch. Some things we're expecting include a Snapdragon 8 Elite chip, a bigger screen, and a larger battery. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="d87cdb96-2f8c-4b48-9aa8-75416fc72183">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HHQbvCqdVy4zwbwAWctofZ.jpg' alt="samsung galaxy s23 render in lavender"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S23</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Not done yet</strong></em></p><p>The Samsung Galaxy S23 is getting older, there's no doubt about that. But with a Snapdragon 8 Gen 2 chipset, Galaxy AI features, and a few software upgrade to come, the Galaxy S23 still has plenty of life left in it.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-vs-galaxy-s23</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Samsung Galaxy S25 might be just enticing enough to make Galaxy S23 users upgrade. Here's everything we know so far.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">3dwoXrX4P4D6r4HzWBu8Y7</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tZQn87CgjBz3JVFDRMHmaN.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 22:42:17 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tZQn87CgjBz3JVFDRMHmaN.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[null]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Holding the Galaxy S23]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Holding the Galaxy S23]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ It's a TRAP! Don't be tempted by this Galaxy Watch FE Black Friday deal; there's a MUCH better option ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>I don't quote Admiral Ackbar lightly, but when our site's Commerce Editor recommended a deal post on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Bluetooth-Smartwatch-Personalized-Manufacturer/dp/B0D3216K2G"><strong>Galaxy Watch FE for $126 (37% off)</strong></a>, the words "It's a trap!" flashed through my mind. Yes, I'm a nerd. But I'm also here to point you to a much better Black Friday smartwatch deal, so don't laugh too hard.</p><p>I recommend you spend just $13 more and buy the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Bluetooth-Smartwatch-Personalized-Advanced/dp/B0C792QRW6"><strong>Galaxy Watch 6 for $139 (53% off)</strong></a>. It's not because of the higher-percentage discount — the last-gen Watch 6 shouldn't really cost $299 at full price anymore — but because it's objectively a much better watch than the FE that'll give you less buyer's remorse.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="7fbbd703-1316-4641-8a45-079ac5667153" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Price comparison: Best Buy - $149" data-dimension48="Price comparison: Best Buy - $149" data-dimension25="$139.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Bluetooth-Smartwatch-Personalized-Advanced/dp/B0C792QRW6" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="ZFk8tX7bD9dZBwf8oaBae8" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Watch-6-square-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZFk8tX7bD9dZBwf8oaBae8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="800" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>The Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 may be a year older than the Galaxy Watch FE, but it has a higher-clocked processor, 33% more RAM, a larger display with doubled brightness, an extra temperature sensor for sleep data, and a thinner design overall. The last-gen Watch FE just can't keep up.</p><p><strong>Price comparison: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-watch6-aluminum-smartwatch-40mm-bt-graphite/6546704.p?skuId=6546704" data-dimension112="7fbbd703-1316-4641-8a45-079ac5667153" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Price comparison: Best Buy - $149" data-dimension48="Price comparison: Best Buy - $149" data-dimension25="$139.99">Best Buy - $149</a> | <a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/watches/galaxy-watch6/buy/galaxy-watch6-40mm-gold-bt-sm-r930nzedxaa/?modelCode=SM-R930NZKAXAA">Samsung - $149</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Bluetooth-Smartwatch-Personalized-Advanced/dp/B0C792QRW6" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="7fbbd703-1316-4641-8a45-079ac5667153" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Price comparison: Best Buy - $149" data-dimension48="Price comparison: Best Buy - $149" data-dimension25="$139.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Black Friday deals</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Black Friday Google Pixel deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Black Friday Motorola deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024">Black Friday Samsung deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Black Friday OnePlus deals</a></p></div></div>
<p>As the person who <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-6-review">reviewed the Galaxy Watch 6</a>, I was tapped to write this guide on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-fe-vs-galaxy-watch-6">Galaxy Watch FE vs. Watch 6</a>, which lays out in excruciating detail all of the downgrades Samsung gave the Watch FE to make it cheap: It has the same last-gen Exynos W920 as the 2021 Galaxy Watch 4, only 1.5GB of RAM, a smaller and thicker-bordered display, an older Bluetooth standard, no skin temperature sensor, and a smaller 247mAh capacity.</p><p>The jump from 1.2- to 1.3-inch display — or 1.5 if you buy the 44mm Watch 6 for $159 — 1,000 to 2,000 nits of brightness, 53mAh extra battery capacity, 1.18GHz to 1.4GHz clock speed, and 0.5GB more RAM may not sound like much on paper, but they really add up in terms of better visibility, longer stretches between charges, and shorter lag waiting for apps to open.</p><p>If the lowest price possible is your concern, then rest assured that the Galaxy Watch FE is a <em>good</em> watch; it tops our list of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-smartwatch-android">best cheap Android watches</a> for a reason. But what made it a good compromise was that other Galaxy Watches cost $100 more; thanks to Black Friday, that's no longer true! And its older CPU ensures it may not keep up with new Wear OS updates as ably as the Watch 6.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="44bd5e83-516e-4115-993e-1b201e8572aa" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Galaxy Watch 4" data-dimension48="Galaxy Watch 4" data-dimension25="$126.71" href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Bluetooth-Smartwatch-Personalized-Manufacturer/dp/B0D3216K2G" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:513px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="ZfXmxxNoMUKPZUVs7mey2M" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Watch-FE-render.jpeg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZfXmxxNoMUKPZUVs7mey2M.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="513" height="513" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>Compared to the Watch 6, the Galaxy Watch FE has most of the same health sensors, a Sapphire Glass layer and MIL-STD-810H ruggedness layer, a cool multi-color watch band for extra character, and years of Wear OS updates to come. It has some downgraded traits from the older <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/samsung-galaxy-watch-4-review" data-dimension112="44bd5e83-516e-4115-993e-1b201e8572aa" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Galaxy Watch 4" data-dimension48="Galaxy Watch 4" data-dimension25="$126.71">Galaxy Watch 4</a>, but it's a great entry-level watch for bargain hunters.</p><p><strong>Price comparison: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-watch-fe-smartwatch-40mm-bt-black/6584970.p?skuId=6584970">Best Buy - $159</a> | <a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/watches/galaxy-watch-fe/buy/galaxy-watch-fe-40mm-pink-gold-bluetooth-sm-r861nidaxaa/">Samsung - $159</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Bluetooth-Smartwatch-Personalized-Manufacturer/dp/B0D3216K2G" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="44bd5e83-516e-4115-993e-1b201e8572aa" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Galaxy Watch 4" data-dimension48="Galaxy Watch 4" data-dimension25="$126.71">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>The Galaxy Watch 6 doesn't need that "cheap" label to be relevant; it's still one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch">best Android watches</a> available today, specifically our pick for the "best last-generation smartwatch" today. Although the Galaxy Watch 7 is <em>also</em> discounted for Black Friday — <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Bluetooth-Smartwatch-Wellness-Manufacturer/dp/B0D1YQKDML"><strong>currently $97 off</strong></a> — the Watch 6 will save you an extra $63 and won't feel as much like a downgrade as the Watch FE.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/its-a-trap-dont-be-tempted-by-this-galaxy-watch-fe-black-friday-deal-theres-a-much-better-option</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Galaxy Watch FE is basically a reskinned Galaxy Watch 4. It's a solid budget option, but there's no way you should buy one when the Watch 6 is $160 off. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">FBJFPSSQQjsUAZc9Ztuh3W</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TTdXzxTHipzSXrHWzAA7n6.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 22:18:21 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TTdXzxTHipzSXrHWzAA7n6.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Watch FE watchface]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Watch FE watchface]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Wear OS 5.1 preview is now available — and it's based on Android 15 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The next version of Wear OS, called Wear OS 5.1, is now available for testing as a developer preview.</li><li>The Android 15-based software update can be manually tested within the Android Studio emulator in a virtual Wear OS device.</li><li>Although it's still early, new features include the ability to play audio out of smartwatch speakers and access the new Credential Manager API.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google is giving us our first look at the next Wear OS update, which is based on Android 15. The company <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://developer.android.com/training/wearables/versions/5-1" target="_blank">released</a> the first developer preview of Wear OS 5.1 last week, and it's now available for testing in an Android Studio virtual device. Although it's still early, Google already revealed two key Wear OS 5.1 features: watch speaker audio playback and a credential manager.</p><p>The build number for the initial Wear OS 5.1 preview release is <strong>AP4A.241205.004.F1</strong>, and there are a few known issues. Google recommends developers start testing their Wear OS apps with the latest version to adjust to behavior changes in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a>. Notably, some Android 15 behavior changes won't be arriving on Wear OS 5.1, like Private Spaces and predictive back animations. The known bugs are as follows:</p>
<ul><li>The emulator doesn't always allow the user to add an account during the setup flow following a device reset.</li><li>When tapping on a notification, the app that sent the notification doesn't open until the user scrolls the screen.</li><li>Wear Health Services sometimes fails to start an exercise.</li></ul>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Confirmed: Wear OS 5.1 is the next version of Wear OS, and it's based on Android 15 just as I previously reported. https://t.co/t0pgSRpCW6 pic.twitter.com/lXLkbyxti6<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1861064684826251701">November 25, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>The update currently includes two "notable features," as described by Google. The first is watch speaker playback, which will allow users to listen to audio sources through a smartwatch's inbuilt speaker. This could be a convenient way to listen to music or podcasts, albeit at low volume and subpar quality. To use your watch speaker as an audio output option, both the device's hardware and the specified app must support it in Wear OS 5.1.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="V4LxpJjZ88vsDoXPQrbNrg" name="Google-Pixel-Watch-3-water" alt="A close up of an info-packed watch face on the Google Pixel Watch 3, held above a pond" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/V4LxpJjZ88vsDoXPQrbNrg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The other notable feature is support for the Credential Manager API. This is already available on Android, and it <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/upgrading-to-a-new-phone-android-can-now-keep-your-apps-signed-in-after-restoring-from-a-backup">enables features like auto-sign-in after restoring from a backup</a>. On Wear OS 5.1, the new credential manager will handle passwords, passkeys, and Sign in with Google. It'll also allow this information to be synced across Wear OS 5.1 and Android 15 devices.</p><p>Depending on the release date of Wear OS 5.1, this update could signal the platform catching up with Android. Typically, Wear OS updates have been based on preceding Android versions. For example, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/wear-os-5">Wear OS 5</a> is based on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review">Android 14</a>. The naming of Wear OS 5.1 could indicate that Google is trying to sync up Wear OS and Android. Or, it could simply mean that this year's Wear OS update is a minor one and not worthy of a full numbered version. After all, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16">Android 16 Developer Preview 1</a> is here, so it's not that surprising that we're seeing a new version of Wear OS made available for testing as well.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/the-wear-os-5-1-preview-is-now-available-and-its-based-on-android-15</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google released the Wear OS 5.1 preview for developers, and it's surprisingly Android 15-based. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Gj5kLz4qXcQPmfyxb7DVHn</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PqXZpoB9SLWbgwNXTMhvZh.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 20:59:17 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PqXZpoB9SLWbgwNXTMhvZh.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Wear OS 5 app drawer on the Google Pixel Watch 3]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Wear OS 5 app drawer on the Google Pixel Watch 3]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung's mid-range Galaxy A56 render leak showcases minimal design changes ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung's next higher mid-range phone to sport same design as the predecessor.</li><li>The Galaxy A56 will again sport three rear cameras, flat display, Key Island, and probably a new pink shade.</li><li>The Galaxy device is also tipped to sport 45W fast charging and with a Exynos 1580 chip underneath.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Samsung might be more than a couple of months away from launching the Galaxy A56 for the masses. However, that doesn’t stop leaks of renders showcasing the device in full.</p><p>OnLeaks and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidheadlines.com/samsung-galaxy-a56">Android Headlines</a> have shared the first high-quality renders of the Galaxy A56, the company’s one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-android-phones">mid-range smartphones</a> for 2025. It should be launched sometime in the first quarter of next year.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Good Morning #FutureSquad! Today comes your very first look at the #Samsung #GalaxyA56 (360° video + gorgeous 5K renders + dimensions)!😏On behalf of @Androidheadline 👉🏻 https://t.co/H4dwH89yZA pic.twitter.com/Dz1bJFAjjA<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1860977134342115647">November 25, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>The shared CAD-based renders again reveal a familiar design as its predecessor, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-launches-galaxy-a55-and-a35">Galaxy A55</a>, featuring flat edges and rounded corners. It will have a flat punch-hole display and three rear cameras stacked vertically on the back. A slight difference; however, is that the A55’s rear cameras were placed individually, whereas the placement on the Galaxy A56 appears to be stacked in a single camera module.</p><p>The publication also implies Samsung should be borrowing the “Key Island” design elements introduced in Galaxy A55 alongside the budget Galaxy A15 and Galaxy 25 phones from last year, where the power button and volume rockers are a bit raised on the right pane of the device to spot them easily.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="mcV2jNHxbtFnXLAQoe5aVj" name="samsung-galaxy-a56-renders-01" alt="Galaxy A56 renders" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mcV2jNHxbtFnXLAQoe5aVj.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OnLeaks/ Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="q3JSoHMdznWy3K3zDxRXVj" name="samsung-galaxy-a56-renders" alt="Galaxy A56 renders" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/q3JSoHMdznWy3K3zDxRXVj.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OnLeaks/ Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>While the expected specifications are still unclear, Android Headlines highlights that the device might feature 45W fast charging similar to the flagship Galaxy phones despite the Galaxy A56 being a mid-range phone. According to a recent Chinese certification, the device is also expected to be powered by the Exynos 1580 SoC, which was announced in October.</p><p>If the launch of the predecessor models is any indication, the Galaxy A56 should be released in March 2025 in markets starting with Europe and likely priced under €500.</p>
<p>On the other hand, Samsung’s other Galaxy A series device, dubbed Galaxy A26, was <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-a26-renders-surface-online-revealing-its-design">spotted in the renders</a>—also shared by OnLeaks last week—giving us a good look at the design and some of the expected specifications of the sub-$300 Galaxy phone.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u><strong><br></strong></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-a56-renders-leak</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The first CAD-based renders of the Galaxy A56 device leak right after us witnessing Galaxy A26 renders last week ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">3g7ksJ2JFe6D4BXneGfnEZ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ShKo6QTKmn4wH2H5URhTVj.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 20:27:20 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ShKo6QTKmn4wH2H5URhTVj.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[OnLeaks/ Android Headlines]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Galaxy A56 renders]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Galaxy A56 renders]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Ask Jerry: Why are there old photos in my Google Drive? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Welcome to Ask Jerry, where we talk about any and all the questions you might have about the smart things in your life. I'm Jerry, and I have spent the better part of my life working with tech. I have a background in engineering and R&D and have been covering Android and Google for the past 15 years.</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Ask Jerry</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="rbW6k4ZmBUAZL7mR2bMnV6" name="jerrydude-avatar.gif" caption="" alt="Android Avatar of Jerry" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rbW6k4ZmBUAZL7mR2bMnV6.gif" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Future)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">Ask Jerry is a column where we answer your burning Android/tech questions with the help of long-time Android Central editor Jerry Hildenbrand.</p></div></div>
<p>I'm also really good at researching data about everything — that's a big part of our job here at Android Central — and I love to help people (another big part of our job!). If you have questions about your tech, I'd love to talk about them.</p><p>Email me at <strong>askjerryac@gmail.com</strong>, and I'll try to get things sorted out. You can remain anonymous if you like, and we promise we're not sharing anything we don't cover here.</p><p>I look forward to hearing from you!</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="why-are-old-duplicate-photos-in-my-google-drive-folders-and-what-should-i-do-with-them-2">Why are old duplicate photos in my Google Drive folders and what should I do with them?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="gLFsyoeKH29Ln8HLjbtDJX" name="google-drive-lifestyle.jpg" alt="Google Drive on an Android phone and a laptop" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gLFsyoeKH29Ln8HLjbtDJX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Future)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><em><strong>Jeremy asks:</strong></em></p><p><em><strong>I just noticed that Google seems to have duplicate copies of my whole photo library, which, I'm guessing, is a waste of space.  There's a whole directory in My Drive that seems to be a duplicate of old family photos I scanned years ago, sorted by year and, I guess, not really needed.</strong></em></p><p><em><strong>What's going on here? Does this count against my Google storage limit? Most importantly, can I delete all this?</strong></em></p>
<p>Hi Jeremy! You've stumbled across a secret Google feature that gives you a look at what sets Google apart when it comes to online services: the unintended, multilayered problem.</p><p>On a serious note, this happens (or <em>happened</em>, as we'll see later) to some folks who used <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-set-google-photos">Google Photos</a> in its early days but didn't affect others. The short answer to your questions: you're seeing duplicates because Google Photos stores its files in a hidden folder in your shared Google storage. Yes, it counts against your storage the same way any files you purposefully uploaded to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-drive">Google Drive</a>, and you can delete the folder(s) from Google Drive after you verify you have copies in the Google Photos app. For a discussion of the mess, read on!</p>
<p>Not everyone sees these old duplicate files. At some point, Google changed how Photos stores its data, but it still is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-photos-uploads-will-soon-count-towards-your-google-drive-storage">part of your overall storage space provided by Google</a>. Before this, you could see your Google Photos storage in Drive if you knew where and how to look for it, but it was intended to be hidden.</p><p>During the transition, some people had folders duplicated while the way they were stored changed. I've heard this has to do with specific metadata, how the files were added to Photos, or what device was used to upload them. These theories could be correct, or they could be 100% wrong; regardless, it happened, and when it happened, the folders became visible like any other folder in Drive.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="kyyZs7NSMFx6cQgMZZ3abg" name="google-photos-lifestyle-widescreen-crop.jpg" alt="Google Photos on a Pixel 4a" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kyyZs7NSMFx6cQgMZZ3abg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>These folders are no longer associated with Google Photos and that means they are duplicated elsewhere in a way you can't (easily) find them. It also means they are taking up space.</p><p>You have a limited amount of space associated with your Google account. You <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-one">can pay to have more if you need it</a>, or you can manage your stored and saved files so you don't reach the limit.</p><p>These duplicate folders can be safely deleted once you've double-checked to make sure the photos are also stored in the Google Photos app. <strong>Do not delete them until you have checked. </strong>Never trust anything without verifying it for yourself.</p>
<p>One thing you might want to look at before you delete anything is the quality of the photo being stored, <em>especially</em> if you used to have an original<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare"> Pixel</a> or a Pixel 2.</p><p>It used to be that if you had a Pixel phone, your photos were stored at full quality without any cost to your shared storage allotment. Other photos had their quality reduced; it was still high-quality and is likely good enough for anything other than trying to have physical prints made, but there is a difference.</p><p>There is a chance that these "duplicate" photos would be full quality and the photos in Google Photos are not. This situation happened to me when I got hit with the weird duplication bug/mess/Googleism. A bunch of photos I took with the first Pixel phone were stored in full resolution and quality in my Google Drive but the "copies" in Google Photos were not.</p><p>It's up to you to decide if you want or need these larger-sized files (I didn't), but if you don't know and don't check, you can't decide.</p>
<p>One last thing to note — this happened to a <em>lot</em> of people, and it's probably worth checking if you are one of them and don't know it. Just open your Google Drive and look through all the stuff that's stored there. If you see folders full of pictures, this is probably why.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/ask-jerry-why-are-there-old-photos-in-my-google-drive</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Have a question about the tech in your life? If so, maybe we can get them answered! ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">YCe8rfM6sWNGFqytFFysGo</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HrmCzNcQDgwjg2sArrBf7S.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 20:24:28 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HrmCzNcQDgwjg2sArrBf7S.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android statues]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android statues]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Roku Channel set to gain deeper integration with Google TV for easier access to free content ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The Roku Channel is becoming deeper integrated with Google TV devices, including televisions, set-top boxes, and Chromecasts.</li><li>You can now search for The Roku Channel content in Google TV, find it on the home screen, and in Google TV's collection of live TV channels.</li><li>Roku says that it offers more than 80,000 movies and TV shows completely free as part of The Roku Channel.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google TV already offers a bunch of free content on its platform, including The Roku Channel. However, it will become much easier to discover and use The Roku Channel on Google TV thanks to deeper integration between the two services, Roku <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.roku.com/blog/trc-googletv" target="_blank">announced</a> today. This will bolster Google TV's free content and make it easier to find and watch the tens of thousands of movies and TV shows made available as part of The Roku Channel.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/roku">Roku</a> first added The Roku Channel to Google TV last year, in limited form. There wasn't support for Google TV's search or discoverability functions at the time. That's beginning to change, as Roku says a more integrated experience will be available "in the coming weeks." For starters, Google TV users will be able to search for content from The Roku Channel using the native search function in Android TV.</p><p>Additionally, 500 live TV channels from Roku will join the live tab on Google TV.  The platform already offers nearly 1,000 free or ad-supported live TV channels, and the new ones from The Roku Channel will provide even more options, including channels with news, sports, cooking, DIY, music, and other types of programming.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="oXcrZwfzk2M2rzeMv2kqtQ" name="google-tv-streamer-review-free-live-tv-2.jpg" alt="Google TV Streamer Free Live TV" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oXcrZwfzk2M2rzeMv2kqtQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>A big part of Google TV is the platform's recommendations. There is so much free content on the platform that some users might want help finding what to watch next, and Google recommends content based on your previous watch history. Soon, free Roku movies and TV shows will appear in the <strong>Featured on The Roku Channel</strong>, <strong>Continue watching</strong>, and <strong>Free live TV</strong> on the Google TV home screen.</p><p>Roku says that the free content available via The Roku Channel includes select live MLB games, ABC News broadcasts, and over 80,000 movies and TV shows.</p><p>Whether you have a brand-new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/google-tv-streamer-review">Google TV Streamer</a> or an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/google-tv-streamer-vs-chromecast-with-google-tv-4k">older Chromecast</a>, your Google TV device will get The Roku Channel integration. It'll also be available on any third-party device with Google TV built-in. If you want to get an early look at the content that'll become more closely engrained in your streaming device, you can try out The Roku Channel on Google TV, Fire TV, Samsung devices, and the Roku web and mobile apps.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/the-roku-channel-set-to-gain-deeper-integration-with-google-tv-for-easier-access-to-free-content</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google TV already had content from The Roku Channel, but it'll now be in more places and easier to find. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">LvUXSiTKtSox4xvYoNyCyV</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NcrVgZ5rEAFFffvDNAvrPg.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 20:22:04 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Streaming &amp; TV]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NcrVgZ5rEAFFffvDNAvrPg.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central / Roku]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Roku Channel on a Google TV device.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Roku Channel on a Google TV device.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Rumors say the OnePlus Watch 3 is coming up on a global launch ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Rumors on X state the OnePlus Watch 3 will "launch soon" in global markets outside of China.</li><li>The tipster lists the watch's upcoming launch alongside the global debut of the OnePlus 13 and 13R, though it's unclear if they will all roll out together.</li><li>Early Watch 3 rumors suggest it could arrive with a 500mAh battery, LTE, and eSIM support.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>OnePlus rolled out its 2024 smartwatch early this year; however, a new set of rumors claims it's looking to double dip.</p><p>According to a post on X by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/heyitsyogesh/status/1860932345097867411">Yogesh Brar</a>, OnePlus is gearing up to launch its next flagship smartwatch with some friends (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/oneplus-watch-3-global-launch-13-13r-3502836/">Android Authority</a>). Brar states in their post that the OnePlus Watch 3 will "launch soon in global markets." Unfortunately, they don't state how soon consumers can expect this device, especially considering we're a week out from December.</p><p>The X post states the Watch 3 is a part of the Chinese OEM's "upcoming product schedule," and alludes to some additional devices.</p><p>Brar lists the next watch alongside the OnePlus 13 and OnePlus 13R series phones.</p><p>The publication notes that the OnePlus 13R didn't join the top-of-the-line model during its launch at the end of October. This development is curious, to say the least, as we're unsure how OnePlus will go about releasing these three devices in global markets since one hasn't appeared on home soil (China).</p><p>A perfect scenario would see them all dropped at once globally, but the odds of that could be lower than we want.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">OnePlus 13 OnePlus 13ROnePlus Watch 3These are the upcoming products scheduled to launch soon in Global markets.<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1860932345097867411">November 25, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>Whispers about a OnePlus Watch 3 started earlier this summer when it appeared for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/new-oneplus-watch-certification-specs-rendering">its TENAA certification</a>. Leaked specs suggest the watch will sport LTE and eSIM support alongside a strong 500mAh battery like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oneplus-watch-2-review">its predecessor</a>. Additionally, it seems the watch could feature 10W wired charging.</p><p>Considering how recently the Watch 2 debuted, those earlier rumors felt closer to a variant rather than a jump in the series.</p><p>On the other hand, the "launching soon" rumor sort of makes sense when you consider the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-13-goes-official-in-china">one-month launch difference</a> for the OnePlus 13. The phone debuted in China on October 31, which was a month and some change earlier than the OnePlus 12's December 5 launch last year. A global launch for that device is expected sooner since it's already out in its home China market.</p><p>With that, perhaps we're looking at a December rollout for the OnePlus 13 overseas — but that's just speculation. For context, the OnePlus 12R rolled out in January 2024, a month after the top-tier model. In any case, these devices might slowly trickle out in a similar cadence to OnePlus' past.</p><p>As always, we'll have to wait and see.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oneplus-watch-3-upcoming-global-launch-rumors</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ OnePlus is rumored to be on the cusp of a Watch 3 launch. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">HT7XRkQchxRziwAAVkz3ET</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/R3c6ejWK5GY2yhoa8HCfgN.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 20:16:56 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/R3c6ejWK5GY2yhoa8HCfgN.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The fitness circles watchface for the OnePlus Watch 2]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The fitness circles watchface for the OnePlus Watch 2]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ It's time to ditch your boring wireless carrier — Mint Mobile's Black Friday deals are NO JOKE ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The biggest sale event of 2024 is almost here, and Mint Mobile is marking the occasion by dropping some of the best Black Friday phone deals I&apos;ve ever seen. I know that sounds like something a deal writer <em>would </em>say, but I&apos;m being serious here. Let me explain.</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Black Friday deals</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Black Friday Google Pixel deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Black Friday Motorola deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024">Black Friday Samsung deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Black Friday OnePlus deals</a></p></div></div>
<p>Some of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones </a>of 2024 are getting major discounts through the MVNO carrier, and Mint is pairing the savings with some deeply discounted wireless when you transfer your existing phone number. For instance, you could get the Google Pixel 9 AND a full year of the Unlimited plan for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9/6810275/"><strong>a single payment of $479 (or $20 per month using affirm)</strong></a>. Alternately, you can grab the Samsung Galaxy S24 and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/samsung-galaxy-s24/5418243/"><strong>simply have your phone bill covered for a year</strong></a>.</p><p>Sure, they aren&apos;t straight discounts, but if you&apos;re looking to switch wireless carriers, just imagine: you could make a single payment right now and not have to think about your phone bill again until December 2025. Plus, you&apos;ll get an incredible 2024 device out of the deal. Yeah, it&apos;s that good. </p><p>Keep reading for all of the best deals from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/deals/"><strong>Mint Mobile&apos;s Black Friday sale</strong></a>, but don&apos;t wait too long to make your move — Mint has been known to run out of stock during events like this. If you have any questions about the carrier, take a look at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/mint-mobile-review">our 4/5-star Mint Mobile review</a> while you&apos;re in the neighborhood. </p>
<h2 id="my-favorite-mvno-is-meeting-my-favorite-android-phones-for-the-holidays-x2014-how-sweet-xa0-2">My favorite MVNO is meeting my favorite Android phones for the holidays — how sweet! </h2>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="07383997-34b4-474c-af11-2e652066b8a9" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9/6810275/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="tik5vWBsBmtqriDgoJ23g5" name="google pixel 9 render 400x500.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tik5vWBsBmtqriDgoJ23g5.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Google Pixel 9 128GB: </strong><a href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9/6810275/" data-dimension112="07383997-34b4-474c-af11-2e652066b8a9" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799"><del>$799</del> <strong>$299, plus 50% off one year of Unlimited at Mint Mobile</strong></a></p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-review">Google Pixel 9</a> was one of the best flagship phones released this year, coming complete with a 6.3-inch AMOLED display, a ton of AI software features, and seven years of guaranteed OS updates. </p>
<p>Purchase the phone from Mint Mobile and you'll score a ridiculous $500 discount AND 50% off a year of the unlimited plan (which just so happens to one of the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/carriers/best-unlimited-data-plans">best data plans</a> we've ever used). </p>
<p><strong>👀 Alternate Black Friday deals: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-Unlocked-Smartphone-Advanced/dp/B0D7HWJDQM"><strong>Amazon - $649</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-9-128gb-unlocked-obsidian/6587819.p"><strong>Best Buy - $649</strong></a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9/6810275/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="07383997-34b4-474c-af11-2e652066b8a9" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="d8f53600-7c00-4fbc-b0f9-ee0204a6490d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799" data-dimension48="$799" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/samsung-galaxy-s24/5418243/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1200px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="NqhoUu3WzqW2D7ngA6rmHK" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-render-square-crop-black.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NqhoUu3WzqW2D7ngA6rmHK.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1200" height="1200" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy S24 128GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/samsung-galaxy-s24/5418243/" data-dimension112="d8f53600-7c00-4fbc-b0f9-ee0204a6490d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799" data-dimension48="$799"><del>$799</del> <strong>$620, plus 50% off one year of Unlimited at Mint Mobile</strong></a></p>
<p>Don't let its relatively plain appearance fool you: the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-hands-on">Galaxy S24</a> is all power under the hood, with a bounty of fun Galaxy AI features, a Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 chipset, and a gorgeous 6.2-inch AMOLED display. </p>
<p>Mint Mobile has just added the flagship to its Black Friday lineup, slashing $180 off the phone and dropping 50% off the unlimited plan for one year. </p>
<p><strong>👀 Alternate Black Friday deals: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CMDRCZBJ"><strong>Amazon - $699.99</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-s24-128gb-onyx-black-verizon/6570416.p"><strong>Best Buy - $699.99</strong></a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/samsung-galaxy-s24/5418243/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="d8f53600-7c00-4fbc-b0f9-ee0204a6490d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799" data-dimension48="$799">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="eaa93446-28a9-460b-ad8f-f80d1d86161a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,300" data-dimension48="$1,300" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra/5418319/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="BF24wtWZfPun3awtdNycRT" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-Ultra-titanium-black.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BF24wtWZfPun3awtdNycRT.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra 256GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra/5418319/" data-dimension112="eaa93446-28a9-460b-ad8f-f80d1d86161a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,300" data-dimension48="$1,300"><del>$1,300</del><strong> $1,100, plus 50% off one year of Unlimited at Mint Mobile</strong></a></p>
<p>One of the best Samsung phones ever built, the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review">Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra</a> boasts a gorgeous 6.8-inch AMOLED display with a built-in stylus, plus you get a ton of AI software features, seven years of OS/security updates, and some of the best camera tech around. </p>
<p>Buy the premium device during Mint's Black Friday sale and you'll enjoy $200 off alongside a year of Unlimited for only $15 per month ($180 upfront).</p>
<p>👀 <strong>Alternate Black Friday deals: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Smartphone-Unlocked-Android-Titanium/dp/B0CMDM65JH"><strong>Amazon - $949.99</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-256gb-unlocked-titanium-black/6569855.p"><strong>Best Buy - $949.99</strong></a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra/5418319/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="eaa93446-28a9-460b-ad8f-f80d1d86161a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,300" data-dimension48="$1,300">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="99e86924-7bf1-4ced-bb1d-b0c43253f941" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold 256GB: $1,799" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold 256GB: $1,799" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9-pro-fold/6810584/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="JissherrZpkPfUPoRgiLgn" name="google pixel 9 pro fold square render 1.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JissherrZpkPfUPoRgiLgn.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="800" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold 256GB: </strong><a href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9-pro-fold/6810584/" data-dimension112="99e86924-7bf1-4ced-bb1d-b0c43253f941" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold 256GB: $1,799" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold 256GB: $1,799"><del>$1,799</del> <strong>$1,449, plus 50% off one year of Unlimited at Mint Mobile</strong></a></p>
<p>Versatile and feature-packed, the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-fold-review">Pixel 9 Pro Fold</a> has just about everything you could want in a foldable phone from Google. You get two glorious displays, a durable folding hinge, and all of the fun AI features you could ever need. </p>
<p>The problem is that the 9 Pro Fold is also pretty expensive. Mint Mobile is helping a bit by carving $350 off the phone when you pair the purchase with 12 months of discounted wireless and transfer your phone number. </p>
<p><strong>👀 Alternate Black Friday deals: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-Pro-Fold-Smartphone/dp/B0D7V1J2Y1"><strong>Amazon - $1,499</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-9-pro-fold-5g-256gb-unlocked-obsidian/6587911.p"><strong>Best Buy - $1,499</strong></a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9-pro-fold/6810584/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="99e86924-7bf1-4ced-bb1d-b0c43253f941" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold 256GB: $1,799" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold 256GB: $1,799">View Deal</a></p></div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/its-time-to-ditch-your-boring-wireless-carrier-mint-mobiles-black-friday-deals-are-no-joke</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Mint Mobile has carving hundreds of dollars off some of my favorite phones of the year for Black Friday, but it gets even better.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">jtSGRuPCFxadk3WnYBRfb9</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AKBQTHAzPxRupBQxVXaBic.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 20:08:07 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AKBQTHAzPxRupBQxVXaBic.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Testing Google Pixel 9&#039;s camera]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Testing Google Pixel 9&#039;s camera]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google app for iOS now adds Search links to third-party websites unless they opt-out ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google is now inserting its own links to Google Search result cards into third-party webpages.</li><li>The feature, called Page Annotations, is now live in the Google app for iOS.</li><li>Web publishers can opt-out of Page Annotations, but the request can take up to 30 days to take effect.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google is adding another tool to its web browser that could pull users away from independent sites and toward Google Search results. The company recently <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/websearch/thread/308719098/page-annotation-in-google-app-browser-for-ios?hl=en"> announced </a>the introduction of Page Annotations to the Google app for iOS, which is a multifunctional app hosting Google Search, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini</a>, and functioning as a miniature web browser. As spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.seroundtable.com/google-ios-app-page-annotation-38451.html">Search Engine Roundtable </a>and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/11/25/google-ios-app-link-annotations-search/">9to5Google</a>, Page Annotations insert links to Google Search results in plain text on third-party websites.</p><p>"Words, topics, products, places, celebrity names, and other entities that are mentioned in a page might be highlighted as clickable annotations in the Google App browser for iOS," the company explains in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://developers.google.com/search/docs/crawling-indexing/control-what-you-share#page-insights" target="_blank">support document</a>. "By clicking the annotation, the user will be navigated to the search page with the results for this annotation."</p><p>Google does give web publishers the ability to opt-out of Page Annotations. They can do so via a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1h9I0TbN-H_1e85CqXYb1ng7rQfg2ijfODc1sBxPBd08/viewform?edit_requested=true" target="_blank">Google Form</a>. However, some site owners may be frustrated by how long it can take for their opt-out request to be processed.</p><p>"Site owners can choose to opt out of this annotation feature by submitting the opt-out form," Google explains. "The Page Annotation feature triggered on your site will be disabled within 30 days after submitting the opt-out form. You only need to do this once."</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="jAbTLUkofY6oM9xkicnETD" name="iphone-16-pro-max-20.jpg" alt="Apple iPhone 16 Pro Max dock" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jAbTLUkofY6oM9xkicnETD.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Page Annotations appear differently than regular in-text links, potentially signaling to the user that you're clicking a Google Search link rather than a redirect link from a third-party website. However, it's still possible that Page Annotations pull users away from the site they're browsing.</p><p>More likely, though, is that Page Annotations will simply be a new way for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google">Google app</a> users to quickly find out more information about a person, place, or thing. The Google Search results cards that appear as Page Annotations are designed in a way that makes it easy to return to the site you were previously browsing. It's also worth noting that iOS has a native <strong>Look Up</strong> feature that basically allows users to do the exact same thing, except it works system-wide on any highlighted text.</p><p>When you consider this context, it's unlikely that Page Annotations will materially change how iPhone users browse the web. If publishers are concerned, they do still have the ability to opt-out. While not explicitly listed as a test, it's fair to wonder whether Page Annotations might make their way to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/what-happens-if-google-has-to-sell-chrome">Chrome</a> or Android if they are successful in the Google app for iOS.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-app-for-ios-now-adds-search-links-to-third-party-websites-unless-they-opt-out</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Web publishers can opt out via a provided form, but changes might not take effect for up to 30 days.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">uuJcQMAZpWQAD5xMJxQwkm</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rgWV3CEtK7wN47W7EsZjJQ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 19:30:40 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rgWV3CEtK7wN47W7EsZjJQ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central / Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Page Annotations in the Google app for iOS. ]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Page Annotations in the Google app for iOS. ]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Alleged Nothing Phone 3 database listing suggests a budget-focused chip ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Following an assumed Nothing Phone 3 database listing, it seems the device could arrive with a midrange-level SoC.</li><li>From the listed chip details, it seems Nothing could pack Qualcomm's Snapdragon 7s Gen 3 into the Phone 3 instead of the 8s Gen 3.</li><li>Nothing's CEO Carl Pei stated that the Phone 3 will have AI at its core when it arrives in 2025 following a purposeful delay this year.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Nothing is developing a Phone 3, but a recent discovery suggests its internal SoC isn't so "flagship."</p><p>The folks at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.gsmarena.com/nothing_phone_3_appears_on_geekbench_-news-65473.php">GSMArena</a> found a new listing via the Geekbench database from Nothing. The device in question, with model number "A059," is rumored to be the next Phone 3 flagship. The listing is a little vague, stating this device in development could debut with 8GB of RAM and Android 15.</p><p>However, the more pressing matter is its supposed chip architecture of one processor and eight cores.</p><p>Per the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://browser.geekbench.com/v6/cpu/9045583">database listing</a>, it seems the assumed Phone 3 will have one "main" core at 2.50GHz. The rest of the setup includes four cores at 1.80GHz and three cores at 2.40GHz. These are likely to arrive as "efficiency" and "performance" cores, respectively.</p><p>The publication notes that this particular core, though the listing lacks its name, points toward Qualcomm's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/ai-is-coming-to-more-budget-phones-thanks-to-qualcomms-new-snapdragon-7s-gen-3">Snapdragon 7s Gen 3</a> SoC. Elsewhere, the post claims the rumored Phone 3 could debut with a 6.5-inch OLED display. Early speculation throws a $600 starting price on the table, as well.</p><p>Take such rumors with a grain of salt as the publication adds a "Phone 3 Pro" could join the lineup.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="QDpxXBVTnCcD8c9yNDoYjn" name="Nothing-phone-2-display-home-screen-01.jpg" alt="The home screen of the Nothing Phone (2) with pink icons and wallpaper" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QDpxXBVTnCcD8c9yNDoYjn.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Rumors about the Nothing Phone 3 have <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/nothing-phone-3-qualcomm-chip-price-rumors">been extremely scarce</a> with the "latest" detailing a chance for a Qualcomm variant. It was rumored this past summer that the device could debut with the Snapdragon 8s Gen 3. The chip is a slightly toned-down version of the 2023 SD 8 Gen 3 flagship. It reached 3.0GHz speeds, which was 0.3GHz slower than the higher-tier chip.</p><p>Qualcomm stated the chip was designed for more on-device AI. However, the Snapdragon 7s Gen 3, which is <em>now </em>rumored for the Phone 3, is aimed at "budget-friendly smartphones." It's based on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/snapdragon-7-plus-gen-3-launch">midrange SD 7 Plus Gen 3</a> from March.</p><p>With that, the Snapdragon 7s Gen 3 is a bit slower than the flagship 8 or 8s chips. Still, it focuses heavily on AI as it boasts support for several models like Baichuan-7B and Llama 2.</p><p>AI is a phone aspect that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/nothing-will-prioritize-ai-over-phone-3-but-is-that-the-right-call">Nothing's CEO, Carl Pei, stated</a> he wanted to focus heavily on with the next device. In June, Pei stated that the company had been "prototyping AI interactions." Moreover, it seemed evident that Nothing purposefully delayed the Phone 3's launch to better flesh out its AI software. The company confirmed that it wouldn't arrive in 2024, pushing us into 2025 for an eventual debut.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/nothing-phone-3-database-listing-chip-details-leak</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Rumors claimed Nothing's Phone 3 appeared in a new listing with a vastly different chipset. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">9S2bYVYKHKemBuuu2dAZyR</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CqoaiemQLuCy6AzPJ2chVL.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 19:27:36 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CqoaiemQLuCy6AzPJ2chVL.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Nothing Phone (2)&#039;s colorways with glyph lights on]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Nothing Phone (2)&#039;s colorways with glyph lights on]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>