<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 21:01:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung's upcoming Galaxy Watch 7 lands on Amazon ahead of launch ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The Samsung Galaxy Watch 7 40mm smartwatch comes in cream and was spotted in an Amazon listing.</li><li>Alongside the price and availability, the listing also confirms a 128GB storage option.</li><li>The upcoming Galaxy Watch 7 will use a 3nm chip and sports a host of AI features, per the listing.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>The Galaxy Watch 7 series will likely be released at next month&apos;s Unpacked event launch, which will likely happen on July 10, although Samsung needs to confirm it officially. Meanwhile, a Canadian Amazon listing has already revealed the Galaxy Watch 7&apos;s pricing.</p><p>Spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://passionategeekz.com/exclusive-samsung-galaxy-watch-7-amazon-listing-revealed-features-and-pricing-ahead-of-launch/">PassionateGeekz</a>, the said Amazon listing showcases the regular Galaxy Watch 7 Bluetooth variant featuring 40mm size and a price tag of CAD 358 (~$268). It further confirms that the smartwatch will feature a round-shaped display and sport at least 128GB of storage. It will be powered by a 3nm SoC that promises to boost power efficiency and carry out smoother all-round operations.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:761px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:78.84%;"><img id="Dc8nHpfnqDLJ4zGRVFXmTU" name="Galaxy-Watch-7-Amazon-lisitng-leak.jpg" alt="Galaxy Watch 7 Amazon listing" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Dc8nHpfnqDLJ4zGRVFXmTU.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="761" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: PassionateGeekz)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>There is BioActiveSensor that carries out users&apos; health tracking features like heart rate monitoring, blood oxygen levels — during workouts, sleep with sleep quality analysis, and more. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-7">Galaxy Watch 7</a> will also have the goodness of AI, and as the description points out, "Personalized Daily AI Companion for AI-Powered Sleep, Exercises, and communication." </p><p>Additionally, users also get to use the Galaxy AI smart reply, which can give reply suggestions when texting from the smartwatch. It also includes an AI-based tone suggestion for replies that lets users know how they sound while having a conversation.</p>
<p>Another crucial detail of the aforementioned Amazon listing is the availability of the Galaxy Watch 7 in Cream (probably one of the multiple color options). The smartwatch will be delivered as early as July 16, corroborating the earlier leak and reaffirming that the launch happened earlier than the predecessor <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-6-review">Galaxy Watch 6</a> series.</p><p>The latest appearance follows the previous <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fcc-listings-foreshadow-galaxy-watch-7-series-and-budget-galaxy-watch-fe">FCC listings</a> of the Galaxy Watch 7 series and the supposed Galaxy Watch 7 Ultra <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-z-flip-6-watch-7-ultra-specs-fcc-listing">FCC spotting</a>, which is all set to take on Apple Watch Ultra models. The Ultra was also seen in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-7-ultra-renders-leak">latest renders</a>, which reveal the full <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch">premium smartwatch</a>.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="7WHLsALvxiberxzotozTBg" name="galaxy-watch-7-ultra-render.jpg" alt="Galaxy Watch 7 Ultra renders" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7WHLsALvxiberxzotozTBg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: SmartPrix/ OnLeaks)</span></figcaption></figure>
<ul><li><strong>Smartwatch deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/searchpage.jsp?st=smartwatch&_dyncharset=UTF-8&_dynSessConf=&id=pcat17071&type=page&sc=Global&cp=1&nrp=&sp=&qp=&list=n&af=true&iht=y&usc=All+Categories&ks=960&keys=keys"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/search?q=smartwatch"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=smartwatch&crid=19YAPQ38561AK&sprefix=smartwatch%2Caps%2C138&ref=nb_sb_ss_ts-doa-p_1_10"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/watches-audio-accessories-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.dell.com/en-us/search/smartwatch"><u><strong>Dell</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/galaxy-watch-7-amazon-listing-leak</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung Galaxy Watch 7's Canadian Amazon listing reveals its attractive CAD 358 price tag. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">BRuVDZJp6xRdnc28MxNRaj</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dm53ejRRMV2tH8XHJTzA5g.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 20:19:01 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dm53ejRRMV2tH8XHJTzA5g.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[SmartPrix/ OnLeaks]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Galaxy Watch 7 Ultra renders]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Galaxy Watch 7 Ultra renders]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Netflix might bring a free, ad-supported plan to specific regions ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A new report claims that Netflix could roll out a free, ad-supported plan, but it will likely be restricted to certain regions.</li><li>The company is reportedly in the early stages; however, if development continues, it could debut in countries like Germany and Japan.</li><li>Netflix detailed its plan for 2024 earlier this year, stating that a price hike is on the way for consumers following its record quarter.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>A new report claims Netflix is thinking about debuting a new free variant of its streaming services but for a select few areas.</p><p>According to information obtained by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2024-06-23/netflix-s-advertising-challenge-it-isn-t-big-enough">Bloomberg</a>, Netflix has held internal discussions about debuting a free, ad-supported plan (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/netflix-free-plan-3454100/">Android Authority</a>). If this happens, those "familiar" with the plan have stated it would apply to viewers in Europe and Asia. Rumors add that this plan could debut in large markets within those regions like Germany and Japan with "popular free TV networks."</p><p>This new plan reportedly deals with Netflix&apos;s scramble to find additional ways to "increase its audience."</p><p>However, the publication&apos;s sources claim that there are no plans to bring a plan of this capacity to U.S. consumers. Netflix "already reaches the majority of its potential customer base" in the region, thus making a move like this unnecessary.</p><p>The post highlights a similar move Netflix <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://about.netflix.com/en/news/netflix-launches-free-plan-in-kenya">made in Kenya</a> in 2021 before discontinuing it. The most notable difference now is the addition of ads, as consumers in Kenya could watch shows and movies without them. The free plan offered personalized recommendations, parental controls, and profile creation options.</p><p>Sources add that these internal talks are still in their infancy, meaning things can go either way from here.</p><p>In other news, Netflix <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/netflix-teases-price-hike-2024-plan">detailed its plans for 2024</a>, which include a (definite) price hike despite achieving a record revenue quarter. It seems as though the company is seeking help from its customers to pay for its larger endeavors with streaming. Netflix&apos;s $5 billion deal with the WWE for the next 10 years was given as an example, alluding to a new trend moving forward.</p><p>Unfortunately, Netflix hasn&apos;t yet detailed the specifics of its impending price hike for 2024.</p><p>What is certain is that the company plans to roll out <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/netflix-highlights-smart-tv-home-screen-changes">a revamped UI</a> for smart TVs. During an interview with Netflix&apos;s senior director of products, Pat Flemming, it was confirmed that the new UI will help viewers see what&apos;s most important when scrolling over shows and movies. The new UI will place a quick preview, description, number of episodes, and more directly on the content card.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/netflix-free-ad-supported-tier-rumored</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A report claimed that Netflix could bring a new free, ad-supported tier to certain regions. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">uyppMTLJXyiX5xvw86G9Te</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2UuBnPiM9TPJE49PMxiggf.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 20:02:39 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Streaming &amp; TV]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2UuBnPiM9TPJE49PMxiggf.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Keegan Prosser/Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Netflix Home]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Netflix Home]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Gemini is now in Gmail to write summaries and craft replies on the fly ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google's Gemini AI is now integrated into Gmail on both web and mobile platforms, offering AI-powered email assistance.</li><li>In the web version of Gmail, Gemini appears in a sidebar with suggestions like "Summarize this email," "List action items," and "Suggest a reply."</li><li>On mobile, a top button enables quick email summaries.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google just announced that its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini AI</a>, which offers AI-powered email assistance, is now available in Gmail on both the web and mobile apps.</p><p>In a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://workspaceupdates.googleblog.com/2024/06/gemini-in-side-panel-of-gmail.html" target="_blank">blog post</a>, Google introduced a bunch of AI features for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gmail-android-how-to">Gmail</a>. The big news is that the "Summarize this email" feature is now available on both iOS and Android. With Gemini&apos;s help, you can quickly shrink down long email threads or get help drafting replies. But Gemini is more than just a summarizer—it also lets you ask questions and dig up specific information from your inbox and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-drive">Google Drive</a> files.</p><p>Google has taken a big step forward by upgrading Gmail with its latest AI, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/gemini-15-pro-side-panel-rolling-out-now-for-google-workspace-labs-testers">Gemini 1.5 Pro</a>. This enhanced version comes with three major improvements: a significantly larger memory for context, a deeper understanding of information, and super-fast processing speeds.</p><p>In Gmail’s web version, Gemini appears in a sidebar on the right, next to your emails. This sidebar kicks things off with several handy suggestions like "Summarize this email," "List action items from this email," and "Suggest a reply to this email."</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1546px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:57.37%;"><img id="FhiAmyKXcfzok4VxL4FXLK" name="gmail-ask-gemini-feature.png" alt="Gemini side panel in gmail on the web" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FhiAmyKXcfzok4VxL4FXLK.png" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1546" height="887" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Jay Bonggolto / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While the prompts are a great way to get started, Gemini’s real strength is in answering your direct questions. Don’t feel limited by the suggested options; you can have a natural conversation with Gemini and ask it anything about your emails.</p><p>The company is also <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://workspaceupdates.googleblog.com/2024/06/gemini-in-side-panel-of-google-docs-sheets-slides-drive.html" target="_blank">expanding</a> the Gemini side panel to include Docs, Sheets, Slides, and Drive. In Docs, this handy tool will aid in polishing your prose, offering summaries, recommending tweaks, and creatively generating new content from your other files.</p><p>In Sheets, Gemini assists with creating tables, generating formulas, and explaining various functions step-by-step. In Slides, it can help you produce custom images and summarize presentations. Meanwhile, Drive can summarize multiple documents at once without opening them individually.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:350px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:214.29%;"><img id="HyWNUqjttnqHFQjc2JJiWc" name="Gmail-summarize-this-email.jpg" alt="Gemini summarize this email feature on gmail for android" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HyWNUqjttnqHFQjc2JJiWc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="350" height="750" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Jay Bonggolto / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>On the other hand, the mobile experience lacks a side panel, but a conveniently placed button at the top of your emails lets you quickly generate summaries. In the future, Gmail will offer contextual smart replies—one-tap responses tailored to your conversations. Plus, Gmail Q&A will soon allow you to find information within your emails using natural language queries.</p><p>Keep in mind that these advanced AI features are available to Google Workspace customers with specific subscription plans. If you have Google One AI Premium, the Gemini Business/Enterprise, or Gemini Education/Education Premium add-ons, you&apos;ll be able to use this functionality.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini-is-now-in-gmail-to-write-summaries-and-craft-replies-on-the-fly</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Gemini can now summarize long emails and write replies for you. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">UK8JJSise48pL6vUqMQfF3</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tX2oBaZPRugXdmgGbvUuJ7.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 19:44:13 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tX2oBaZPRugXdmgGbvUuJ7.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nick Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Gmail logo on a Pixel 6 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Gmail logo on a Pixel 6 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Some lucky Meta Quest 3 owners are already getting the new UI update ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Meta is working on a massive UI update for the Meta Quest line, allowing users to place windows anywhere in 3D space, as well as resize and reshape them.</li><li>The beta July v67 system update includes a new experimental feature for window management.</li><li>It's expected that Meta will launch the new major update in time for Connect 2024 and the Meta Quest 3s launch.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>It&apos;s almost July and you know what that means! A new Meta Quest update has begun rolling out to beta testers and it includes the new UI update that Meta teased <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-3-mysterious-new-ui-ad">back at the end of May</a>.</p><p>The July v67 Meta Quest update includes a new experimental feature that lets users treat windows more like they were on a traditional desktop computer with the added advantage of moving them around in 3D space! Users <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/OculusQuest/comments/1dnsdzi/quest_3_ptc_v67_new_windows_design/">on Reddit</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.threads.net/@lostinartmagic/post/C8ou8FlKSl0?xmt=AQGzHF-M7XxZ9Ziq_w4r0xcb1r-m0VQGfuEMlD-yLa-vPg">Threads</a> have already begun posting about it, showing off all the capabilities of the new experimental feature.</p><p>The update seems to add two major changes to window management. First, users can now launch apps in windowed mode and move them anywhere they want. Previously, only three apps could run at a time and would have to be snapped into one of three predetermined locations side-by-side, similar to a standard triple-monitor computer setup.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Meta Quest OS v67 PTC has finally done it...🔗 https://t.co/L7i2lUWS8i 🔗 pic.twitter.com/rb7hBPS9lu<a href="https://twitter.com/Lunayian/status/1805434151111110805">June 25, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>Now, windowed apps like the Quest browser, Threads, YouTube, and others can be moved around and placed anywhere. You can also move windows forward and backward in space, allowing windows to be placed in front of or behind one another. This works well for spacing windows around a room for a better mixed-reality setup.</p><p>The new UI now allows up to six apps to run at once: three pinned and three floating. Apps can be dragged to appear to be placed on walls, as well, giving them similarities to window management on Apple Vision Pro.</p><p>Windows can also be resized and reshaped in any way you like. Grabbing a window from the bottom right corner and dragging it out will resize it, allowing users to change not only the size of the window but also its shape. That means apps aren&apos;t confined to running in traditional "landscape" or "portrait" modes like a mobile app usually would.</p><p>If you&apos;d like to test the new features, you must be enrolled in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.meta.com/help/quest/articles/headsets-and-accessories/using-your-headset/quest-ptc/">Meta Quest PTC</a> beta update channel. Once that&apos;s done, you&apos;ll eventually get the update when it rolls out to your headset. Meta updates headsets in waves, so not all users get the same update simultaneously. My Quest 3 still doesn&apos;t have the update despite being enrolled in the PTC group, so you may need to wait a while for it.</p>
<hr>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="4b09e928-d63f-4082-ac55-de6b90d9834e">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/E75vg2n9urJXwhnVrgFvsQ.jpg' alt='Meta Quest 3 headset and controller render on a white background'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Meta Quest 3</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>The Meta Quest 3 is a mixed reality powerhouse, letting you multitask with virtual windows and apps any way you want to. Ditch that tablet and save your neck!</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-3-july-v67-update-new-ui</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A new Meta Quest UI update has been in the works for some time, and July's v67 update looks to begin implementing them for some users. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">HeHxwHGD7A5HqRi78zR99b</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/H5tPH6BMHb2K8qThA2uSBA.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 19:26:33 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/H5tPH6BMHb2K8qThA2uSBA.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[u/pullRequest18 on Reddit]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A screenshot of an updated Meta Quest 3 UI on beta build v67]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A screenshot of an updated Meta Quest 3 UI on beta build v67]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google starts sending out Made by Google event invites for the Pixel 9 series ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>According to recent invites from the search giant, the Made by Google event will be held on August 13.</li><li>The event will introduce the Pixel product portfolio, the best of Google AI, and the latest Android.</li><li>It is an earlier launch than previous Pixel product releases, and registrations will begin July 31.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>It looks like we might see the Pixel 9 series earlier than ever, as Google has started sending out invites for its next Made by Google event. Next to the flagships, we could also see the Pixel Watch 3, Android 15&apos;s official rollout, and maybe the Pixel Fold 2. </p><p>Android Central and several others across the industry have started receiving emails from Google revealing the launch date of the Made by Google event. It will be held on August 13 (Tuesday) at Google headquarters in Mountain View. The accompanying keynote will begin at 10 AM PT, followed by a hands-on product experience.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:324px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:185.19%;"><img id="fy6di589WZfdAJhdGyS62N" name="Made-by-Google-2024-invite.jpg" alt="Made by Google event invite" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fy6di589WZfdAJhdGyS62N.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="324" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:319px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:188.09%;"><img id="VSBVd98sgd5Hx9YNvC8t7N" name="Made-by-Google-2024-invite-01.jpg" alt="Made by Google event invite" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VSBVd98sgd5Hx9YNvC8t7N.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="319" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>The event coming a month early looks interesting because the usual timeframe of new flagship Pixel phones is generally not until fall every year. While it is still unclear why Google is choosing to come early, it is good to know we should be seeing some great Pixel product folio, which, as mentioned, can include <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9">Pixel 9</a>, Pixel 9 Pro, and Pixel 9 Pro XL (the new one in the lot), and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-3">Pixel Watch 3</a>, and new generation Pixel Buds, Pixel Fold, and a new Pixel Tablet are also expected at the event. </p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a>, which is currently in beta, might also have an early official rollout, as the Pixel 9 series would ship with it right out of the box. Similarly, the next version of Wear OS may also be early in the pipeline.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Découvrez celui qui vous fera apprécier le latin.XIII.VIII.MMXXIV. pic.twitter.com/WJqL6g9ahO<a href="https://twitter.com/GoogleFR/status/1805647362259402828">June 25, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>The invite sent out by the search giant also indicates that Made by Google will showcase “the best of Google AI, ” which could mean the Gemini advancements coming to the Pixel 9 series alongside the AI prowess for Pixel photography and post-edit features.</p><p>Since the launch date is now final, we should see more about the Pixel 9 lineup, particularly the new one, the Pixel 9 Pro XL, which recently hit the benchmark test next to the regular Pixel 9. The launch also falls right after the Samsung Galaxy Unpacked event, which is tentatively happening on July 10. Meanwhile, registrations for the Made by Google event will begin on July 31.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/made-by-google-event-2024-date-announced</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Pixel 9 models, Pixel Watch 3, and Android 15 will be coming sooner than their previous iterations. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">VYEsohEKB9ZiorxpzkyeFf</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/K9XbFK3fRugen5ZedPqhZK.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 19:09:46 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/K9XbFK3fRugen5ZedPqhZK.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Made by Google event date]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Made by Google event date]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google details Gemini for students and new AI-powered tools for educators ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google announced that it's preparing to bring Gemini to teen students using school accounts in "over 100 countries."</li><li>Gemini will lend its AI brains, but with guardrails to ensure teens don't receive inappropriate responses and with the ability to fact-check its responses.</li><li>Educators are preparing to pick up 16 new add-ons for Classrooms, AI tools for Read Along, and more for Chromebooks.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Today (June 24), Google announced that it&apos;s bringing its AI model Gemini to teen students and educators.</p><p>According to a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/education/ai-workspace-chromebook-iste-2024/">Keyword post</a>, the company detailed that "in the coming months," teens at the minimum age requirement (13) can chat with Gemini through their school account. Google states that Gemini&apos;s capabilities will be disabled by default, but school admins can enable it through the "Admin console."</p><p>Moreover, Gemini&apos;s services for teens in school will arrive as a free feature in "over 100 countries."</p><p>A <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/education/workspace-gemini-classroom-iste-2024/">subsequent post</a> states students using Gemini through a school account will experience safeguards to block inappropriate content. Google states Gemini will filter out "illegal or age-gated substances" from appearing in the results it delivers. Additionally, the AI will run a fact-check on a response when asked for the first time.</p><p>The AI will then encourage students to run the double-check function when asking a "fact-based" question.</p><p>Google is preparing to roll out a custom version of LearnLM called "Coach" for students. The feature is detailed as a step-by-step tool to help students build their knowledge of various subjects through quizzes and games.</p><p>A safer Google Chat is en route, with the company detailing that admins can soon restrict students from initiating DMs and creating spaces.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8BNo1sM7wFw" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>Google is also looking to bolster Read Along in Classrooms by implementing AI. The post states that educators will soon be able to assign reading activities to their students based on grade or phonics skills. With the help of AI, educators will gain insights about a student&apos;s "reading accuracy, speed, and comprehension."</p><p>Soon, Google hopes to bring AI-generated personalized stories for educators to give to their students. Those who&apos;re interested can sign up for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSc3G74p3Htp5KMMTAEnNI4zKgcbrQNXgiZOhYWGxZUbOHBLLA/viewform">its pilot program</a>.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-vids-cloud-next-2024-gen-ai-announcements">Google Vids</a> is set to bring a generative AI-less variant for educators and students through Workspace for Education Plus "later this year."</p><p>Chromebooks and Workspace for Education will soon gain 16 new Classroom add-ons. These additions include Kami, Quizizz, Screencastify, Boom Learning, and more. The company is also bringing in a few more partners through its app licensing program, such as Canva, codeSpark, Equatio, Genially, Sora, and Sumo.</p><p>Google then reiterated its recent announcement of bringing <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/chromebooks-finally-get-deeper-gemini-integration-and-much-more">Gemini to Chromebooks</a> and its Chromebook Plus. Consumers can expect a few features like Help Me Write, Generative AI Wallpaper, and Magic Editor in Google Photos. However, Google teases that "Read Aloud" is on its way for Chromebooks through the Chrome browser through the reading mode.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini-for-students-educator-features-detailed</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google announced it will bring Gemini to teen students alongside several new tools for educators. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">EzFzQ6SFzMFDx6Bprrom8N</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CWkqBjQwgmSW9hT6fCrVL.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 18:48:11 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CWkqBjQwgmSW9hT6fCrVL.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Gemini comes to Canada]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Gemini comes to Canada]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Prime Day, who? You can score $80 off our favorite wireless headphones at Walmart TODAY ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Great wireless headphone deals don&apos;t come up all that often, and especially not for the market&apos;s top models. Out of nowhere, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Sony-WH-1000XM5-Wireless-Industry-Leading-Noise-Canceling-Headphones-Black/386006068"><strong>Best Buy has dropped $80 OFF the Sony WH-1000XM5 wireless headphones</strong></a>, our favorite over-ear headphones on the market. We love these for their super crisp audio quality, great microphone clarity for use with voice commands and active noise cancellation. In addition, these boast an easy-to-use mobile app, up to 30 hours of battery life, and extremely comfortable speaker cups that can be worn for long periods of time.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="68ac2a30-2b52-4456-8a9e-2474ab8fc1c4" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$399.99" data-dimension48="$399.99" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Sony-WH-1000XM5-Wireless-Industry-Leading-Noise-Canceling-Headphones-Black/386006068" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="rdySiDNHum7Zj77MVRogz6" name="Sony-WH-1000XM5-render-with-space.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rdySiDNHum7Zj77MVRogz6.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="800" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Sony WH-1000XM5 Headphones:</strong> <a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Sony-WH-1000XM5-Wireless-Industry-Leading-Noise-Canceling-Headphones-Black/386006068" data-dimension112="68ac2a30-2b52-4456-8a9e-2474ab8fc1c4" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$399.99" data-dimension48="$399.99"><del>$399.99</del> <strong>$319.98 at Walmart</strong></a></p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/headphones/sony-wh-1000xm5-review">Sony WH-1000XM5 headphones</a> are our favorite headphones, and an $80 discount makes them even more appealing. From their solid audio quality to their superb battery life, you definitely get what you pay for with these premium headphones. They also offer lightning-fast charging speeds, great app support, comfortable ear cups, and better call quality than Sony's prior generation of these headphones.</p>
<p><strong>Price comparison:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/sony-wh1000xm5-wireless-noise-canceling-over-the-ear-headphones-black/6505727.p?skuId=6505727">Best Buy - $399.99</a> | <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WH-1000XM5-Headphones-Hands-Free-WH1000XM5/dp/B0BXYCS74H">Amazon - $398.00</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Sony-WH-1000XM5-Wireless-Industry-Leading-Noise-Canceling-Headphones-Black/386006068" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="68ac2a30-2b52-4456-8a9e-2474ab8fc1c4" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$399.99" data-dimension48="$399.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>✅<strong>Recommended if: </strong>you want a good deal on high-quality over-ear headphones; you&apos;re looking for headphones that offer long battery life and fast charging speeds; having comfortable speaker cups in your headphones is important to you.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>you&apos;d prioritize a super-cheap sticker price over getting premium-level headphones; you need a pair of headphones that has support for aptX codec.</p><p>AC&apos;s top pick for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/headphones/sony-wh-1000xm5-review">best wireless headphones</a>, largely due to their customizable audio, eight microphones boasting impressive ANC performance and crystal-clear phone calls, and super-long battery life with fast charging speeds. As added benefits, these are also some of the most comfortable wireless headphones available, even when being worn for longer periods of time.</p><p>To be sure, they&apos;re a little on the pricey side, even at this discounted price. However, if you were already considering spending a little more, this is definitely a good price on a great pair of headphones that might be worth considering.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/headphones/prime-day-who-you-can-score-dollar80-off-our-favorite-wireless-headphones-at-walmart-today</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Walmart has cut $80 off the capable Sony WH-1000XM5 wireless headphones, marking a great deal on our favorite headphones out there. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">owQSaBEavmgSw4mB2LozxA</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hdsWiCLyMrGqCkhLzHCQWm.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 17:49:01 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Headphones]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hdsWiCLyMrGqCkhLzHCQWm.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Sony]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Sony WH-1000XM5 wireless headphones]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Sony WH-1000XM5 wireless headphones]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Motorola Razr Plus 2024: Release date, specs, and everything you need to know ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The new Motorola Razr Plus 2024 is here as the latest compact foldable phone to grace our pockets. After a few underwhelming attempts to make a compelling foldable phone, Motorola&apos;s Razr Plus 2023 was a surprise hit, offering much of what consumers wanted in a clamshell. It launched with a flagship chipset, an impressively specced display, and a large and functional cover screen. But despite the highs, there were still plenty of lows that would make some hesitate to drop $1,000 on the phone. Now, with the launch of the Razr 2024, now might be a good time to throw your money in.</p><p>The latest Razr Plus brings plenty of welcome improvements while sticking largely to the same formula as its predecessor. In fact, Motorola doubled down on just about everything introduced in the last model. That means a similar design but with a larger cover screen, more vegan leather, a more up-to-date flagship chipset, and so much more. Meanwhile, the cheaper Razr 2024 borrows just about everything that made the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2023-how-it-started-how-its-going">Razr Plus 2023</a> so great.</p><p>Here&apos;s everything you need to know about Motorola&apos;s latest flagship.</p><p><strong>Note</strong>: <em>Motorola markets the Razr phones under different names between North American and international markets. We will mostly refer to the phone by its North American branding as the "Razr Plus 2024," although it will be branded as the Razr 50 Ultra outside of the U.S.</em></p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-motorola-razr-plus-2024-price-and-availability"><span>Motorola Razr Plus 2024: Price and availability</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3076px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="v2RzjNbauznFwtSRo3Cgx8" name="Motorola-Razr-Plus-2024-hot-pink-lifestyle.png" alt="The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 held up to a woman's face" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/v2RzjNbauznFwtSRo3Cgx8.png" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3076" height="1730" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Motorola)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Motorola launched the Razr Plus 2024 on June 25 at an event in New York City. The phone will be available for preorder on July 10 and will go on sale on July 24.</p><p>As for pricing, Motorola is retaining last year&apos;s price tags, meaning the flagship Razr Plus 2024 will cost $999, while the cheaper Razr 2024 will cost $699. The phones will be available in one configuration, with 256GB on both and 12GB of RAM on the Razr Plus, while the Razr 2024 gets 8GB of RAM.</p><p>The Razr Plus 2024 comes in four colors: Midnight Blue, Spring Green, Peach Fuzz, and Hot Pink. The Razr 2024 comes in three colors: Koala Grey, Beach Sand, and Spritz Orange. Availability of these color options may vary on carrier or region.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-motorola-razr-plus-2024-hardware-and-design"><span>Motorola Razr Plus 2024: Hardware and design</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:5000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.26%;"><img id="HQX6DUtcd5wyJLZUJmtdvf" name="Motorola-Razr-Plus-2024-colors.jpg" alt="The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 colors" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HQX6DUtcd5wyJLZUJmtdvf.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="5000" height="2813" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Motorola)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-review">Razr Plus 2023</a> was a fairly drastic design shift for Motorola, offering a hole-punch display, refined hinge, and an overall more modern look. With the Motorola Razr Plus 2024, the company took that same design philosophy and ran with it, adopting a largely identical design with front and back panels that curve into the rounded 6000-series aluminum frame.</p><p>The front is protected by Gorilla Glass Victus, while the back of the phone has a vegan leather finish on each of the color variants. There are four different colors, and each has a slightly different texture on the back. The frame also matches the color of the rest of the phone. Meanwhile, the larger cover screen takes up the entire front panel, with two cameras protruding from the bottom corner.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="zzttxnWvHBCcqEyapM7rs4" name="Motorola-Razr-Plus-2024-hands-on-05.jpg" alt="The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 cover screen" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zzttxnWvHBCcqEyapM7rs4.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Internally, the pOLED display measures 6.9 inches but has been improved with a peak brightness of 3,000 nits. There is still a built-in screen protector on the display, but it&apos;s more seamless and covers more of the panel, including the front-facing camera. The hinge design is largely the same as well, resulting in a very minimal crease across the display. The hinge is also slightly smaller, with more dust protection. The phone itself also has more water resistance, now with an IPX8 rating, meaning the phone can be completely submerged without damage (although we still would not recommend this).</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="78tE4SHLAESmQ2jbu5zXTe" name="Motorola-Razr-Plus-2024-hands-on-06.jpg" alt="The back of a Motorola Razr Plus 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/78tE4SHLAESmQ2jbu5zXTe.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="caption-text">A leaked render of the Razr 50 Ultra/Razr Plus 2024. </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>At 7.1mm thick when open, the phone is slightly thicker than its predecessor, but not by much. Otherwise, the phone has similar dimensions to its predecessor, so anyone coming from the previous phone should feel familiar when handling this new one. The cameras protrude much more than before, so you&apos;ll want to be careful to avoid damaging the lenses.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-motorola-razr-plus-2024-specs"><span>Motorola Razr Plus 2024: Specs</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3733px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.26%;"><img id="t5eAaVoTNk4BxVU5VvJiq" name="Motorola-Razr-Plus-2024-midnight-blue-lifestyle.jpg" alt="The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 going into a pocket" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/t5eAaVoTNk4BxVU5VvJiq.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3733" height="2100" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Motorola)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 is powered by one of the latest Qualcomm chips, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-snapdragon-8s-gen-3-announced">Snapdragon 8s Gen 3</a>. It&apos;s not as powerful as the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-3">Snapdragon 8 Gen 3</a>, but it still retains many of the capabilities, especially when it comes to AI. The chipset is paired with 12GB of RAM, so the phone should be able to handle on-device AI and have a better handle on juggling multiple apps or keeping them running in the background.</p><p>Just like its predecessor, the Razr Plus 2024 has 256GB of non-expandable <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-is-ufs-40-storage-and-why-should-you-care">UFS 4.0</a> storage, meaning you&apos;ll get what you get and no more. Of course, there are options for cloud storage, such as <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-one">Google One</a>.</p>

<p>One of the most significant changes is to the battery. The capacity has grown to 4,000mAh, up from 3,800mAh on the Razr Plus 2023. That&apos;s a fairly significant capacity jump, and battery life should be much better with a more efficient chipset. This was a weak point for the Razr Plus 2023, and Motorola claims all-day battery life with the Razr Plus 2024.</p><p>Charging specs have also improved, with 45W wired charging, 15W wireless charging, and even 5W reverse-wireless charging.</p><p>Other specs include support for Wi-Fi 7, Bluetooth 5.4, Dolby Atmos with spatial sound, and the latest Snapdragon Sound technology.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-motorola-razr-plus-2024-software-and-features"><span>Motorola Razr Plus 2024: Software and features</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3629px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="NQwygSPfyCnqp9rymWnYtn" name="Motorola-Razr-Plus-2024-content-creation-lifestyle.jpg" alt="The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 folded on a stair" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NQwygSPfyCnqp9rymWnYtn.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3629" height="2042" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Motorola)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 runs Android 14 out of the box with the company&apos;s latest Hello UX on top. Some aspects of the software are similar to what you&apos;d find on the Pixel, but Motorola has added more of its own flair to the UI while borrowing from others. For example, the settings menu is revamped and much more compact than before. Users can also choose a more modern style Control Panel that separates notifications from the quick settings menu, depending on what side of the display you swipe down from.</p><p>Aside from newer Android 14 flourishes, Motorola is also touting some AI features, such as support for the Gemini app, something that has thus far been poorly supported on flip phones. The app can even be used from the phone&apos;s cover screen, and the phone also supports Gemini Nano with features like Magic Compose.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="sD23hzsuGfwhnDWk7fDR6X" name="Motorola-Razr-Plus-2024-hands-on-01.jpg" alt="Gemini on the Motorola Razr Plus 2024 cover screen" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sD23hzsuGfwhnDWk7fDR6X.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The company is also readying a suite of new AI features called Moto AI, which promise to bring more interesting capabilities to the phone. With these features, the phone will be able to "pay attention" to what the user is saying or doing and transcribe or summarize afterward. Moto AI can also summarize notifications and even recall live or on-screen moments so you don&apos;t forget anything.</p><p>Motorola says these features will be available "in the coming months" following the launch of the Razr Plus 2024.</p><p>Lastly, the company promises the Razr Plus 2024 will receive three OS upgrades and four years of software updates, which is in-line with the previous Razr models.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-motorola-razr-plus-2024-cameras"><span>Motorola Razr Plus 2024: Cameras</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4752px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="oy6csgRftfn4QqXbexjBxP" name="Motorola-Razr-Plus-2024-camcorder-mode-lifestyle.jpg" alt="The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 in Camcorder Mode" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oy6csgRftfn4QqXbexjBxP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4752" height="2673" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Motorola)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Motorola has included a new set of cameras on the Razr Plus 2024, giving the phone dual 50MP sensors. The primary sensor is a standard wide-angle lens, while the secondary rear camera is a 2x telephoto. Motorola says this should allow users to capture more natural portraits of users without losing any detail when zoomed in.</p><p>The Razr Plus 2024 also promises improved quality over its predecessor, thanks to the Photo Enhancement Engine, which fine-tunes images "for optimal detail, clarity, highlights, shadows, color, and bokeh effects." Other AI-powered features include Adaptive Stabilization to keep the phone steady when there&apos;s a lot of movement, Action Shot for capturing fast-moving objects or people, and Super Zoom to enhance close-ups using AI.</p><p>Users will also have access to various shooting modes that take advantage of the hinge, like Auto Camcorder Mode, which automatically starts recording video when the phone is held in a camcorder-like position (as seen in the image above). This mode is also capable of shooting video in a vertical orientation, which is ideal for social media.</p><p>Lastly, on the front is a 32MP selfie camera capable of shooting 8MP images thanks to pixel binning.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-motorola-razr-2024-everything-you-need-to-know"><span>Motorola Razr 2024: Everything you need to know</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:10231px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="FeE6qpTu7DwUcTQQewxzWM" name="Motorola-Razr-2024-colors.jpg" alt="The Motorola Razr 2024 colors" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FeE6qpTu7DwUcTQQewxzWM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="10231" height="5755" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Motorola)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In addition to the flagship Razr Plus 2024, Motorola has also launched the cheaper Razr 2024, which comes less than a year after the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-2023-review">Razr 2023</a> made its way to North America. The phone adopts a nearly identical design to the Motorola Razr Plus 2023, bringing a larger 3.6-inch OLED panel that allows the use of apps and other features. The phone also comes in vegan leather finishes and, as mentioned before, is available in three different colors.</p><p>The phone is powered by a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/mediatek-dimensity-7300-series-chips-announcement">MediaTek 7300X</a> chipset, which is one of the newest midrange chips at the time of writing and should be a step up from the previous model&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/snapdragon-7-gen-1-launch">Snapdragon 7 Gen 1</a>. The phone retains 8GB of RAM but doubles its storage capacity to 256GB.</p>

<p>The Razr 2024 gets the same 50MP sensor as the Razr Plus 2024, so the camera should get many of the same improvements. The difference is that the secondary lens is a 13MP ultrawide/macro sensor, seemingly the same as last year&apos;s Razr Plus 2023. The front-facing camera is 32MP.</p><p>Compared to last year&apos;s models, the OLED display has also been improved, with a peak brightness of 3,000 nits, although the refresh rate is down to 120Hz. Meanwhile, the cover screen now has a peak of 1,700 nits, but it should also be more battery efficient with a 90Hz refresh rate compared to the 144Hz on the Razr Plus 2023.</p><p>The phone gets the same IPX8 rating as the Razr Plus 2024, so the device is protected from submersion. The battery capacity is the same as last year&apos;s model, but wireless charging has been improved with 15W speeds.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="d928a026-dc84-4555-b505-157326dd4a10">
            <a href="https://www.motorola.com/us/" data-model-name="null"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/znCGGT5zMeoWnypVRNhjQW.jpg' alt='The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 in Spring Green'></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Motorola Razr Plus 2024</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Flipping the script</strong></em></p>
<p>The new Motorola Razr Plus 2024 comes with the latest Snapdragon processor for access to new AI features, an even larger cover screen for a better app experience, and an improved camera system that lets you get up close and personal with Portrait photos.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="34c59b56-7c52-45d0-be38-bbd020a24995">
            <a href="https://www.motorola.com/us/" data-model-name="null"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/aQmkmwcXHNYdm3tKYBM5oK.jpg' alt='The Motorola Razr 2024 in Spritz Orange'></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Motorola Razr 2024</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Bigger is better</strong></em></p>
<p>The new Razr 2024 keeps the same price but adds a larger cover screen so you can use apps, take selfies, respond to messages, and much more without opening the phone. It also comes with a large battery, wireless charging, and a vegan leather finish, which feels great.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2024</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ We loved the Motorola Razr Plus 2023, but the Razr Plus 2024 brings plenty of welcome improvements. Here's everything you need to know. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">3PY2oco8TibefmnkmsD5zK</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wN7aUUTqqmbHTCQApMD5Ro.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 17:06:50 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ derrek.lee@futurenet.com (Derrek Lee) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wN7aUUTqqmbHTCQApMD5Ro.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Motorola]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Motorola Razr 2024 series colors]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Motorola Razr 2024 series colors]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Best screen protectors for Motorola Edge 2024 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Motorola has been on a roll lately. The brand never falters, relentlessly pushing out one new iteration after another time and time again. The Edge series has been refreshed to include the Motorola Edge 2024. If you&apos;ve bagged one for yourself, the first order of business is getting a screen protector.</p><p>Screen protection comes in multiple flavors, with tempered glass being a crowd favorite. You can also opt for TPU films or those fancy new hybrid screen guards which some call "glasstic". Regardless of your personal preference, here are all the best screen protectors for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-edge-2024-review">Motorola Edge 2024</a> gathered in one place for your perusal.</p>
<h2 id="say-hello-to-the-most-robust-screen-protection-for-your-moto-edge-2024-2">Say hello to the most robust screen protection for your Moto Edge 2024</h2>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="36b4cef5-73d9-4c52-854c-33a4fba40b54">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hQ3PUX8pySChNNMweKBWf3.jpg' alt='Supershieldz 2 Pack Motorola Edge 2024 Screen Protector TPU'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Supershieldz 2 Pack Motorola Edge 2024 Screen Protector TPU</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best overall</strong></em></p>
<p>Supershieldz excels at making both tempered glass and TPU film screen guards. This two-pack of TPU films can self-heal from minor scratches and it fits the Motorola Edge 2024's curved edges perfectly. You get unmatched touch sensitivity as well.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="c8775603-e8cd-4ab3-bf9c-171880967d1d">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oXCbut3Zg9rXuPT7ZxXJGX.jpg' alt='VIESUP Motorola Edge 2024 3D Curved Screen Protector'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">VIESUP Motorola Edge 2024 3D Curved Screen Protector</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best tempered glass</strong></em></p>
<p>If tempered glass is king in your books, get the VIESUP Motorola Edge 2024 3D Curved Screen Protector. There are two notch-less tempered glass screen guards in the box with curved edges and you get wipes to clean up the screen.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="a5984aab-8cb0-4713-bfb6-1a68e11d2166">
            <a href="https://www.t-mobile.com/commerce/accessory/goto-flex-screen-protector-for-motorola-edge-2024" data-model-name="null"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fVrnfRmiMYShLZLHuocqCb.jpg' alt='GoTo Flex Screen Protector for motorola edge 2024'></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">GoTo Flex Screen Protector for motorola edge 2024</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best high-end</strong></em></p>
<p>Sitting at the higher end of the spectrum, the GoTo Flex Screen Protector is a premium screen protection option for the Motorola Edge 2024. This high-grade TPU film comes with a very helpful installation kit.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="c37bc586-382e-4040-a1d8-95dfc2c30a36">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oBEw3RhKBvc59t4AKvP4T3.jpg' alt='KJYFOANI Motorola Edge 2024 Screen Protector Tempered Glass'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">KJYFOANI Motorola Edge 2024 Screen Protector Tempered Glass</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best budget</strong></em></p>
<p>It's nothing fancy, but the KJYFOANI Motorola Edge 2024 Screen Protector Tempered Glass does the job. This tempered glass protector is as cheap as crisps and has no camera cutout, making for a smoother application.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="9cc3fcb9-6525-4e5d-a975-0b12ad2221fb">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VEjCqXghmd5b84nZXAtf88.jpg' alt='Anbzsign 2 Pack Motorola Edge 2024 Soft TPU Screen Protector'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Anbzsign 2 Pack Motorola Edge 2024 Soft TPU Screen Protector</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best oleophobic</strong></em></p>
<p>Anbzsign usually stands out for its privacy screen protectors, but this regular flexible film is worth highlighting too. This two-pack has oleophobic soft films, which means they repel liquids and solids alike. This includes fingerprints too.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="abd51bd1-577d-4ac1-a96e-e1e95aab66bc">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JEbs5pm4GF3q67HHD4JMwC.jpg' alt='Fhyeugfy Hydrogel Screen Protector for Motorola Moto Edge 2024'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Fhyeugfy Hydrogel Screen Protector for Motorola Moto Edge 2024</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best hydrogel</strong></em></p>
<p>Hydrogel is a new breed of screen protector that's very similar to TPU films. It's hard to find hydrogel screen guards for brands like Motorola, but luckily, you can grab the Fhyeugfy Hydrogel Screen Protector for the Motorola Edge 2024.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<ul><li><a href="#main"><strong>Back to the top ^</strong></a></li></ul>
<h2 id="score-some-sturdy-screen-protectors-for-your-motorola-edge-2024-2">Score some sturdy screen protectors for your Motorola Edge 2024</h2>
<p>The Motorola Edge 2024 sports a lovely 6.6-inch pOLED display with a blazing-fast 144Hz screen refresh rate. This is the main attraction of the device, which is why it deserves a whole lot of tender love and caring.</p><p>Your best bet is the Supershieldz 2-Pack Motorola Edge 2024 Screen Protector TPU. This set of two screen protectors includes two flexible, high-grade TPU films that apply easily and self-repair scratches and small nicks. It&apos;s also really easy on your wallet, which is undoubtedly a big upside.</p><p>As for tempered glass options, the VIESUP Motorola Edge 2024 3D Curved Screen Protector is the optimal choice. There are two tempered glass screen protectors that are free of notches of cutouts. Plus, the edges are curved so they fit the Motorola Edge 2024 perfectly, without interfering with any case that you put on.</p><p>Speaking of cases, be sure to grab one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-cases-for-motorola-edge-2024">best cases for the Motorola Edge 2024</a> while you&apos;re at it. The sleek body of the device needs protection too.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-screen-protectors-for-motorola-edge-2024</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Your Moto Edge is incomplete without one of the best screen protectors for Motorola Edge 2024 protecting its gorgeous display. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">PCCuD7C5LvxyeKdjXxjEsk</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/i4pZZvLZrTTi5FZhp67c5U.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 16:38:53 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/i4pZZvLZrTTi5FZhp67c5U.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Motorola Edge (2024)&#039;s pOLED display showing the boot logo]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Motorola Edge (2024)&#039;s pOLED display showing the boot logo]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The new Moto Tag joins Google's Find My Device as a do-it-all tracker for $29.99 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-32">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The Moto Tag is here with a sleek, small design for users to clip onto their accessories with ease, boasting an IP67 rating for dust, dirt, and water resistance.</li><li>The Tag is available for Google's Find My Device network, bringing stronger security parameters and unwanted tracker alerts.</li><li>The Moto Tag's battery keeps it going for "a year" and is replaceable.</li><li>Consumers in the U.S. can grab the Moto Tag for $29.99 (pack of one) or $139.99 (pack of 4).</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>On June 25, Motorola debuted its brand new Bluetooth tracker alongside the new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2024-hands-on">Razr Plus 2024</a>, which will join Google&apos;s revamped Find My Device network.</p><p>According to a press release, the Moto Tag boasts a sleek design that should fit on most of the devices consumers are eager to track. The company states that the device features an IP67 rating to help it withstand dust, dirt, and water immersion (up to one meter) for around thirty minutes. Additionally, the Moto Tag&apos;s replaceable battery is said to keep users going for at least "one year" on a single charge before another is needed.</p><p>Google&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/testing-new-google-find-my-device-trackers">Find My Device network</a> is the kicker for the Moto Tag, and the company states users will experience "pinpoint" locations to find their lost items. Moreover, Moto states that when the Tag is paired with a device with a UWB (ultra-wideband) supported phone, like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-edge-50-ultra-launch">Edge 50 Ultra</a>, the accessory gains a boost in tracking capabilities.</p><p>Consumers can also ping their lost device using the Moto Tag to find it quickly.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:396px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:151.52%;"><img id="ejhN9aixPh7MyUAJczqXbn" name="motorola-tag-lifestyle-promo.jpg" alt="The Moto Tag." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ejhN9aixPh7MyUAJczqXbn.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="396" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Motorola)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Additionally, the Moto Tag features a "dedicated multifunctional button." Pressing it will enable users to find lost items quickly, but it can also be used as a remote camera controller for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phones</a>.</p><p>Setting up the Moto Tag is seamless, with the company stating that it only needs to be near your device. Google&apos;s Fast Pair technology takes over from there. After the connection is established, users can customize their Tag&apos;s name, alert volume, battery life, and more.</p><p>Motorola states that privacy remains secure through the Tag. Users&apos; location data is end-to-end encrypted, keeping their information between them and the Find My Device app. The Moto Tag is also compatible with iOS and Android&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-unknown-tracker-alerts-roll-out">unwanted tracker alerts</a>, so users have peace of mind when traveling. Motorola reiterates that users can run a manual scan to ensure there are no unwanted trackers on their person or luggage.</p><p>The new Motorola Tag will be available on motorola.com starting August 2 for those in the U.S., retailing for $29.99 or $99.99 for a pack of four. Those in Canada can grab it for $39.99 (one pack) or $139.99 (pack of four).</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/moto-tag-bluetooth-tracker-launch</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Motorola debuted the new "Moto Tag" Bluetooth tracker, available for Google's Find My Device network. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">FUoPV7bigZqbPuKEfriX4m</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ATXdkTHsvdR83mroonnjKf.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 16:26:01 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ATXdkTHsvdR83mroonnjKf.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Motorola]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Moto Tag in green.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Moto Tag in green.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>