<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 13:42:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Pixel Phone app might let you respond with AI replies to calls soon ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The Phone app might soon use Google’s Gemini AI to create dynamic, context-aware replies, making call screening more personalized.</li><li>Internally, Call Screen is known as "dobby," but with the addition of "dobby_AI" and "dobby_LLM," AI-generated responses are on the way.</li><li>The AI Replies feature will use Gemini Nano for smarter responses, so it could be exclusive to Pixel 8 Pro and Pixel 9 due to their AI capabilities.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google has been spotted cooking up an "AI Replies" feature for Pixel’s Call Screen, offering smarter, more relevant responses than the current basic options.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/11/06/pixel-phone-call-screen-ai-replies/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a> recently discovered that the Phone app will soon use Google’s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini AI</a> to create dynamic, context-aware responses for incoming calls, making call screening smarter and more personalized.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-use-call-screen-feature-pixel">Call Screen feature</a> is currently labeled "dobby" internally, but with the recent appearance of "dobby_AI" and "dobby_LLM" in the code, it looks like Google is ready to integrate an AI model to power AI-generated responses.</p><p>Android 12 introduced the call-screening feature that lets you filter calls and have <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-assistant">Google Assistant</a> handle the first chat. It plays an auto-message, grabs the caller's reply, and transcribes it, so you can decide whether to answer or just text back.</p><p>Last December, Google <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-pixel-feature-drop-december-2023">introduced "contextual replies,"</a> which personalize audio responses based on the call's context. The new upgrade is likely to make those replies more dynamic and detailed. You’ll still have the option to select from preset responses on screen rather than typing one out.</p><p>Apparently, Google’s upcoming AI Replies feature will tap into the power of Gemini Nano to offer smarter response suggestions. This could mean that to make the most of Gemini Nano, the feature will be exclusive to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-pro-review">Pixel 8 Pro</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9">Pixel 9</a> devices, which have the AI processing power needed.</p><p>Though the full capabilities of AI Replies aren’t fully revealed yet, the AI integration is set to greatly improve its ability to understand caller intent and offer more relevant response options.</p><p>AI Replies could totally shake up how we deal with calls. Imagine letting AI handle the awkward conversations, saving you time, and keeping your day from getting interrupted by every random call. This could be what Google had in mind when it <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-injecting-ai-into-pixel-call-screen">talked about “multi-step, multi-turn conversational AI” last year</a>.</p>
<hr>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="2b739e63-76ba-47de-8116-6ea4ee5659c3">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9r2TB3ryPNaJv37UDZK25j.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 official render Porcelain back"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>The Pixel 9 brings a fresh design that’s got a bit of an iPhone vibe. Not everyone might be a fan of the new look, but it definitely feels more premium than previous models. Plus, the upgraded camera takes photo and video quality to a whole new level.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/the-pixel-phone-app-might-let-you-respond-with-ai-replies-to-calls-soon</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Pixel's Call Screen could get smarter with AI-assisted replies. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">fmFvg7CKjV8bT4sgsjSieB</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/E2Ym3FmaJDtZHuz8fKJLvk.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 11:58:10 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/E2Ym3FmaJDtZHuz8fKJLvk.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Future]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Phone call being screened on a Pixel phone]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Phone call being screened on a Pixel phone]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Galaxy S25 'Slim' could pack a serious camera punch despite its thin profile ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung is reportedly planning the S25 Slim to compete with the rumored iPhone 17 Slim, alongside the usual S25 Ultra, Plus, and standard models.</li><li>Leaker @UniverseIce hints that the S25 Slim could pack a camera similar to the Galaxy Ultra line.</li><li>Details on the Slim’s secondary lenses are unclear, but they might not match the rumored 50MP ultrawide and variable telephoto lens of the S25 Ultra.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Recent reports <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/a-slim-galaxy-s25-might-be-samsungs-answer-to-apples-rumored-thin-iphone-17">suggest there’s a Galaxy S25 Slim model in the works</a>, and a new rumor hints it might come packed with an "Ultra" camera in a slim design.</p><p>Alongside the regular <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-preorder-deals-what-to-expect">Galaxy S25</a>, Plus, and Ultra models, Samsung is reportedly rolling out a slimmer S25 variant to challenge the rumored iPhone 17 Slim.</p><p>Slim phones usually mean compromises to hardware, especially with the camera, but the Galaxy S25 Slim seems to break that mold.</p><p>Renowned leaker @UniverseIce claimed that the device will pack a camera similar to Samsung's Galaxy Ultra line. While exact specs are still under wraps, it’s rumored this could mean one or more camera sensors from the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review">Galaxy S24 Ultra</a>—or maybe even the upcoming S25 Ultra.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Exclusive: The Galaxy S25 Slim is equipped with an “Ultra” camera.<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1854367791438336189">November 7, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-special-edition-announced">Galaxy Z Fold Special Edition</a>, with its 200MP main camera, shows Samsung is ready to bring top-notch camera tech to more than just its Ultra models.</p><p>While the slimmer Galaxy S25 is expected to pack a strong main camera, details on its secondary lenses are still coming to light. It’s yet to be seen if they’ll match the rumored specs of the Galaxy S25 Ultra, which is said to have a 50MP ultrawide sensor and a smart variable telephoto lens that makes a second telephoto camera unnecessary.</p><p>While the source behind this leak has a solid track record, it’s best to take it with a grain of salt. Given the slim design, it’s likely the Galaxy S25 Slim will have fewer or less advanced camera sensors compared to the other S25 models.</p><p>Recent discoveries from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.smartprix.com/bytes/samsungs-mysterious-galaxy-s25-slim-smartphone-officially-spotted-for-first-time/" target="_blank">Smartprix</a>, including a product listing for a phone with the model number SM-S937U in the GSMA IMEI database, offer more proof that the Galaxy S25 Slim is real.</p><p>Smartprix notes that the model number SM-S937 fits the expected naming pattern for the Galaxy S25 series. With the Galaxy S25 likely being SM-S931, the S25 Plus SM-S936, and the S25 Ultra SM-S938, the SM-S937 for the Slim model would make sense as it sits between the Plus and Ultra variants.</p><p>That said, it’s possible the Galaxy S25 Slim won’t launch alongside the main S25 series in early 2025. Smartprix points out that Samsung usually adds devices to the GSMA database about six to seven months before their official release, which lines up with a late spring launch. Since Samsung's next line of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-samsung-phones">flagship Galaxy phones</a> is expected to drop in late January or early February, the Slim model likely won’t arrive until May or June 2025.</p>
<hr>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="c133d507-c9c3-4174-b38d-0ddce0279037">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/EHj6g5yMqMQDLfkqaYuXzX.jpg' alt="Samsung s24 "></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S24</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>If you're all about the Samsung ecosystem, the Galaxy S24 is the most budget-friendly pick from the new S24 lineup. Launched in early 2024, it’s packed with premium specs, Google’s Gemini AI, and a little extra Samsung flair—think Samsung Health and the One UI overlay.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-galaxy-s25-slim-could-pack-a-serious-camera-punch-despite-its-thin-profile</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung’s rumored Galaxy S25 Slim might squeeze an 'Ultra' camera into its sleek frame. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">JpuvhkzHzRoChRm5rFqcoa</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9qKXtbtAV6H5ijMbkftky9.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 09:16:24 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9qKXtbtAV6H5ijMbkftky9.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[All four retail colors of the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[All four retail colors of the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ My favorite flagship earbuds from EarFun are already on sale before Black Friday ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>EarFun is one of the most underrated audio brands to exist in the market. The EarFun Air Pro 4 earbuds are thoroughly premium and fresh out of the oven. So it&apos;s really hard to believe that this August 2024 release is already on sale — and it&apos;s not even Black Friday yet!</p><p>Don&apos;t wait around for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024-early-deals-and-how-to-prepare-for-the-big-sales">Samsung&apos;s Black Friday discounts</a> to get a good pair of wireless earbuds. I wholeheartedly recommend the fabulous EarFun Air Pro 4 wireless earbuds for top-notch sound quality, an uber-comfortable fit, and state-of-the-art features. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D5M9SH1X"><strong>Amazon is offering 27% off these buds</strong></a> at the moment, bringing the price down from $89.99 to a more budget-friendly $65.99.</p><p>EarFun gives you everything and more for very little money. You get Google Fast Pair and support for codecs like Qualcomm aptX Adaptive and LDAC. Even the battery life is awesome, lasting for several days with heavy use. These hi-res earbuds are even Auracast-ready, which makes them incredibly future-proof. These are some of the many reasons why the Air Pro 4 are our top budget pick for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-earbuds">best wireless earbuds</a>.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="26f1aaf9-5411-4954-b579-bd75fe9ceb28" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$89.99" data-dimension48="$89.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D5M9SH1X" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1484px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="rewm52LKkCXKUKd5gioayM" name="EarFun Air Pro 4 render square.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rewm52LKkCXKUKd5gioayM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1484" height="1484" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>EarFun Air Pro 4:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D5M9SH1X" data-dimension112="26f1aaf9-5411-4954-b579-bd75fe9ceb28" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$89.99" data-dimension48="$89.99" data-dimension25=""><del>$89.99</del> <strong>$65.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/earfun-air-pro-4-review">EarFun Air Pro 4</a> wireless earbuds just came out in August 2024, so it comes as a very welcome surprise to see them 27% off already. You can these nearly-$100 earbuds for a lot more accessible price tag while this pre-Black Friday deal lasts. Equipped with premium features like Bluetooth Auracast, LDAC, and hi-res audio support, these are some high-end earbuds that sound good, look good, and feel good.</p>
<p>The deal ends in just a couple hours, so don't wait if you're interested!<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D5M9SH1X" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="26f1aaf9-5411-4954-b579-bd75fe9ceb28" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$89.99" data-dimension48="$89.99" data-dimension25="">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>you want all the best audio codecs for audiophiles; finding comfortable earbuds is tough for you; you want something with Bluetooth Auracast to be future-proof; longevity of battery life is very important to you; you want wireless charging.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>you want a more robust dust-proof rating; colorful options are high up on your list of must-haves.</p><p>Back when I reviewed the last-gen <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/earfun-air-pro-3-review">EarFun Air Pro 3 buds</a>, I said that they set the bar for 2023. Somehow, EarFun managed to one-up itself this year. The 2024 follow-up isn&apos;t just as good as its prequel — it beats it fair and square.</p><p>You&apos;ll be hard-pressed to find such an awesome mix of features for so less, especially with this deal which slashes a neat 27% off the retail price. EarFun even threw in wireless charging and LED lights to indicate the battery life of the buds.</p><p>The only area where the EarFun Air Pro 4 earbuds are lacking is ingress protection. You get an IPX5 splash-proof rating with these buds, which is mediocre at best. Other than that, everything else is a home run.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/earbuds/my-favorite-flagship-earbuds-from-earfun-are-already-on-sale-before-black-friday</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The EarFun Air Pro 4 earbuds only just released and they're already on sale! Who even needs Black Friday? ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">68VUqN73XPuJovNGR2n3XP</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7GqwEQfp6GVzU8eVBXaHq6.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 21:06:53 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Earbuds]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7GqwEQfp6GVzU8eVBXaHq6.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[EarFun Air Pro 4 wireless earbuds in black]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[EarFun Air Pro 4 wireless earbuds in black]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ OnePlus 13 might grab Google's offline Find My Device feature for Pixels ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A report claims the OnePlus 13 could receive Google's offline rediscovery feature, which the Pixel 9 and 8 series have.</li><li>The OnePlus 12 reportedly lacks such "hardware capabilities" to support it; however, the OnePlus 13's Snapdragon 8 Elite is capable.</li><li>Google detailed the function shortly after Find My Device hit more devices, stating (at the time) the Pixel 8 could report its location for "several hours" after turning off.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>The latest OnePlus flagship phone is here, but a recent discovery could indicate more to come.</p><p>According to Mishaal Rahman (<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/oneplus-13-powered-off-finding-3497244/">Android Authority</a>), a previous beta for OxygenOS 15 might've teased an upcoming Pixel-exclusive feature for the OnePlus 13. Rahman states that he downloaded the beta on a OnePlus 12 and discovered an Android-provided message when looking at its power options.</p><p>Attempting to shut down the phone displayed, "you can locate this phone with 'Find My Device' even when powered off."</p><p>Curiously, last year's flagship phone isn't receiving such support. The Chinese OEM reportedly confirmed as much to the publication. According to OnePlus' statement, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12-review">OnePlus 12</a> contains an "8650 platform" via the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 chipset. This limits its capability to support offline rediscovery through the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-find-my-device-network-rolls-out">Find My Device network</a>.</p><p>Confirmation of the OnePlus 12's lack of the offline discovery feature pushed Rahman toward the 2024 flagship. The post adds that the recent <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-announces-snapdragon-8-elite-chip">Snapdragon 8 Elite</a> SoC contains a FastConnect 7900 connectivity subsystem. Rahman states that Qualcomm confirmed that this subsystem features all the necessities behind the appropriate connection for the Find My Device network's "Power Off Finding."</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="t8sWjiJCHqgnHTnPQahecR" name="find-device-2.jpg" alt="Find My Device home page log in to Google account against colorful background" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/t8sWjiJCHqgnHTnPQahecR.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The OnePlus 13 <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-13-goes-official-in-china">debuted on October 31</a> on home soil in China. Qualcomm's latest flagship SoC grants the device a massive power boost in efficiency and performance. What's more, consumers in China can experience its 6.8-inch <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-13-display-sourced-by-boe-surfaces-online">2K Oriental display</a> with a 120Hz refresh rate alongside its large 6,000mAh battery.</p><p>The inclusion of the Snapdragon 8 Elite makes it possible for OnePlus to bring offline discovery to its latest smartphone. However, Qualcomm informed Rahman that this feature is "up to OEMs to implement and use it." OnePlus did not announce "Power Off Finding" for the 13 series in October, meaning it's likely still developing it.</p><p>It's speculation, but this function <em>could </em>arrive with a future OxygenOS 15 (Android 15) update.</p><p>Shortly after the revamped Find My Device network hit more devices, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-explains-pixel-8-find-my-device-powered-off">Google detailed</a> how its unique Pixel-exclusive feature works. Per its document, the Pixel 8 and 9's offline discovery can function "for several hours" after the phone turns off. Google's recent two flagships were the only ones to have such functionality due to some "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-find-my-device-network-rolls-out">specialized Pixel hardware.</a>" With Qualcomm's latest SoC including such hardware, we may see more OEMs adopt this useful rediscovery feature.</p><p>In other news, OxygenOS 15 (Android 15) <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-oneplus-12-is-now-getting-the-stable-android-15-update">started hitting the OnePlus 12 </a>and is on tap to continue to more of its past-gen devices throughout the year.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-13-offline-find-my-network-feature-potential-support</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A report states the OnePlus 13 could grab offline Find My Device capabilities like the Pixel 9 and 8. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">vy4wPvKpjZ4U39JnHNWJWM</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LK6ZtRVbAb4To3UytPsuiY.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 20:57:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LK6ZtRVbAb4To3UytPsuiY.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[OnePlus]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus 13]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus 13]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Black Friday OnePlus deals — all the best discounts I've found so far, plus some smartphone shopping tips ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Black Friday isn&apos;t for another couple of weeks, but retailers are already dropping some pretty impressive OnePlus deals ahead of the big holiday sales. Whether you&apos;re in the market for a discounted flagship or an innovative foldable, all of the best OnePlus discounts of Black Friday 2024 (so far) can be found in this guide. </p>
<ul><li><em><strong>See more Black Friday phone deals: </strong></em><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare"><em><strong>Google</strong></em></a><em><strong> | </strong></em><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024-early-deals-and-how-to-prepare-for-the-big-sales"><em><strong>Samsung</strong></em></a><em><strong> | </strong></em><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more"><em><strong>Motorola</strong></em></a></li></ul>
<p>The early offers range from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CQ5MYYZL"><strong>$150 off the OnePlus 12</strong></a> at Best Buy (which just so happens to be <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">our favorite Android phone</a> of the year) to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-Dual-SIM-Unlocked-Smartphone-Hasselblad/dp/B0CHN8FNW3"><strong>a whopping 24% off the premium OnePlus Open</strong></a>. We&apos;re sure to see even more discounts in the coming days, but for now, these are the best holiday offers from one of the world&apos;s best OEMs.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-quick-links"><span>Quick links</span></h3>
<ul><li><strong>OnePlus 12:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oneplus-12-512gb-unlocked-flowy-emerald/6570639.p"><del>was $799.99</del><strong> now $649.99 at Best Buy</strong></a></li><li><strong>OnePlus Open: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oneplus-open-16gb-512gb-unlocked-voyager-black/6562713.p"><del>was $1,699.99</del><strong> now $1,299.99 at Best Buy</strong></a></li><li><strong>OnePlus Buds 3: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-Metallic-Immersive-Playtime-Bluetooth/dp/B0CRZCMPMW"><del>was $99.99</del> <strong>now $68.99 at Amazon</strong></a></li><li><strong>OnePlus 12R:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CQ9SZJN6"><del>was $599.99</del><strong> now $529.99 at Amazon</strong></a></li><li><strong>OnePlus Nord N30 5G: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-Unlocked-Dual-SIM-Charging-Chromatic/dp/B0C22BRGLG"><del>was $299.99</del> <strong>now $249.99 at Amazon</strong></a></li><li><strong>OnePlus Pad 2:</strong> <a href="https://www.oneplus.com/us/buy-oneplus-pad-2"><del>was $549.99</del><strong> now $499.99, plus free earbuds at OnePlus</strong></a></li></ul>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-oneplus-deals"><span>OnePlus deals</span></h3>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="92cc86e1-c5e6-4c63-a6e9-bb9657d85edd" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799.99" data-dimension48="$799.99" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oneplus-12-512gb-unlocked-flowy-emerald/6570639.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="yf3PmQ3byJBHbWmMtoDrv8" name="OnePlus-12.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yf3PmQ3byJBHbWmMtoDrv8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>OnePlus 12 256GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oneplus-12-512gb-unlocked-flowy-emerald/6570639.p" data-dimension112="92cc86e1-c5e6-4c63-a6e9-bb9657d85edd" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799.99" data-dimension48="$799.99"><del>$799.99</del> <strong>$649.99 at Best Buy</strong></a></p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12-review">OnePlus 12</a> ranks among the best phones of 2024 because it balances elegant design with lightning-fast performance and some of the best camera tech we've used all year. You miss out on some AI features and won't get the same number of OS updates as you would with a Samsung or Pixel device, but with a whopping $150 discount on the phone at Best Buy, I'm not complaining. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oneplus-12-512gb-unlocked-flowy-emerald/6570639.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="92cc86e1-c5e6-4c63-a6e9-bb9657d85edd" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799.99" data-dimension48="$799.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="c2aed360-64de-4737-a130-c7a07f001be6" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,699.99" data-dimension48="$1,699.99" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oneplus-open-16gb-512gb-unlocked-voyager-black/6562713.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="rdUQJmXLM9wq3V6vTrDPa4" name="OnePlus Open bg render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rdUQJmXLM9wq3V6vTrDPa4.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>OnePlus Open 512GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oneplus-open-16gb-512gb-unlocked-voyager-black/6562713.p" data-dimension112="c2aed360-64de-4737-a130-c7a07f001be6" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,699.99" data-dimension48="$1,699.99"><del>$1,699.99</del> <strong>$1,299.99 at Best Buy</strong></a></p>
<p>Currently $400 off during Best Buy's early Black Friday sale, the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-open-review">OnePlus Open</a> is a powerful folding smartphone with a super-efficient processor, awesome cameras, and a nearly-invisible hinge. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oneplus-open-16gb-512gb-unlocked-voyager-black/6562713.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="c2aed360-64de-4737-a130-c7a07f001be6" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,699.99" data-dimension48="$1,699.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="9d7b3d19-a696-404e-8907-3931d7e8b2a9" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$99.99" data-dimension48="$99.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-Metallic-Immersive-Playtime-Bluetooth/dp/B0CRZCMPMW" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1498px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="SuMj4dmwaQBCgaVgUQDYEJ" name="OnePlus Buds 3 square render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SuMj4dmwaQBCgaVgUQDYEJ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1498" height="1498" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>OnePlus Buds 3:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-Metallic-Immersive-Playtime-Bluetooth/dp/B0CRZCMPMW" data-dimension112="9d7b3d19-a696-404e-8907-3931d7e8b2a9" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$99.99" data-dimension48="$99.99"><del>$99.99</del> <strong>$68.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>If you're looking for a cheap pair of <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-earbuds">wireless earbuds</a>, don't sleep on the OnePlus Buds 3. These earbuds boast great audio quality and battery life with some decent-for-the-price noise cancellation, and thanks to Amazon's early Black Friday sale, you can get them with a whopping 31% discount. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-Metallic-Immersive-Playtime-Bluetooth/dp/B0CRZCMPMW" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="9d7b3d19-a696-404e-8907-3931d7e8b2a9" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$99.99" data-dimension48="$99.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="933514b6-69db-481c-b7ef-dc0b5889f8d7" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$599.99" data-dimension48="$599.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CQ9SZJN6" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="Rxy5RqYz7L5eAVG3FMuHeY" name="OnePlus-12R-square-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Rxy5RqYz7L5eAVG3FMuHeY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1500" height="1500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>OnePlus 12R 256GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CQ9SZJN6" data-dimension112="933514b6-69db-481c-b7ef-dc0b5889f8d7" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$599.99" data-dimension48="$599.99"><del>$599.99</del> <strong>$529.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>Looking for a flagship phone experience at a midrange price? The <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12r-review">OnePlus 12R</a> is the answer, coming in hot with a vibrant AMOLED display, efficient software, and two days of battery life on a single charge. Grab the 256GB phone unlocked from Amazon today and you'll score a straight $70 discount, no strings attached. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CQ9SZJN6" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="933514b6-69db-481c-b7ef-dc0b5889f8d7" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$599.99" data-dimension48="$599.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="20a3e61c-5d78-4415-87ce-aa558cab669f" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="OnePlus Nord N30 5G 128GB: $299.99" data-dimension48="OnePlus Nord N30 5G 128GB: $299.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-Unlocked-Dual-SIM-Charging-Chromatic/dp/B0C22BRGLG" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="f8KVXqLsT23t2wRZQ7LB8d" name="oneplus nord n30 5g 400x500.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/f8KVXqLsT23t2wRZQ7LB8d.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>OnePlus Nord N30 5G 128GB: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-Unlocked-Dual-SIM-Charging-Chromatic/dp/B0C22BRGLG" data-dimension112="20a3e61c-5d78-4415-87ce-aa558cab669f" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="OnePlus Nord N30 5G 128GB: $299.99" data-dimension48="OnePlus Nord N30 5G 128GB: $299.99"><del>$299.99</del> <strong>$249.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>Although it's well over a year old at this point, the OnePlus Nord N30 5G remains a pretty solid option if you're looking for an Android phone under $300. The device boasts a reliable 5,000mAh battery with a fast processor and 8GB of RAM, and there's even a 3.5mm headphone jack. Best of all, if you buy the N30 unlocked from Amazon you'll enjoy a straight 17% discount. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-Unlocked-Dual-SIM-Charging-Chromatic/dp/B0C22BRGLG" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="20a3e61c-5d78-4415-87ce-aa558cab669f" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="OnePlus Nord N30 5G 128GB: $299.99" data-dimension48="OnePlus Nord N30 5G 128GB: $299.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="025be18e-4b5f-4b71-8894-35dabd3f4fb6" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$549.99" data-dimension48="$549.99" href="https://www.oneplus.com/us/buy-oneplus-pad-2" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:625px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="oCCvssnMbjX6NBeSHEnmMJ" name="OnePlus-Pad-2-render-square.jpeg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oCCvssnMbjX6NBeSHEnmMJ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="625" height="625" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>OnePlus Pad 2 256GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.oneplus.com/us/buy-oneplus-pad-2" data-dimension112="025be18e-4b5f-4b71-8894-35dabd3f4fb6" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$549.99" data-dimension48="$549.99"><del>$549.99</del> <strong>$499.99, plus FREE OnePlus Buds 3 Pro at OnePlus</strong></a></p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/oneplus-pad-2-review">OnePlus Pad 2</a> is a powerful tablet with a Qualcomm processor, great battery life, and a 12.1-inch display with a refresh rate of up to 144Hz. Pick up the device directly from OnePlus and you'll score a $50 discount AND a free pair of Buds 3 Pro earbuds (a $179.99 value).<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.oneplus.com/us/buy-oneplus-pad-2" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="025be18e-4b5f-4b71-8894-35dabd3f4fb6" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$549.99" data-dimension48="$549.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-faq"><span>FAQ</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="wqSPhic2VDgqBuGjam8e8J" name="oneplus-12-26.jpg" alt="OnePlus 12 app sorting" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wqSPhic2VDgqBuGjam8e8J.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<h2 id="when-does-the-oneplus-13-come-out-2">When does the OnePlus 13 come out?</h2>
<p>The new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-13">OnePlus 13</a> was officially announced at a launch event in China on October 30th and was released in that country on November 4th. While we don&apos;t have a global release date just yet, if the new flagship follows the trend set by the OnePlus 12 we&apos;ll probably get our hands on the phone sometime in January. </p>
<h2 id="when-do-the-black-friday-sales-start-2">When do the Black Friday sales start?</h2>
<p>Although Black Friday doesn&apos;t technically arrive until November 29th this year, retailers have wasted no time in dropping holiday deals before the big weekend. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/best-buy-black-friday-sale-top-android-deals-2024">Best Buy formally launched its sale this week</a>, and we expect other sites to follow suit in the coming days. Needless to say, we&apos;ll be keeping track of all of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/black-friday-2024">best Black Friday Android sales</a> throughout the holiday season, so stick with us if you want regular deal coverage. </p>
<h2 id="which-retailer-has-the-best-phone-deals-on-black-friday-2">Which retailer has the best phone deals on Black Friday?</h2>
<p>If you&apos;re planning on buying a new smartphone this holiday season, I&apos;d suggest checking with your wireless carrier before hitting up Amazon, Best Buy, or Walmart. Unless you prefer to buy your phones unlocked, you might be surprised to see what kind of trade-in opportunities and wireless promos your phone company is offering around Black Friday. Naturally, I also suggest that you keep an eye on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/deals">Android Central&apos;s deal coverage</a> around all sale events, as we&apos;ll be working around the clock to find all of the best smartphone deals across the web so you don&apos;t have to. </p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Black Friday is nearly upon us, but retailers have wasted no time in dropping some of the best OnePlus deals that we've seen all year. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">5SYPEDzoDeEWdpuQJX6NfB</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZvaqeXhwBnRUeDTvFUHLwE.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 20:33:27 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZvaqeXhwBnRUeDTvFUHLwE.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus Open review]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus Open review]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Latest Motorola Rizr rollable phone patent highlights new security tricks ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A report highlights Motorola's updated patent for its rollable phone concept, Rizr.</li><li>The U.S. patent shows Motorola's plans to incorporate additional fingerprint-on-display (FOD) sensors on the "front" and "back" of the device.</li><li>Motorola showcased the Rizr during MWC 2023, showcasing its default 5-inch display and fully extended 6.5-inch screen when rolled out.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Motorola has had a rollable phone concept stewing for a while and a newly published patent details some additions.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.mysmartprice.com/gear/mobiles/mobiles-news/motorola-new-patent-rollable-display-full-screen-fingerprint-sensing/">MySmartPrice</a> spotted an updated patent for the company's rollable phone concept, the "Motorola Rizr." The patent details a device with multiple fingerprint-reading sensors in the USPTO database listing. According to the abstract, Motorola states the device in question "provides a predictable external fingerprint area on a 'rollable display device' for fingerprint authentication."</p><p>The company adds, "this is available at least in both a fully retracted position and fully extended position."</p><p>U.S. patents published on November 5 show at least two positions users <em>could </em>utilize on this rollable phone. The first fingerprint-on-display (FOD) sensor is on the "front" of the phone in its retracted state. Motorola's patent states a user would find this sensor centered near the bottom of the device.</p><p>The second is featured on the back of the phone. At the very least, such a design would give some additional purpose to the "backside" of the display when it's in a compact state.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:964px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:62.24%;"><img id="5i3vEidhciDNoMYPs2ZHR5" name="motorola-rizr-updated-patent-fingerprint-on-display" alt="An updated Motorola Rizr patent highlighting its double fingerprint-on-display (FOD) sensors." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5i3vEidhciDNoMYPs2ZHR5.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="964" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: MySmartPrice)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The publication dove into the patent further, but couldn't find any additional changes/updates. The post states the device's concept retains its 6.5-inch display when fully rolled out (5 inches when retracted).</p><p>Motorola showed off its rollable phone <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-rizr-concept-mwc-2023">during MWC 2023</a>. During the event, users quickly discovered a hidden front-facing camera and speaker. The device offers a 5-inch display by default, but this display rolls back even further automatically when taking a selfie or on a call. Moreover, additional insight by Android Central during <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-motorola-rizr-is-the-sharper-image-of-the-smartphone-world">a visit to Motorola's HQ in Chicago</a> showed that shifting its orientation (from portrait to landscape) during a video would see it extend on its own.</p><p>While it's a cool concept, the durability of such a device was called forward. The display isn't flush to the chassis and some parts seem far too exposed when fully rolled out. This is a concept, meaning things can always change — or it could never see a store shelf.</p><p>However, there's no hiding that OEMs are consistently seeking the "next big thing," like a rollable phone. Motorola has the Rizr still in its concept era and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/oppo-x-2021-rollable-concept-phone-tablet-74-inch-screen">OPPO X 2021</a> took the spotlight in 2020. More importantly, Samsung was <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-rollable-phone-pursuit-alleged-report">rumored to be <em>more </em>interested</a> in a rollable phone after Huawei's Mate XT (tri-fold) debuted.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-rizr-rollable-phone-updated-fingerprint-patent</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A new patent for Motorola's rollable phone concept was spotted with a new addition. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">h7FmUa6y2nJzLgmzfZyjVE</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/d2G6c5pnyncie3cmjPuNgY.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 19:46:32 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/d2G6c5pnyncie3cmjPuNgY.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Motorola Rizr foldable phone concept]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Motorola Rizr foldable phone concept]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Three reasons you should wait for the Galaxy S25 (and one reason you shouldn't) ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>After receiving my first early samples of Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra cases, I'm more stoked for Samsung's 2025 phone releases than ever. The Galaxy S25 Ultra seems to be getting the lion's share of the attention this time around, similar to what we saw earlier this year, but that doesn't mean the rest of the pack is any less exciting.</p><p>Quite the contrary, actually. It's actually been difficult narrowing it down to the three things I'm looking forward to the most, but I think I can be confident that the following list represents the best of what we're expecting to see from Samsung in January.</p>

<h2 id="round-yet-square-2">Round, yet square</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="GbvfHgckkaBuPKC3tkr7XQ" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-Ultra-case-vs-Galaxy-S25-Ultra-case-back" alt="Comparing a Fiberborne Galaxy S25 Ultra case with a Galaxy S24 Ultra case and the Galaxy S24 Ultra" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GbvfHgckkaBuPKC3tkr7XQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Galaxy S Ultra series has had a bit of a controversial design over the past few years. The Galaxy S22 Ultra took many design cues from the Galaxy Note 20 Ultra, carrying on the Note line in everything but the name. Largely, this design meant sharp, square corners and rounded edges.</p><p>I've never been a fan of this design and apparently someone else hasn't either, as Samsung may be switching things up this time arounf, quite literally flipping the squared and rounded edges according to all the rumors and leaks we've seen so far. That means the Galaxy S25 Ultra may have round corners and flat sides just as we saw Samsung do with the Galaxy S24 <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-hands-on">earlier this year</a>.<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.fiberborne.com/products/super-thin-galaxy-s25-ultra-case-aramid-fiber-magsafe"></a></p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="3PFGcFhrvHLEFfg8xD4YUQ" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-Ultra-with-Galaxy-S25-Ultra-case-back" alt="Comparing a Fiberborne Galaxy S25 Ultra case with a Galaxy S24 Ultra case and the Galaxy S24 Ultra" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3PFGcFhrvHLEFfg8xD4YUQ.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="G6UdmVkTJhSLcGY3D8JoTQ" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-Ultra-with-Galaxy-S25-Ultra-case-corners" alt="Comparing a Fiberborne Galaxy S25 Ultra case with a Galaxy S24 Ultra case and the Galaxy S24 Ultra" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/G6UdmVkTJhSLcGY3D8JoTQ.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="FqGsrNL7UG4n4WFcDu6FVQ" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-Ultra-case-vs-Galaxy-S25-Ultra-case-bottom" alt="Comparing a Fiberborne Galaxy S25 Ultra case with a Galaxy S24 Ultra case and the Galaxy S24 Ultra" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FqGsrNL7UG4n4WFcDu6FVQ.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 4 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.30%;"><img id="52BzQvqJvwU7KNXuEGSoVQ" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-Ultra-case-vs-Galaxy-S25-Ultra-case-corners" alt="Comparing a Fiberborne Galaxy S25 Ultra case with a Galaxy S24 Ultra case and the Galaxy S24 Ultra" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/52BzQvqJvwU7KNXuEGSoVQ.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1153" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 5 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="mvdmWH8T9nD4m2e9gW9nVQ" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-Ultra-with-Galaxy-S25-Ultra-case-back-angle" alt="Comparing a Fiberborne Galaxy S25 Ultra case with a Galaxy S24 Ultra case and the Galaxy S24 Ultra" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mvdmWH8T9nD4m2e9gW9nVQ.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>I just received the first samples of Galaxy S25 Ultra cases from Fiberborne, the new name for the Thinborne aramid fiber cases we've regularly crowned as the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-galaxy-s24-cases">best Galaxy S24 cases</a>.</p><p>These <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.fiberborne.com/products/super-thin-galaxy-s25-ultra-case-aramid-fiber-magsafe" target="_blank">new Fiberborne cases</a> aren't on sale quite yet, but they do reveal what may be the new design of the Galaxy S25 Ultra, and I'm mostly loving it. I'm not the biggest fan of phones with completely flat sides — I said as much in my <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-review">Google Pixel 9 Pro review</a> — but the rounded corners will certainly go a long way to making this phone more comfortable than the last three years of Galaxy S ultra models with their overly sharp corners.</p>
<h2 id="laptop-grade-processor-2">Laptop-grade processor</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2561px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="iSwnGsFpVnXEJKXLtGX2bR" name="Snapdragon-8-Elite-Night-Photo" alt="A Qualcomm photo showing a hand holding a smartphone with a photo taken at night on screen, with the Snapdragon 8 Elite logo hovering above it." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/iSwnGsFpVnXEJKXLtGX2bR.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2561" height="1441" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Qualcomm)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Mobile processors have been pretty boring for the past few years now. While we've seen performance gains year over year, most of those improvements end up being lost to excess heat when playing games for more than 20 or 30 minutes. A lot of emphasis has been placed on AI processing because of it, but the new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/snapdragon-8-elite">Snapdragon 8 Elite</a> processors substantially improve all aspects of mobile processing without breaking a sweat.</p><p>Early results <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.antutu.com/doc/133085.htm">from benchmark company Antutu</a> paint the picture we were hoping to see. Not only does the Snapdragon 8 Elite run significantly faster than the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-3">Snapdragon 8 Gen 3</a> in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24">Galaxy S24 series</a>, but it runs several degrees Celsius cooler, too.</p><p>According to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://browser.geekbench.com/v6/cpu/compare/8681992?baseline=8681811">Geekbench results</a> from the Xiaomi 15, one of the first phones to ship with the Snapdragon 8 Elite, the new processor runs about 40% faster than the one that launched earlier this year. That's a huge improvement!</p><p>This level of speed has been achieved because Qualcomm was able to pack its brand new custom Oryon processing cores into the Snapdragon 8 Elite, the same exact cores it uses in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/qualcomm-is-betting-its-future-on-ai-and-google-could-benefit-the-most">Snapdragon X Elite</a> that powers many popular Windows laptops in 2024.</p>
<h2 id="one-ui-7-2">One UI 7</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1073px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:55.92%;"><img id="53xsrHgfAhYnTg8D9Lvd7d" name="one-ui-7-quick-settings-panel-sdc-2024-demo.jpg" alt="Samsung had a demo of One UI 7 on an S24 Ultra, which showed off its revamped Quick Settings." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/53xsrHgfAhYnTg8D9Lvd7d.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1073" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: SammyGuru)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>One UI 7 won't be a Galaxy S25 exclusive but Samsung <em>is</em> using its next phones <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-confirms-one-ui-7-wont-hit-beta-until-end-of-this-year">to launch its latest OS update</a>. Built on Android 15, One UI 7 promises to be the biggest overhaul to Samsung's storied Android skin since the introduction of One UI exactly 6 years ago on November 7, 2018.</p><p>Aside from the potentially exciting visual refresh — which includes not only a fresh coat of paint but also some <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/huge-one-ui-7-samsung-parent-ai-features-leak">snazzy new animations</a> — Samsung looks to be including fantastic new AI features that will make your everyday smartphone experience all the better.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:694px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:86.46%;"><img id="g5R7Ra2k3tyXsbBdLpxQf6" name="one-ui-7-rumored-lock-screen-enhanced-notifications-example" alt="One UI 7 is rumored to debut an "enhanced lock screen" and other "smart management" tools for alerts." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/g5R7Ra2k3tyXsbBdLpxQf6.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="694" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I'm not talking about a better spell checker or some niche AI feature you probably won't use more than once, though. I'm talking about <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/one-ui-7-beta-could-be-just-around-the-corner-with-an-apple-intelligence-like-twist">smart notification upgrades</a> that summarize what's happening so you don't get overwhelmed and miss things.</p><p>I tend to leave my phone in my pocket or on a desk for a long time before picking it up, only to see a hundred notifications that quickly become too much to deal with. What happens then? I usually just hit clear all and figure it out later.</p><p>This new notification summary feature will help deliver quick, concise summaries of groups of notifications so I can stay in the know without feeling overwhelmed. That's the real AI upgrade I've been waiting for, and the phone's hardware will be perfectly equipped to handle these new AI features, especially with the new Snapdragon 8 Elite chip.</p>
<h2 id="why-not-wait-2">Why not wait?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="rE4YGhpZYsVBh7ahzPSyhT" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-Ultra-vs-Galaxy-S23-Ultra-camera-lenses-01.jpg" alt="Comparing the camera lens bumps on the Samsung Galaxy S23 Ultra vs S24 Ultra" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rE4YGhpZYsVBh7ahzPSyhT.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>My three favorite things about the Galaxy S25 certainly sound compelling, but they allegedly come with a price hike that no one wants to pay. That's where <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/best-samsung-galaxy-s24-deals-of-the-month">Galaxy S24 Black Friday deals</a> come in. No matter what Samsung will be selling the Galaxy S25 for, it's impossible for the company to offer its phones at any better price than the Galaxy S24 is selling these days.</p><p>In just a few weeks, we'll be in the midst of Black Friday and all the crazy sales. Since the Galaxy S24 debuted 10 months ago, you know you'll be getting the best price possible on Samsung's 2024 phones so that they can make room for the 2025 models.</p><p>If price is a big concern in the coming months, it's probably best to stick with what's currently available, especially since Samsung offers seven years of software upgrades for its Galaxy S24 line. That means One UI 7 is the first of seven total OS updates that'll debut on the phones until support officially ends.</p><p>Getting a phone at a reduced price <em>and</em> getting seven years of guaranteed updates is a surefire way to ensure that you're getting the very best deal this year with no compromises.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="32899962-7226-4af0-b6f9-46c6385e3b75">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PBHvpjpX26yLAmUkjL5o3W.jpg' alt="Galaxy S24 Ultra in Titanium Yellow"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Top of the line</strong></em></p><p>The Galaxy S24 Ultra is one of the best phones to come out of 2024, and you won't be disappointed by its performance, camera quality, or collection of fun and useful AI features. Even with the Galaxy S25 on the horizon, 7 years of updates means you'll be supported for a long time with many of the latest features.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-should-you-wait</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Black Friday is on the horizon but sometimes it's better to wait for something new. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">bEhoj5ZpaQkgLUXqG4azz</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dek9ujiLy6hDtd5cJSGhVQ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 18:57:54 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dek9ujiLy6hDtd5cJSGhVQ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Comparing a Fiberborne Galaxy S25 Ultra case with a Galaxy S24 Ultra case and the Galaxy S24 Ultra]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Comparing a Fiberborne Galaxy S25 Ultra case with a Galaxy S24 Ultra case and the Galaxy S24 Ultra]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Matter 1.4 upgrade rolls out to help you stay warm in the colder months ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The CSA highlighted the arrival of its Matter 1.4 upgrade for smart homes.</li><li>The update adds support for more devices like water heaters and heat pumps, as well as improved thermostat support for preset modes.</li><li>Matter rolled out its 1.3 upgrade earlier this year, where it welcomed EV chargers and smart home appliances.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>The CSA continues its mission to improve the connectivity of consumers' smart home devices as the latest major upgrade rolls out.</p><p>Yet again, the CSA (Connectivity Standards Alliance) <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://csa-iot.org/newsroom/matter-1-4-enables-more-capable-smart-homes/">detailed a host of newly supported</a> smart home devices for the 1.4 update. According to the post, Matter connectivity now supports solar-powered devices such as inverters, individual and panel arrays, and hybrid solar/battery systems. Batteries (battery walls, storage units, etc.) are also said to be supported with the latest update.</p><p>In time for the colder months, the CSA states Matter welcomes Heat Pumps and Water Heaters. The post states that the connectivity's "energy management" capabilities should aid homeowners with (power) consumption forecasts alongside the ability to "adjust" its usage during peak hours. For the latter, the CSA says the 1.4 upgrade adds a new "Water Heater Mode Cluster." This is designed to bring a toggling feature for set schedules.</p><p>Moreover, thermostats receive support for scheduling and "preset modes." The CSA states that its supported preset modes include "home/away and vacation." The post adds that presets can be triggered via motion detection, calendar events, and integration with other devices.</p><p>The CSA highlights support for electric vehicle supply equipment and its "Device Energy Management" to help users optimize the energy usage of their smart home products.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:944px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="Y4FJDGNJXUUJZmqr9erBeK" name="Matter-lifestyle-16x9-01.jpg" alt="Matter certified device" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Y4FJDGNJXUUJZmqr9erBeK.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="944" height="531" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Matter)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Battery-powered devices receive enhancements to help "optimize" battery life and communication with switches, buttons, and sensors.</p><p>Elsewhere, the post states the 1.4 upgrade introduces better "Multi-Admin" support. The CSA informs users that this should help make management easier as it brings "single user consent" for devices. In short, homeowners can seamlessly connect new or existing smart home devices to "multiple ecosystems automatically."</p><p>The Alliance is also upgrading its Matter-certified HRAP devices to combine a home's Wi-Fi access point and Thread Border Router. The post states this is designed to strengthen the required infrastructure for other Matter products.</p><p>The 1.4 upgrade is available now; however, it may take a while before a given platform integrates it for users.</p><p>Matter's latest update is the second rollout in 2024, as its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/matter-1-3-upgrade">1.3 upgrade arrived in May</a>. That update brought support and energy management controls for EV chargers alongside home appliances. Water management devices were also roped into the Matter connectivity push as the CSA included "leak and freeze detectors, rain sensors, and controllable water valves."</p><p>It's worth noting that Google was spotted preparing enhanced Matter-supported device controls <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/android-15-matter-thread-netowrk-support-previewed">over the Thread network</a>. Devices that contain the appropriate Thread radio may receive increased efficiency and "performance enhancements" through Android 15.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/matter-1-4-upgrade-more-device-support-roll-out</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The CSA detailed its latest Matter 1.4 upgrade for smart homes. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">MfL3CLTHYjm8AKoey6DLCX</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PnAcPrunixMtEJvqNQm6yK.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 18:39:58 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Smart Home]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PnAcPrunixMtEJvqNQm6yK.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Business Wire]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Matter logo.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Matter logo.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Don't wait for Black Friday: Best Buy just slashed $130 off one of my favorite Chromebooks ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Black Friday might still be a few weeks away, but you don't have to wait to save big on the Acer Chromebook Plus Spin 714. This beast of a machine normally costs around $700, but you can <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/acer-chromebook-plus-spin-714-laptop-with-google-ai-14-wuxga-touch-intel-core-ultra-5-115u-8gb-lpddr5-256gb-ssd-steel-gray/6576960.p?skuId=6576960"><strong>get it from Best Buy for $130 off</strong></a>.</p><p>While there have been a bunch of new and exciting <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-chromebook">Chromebooks</a> released in 2024, the Chromebook Plus Spin 714 remains one of the best. It's packed to the gills with all of the Google Gemini AI features you could want while offering an excellent 2-in-1 laptop experience.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="cd8d9c9b-78fe-4eb3-b40a-ffb71ce99630" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Even without any sales, the Acer Chromebook Plus Spin 714 is already one of the best laptops out there. Throw in 12 months of Gemini Advanced and a $130 discount, and this deal from Best Buy is a no-brainer." data-dimension48="Even without any sales, the Acer Chromebook Plus Spin 714 is already one of the best laptops out there. Throw in 12 months of Gemini Advanced and a $130 discount, and this deal from Best Buy is a no-brainer." data-dimension25="$569" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/acer-chromebook-plus-spin-714-laptop-with-google-ai-14-wuxga-touch-intel-core-ultra-5-115u-8gb-lpddr5-256gb-ssd-steel-gray/6576960.p?skuId=6576960" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="vLphCA53ud8i8typoiLNKU" name="acer-chromebook-plus-spin-714-square-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vLphCA53ud8i8typoiLNKU.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="500" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>Even without any sales, the Acer Chromebook Plus Spin 714 is already one of the best laptops out there. Throw in 12 months of Gemini Advanced and a $130 discount, and this deal from Best Buy is a no-brainer.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/acer-chromebook-plus-spin-714-laptop-with-google-ai-14-wuxga-touch-intel-core-ultra-5-115u-8gb-lpddr5-256gb-ssd-steel-gray/6576960.p?skuId=6576960" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="cd8d9c9b-78fe-4eb3-b40a-ffb71ce99630" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Even without any sales, the Acer Chromebook Plus Spin 714 is already one of the best laptops out there. Throw in 12 months of Gemini Advanced and a $130 discount, and this deal from Best Buy is a no-brainer." data-dimension48="Even without any sales, the Acer Chromebook Plus Spin 714 is already one of the best laptops out there. Throw in 12 months of Gemini Advanced and a $130 discount, and this deal from Best Buy is a no-brainer." data-dimension25="$569">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>This model specifically, is powered by the Intel Core Ultra 5 115U, paired with 8GB of RAM, and 256GB of storage. Not to mention that if you decide to snag this deal, you'll also get <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini Advanced</a> for 12 months. With this, you'll get 2TB of cloud storage, in addition to having access to Gemini in all of your Google services.</p><p>When it comes to the design, it's pretty much identical to Acer's previous <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/acer-chromebook-spin-714-2023-review">Chromebook Spin models</a>. That includes being able to either prop it up with "Tent Mode," or flip the screen all the way around, to use the Spin 714 as a tablet paired with a USI stylus. The only downside here is that you'll need to pick up a compatible USI pen, as Acer doesn't include one.</p><p>Although the Acer Chromebook Plus Spin 714 might lack the "pizazz" of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/samsung-galaxy-chromebook-plus-review">Galaxy Chromebook Plus</a>, that doesn't mean you should ignore it. This is still easily one of the best Chromebooks that money can buy, providing a near-perfect blend of sleek design with plenty of horsepower.</p><p>Recently, Google added even more fun with the release of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/google-chromeos-130-chromebook-plus-update-rollout">ChromeOS 130</a>. This update includes a variety of AI features, such as the Recorder app, Quick Insert, and so much more. There's even the new "Focus" option that lets you start a timer and work on a task without needing to worry about distractions.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/early-black-friday-acer-chromebook-plus-spin-714-deal</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Best Buy has knocked the price of the Chromebook Spin Plus 714 to something quite a bit more affordable. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">EyEXhfa6ThSyWYbNR9KqQ7</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/o4zf8xncr7Eii4ZVaJ3BmZ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 17:47:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Chromebooks &amp; Laptops]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ andrew.myrick@futurenet.com (Andrew Myrick) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/o4zf8xncr7Eii4ZVaJ3BmZ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Acer Chromebook Plus Spin 714 with lid closed]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Acer Chromebook Plus Spin 714 with lid closed]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Metro Awakening is the horror game I didn't know I needed ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">AC thVRsday</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="LGmZZrc8DWcxmZm6RRUYbC" name="ac-thvrsday-logo.jpg" caption="" alt="AC thVRsday logo" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LGmZZrc8DWcxmZm6RRUYbC.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">In his <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/ac-thvrsday">weekly column</a>, Android Central Senior Content Producer Nick Sutrich delves into all things VR, from new hardware to new games, upcoming technologies, and so much more.</p></div></div>
<p>Metro Awakening is the horror game I didn't know I needed. I say that because, first off, I'm not exactly a fan of the horror genre. I've enjoyed the occasional scary movie or game from time to time, but those are exceptions rather than the rule. I've also never really gotten into the Metro series despite enjoying the theme and the original release of Metro 2033.</p><p>But Metro Awakening is something special. It's a narrative-heavy, linear first-person shooter — just like the rest of the series — that had me hooked from the moment its clever intro began. It's also the first made-for-VR entry into the storied series, developed entirely by veteran VR developer Vertigo Games, the same company behind VR classics like Arizona Sunshine and After the Fall.</p><p>Despite being from a different developer, Metro Awakening feels incredibly similar to Metro 2033 in all the right ways. As the story goes, it takes place primarily in the metro train tunnels under a once great city, where you'll find yourself uncovering the horrors that both radioactivity and desperate humans created. It's easily one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-meta-quest-games">best Meta Quest games</a> I've ever played.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="b0c78fc9-725f-49a6-a9e0-119d3514fd9d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Meta Horizon Store" data-dimension48="Meta Horizon Store" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="47CzHCHRx5e6EyRwem7qkf" name="metro-awakening-art-1x1" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/47CzHCHRx5e6EyRwem7qkf.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1000" height="1000" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><em><strong>Metro Awakening</strong></em></p><p>It's not just the first made-for-VR entry into the storied Metro series, it's also the most personal tale yet in the post-apocalyptic universe.</p><p><strong>Buy now at</strong> <a href="https://www.meta.com/en-gb/experiences/metro-awakening-deluxe-edition/5096918017089406/" data-dimension112="b0c78fc9-725f-49a6-a9e0-119d3514fd9d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Meta Horizon Store" data-dimension48="Meta Horizon Store" data-dimension25="">Meta Horizon Store</a> | <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2669410/Metro_Awakening/">Steam</a> | <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/metro-awakening/?">PlayStation Store</a></p></div>
<h2 id="feeling-vertigo-2">Feeling Vertigo</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="WbduR3w9vMrRioWPXtvYP9" name="metro-awakening-official-screenshot-01" alt="An official screenshot of Metro Awakening" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WbduR3w9vMrRioWPXtvYP9.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Vertigo Games)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>If you've played the Arizona Sunshine games or After the Fall, you'll immediately feel familiar with the mechanics in Metro Awakening. That's not to say things are identical — the dual backpack-based inventory system is a clever new design I haven't seen yet — but everything that's good about the company's previous apocalyptic shooters sits on display for players to experience in Metro Awakening.</p><p>Intuitive on-body inventory systems, where you can consistently depend on grabbing the same item every time you reach for it, make them feel as good as a hot bar in a flat-screen game.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>The first time you pull the hammer back and peer into the gun's body to make sure you still have a bullet in the chamber isn't just clutch. It's vital for immersion.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>This is particularly important given the level of fear the game consistently holds you in, as you'll be able to make better split-second decisions because you won't be fumbling with an unreliable inventory system. Healing is always on your left hip, a pistol always on your right, and reaching into the pocket on your chest always delivers the proper ammo or refill for the weapon you're holding.</p><p>That is, of course, so long as you've been able to hold on to enough ammo to get you through the next section. One of Metro Awakening's biggest strengths is its consistent difficulty level, which is directly relative to how much ammo you're given between any of the game's encounters.</p><p>The first time you pull the hammer back and peer into the gun's body to make sure you still have a bullet in the chamber isn't just clutch. It's vital for immersion.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X3GOkKkAW7U" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<figure><blockquote><p>While running from a giant mutant rat, I grabbed a large sliding door and closed it three-quarters of the way, blocking the rat's entry and giving me enough space to blast it to smithereens.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>Metro Awakening's combat encounters are as often about taking the stealthy approach as they are about blindly shooting at unseen enemies like a character in one of Ridley Scott's Alien movies. Most encounters with humans give you the option to be stealthy — which I'll encourage you to use — in order to save up as much ammo for the next encounter as possible.</p><p>But every single encounter — even the ones that very obviously imply a stealthy approach is best — can be run through Rambo style. Enemies' weapons can be taken after they are downed, and while ammo in those weapons is always severely limited, they allow skilled players to hop from enemy to enemy and piggyback in creative ways. Cans and bottles can be brought from place to place and used to distract enemies, so you can use a stealthy melee attack to take them out.</p><p>The ability to act naturally in VR dawned on me during one early encounter. While running from a giant mutant rat, I grabbed a large sliding door and closed it three-quarters of the way, blocking the rat's entry and giving me enough space to blast it to smithereens.</p><p>There's no way to do this in a non-VR game, and it makes the game feel special and bespoke in a way that another flatscreen entry couldn't.</p>
<h2 id="variety-and-a-bit-of-half-life-2">Variety and a bit of half life</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="4nh5Xz5qTZA5iqAUsqokKD" name="metro-awakening-screenshot-01" alt="A screenshot of Metro Awakening taken on a Meta Quest 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4nh5Xz5qTZA5iqAUsqokKD.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>There was never a time in Metro Awakening's 12-hour campaign where I felt like I was repeating the same old situation over and over again. Each hallway, air vent, metro tunnel, or other space you walk through feels unique in a way that's rarely achieved outside of something as good as Metroid Prime. While this isn't a Metroidvania by any stretch of the imagination, the variety of locales and the compelling story kept me coming back to the game for more each day.</p><p>Metro Awakening has you playing the community's doctor whose eccentric wife seems to always cause problems. When she starts hearing the voice of your long-dead son in the steam pipes, you know something bad's about to happen. The rest of the journey will have you wondering if she's sane, prophetic, or maybe somewhere in between the two. Either way, you'll be venturing further than your character's hard past has ever gone before.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="gmSprtaPc7XWtkK2taHUJD" name="metro-awakening-screenshot-02" alt="A screenshot of Metro Awakening taken on a Meta Quest 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gmSprtaPc7XWtkK2taHUJD.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Since many parts of the world you'll explore are radioactive, you'll need to occasionally put on a gas mask and keep track of how effective its filter is working. Finding and swapping out filters will let you explore these areas more, often helping you find survival supplies and a few collectible items. If there's any replayability in the game, it's for folks who love to re-experience specific events or to find all three postcards hidden in each chapter.</p><p>Despite not being a big fan of the horror genre, the macabre scenes depicted constantly throughout the game were fascinating in a way I didn't expect. Likewise, the horrifying creatures that had me jumping and blindly shooting were always interesting to encounter, and I regularly tried to find creative ways to dispatch them before they got too close.</p><p>While I wouldn't put Metro Awakening in the same general category as a horror game like Wraith: The Oblivion - Afterlife, there's no denying the importance of horror to the story and the overall atmosphere of the game. Even if you're not a fan of horror like me, I'd encourage you to try it. The Meta Quest store has a 2-hour return window, anyway, and you'll definitely get the feeling of the game in the first 30 minutes, let alone two hours.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="NqiY5JXo7uvd3UMkoK36ND" name="metro-awakening-screenshot-03" alt="A screenshot of Metro Awakening taken on a Meta Quest 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NqiY5JXo7uvd3UMkoK36ND.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>If I had to name one specific critique of the Quest version of the game, it would be that I expected to see the game running at a higher resolution than it does. I used Quest Games Optimizer to boost the resolution to 130%, and it looked downright breathtaking at times, all without any noticeable performance hitches. Hopefully, Vertigo Games can patch in something like this soon.</p><p>The VR community has had its share of ups and downs with big releases this year, but this last quarter has proven to pack a serious punch that gives me high hopes for the future of big-name VR games. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/batman-arkham-shadow-review">Batman Arkham Shadow</a> sits firmly at the top as game of the year, although Metro Awakening has already making me question which title will get the crown at the end of the year.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="46304147-8487-4786-950b-ed752428bf5c">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fCUPHg8DY6xth6JoYMuDGK.jpg' alt="An official product render of the Meta Quest 3S with its controllers"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Meta Quest 3S</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>Get the power of a Meta Quest 3 in a more affordable package with the Meta Quest 3S, the new VR headset from Meta. Plus, get Batman Arkham Shadow and three months of Meta Quest Plus when you buy one before April 2025.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/metro-awakening-review</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The first made-for-VR entry into the Metro 2033 game series is spectacular and frightening in equal portions. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">WpvxBjDFh9dA8yYLteTHzV</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kV46qBfT2ngeVcc22e8j3S.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 17:15:34 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kV46qBfT2ngeVcc22e8j3S.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central / Nicholas Sutrich / Vertigo Games]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A version of official Metro Awakening artwork featuring me wearing a Meta Quest 3 headset]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A version of official Metro Awakening artwork featuring me wearing a Meta Quest 3 headset]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>