<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 14:23:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Galaxy S25 Ultra could bump up RAM in its higher-end models ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Leaks hint at RAM and storage upgrades for the Galaxy S25 Ultra, with some models getting more RAM than before.</li><li>The base model will likely have 12GB of RAM and 256GB storage, while premium versions could offer 16GB RAM and up to 1TB of storage.</li><li>With AI apps becoming more demanding, the RAM boost is likely aimed at keeping up with these trends.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>A fresh leak hints at some exciting RAM and storage upgrades for Samsung’s upcoming Galaxy S25 Ultra. It looks like certain models could pack more RAM than their predecessors.</p><p>A recent post by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/Jukanlosreve/status/1865744112072442342" target="_blank">@Jukanlosreve</a> on X suggests the top-tier <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25">Galaxy S25</a> model might bring a RAM boost for its higher-end models. The base version will likely stick to 12GB of RAM and 256GB of storage, but the premium variants could offer 16GB of RAM with storage options up to 512GB or 1TB (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidpolice.com/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-could-rival-pixel-9-pro-where-matters/" target="_blank">Android Police</a>).</p><p>If this is accurate, the 512GB and 1TB versions of the Galaxy S25 Ultra are set to beat the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review">Galaxy S24 Ultra</a> in RAM, offering 16GB instead of 12GB. Samsung’s move lets users go for more storage without sacrificing RAM, giving them more options to choose from.</p><p>Samsung has always offered different storage options in its Ultra series, but the RAM has mostly stayed the same. The last Ultra model with 16GB of RAM was the Galaxy S21 Ultra, and the ones that followed stuck with 12GB. But it looks like the Galaxy S25 series is ready to change things up.</p><p>This RAM boost will definitely appeal to users who need top-notch performance for multitasking, gaming, and heavy apps. With the higher RAM option, Samsung is looking to strengthen its spot in the competitive smartphone market.</p><p>Moreover, Samsung is apparently looking to stay on top of industry trends with this RAM upgrade, especially with the rise of AI-powered apps. As AI models get more complex and demanding, having more RAM is key for smooth performance.</p><p>That said, the 12GB RAM setup for the 256GB model raises some questions. It’s unclear if this model will have any AI performance limits or if the extra RAM is meant for other performance boosts. Either way, the added RAM will likely improve overall performance, including AI tasks. Hopefully, this upgrade won’t come with a big price increase.</p>
<hr>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="aa703187-580d-4c78-8706-72f644ba13c2">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jH2nkHNQPuwBpm8KyQ6u4c.jpg' alt="samsung galaxy s24 ultra square render - 1"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>The Galaxy S24 Ultra is a tech powerhouse, with an impressive AMOLED display, top-tier hardware, seamless S Pen integration, and a sleek quad-lens rear camera system.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-galaxy-s25-ultra-could-bump-up-ram-in-its-higher-end-models</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Certain Galaxy S25 Ultra models might get a nice performance upgrade. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">ZBoawMAY5fWYXgkvhe7j8M</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/X65GexZdyC98NmHwvCEFNJ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 06:56:06 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/X65GexZdyC98NmHwvCEFNJ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[OnLeaks / Android Headlines]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Galaxy S25 Ultra renders leak]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Galaxy S25 Ultra renders leak]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Docs is tapping into Gemini to whip up formatted documents ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google Docs is testing a new "Help me create" feature powered by Gemini, allowing you to create formatted docs from scratch.</li><li>You can easily integrate Google Drive files by typing "@" followed by the file name, pulling your content right into the doc.</li><li>While it pulls from Workspace files, it doesn’t keep the original layout or style and can’t generate images of people yet.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google Docs is stepping up its AI capabilities with "Help me create," a Gemini-powered feature that crafts formatted docs from the ground up.</p><p>According to Google Docs' <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/docs/answer/15541387" target="_blank">support page</a>, the experimental "Help me create" feature, powered by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini</a>, lets you generate formatted docs straight from your Google Workspace files. Just type "@" and the file name, and your Drive files are instantly in the mix (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/12/06/google-docs-help-me-create/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a>).</p><p>This new feature pairs perfectly with the "Help me write" tool, letting you tweak text or whip up something totally new. You can create anything from proposals and project trackers to dinner menus, vacation plans, or even brainstorms and blog posts.</p><p>Give Gemini AI a bit of context—like your audience, purpose, or goals—and it can fine-tune templates to fit your needs.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1280px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:62.50%;"><img id="JoeyFGxT7uj4CCk8SKoTRg" name="Google-Docs-help-me-create" alt="Help me create feature in Google Docs" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JoeyFGxT7uj4CCk8SKoTRg.gif" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1280" height="800" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While the "Help me create" feature can pull from various <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/everything-you-need-know-about-google-workspace-spaces-and-smart-canvas">Workspace</a> files, it won’t keep the original layout or style. It also can’t generate inline or cover images of people yet. For best results, try using natural, conversational language when making prompts.</p><p>When it’s ready, you’ll see the "Help me create" prompt pop up at the top, right next to your usual options like meeting notes, cover images, polls, and the like.</p><p>Alternatively, you can find "Help me create" by going to the "File" menu, hitting "New," and selecting it from there. Then, just pick the type of doc you want to make.</p><p>The latest addition is part of the company’s focus on boosting productivity and creativity. This fits right in with the latest AI advancements, including the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-docs-now-uses-imagen-3-for-custom-image-generation-if-youre-a-paid-user">ability to generate images in Google Docs with Gemini</a>.</p><p>The "Help me create" feature is currently web-only and available only to those in the Gemini for Google Workspace Alpha and Workspace Labs programs. It's also limited to new, blank docs and being rolled out slowly.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-docs-is-tapping-into-gemini-to-whip-up-formatted-documents</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ With Gemini, you can now create formatted docs in Google Docs from scratch. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">AdaKKJ7dyW6h7SVJ7YABpa</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HmgT6NLvyE4WELvEBJTPtb.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 05:37:51 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HmgT6NLvyE4WELvEBJTPtb.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Docs logo on a laptop screen]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Docs logo on a laptop screen]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ First 11 things to do with your new Google Pixel Watch 3 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Whether you picked up a new Pixel Watch 3 during the recent Black Friday/ Cyber Monday hullabaloo or are simply looking for tips and tricks with your months-old watch, I'm here to help.</p><p>Based on my time reviewing the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-3-review">Pixel Watch 3</a> and other Wear OS watches, I've created this Google Pixel Watch 3 beginner's guide to run through our favorite features that Google itself doesn't fully explain during setup.</p><p>None of these features will be groundbreaking to anyone who's fluent in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wear-os-watch">Wear OS watch</a> software, but it'll hopefully prove useful to have it all listed out in one place. That way you won't forget to set up Emergency SOS, Watch Unlock, and other handy tools with your new watch!</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-switch-up-your-watch-faces"><span>Switch up your watch faces</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="zjwBhKDoU9EjwLba4uxJE3" name="Pixel-Watch-3-change-watch-face" alt="Changing a watch face on the Google Pixel Watch 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zjwBhKDoU9EjwLba4uxJE3.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>As always with Wear OS, you <strong>tap and hold</strong> your main watch screen to swap between default watch face options. Tap the <strong>pencil</strong> icon to change the colors, layout, complications, and boldness of the main clock.</p><p>By default, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-3">Pixel Watch 3</a> has 13 different watch faces installed. In the Pixel Watch companion app, you'll see a <strong>Watch faces</strong> option directly under the watch icon, where you'll see more options (about 25 different types in total, each with different "flavors"). My favorite is one tied to Google Photos, where you pick up to 30 photos and can tap between them by tapping the main watch face, swapping between them at your leisure.</p><p>Unfortunately, the Pixel Watch 3 can't use any watch faces without the XML Watch Face Format (WFF) — it's a Wear OS 5 restriction — which means you <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/wear-os-5-blocks-facer-and-makes-watch-faces-boring">can't add them from Facer</a> anymore. For the few compatible third-party options, open the <strong>Play Store</strong> on your phone, tap <strong>Search</strong>, select <strong>Watch apps</strong> under "Explore apps," select <strong>Pixel Watch 3</strong> under "Your devices" at the top, and finally tap <strong>Watch faces</strong>. You'll see XML watch faces for you to buy and download to the Pixel Watch 3.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-filter-your-notifications"><span>Filter your notifications</span></h2>
<p>Nothing drives me crazier than getting an endless buzz of unimportant notifications on my wrist. One of the first things I did with my Pixel Watch 3 was open the <strong>Pixel Watch app</strong> on my phone, tap <strong>Notifications</strong> under Settings, then tap <strong>Mute notifications from phone</strong> so I'm not buzzed in two places if I'm currently using my phone. I also like to <strong>Mute phone calls</strong> while wearing my watch, since I know I'll be buzzed on my wrist anyways.</p><p>Most importantly, I tap <strong>Watch apps</strong> and disable any notifications from apps I know I don't care about seeing urgently, knowing that I can check my notification feed on my phone later.</p><p>One thing I wish Android and Wear OS offered was a way to disable multiple notifications from the same source in quick succession, like when a group Telegram chat buzzes my wrist thirty times during a run. So I found the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.samruston.buzzkill&hl=en_US">Buzzkill Notification Manager app</a> so I can set a cooldown on repeat notifications within a certain span. It doesn't have a Wear OS app, but its effects trickle down to the Pixel Watch 3, and it's worth the small cost if you're similarly bothered by back-to-back buzzes.</p><p>Lastly, remember every night to swipe down from the watch face and tap the <strong>Crescent Moon icon</strong> to turn on Bedtime Mode, which filters all calls and notifications except for starred callers and alarms. By default, the Pixel Watch 3 has <strong>Auto-Bedtime mode</strong> enabled based on your sleep zones and heart rate, and syncs with your Pixel phone's DND settings — though not other phone brands like Samsung, frustratingly. Either way, the display will still blind you if you move your arm in a dark room before you first fall asleep, so I turn it on manually.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-dive-into-the-settings"><span>Dive into the settings</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.30%;"><img id="4VWzwYM3b2xvaPNLUwKzM3" name="Pixel-Watch-3-developer-mode" alt="Developer options on the Google Pixel Watch 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4VWzwYM3b2xvaPNLUwKzM3.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="2259" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>This is a bit of a boring and obvious entry, but it's still worth mentioning. Swipe down from the main watch face view, tap the <strong>Cog icon</strong>, and spend five minutes running through the options, enabling or adjusting things as needed. Here are my specific Pixel Watch 3 settings recommendations:</p>
<ul><li><strong>Display: </strong>Change the text size if you're near-sighted; make sure <strong>Adaptive brightness</strong> is turned on; change the <strong>screen timeout</strong> to 10 seconds but the <strong>Go to watch face</strong> to either 2 or 5 minutes so you don't have to navigate back to things if you're distracted and the screen turns off; and <strong>turn off always-on screen</strong> if you're trying to save battery life.</li><li><strong>Sound: </strong>I leave sound off for calls and notifications in favor of vibrations, but you can change the volume here if you want both.</li><li><strong>Vibration: </strong>Lower the force of the haptics if, for example, you want to be gently jostled awake by your alarm instead of buzzed awake.</li><li><strong>Battery: </strong>Change Battery Saver to trigger at a higher or lower percentage, depending on your priorities.</li><li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> Useful features like TalkBack, color correction, or the option to vibrate the current time are available here, for anyone with visual impairments.</li><li><strong>System: </strong>Aside from checking for <strong>system updates</strong> and restarting or turning off the watch, this menu has a secret method for turning on <strong>developer mode</strong>. Tap <strong>About > Versions</strong> and then tap the <strong>Build number seven times</strong>.</li></ul>
<p>Under <strong>Developer options</strong>, you can enable niche tools like having your watch stay awake while charging on your desk, or to <strong>Force full GNSS measurements</strong> to improve location accuracy during workouts (theoretically). As I noted in my <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-ultra-tips-and-tricks">Galaxy Watch Ultra beginner's guide</a>, many people use dev options specifically to reduce the animation time when swapping between or opening apps, so that you see information more quickly.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-control-your-google-devices"><span>Control your Google devices</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="SJjsSKMQGc6UuycG4WeaB7" name="Google-Pixel-Watch-3-nest-cam-live-feed.jpeg" alt="Nest Doorbell live feed on the Pixel Watch 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SJjsSKMQGc6UuycG4WeaB7.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nick Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Depending on what other Google devices you own, the Pixel Watch 3 can act as a hub to control your smart home or Pixel phone, thanks to some new tricks added with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/wear-os-5">Wear OS 5</a>.</p><p>If you have a Nest Camera or Doorbell associated with your Google Home account, you'll receive notifications on your wrist when motion is detected; tapping it will send you to the live feed for that camera. Otherwise, you can tap the <strong>Camera device tile</strong> in Google Home and select a specific camera.</p><p>If you tap the <strong>triple-line icon</strong> underneath the feed, you can tap a <strong>mic icon</strong> to enable 2-way talk and speak to whoever's there, or the <strong>chat icon</strong> for Quick Responses like "We'll be right there." On the feed itself, you can <strong>double-tap</strong> the display to zoom in, then swipe left or right to pan your view.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="SUYun2bhF7fsxK5qmDnV5i" name="google-pixel-watch-3-google-tv-controls.jpg" alt="Google TV controls on Pixel Watch 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SUYun2bhF7fsxK5qmDnV5i.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2500" height="1406" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In terms of other Google Home functions, if you have an Android TV or Google TV dongle on your account, tap and hold any <strong>tile</strong> on your Pixel Watch, press the <strong>+ button</strong>, and add the <strong>TV tile</strong> to your carousel; you may need to remove a tile to make room if your carousel is full.</p><p>If necessary, select the specific Home and TV you want to control; for most people, your one Google TV device's controls will become visible by default. You'll be able to play/ pause, check how much time is left, skip forward or backward on a playlist, or change the volume. If you need to select options on screen, tap the <strong>Remote button</strong>, which has a D-pad and select button.</p><p>Otherwise, any other <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-home">Google Home devices and automations</a> like smart light routines or Nest Thermostat controls are controllable on your watch; that linked guide will walk you through building a Google Home ecosystem, if you're interested!</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-download-offline-google-maps"><span>Download offline Google Maps</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="mN2pxKeBZUFFyDLoeuGmE3" name="Pixel-Watch-3-google-maps-offline" alt="The Google Pixel Watch 3 showing a regional park map in Google Maps" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mN2pxKeBZUFFyDLoeuGmE3.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Some fitness watches can download specific GPX maps and courses to follow for workouts in areas with no signal. The Pixel Watch 3 <em>isn't</em> one of those watches, but Google Maps can at least store offline maps for whole areas so that you can search for directions in a pinch. It's a good idea to save whole areas like national or regional parks where the signal is poor, and to have these offline maps on your watch in case your phone dies.</p><p>To add offline maps to your Pixel Watch 3, start on the mobile Google Maps app, search for a specific place, tap the <strong>top-right ellipsis</strong>, and then <strong>download offline map</strong>. Scroll or pinch to select the right rectangular area, then <strong>Download</strong> it. It'll save to your phone.</p><p>Next, make sure your Pixel Watch 3 is connected to WiFi, then place it on its charger. Google auto-syncs your offline maps from your phone to your watch, but only when it's charging and on-network.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-set-up-google-wallet-and-transit-passes"><span>Set up Google Wallet and transit passes</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="MqR97nhWDLouM2SmndZgF3" name="add-card-to-google-wallet-pixel-watch.jpg" alt="Add new card to Google Wallet on Pixel Watch" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MqR97nhWDLouM2SmndZgF3.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4080" height="2294" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>By default, double-tapping the Pixel Watch 3 crown pulls up <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet">Google Wallet</a>, with your default card ready to be tapped for contactless payments. Setting it up is relatively simple, but adding Google Wallet cards will <strong>require a PIN or Pattern</strong> for security reasons; you should only have to enter it every time you take off your watch for charging, but if you forget your pattern you'll have to reset the watch to factory settings.</p><p><strong>Double-tap the crown</strong>, then create a PIN if prompted. The app will then tell you to continue on your synced phone in the <strong>Watch app</strong>; assuming you already have Google Wallet on your associated account, you will simply need to enter the <strong>CVV</strong> for the card you want to use, agree to certain terms and conditions, and wait for the bank to verify your information. Then a double crown tap will prime the default card for payment without having to select anything.</p><p>If you haven't used Wallet before, the app will use your phone camera to scan your card details, or else you can enter them manually. Plus, you can add a transit pass to Wallet if you live near Puget Sound (ORCA), the SF Bay Area (Clipper/BART), Toronto (PRESTO), or D.C. (SmarTrip/Metro) and want to tap past turnstiles with your phone in your pocket.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-sync-your-pixel-and-pixel-watch"><span>Sync your Pixel and Pixel Watch</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="CmDE2VGSzAdLS2ZsLDJybM" name="" alt="Using the recorder app on the Google Pixel Watch 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CmDE2VGSzAdLS2ZsLDJybM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google gave the Watch 3 a few Pixel-exclusive features rewarding those who buy within its family of devices. The first is the new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/using-google-keep-and-recorder-app-on-pixel-watch"><strong>Recorder app</strong></a>: Anyone can record things on their wrist, but Pixel owners will have their recordings auto-sync to their Pixel phones, where they can copy the AI transcripts as needed.</p><p>Perhaps the most important tool is <strong>Call Screening</strong>, which is only available to U.S.-based Pixel Watch owners with a Pixel 6 phone or later. In your mobile <strong>Phone app</strong>, tap the top-right <strong>ellipsis > Settings > Caller ID & spam</strong> and make sure you auto-filter spam calls and make caller ID available by default.</p><p>If you want to prop your Pixel phone to take a remote photo, the <strong>Camera app</strong> acts as a viewfinder for your Pixel phone. With this view, you can tap the Camera or Video icon to switch the type, double-tap the main view to swap between front and rear cameras, slide the magnification up and down, and tap the triple-line icon to change settings like the Mode and Timer.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="Ywq6u4SwGvBYS9VFqioWtd" name="Pixel-Watch-3-unlock-Pixel-9" alt="The Pixel Watch 3 with the screen "Pixel 9 Unlocked by this watch" and a "Lock" option, worn on a wrist hovering above the Pixel 9" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Ywq6u4SwGvBYS9VFqioWtd.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Lastly, you can use your Pixel Watch 3 to unlock your nearby Pixel phone with UWB, so long as you have a watch passcode set up — and are okay with using a little extra watch battery life. Open the <strong>mobile Watch app</strong> and tap <strong>Watch preferences > Security > Watch Unlock</strong>, then enter your phone PIN and hit <strong>Confirm</strong> on the next page.</p><p>If you enable this, your phone will unlock with any upward swipe or tapped notification on the lock screen. Your watch will get a phone-unlock notification any time you do this; <strong>tap the notification to re-lock your phone</strong> in case someone else grabbed your phone and unlocked it nearby.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-turn-on-emergency-sos-and-fall-detection"><span>Turn on Emergency SOS and fall detection</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1427px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="USum6Vwp8tNPXCK4WsqgDQ" name="emergency-sos-wear-os-pixel-watch.png" alt="Emergency Alerts on Wear OS" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/USum6Vwp8tNPXCK4WsqgDQ.png" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1427" height="803" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Pixel Watch app prompts you to set up Emergency SOS and fall detection in the Watch app after setup, but I imagine plenty of people dismiss the notifications in their initial unboxing excitement and then forget about it...until an emergency makes them regret their short-sightedness.</p><p>We have step-by-step guides on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/how-to-use-emergency-sos-pixel-watch">setting up emergency SOS</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/how-to-enable-fall-detection-pixel-watch">turning on fall detection</a> on Pixel Watches, so I won't waste space recreating those steps here.</p><p>The main thing is that you need to choose in advance which contacts will receive an emergency alert and make sure that the Personal Safety watch tool has access to your location so that emergency services know where to find you. Look in your app drawer for the <strong>Personal Safety app</strong>, where you can choose emergency contacts and set up things like Car Crash Detection or add your Medical Info for EMTs.</p><p>Another lesser-known feature you may want to try is <strong>Safety Check</strong>, which broadcasts your location to your emergency contacts if you don't check in after a certain time period. This is a useful preventative measure if, say, you're going for a nighttime run.</p><p>Plus, if you got your hands on the Pixel Watch 3 LTE, you automatically benefit from <strong>Safety Signal</strong>, which allows Emergency SOS, Fall Detection, and Safety Check to work even if your phone isn't around and you haven't added it to a carrier. The default Google Fi connection will send your crisis info where it needs to go.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-use-fitbit-run-coaching-to-get-healthier"><span>Use Fitbit Run Coaching to get healthier</span></h2>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="SHciSG6pzyGTQp6VnYhaMg" name="fitbit-running-coach-setup.jpg" alt="Fitbit app screenshots showing how to set up Fitbit Premium run coaching." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SHciSG6pzyGTQp6VnYhaMg.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="HjgvAmutoj6D2tSogkeKYg" name="fitbit-running-coach-generated-workout.jpg" alt="Fitbit app screenshots showing auto-generated workouts and the option to edit them." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HjgvAmutoj6D2tSogkeKYg.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Google put major emphasis on improving Fitbit's running software on the Pixel Watch 3. Using your six-month free trial of Fitbit Premium, you'll get daily AI-generated run recommendations based on your current fitness level and training plan.</p><p>My <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/how-to-use-google-pixel-watch-3-run-coaching">how-to guide for Fitbit run coaching</a> goes into depth, but essentially you need to open the <strong>Coach tab</strong> in the mobile Fitbit app and tap the banner about personalized workouts. You'll choose whether you're a beginner, intermediate (regularly run 5Ks), or advanced runner (run 10Ks, half marathons), then choose a plan based on whether you want to improve your <strong>Endurance</strong>, <strong>Pace</strong>, or both (<strong>Balanced</strong>).</p><p>At that point, you'll be given a daily recommendation like "tempo run" or "sprint intervals" that you can send to your watch and follow; the activity will have you stick to a specific heart rate zone, so it's less about hitting a specific pace and more about working hard for your ability level.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="JFEinvHnr69Bpsq56CYyM8" name="fitbit-premium-create-running-workout.jpg" alt="Fitbit app screenshots showing how to create a run workout." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JFEinvHnr69Bpsq56CYyM8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>If you'd rather choose your own workout pace, you can easily create your own custom workouts. In the mobile Fitbit app, tap the bottom-left <strong>+ symbol</strong>, then <strong>build a run</strong> and then the <strong>+ sign</strong> next to <strong>Intervals</strong>. You can create a running interval based on criteria like distance, time, calories burned, or a "time trial" to finish X miles in Y minutes. You can also set a <strong>target</strong> to stay within a certain pace or HR range, with your watch buzzing your wrist if you stray outside of the target zone.</p><p>Once you're done, tap <strong>Save and start on watch</strong>, and it'll cue up the activity you just made and start connecting to GPS. If you want to create a workout but save it for later, simply exit out of the app after exporting it; it'll be saved permanently in your watch workouts. Simply start a <strong>Run activity</strong>, tap the right <strong>stack icon</strong>, then choose the workout from the list.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-build-up-your-fitbit-cardio-load"><span>Build up your Fitbit Cardio Load</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="sLkyDEujbGwJJKYeMt7nUW" name="google-pixel-watch-3-readiness-score.jpg" alt="Morning Brief Readiness Score on Pixel Watch 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sLkyDEujbGwJJKYeMt7nUW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2500" height="1406" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Fitbit Run Coaching is great, but it doesn't help non-runners build workouts and it requires a Premium subscription. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fitbit-cardio-load-and-target-load-explained">Fitbit Cardio Load</a> is a free metric that scores your activity level for <em>any</em> type of workout, as well as non-workout activities like lifting heavy boxes at work or walking around town that still elevate your heart rate.</p><p>You'll get Cardio Load scores by default, appearing in the main Fitbit Today tab. But to get the most out of Cardio Load, you need to wear your Pixel Watch 3 for sleep tracking for two weeks. This will help the watch figure out your health and sleep baseline to generate a Daily Readiness score, then give you a daily Target Load for the amount of cardio load you should try to hit that day, based on your past workouts and fitness level.</p><p>All of this to say, just start sleeping while wearing the Pixel Watch 3, and eventually your daily Morning Brief will show screens like the photo above with a target load score. Your AI-generated runs will take that Target Load into account, but you can also look at <em>past</em> workouts to see how much load you generate from a typical run or HIIT activity, and design your workout accordingly.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-buy-backup-watch-bands"><span>Buy backup watch bands</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2316px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.26%;"><img id="x4H2so59RK3eKNV49PLGQg" name="Google-Pixel-Watch-3-band-lineup-official-photo.jpg" alt="A press photo of the official Google Pixel Watch 3 bands" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/x4H2so59RK3eKNV49PLGQg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2316" height="1303" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google uses a proprietary watch band system, so most of the bands comparable with other watches won't work with it. We have a guide on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-google-pixel-watch-3-bands">best Pixel Watch 3 bands</a> that'll spice up your watch's look or give you a more comfortable band than the default Active band.</p><p>Unfortunately, we <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/third-pixel-watch-still-doesnt-have-good-third-party-bands">don't have many good third-party options</a> because Pixel Watch sales aren't as high as Galaxy or Apple Watches. Still, we've found various rugged, woven, steel, and solo loop options that'll give you some variety and won't cost as much as <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://store.google.com/category/pixel_watch_bands?hl=en-US"><strong>Google's first-party bands</strong></a>, which are excellent but quite expensive (especially for leather or metal).</p><p>Whichever you choose, make sure that you buy the right size; the 41mm and 45mm Pixel Watch 3 use different band sizes, though your Pixel Watch 2 bands will carry over to the 41mm PW3.</p>
<h2 id="unpeel-your-pixel-watch-3-s-layers-2">Unpeel your Pixel Watch 3's layers</h2>
<p>I didn't cover <em>everything</em> the Pixel Watch 3 can do. Fitbit Premium has other perks like Peloton workouts, meditation guides, and video coaching that may get you working out with your Watch 3. You can use Tiles to take an ECG reading or follow your Body Responses (aka stressful moments) throughout the day. And I didn't even bring up Google Assistant, which you call by holding down the back button above the crown.</p><p>Not to mention, you should open the Play Store on your phone, tap <strong>Other devices</strong> in the top menu, and look at the "top free watch apps" to see what third-party options will be helpful for you. Don't just stick to Google apps!</p><p>The Pixel Watch 3 is one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch">best Android watches</a> available today, thanks in part to its new Wear OS 5 tricks. And I have no doubt it'll get even smarter, since Google gives its watches three years of updates. Hopefully by the time Wear OS 6 arrives next fall with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-4">Pixel Watch 4</a>, you'll have mastered what your Pixel Watch 3 has to offer.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="3c4b8387-08a9-4321-9a2b-3b30dcfe7c33">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sW9CTBf4mfXe5VckiKx9G4.jpg' alt="Render of the Obsidian Google Pixel Watch 3 smartwatch."></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel Watch 3</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="90" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Start exploring</strong></em></p><p>If you haven't bought your <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-3">Pixel Watch 3</a> yet, rest assured that it's one of our staff's favorites. We love its new 2,000-nit, 60Hz display that comes in two sizes for the first time, plus its surprisingly competent 2-day battery life. Google Home tricks make the Watch 3 a convenient controller for your entire smart home of devices, and Fitbit will help you figure out how much to work out on any given day without overtraining.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-3-tips-and-tricks</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ We run through everything you need to know after unboxing your Pixel Watch 3, from Fitbit tricks and Pixel exclusives to developer options. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">k6qM7W4fW2WavmLck3cmBf</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9PFRDmhKzWyC74XwvEuc3o.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 17:19:08 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wear Os]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9PFRDmhKzWyC74XwvEuc3o.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Recorder app on Pixel Watch 3]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Recorder app on Pixel Watch 3]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Wallet adds digital ID support in yet another US state ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>New Mexico is the latest state to let residents store their state IDs in Google Wallet, joining states like California, Arizona, and Georgia.</li><li>While physical IDs are still required for law enforcement and age checks, more businesses and TSA checkpoints are using the NM Verifier app for smartphone-based verification.</li><li>Google Wallet is also rolling out digital passport IDs, making travel through TSA checkpoints a bit smoother.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>New Mexico is getting with the times, as residents can now save their driver’s licenses and state IDs in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet">Google Wallet</a>.</p><p>New Mexico is the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.mvd.newmexico.gov/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/AA-Mobile-license-release-final_SSC.pdf" target="_blank">latest state to adopt Google's digital identification technology</a>. This makes it the sixth state to join, with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/california-preapres-google-wallet-id-support">California joining the club back in August</a>. The other states include Arizona, Colorado, Georgia, and Maryland.</p><p>Adding your New Mexico ID to Google Wallet is super easy. Just open the app, tap "Add to Wallet," pick "ID," and follow the steps. You’ll snap photos of both sides of your ID and record a quick selfie video for verification. In a few minutes, you’ll get a notification that your digital ID is ready to use. Once it’s set up, you can access it just like your payment cards.</p><p>Although New Mexico law still requires carrying physical IDs for law enforcement and age checks, more businesses and TSA checkpoints are using the NM Verifier app, letting residents verify their IDs with just their smartphones.</p><p>Furthermore, Google Wallet is rolling out <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-will-soon-let-users-create-a-digital-id-in-wallet-from-their-passport">support for digital passport IDs</a> in the coming weeks. This new feature, being rolled out to eligible users, lets you store a digital version of your US passport in the app, making it easier to get through certain TSA checkpoints.</p><p>While Google Wallet’s digital ID feature is super convenient, it doesn’t fully replace your physical ID just yet. Google recommends still carrying your physical ID, especially when traveling, until digital IDs become more widely accepted.</p><p>To create a digital US passport ID in the app, just tap the option to "create an ID pass with your U.S. passport." Then, follow the on-screen instructions to finish the setup.</p><p>If you’re planning a domestic flight with a digital passport, it’s a good idea to check the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.tsa.gov/travel/digital-id/map" target="_blank">TSA’s map</a> of supported states and airports.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet-adds-digital-id-support-in-yet-another-us-state</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ You can now add New Mexico state IDs to your digital wallet. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">sfYpqErgKL27CGv4REsBDM</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MVmCk9Ug8dRT4g9HQBSgYX.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 08:43:34 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MVmCk9Ug8dRT4g9HQBSgYX.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Chris Wedel / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[College IDs sitting next to an Android phone with the Google Wallet app logo]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[College IDs sitting next to an Android phone with the Google Wallet app logo]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Without saying it, Google basically confirmed Android 16 and 17 won't offer any fantastic new features ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Google has <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-confirms-the-pixel-6-pixel-7-and-pixel-fold-will-get-two-extra-android-os-upgrades">added two more years of software support</a> to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-pixel-6">Pixel 6 series</a>, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-7-review">Pixel 7 series</a>, and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-fold-review">original Pixel Fold</a>. That's fantastic news for anyone using these phones; since they use a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-tensor">Google-designed Tensor chip</a>, it's what should have been promised all along.</p><p>It says a bit more about Android's immediate future, even if it doesn't spell it out: don't expect the next killer feature(s) to be part of Android.</p>
<p>You're right if you're thinking that Google hasn't said anything about Android 17 yet and really hasn't told us much about Android 16. but it doesn't need to because we now know that whatever it is, the Pixel 6 will (hopefully) be able to run it.</p><p>The Pixel 6 wasn't a bad phone, but let's be honest — its Tensor chip isn't a powerhouse, and having "only" 8GB of RAM means it's missing many <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/why-on-device-ai-processing-is-important">on-device AI</a> features. It was built before Pixel phones needed chips that could process AI even faster and the memory to power the features that came along with it. We quickly saw that just one year later.</p>

<p>Here's the thing — none of that, or any of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Google's AI magic</a>, is part of Android. It's all proprietary Google property that it releases to select devices as it sees fit. Android has been like this for a while, with Google holding back many of the features you <em>think</em> come with it and deciding which phones from which companies can have them. If you ever get your hands on a device that runs the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/aosp">free and open version of Android</a>, you'll easily see how it is lacking.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="CLLBr5hHqT23MmCYwg5RFk" name="android-15-1.jpg" alt="Android 15 Easter egg on Pixel 9 Pro XL, Pixel 9, and Pixel 9 Pro Fold" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CLLBr5hHqT23MmCYwg5RFk.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I like to call this the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-is-keeping-some-of-androids-best-features-behind-a-pixel-paywall">Pixel paywall</a>. Google shows us a new feature, spends 30 minutes on a stage to tell us how great it is and why we should want it, then says you only get it if you buy a new Pixel phone.</p><p>This isn't nothing new; every other tech company does the same thing. The difference is other tech companies don't offer a "free" operating system that powers billions of smartphones.</p>
<p>We're going to see this again with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/when-will-my-phone-get-android-16">Android 16</a> when Google debuts a new Pixel phone. All of the new features are going to be Google's own and not freely available as part of Android, and a handful of them will only be available for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-10">Pixel 10</a>. Don't expect many (or any) of them for your Pixel 6. You won't be disappointed that way.</p><p>There's nothing wrong with this. I don't like it, and I know other people who feel the same way, but nobody should expect a for-profit company to turn over its best software features or the secret algorithms that power them as free software, no matter how restrictive the licensing is. Google is doing what we should expect it to do.</p><p>Future versions of Android will have plenty of other changes under the hood, and those can be very important, especially in terms of stability, security, and privacy. Many of those "API changes" that don't get much press do just that and are 100% necessary and important.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="L7wwsTMZVAYRdX4CE3cyDU" name="nvidia-shield-tv-pro-3.jpg" alt="NVIDIA Shield TV Pro against green background" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/L7wwsTMZVAYRdX4CE3cyDU.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Things like camera tricks or fancy AI-powered home screen features are separate, the same way Samsung's are for Samsung phones or Apple's are for iPhones. Google realizes their value and knows it will entice a few people enough to buy a new Pixel phone even though their Pixel 6 is still supported and does everything it did when it was new and more.</p><p>It's still great that Google realizes it has an obligation (yes, I said obligation) to support Tensor-powered devices as long as possible. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/nvidia-shield-tv-october-2024-update">Nvidia can tell them a thing or two</a> about how having control over the brains of an Android device means you can <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/geforce/forums/shield-tv/9/522242/shield-experience-upgrade-911-hotfix-image/3485054/">support it for a decade</a>. Or longer.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/android-16-and-17-may-not-come-with-fantastic-new-features-heres-why</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Adding support for two more versions of Android to the Pixel 6 means most new features will be locked behind the Pixel paywall. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">zxu4XR7QyTUqYtogCUY6w6</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/g9xBscuVR8DrkdD9Bt36PX.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/g9xBscuVR8DrkdD9Bt36PX.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android 13 lock screen clock on a Google Pixel 6]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android 13 lock screen clock on a Google Pixel 6]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Yes, you can still score $350 OFF the Galaxy S24 Ultra at Amazon — but should you? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The holidays are swiftly approaching, so folks from all over are on the hunt for great Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra deals. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Smartphone-Unlocked-Android-Titanium/dp/B0CMDJ844V/"><strong>Amazon, for example, has extended an excellent Cyber Monday discount that carves 27% off</strong></a> the super-powered smartphone, but before you smash that Buy Now button, it&apos;s important to ask yourself one question: <em>is it worth buying a Galaxy S24 when the S25 is likely to be released next month?</em></p><p>Indeed, rumors and leaks have suggested that the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25">S25 series</a> is likely to be unveiled in January, and we&apos;re sure to see a number of great <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-preorder-deals-what-to-expect">Galaxy S25 preorder deals</a> that make the flagship phones cheap (or even free). So what should you do? Let&apos;s discuss. </p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="9c623ee1-4834-4aa0-b8d6-7d948993021d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,299.99" data-dimension48="$1,299.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CMDJ844V/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="GgWobTBkWru648FmweBtcg" name="samsung galaxy s24 ultra square render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GgWobTBkWru648FmweBtcg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="800" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra 256GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CMDJ844V/" data-dimension112="9c623ee1-4834-4aa0-b8d6-7d948993021d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,299.99" data-dimension48="$1,299.99"><del>$1,299.99</del> <strong>$949 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>The Galaxy S24 Ultra is easily one of the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best phones</a> released in 2024, with a powerful Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 chipset, titanium build (with embedded stylus), and all of the useful AI-powered software features you could ever want. Grab the premium device unlocked from Amazon today and you'll score a straight 27% discount, just in time for the holidays. If you're looking for a great Android phone to buy ASAP, you can't beat this deal. </p>
<p><strong>👀 Alternative holiday deal: </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/smartphones/galaxy-s24-ultra/buy/galaxy-s24-ultra-256gb-unlocked-sm-s928uzoexaa/"><strong>Get $350 off the Galaxy S24 Ultra | up to $800 off with trade-in at Samsung</strong></a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CMDJ844V/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="9c623ee1-4834-4aa0-b8d6-7d948993021d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,299.99" data-dimension48="$1,299.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/"><em><strong>Samsung's Cyber Week sale ends Sunday! See all the best deals now</strong></em></a></li></ul>
<p>If past years are any indication, we can expect the Galaxy S25 series to be revealed sometime in mid-January with a street date set for a week or two after the announcement. The flagship lineup is likely to include at least three phones — the Galaxy S25, Galaxy S25 Plus, and S25 Ultra — all packed to the brim with the latest Snapdragon processors and Galaxy AI features. </p><p>There&apos;s no doubt that the phones will be impressive, but there&apos;s good reason to expect that they won&apos;t be <em>dramatically</em> different from the S24 series. After all, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-samsung-phones">Samsung phones</a> released this year all come with seven years of OS/security updates and deliver outstanding AI-powered performance, and Samsung typically focuses more on careful refinement than dramatic reinventions with its new releases. </p><p>So how badly do you <em>really</em> need the latest devices on the street? The choice is yours, but if you&apos;re looking for a great holiday gift, I wouldn&apos;t snooze on this S24 Ultra deal.</p><p>In conclusion.. </p><p><strong>✅I recommend this deal if: </strong>you&apos;re shopping for the holidays and you want an amazing Android phone at a stellar discount (even if it&apos;s going to be considered last-gen very soon); you want a phone with years of software support, excellent cameras, and AI features. </p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>you want the latest and greatest from Samsung and don&apos;t mind waiting until January; you&apos;re looking for a good trade-in opportunity or carrier deal. </p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/yes-you-can-still-score-usd350-off-the-galaxy-s24-ultra-at-amazon-but-should-you</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra is one of the best Android phones ever built, but with the S25 series just around the corner, is it worth the investment?  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Q7D6XEsuY8oRZNQvBSLoFa</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WGZFcwvp3vUr2yezPByNfN.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 14:00:08 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WGZFcwvp3vUr2yezPByNfN.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The back of the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra in the Titanium Grey colorway]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The back of the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra in the Titanium Grey colorway]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ OnePlus makes a bold move to tackle green line issues once and for all ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>OnePlus has launched a new program offering a lifetime warranty for all of its devices affected by the green line issue.</li><li>OnePlus is also improving AMOLED durability with a new PVX edge-seal to block moisture and oxygen, and displays now go through 180+ tests to prevent green lines.</li><li>The lifetime warranty is currently available in India, while U.S. and Europe users get the standard one- or two-year warranty.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Many OnePlus users have faced a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/green-line-of-death">stubborn green line issue</a> on their phone displays. In response, OnePlus has rolled out a program to fix the problem for good.</p><p>Older <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-oneplus-phones">OnePlus flagship devices</a> have been making waves lately, but not for the best reasons—a pesky “green line” display glitch has been causing headaches for users. The issue, which is common on OLED models, gained traction last year as more cases piled up.</p><p>To tackle the problem, OnePlus started offering free screen replacements under certain conditions. Now, the company has taken it up a notch with its new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://community.oneplus.com/thread/1743847105291616260" target="_blank">“Green Line Worry-Free Solution” program</a>, promising lifetime coverage for all devices facing this annoying problem.</p><p>The warranty covers all OnePlus devices, old and new. To tackle the green line issue, OnePlus has laid out a three-step plan, with the highlight being the lifetime warranty solution. The company explained that the problem isn’t tied to one cause but stems from a mix of factors.</p><p>In response, OnePlus is upgrading its AMOLED screens with an Enhanced Bonding Layer. This PVX edge seal blocks moisture and oxygen, keeping your display sharper and lasting longer.</p><p>Additionally, OnePlus' AMOLED displays now go through over 180 intense tests, simulating extreme real-world conditions, to keep those green lines at bay and set a new standard for reliability.</p><p>The green line issue seems to be more of a problem in India, so OnePlus is offering the lifetime warranty there for now, as per <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidpolice.com/oneplus-lifetime-warranty-green-line-issue/" target="_blank">Android Police</a>. In the U.S. and Europe, though, it’s still the regular one- or two-year warranty, depending on where you are.</p><p>This isn’t the first time OnePlus has stepped in to fix the green line issue. In the past, it offered discount vouchers to some affected users in India as a way to make up for the problem.</p><p>OnePlus also clarified that if replacement parts for older devices aren’t available, the company might offer upgrade vouchers to help users grab a newer OnePlus model.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-makes-a-bold-move-to-tackle-green-line-issues-once-and-for-all</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ OnePlus is now offering a lifetime guarantee to fix the green line problem on all its phones. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">XQXzt5uaNXLgcXuhUuStJW</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/B2MFs7VRHwvKR3Sk6RE92H.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 08:46:56 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/B2MFs7VRHwvKR3Sk6RE92H.jpeg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Alex Dobie / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Holding the OnePlus 9]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Holding the OnePlus 9]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Does it matter that the Galaxy Z Fold 6 didn't get the One UI 7 beta? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title"> Beyond the Alphabet</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="74uXEL5FbSyzjPgHM9K6b7" name="lloyd-beyond-the-alphabet2.png" caption="" alt="Android Central's LLoyd with a projection with a Google logo" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/74uXEL5FbSyzjPgHM9K6b7.png" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text"><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/beyond-the-alphabet">Beyond the Alphabet</a> is a weekly column that focuses on the tech world both inside and out of the confines of Mountain View.</p></div></div>
<p>Oh the woes of living on the edge. Earlier this week, Samsung started rolling out the first One UI 7 beta. Naturally, it's first being made available to those that own one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24">Galaxy S24</a> flagship models (sorry, S24 FE.)</p><p>However, when the rumor mill picked up steam leading up to the official announcement, I was hoping to spend my weekend messing around with One UI 7 on the Galaxy Z Fold 6. The announcement came and went, and there was no mention of the Fold 6 being included in the beta program.</p><p>In fact, there wasn't any mention of Samsung's flagship foldable phones at all. Instead, they've just been roped in with the rest of the company's lineup, with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://news.samsung.com/global/samsung-one-ui-7-beta-starts-to-roll-out-in-select-markets">Samsung stating</a> "In line with Samsung’s commitment to extend its OS upgrade policy, the update will gradually roll out to other Galaxy devices."</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="y25BmS6tkpUTKKSGXq4LLD" name="one-ui-7-beta-features-galaxy-s24-ultra" alt="One UI 7 features on the Galaxy S24 Ultra" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/y25BmS6tkpUTKKSGXq4LLD.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Samsung)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I didn't <em>actually</em> expect the Galaxy Z Fold 6 to be included in the One UI 7 beta program. Especially considering how many times <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/dreary-one-ui-7-beta-forum-update">rumors</a> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/one-uis-next-release-is-delayed-and-samsung-wants-it-on-your-tvs-and-appliances">have</a> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-one-ui-7-beta-pushed-back-again">surfaced</a> about Samsung needing to delay the rollout. It's apparent that this isn't just your run-of-the-mill update, as more <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-galaxy-ai">Galaxy AI</a> features are on the way, along with the new "Now Bar" and improved camera controls.</p><p>Obviously, Samsung is going to prioritize its slab phones over foldables, but there's just something that leaves me feeling a bit disappointed.</p><p>We're heading into year 6 of the foldable phone experiment, with Samsung arguably providing the most useful and reliable software experience of them all. So why is it that the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Galaxy Z Fold 6</a> or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-6-review">Flip 6</a> aren't even mentioned in a footnote for being included or next in line?</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1131px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="hXWgyEfPvQgs4vgXNzLxwM" name="samsung-galaxy-z-fold-special-edition-promo-render.jpg" alt="Samsung Galaxy Z Fold Special Edition promo render" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hXWgyEfPvQgs4vgXNzLxwM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1131" height="636" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Samsung)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Yet again, it feels as if foldable phone enjoyers are being treated like second-class citizens who have a first-class budget. Samsung has made it abundantly clear that it is more than willing to ship out the same phone for three years in a row, raking in profits and then apologizing for "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/is-samsung-sorry-for-failing-to-innovate-or-just-sorry-sales-are-down">failing to innovate</a>." Only to release a phone with the changes we've been wanting, but limit it to just one specific region.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">Foldable phones</a> are a niche product category, I get it. And I know that within that niche, there's an even smaller group that would entertain the idea of installing beta software. But here's my counterargument — if I already know that I'm part of an experiment, what makes you think that I wouldn't want to be included in another one?</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4480px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="MLCKfeSHeDZWCUwT9QjhHA" name="Android-16-Pixel9PF" alt="The logo for Android 16 on a Pixel 9 Pro Fold." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MLCKfeSHeDZWCUwT9QjhHA.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4480" height="2520" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Brady Snyder / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It's been more than two years since I wrote about my experiences living in the "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/beta-apps-anonymous">beta lifestyle</a>," but nothing's changed. Well, I take that back. The devices and some of the apps have changed, but everything else I expressed in that article still rings true.</p><p>Some of it definitely has to do with FOMO, as there are some intriguing additions coming to One UI 7. However, there's also a sneaking suspicion that this might be a sign of things to come. Not that Samsung is going to ditch its foldable phones, but that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/delayed-one-ui-7-update-has-me-worried">we might be heading for a rough patch</a> with One UI software updates.</p><p>We've had the stable version of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-review">Android 15</a> since mid-October, yet here we are almost two months later, and there's no clear timeline for when it will come to the Fold. And if Samsung is having this much of an issue already, what does that say for older models like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/i-spent-a-week-with-the-z-fold-5-coming-home">Galaxy Z Fold 5</a> or even the Galaxy S23 Ultra?</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="R58kspU9haSWsVA2tVErqh" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-camera-lenses-01.jpg" alt="Hands-on with the smaller Samsung Galaxy S24" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/R58kspU9haSWsVA2tVErqh.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I was going to just bypass the money argument until I realized that the $850 Galaxy S24 gets a taste before the $1,800 Z Fold 6. Yes, I know that I answered the reason as to why this is the case already, but my point still stands.</p><p>It's not like we're talking about a company with limited budgets and resources that might issue one or two updates, six months after the release. This is Samsung. You know, the company that generated almost $60 BILLION in revenue in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-confirms-galaxy-s25-teases-cheaper-foldable-xr-device-2025">Q3 2024</a>. In my mind, there's really no excuse for any of its flagship phones to be left behind, even if they aren't as popular or selling as well.</p><p>Hell, Google not only included the Pixel 9 Pro Fold in its first <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16-developer-preview-1-is-here-with-new-features-and-a-snappier-release-timeline">Android 16 Developer Preview</a> release, but it's also available for the original Pixel Fold. Sure, some features are bound to be missing, but that's to be expected given that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/i-hope-google-doesnt-limit-assistant-with-bard">Google fumbled the release</a> anyway.</p><p>The point is that if Google can do it, why can't Samsung? If it wanted to, Samsung could, and for reasons that are below my pay grade to know, chose not to.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/does-it-matter-that-the-galaxy-z-fold-6-didnt-get-the-one-ui-7-beta</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Now that Samsung has released the first One UI 7 beta, I can't but feel left out since the Galaxy Z Fold 6 wasn't included. But, I'm also worried about what that means for the future.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">NQ3vaBSmFqZXBmjESBLbEA</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FJh5pfxdvc8kEW5xXCnzXf.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 20:15:24 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ andrew.myrick@futurenet.com (Andrew Myrick) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FJh5pfxdvc8kEW5xXCnzXf.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 on cobblestone road]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 on cobblestone road]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Tipster claims we won't see the Xiaomi 15 Ultra anytime soon ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Rumors from Weibo claim Xiaomi has "postponed" the launch of its planned 15 Ultra.</li><li>The tipster doesn't suggest a reason why; however, the post notes a recent listing that shows it will feature 90W fast charging and satellite call/text capabilities.</li><li>The Xiaomi 15 was spotted at the FCC recently, signaling its upcoming global launch, but the alleged Ultra delay could effect it.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>There's an Ultra-level device set to grace Xiaomi's latest series; however, a new rumor claims it's a bit further away than previously anticipated.</p><p>According to Weibo leaker <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://weibo.com/6048569942/P3vA3qgZg?pagetype=profilefeed">Digital Chat Station</a> (DCS), Xiaomi has supposedly "postponed" the launch of the 15 Ultra (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidheadlines.com/2024/12/xiaomi-15-ultra-wont-launch-as-soon-as-expected.html">Android Headlines</a>). Despite the curiosity about this (alleged) delay, the tipster did not suggest <em>when </em>consumers could see the device launching.</p><p>In a subsequent post, DCS <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://weibo.com/6048569942/P3pSzsxus">spotted a website certification</a> listing for the Xiaomi 15 Ultra.</p><p>The listing shows the phone will debut with 90W fast charging, which is likely the strength of its wired method. The publication adds that the device may arrive with a battery within the ~5,400mAh to ~5,800mAh range and with the potential for 50W wireless charging. The listing DCS discovered included connectivity support, which leans on satellite capabilities.</p><p>The listing shows the phone will support satellite communications via calls and texts.</p><p>The certification didn't point to any sort of launch, meaning we'll have to play things by ear as 2025 rolls in.</p><p>Xiaomi's 15 and 15 Pro <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/xiaomi-15-and-15-pro-with-snapdragon-8-elite-soc-announced-in-china">debuted in China</a> late in October with Qualcomm's Snapdragon 8 Elite. The devices feature a flat design with rounded corners for an easy handheld experience. The Pro delivers a 6.73-inch LTPO AMOLED 120Hz display and a large 6,100mAh battery. This phone also borrows the same camera from the Xiaomi 14 Ultra: a Sony IMX858 telephoto lens with 5x zoom.</p><p>Speaking of the 14 Ultra, the current 15 Ultra battery rumors claim that a ~400mAh or ~800mAh upgrade is in the cards for its previous 5,000mAh.</p><p>In other news, discussions have been heating up about the Xiaomi 15 series ever since it was <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/xiaomi-15-preps-global-debut-8-elite-fcc-listing">spotted at the FCC</a>. The listing showcased Xiaomi's intent to provide the global phone with HyperOS 2.0 and two RAM/storage configs: 12/256GB, and 12/512GB. It seems likely that the base 15 will debut without the 15 Pro, which would stick to Xiaomi's previous behavior.</p><p>Moreover, the publication wonders if the rumored delay of the 15 Ultra will effect the base model's global appearance. If so, speculation states we could see the phones in February, but there's nothing set just yet. However, a February launch isn't that crazy as Xiaomi <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/xiaomi-14-launch-and-14-ultra">did just that earlier this year</a>.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/xiaomi-15-ultra-alleged-delay-and-certification</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Xiaomi's 15 Ultra allegedly receives some bad news about its launch. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">qEdzwBik3ujaYfssJgGSfP</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qP9rBWmw2LTxfL4GTVUT9B.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 20:13:13 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qP9rBWmw2LTxfL4GTVUT9B.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Xiaomi]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Xiaomi 15 colors]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Xiaomi 15 colors]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ 'Help me create' in Google Home is live for some in Public Preview ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google has started rolling out its "help me create" Gemini feature in the Home app through its Public Preview.</li><li>The experimental feature lets users quickly make an automation for lights, security, and more through the AI model, Gemini.</li><li>Google states this is appearing "gradually" for enrolled Public Preview testers.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google highlighted an upcoming smart home addition in November and that's finally arriving for (a few) enrolled testers.</p><p>According to a new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/googlenest/answer/15684131#zippy=">support page</a>, Google has started rolling out its new automation creation feature for Home in Public Preview. Per the explainer, AI is at the core of this feature as Google states Gemini enters to bring a "help me create" prompt. Essentially, users can control their smart home devices and automation with ease and the potential for more customization.</p><p>Since it's rolling out, enrolled testers can open the Google Home app and find the  Automation button (with a starry icon), tap "Add" and, finally, "help me create." Google states users can get going by using their voice or by writing to the AI in English. However, the company states that you will find Gemini's suggestions for what to automate.</p><p>You can select one of these if you prefer and find the option to edit them to better fit your needs.</p><p>Users can then tap "create" and wait a few moments while the AI does its thing. After, there will be an option to "rate" or save the automation, as well as an "Ask again" button.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:954px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:55.97%;"><img id="nnhyxeVGMUZKwzpqxEkmbc" name="google-home-help-me-create-public-preview" alt="Google Home's "help me create" enters the Public Preview." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nnhyxeVGMUZKwzpqxEkmbc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="954" height="534" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Similar to doing it manually, the post highlights the necessity for three components in "help me create." Those include "Starters," which lets users tell the app/AI "when to begin" alongside "Conditions" for "optional restrictions" when it begins. Then, you have the "Action," which is what <em>should </em>be done.</p><p>Additionally, Google is still working on expanding its device support. There's another page that details which starters, conditions, and actions the prompt supports. Also, "help me create" is stated to only work with Nest cameras "setup or migrated to" the Google Home app.</p><p>This "help me create" feature is rolling out to "eligible users" who've enrolled in Google Home's Public Preview. It seems that only a few are seeing this today (Dec 6), which is also something the company notes. The post states that everyone won't see it simultaneously as it appears "gradually."</p><p>Google teased this <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-home-integrates-gemini-for-smarter-home-automation">new experimental feature</a> during its fall update in early November. The company highlighted a few of its uses, such as the ability for users to automate security, health/wellness, home convenience, and more. That early post said "help me create" would be available "later this year;" however, its arrival in the Public Preview will assist in ironing out any issues before that happens.</p><p>If you're interested in testing "help me create," the post states you can tap the Public Preview icon (it looks like a beaker) and tap the experimental AI features. After agreeing to the terms, the experiment should toggle "on" and the feature should appear shortly after.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/google-home-gemini-help-me-create-public-preview</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google detailed the slow arrival of its "help me create" Gemini-based option in the Home app. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">P4xDdy3eKhvC9gCy4ojtk6</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RhYdgjdYgJhyLt97hqUVtd.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 19:18:35 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Smart Home]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RhYdgjdYgJhyLt97hqUVtd.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Household routines]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Household routines]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>