<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 20:35:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Pixel Buds Pro 2 reportedly spotted picking up its battery certification ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The Pixel Buds Pro 2 has reportedly appeared in two databases as Google proceeded with its charging case certification.</li><li>The listings show the case may feature a 650mAh battery capacity, which would be a 30mAh increase from 2022.</li><li>Little else is known about the buds, but there are specs from its original iteration to look back on.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Information about Google&apos;s upcoming Pixel Buds Pro model has appeared following its certification appearance overseas.</p><p>The assumed charging case for the Pixel Buds Pro 2 was spotted on UL Demko (Denmark) and Safety Korea, according to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.91mobiles.com/hub/google-pixel-buds-pro-2-charging-case-battery-leaked/">91Mobiles</a>. Regarding the former, the case&apos;s listing shows model number GH8TQ, with the database stating it features a rechargeable Li-ion battery.</p><p>What&apos;s important here is that the charging case has been given a battery capacity of 650mAh.</p><p>A photo of the Pixel Buds Pro 2&apos;s battery for its charging case appeared on Safety Korea&apos;s listing. However, further images of the device (such as its case) weren&apos;t spotted in the database as Google continued the certification process.</p><p>More information regarding the Buds wasn&apos;t detailed in the assumed Pro 2 listing, either. The publication speculates that the upcoming device could launch sometime after I/O 2024 in May, which would (ideally) feature its official launch. Rumors add that the device could be delayed and withheld until Google&apos;s fall launch of the Pixel 9 series.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:709px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:84.63%;"><img id="hCGMetgBhCCnjdHTANanuV" name="google-pixel-buds-pro-2-rumored-certification-listing.jpg" alt="A database listing for the assumed Pixel Buds Pro 2's charging case." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hCGMetgBhCCnjdHTANanuV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="709" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: 91Mobiles)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While rumors of the new device are limited, we have the original <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/earbuds/google-pixel-buds-pro-review">Pixel Buds Pro</a> from 2022 to look back on. The original device featured a charging case with a 620mAh battery, which means the rumors could spell a 30mAh boost if true. As the publication notes, the Buds Pro could deliver 31 extra hours of battery. The increase might see that number increased slightly, but we&apos;ll have to wait to be sure.</p><p>Moreover, the original Buds Pro could last for around 11 hours with ANC disabled and seven with it on. If Google is looking to boost its case&apos;s battery, then perhaps there&apos;s more in store for the buds, too.</p><p>Also, with Google&apos;s newfound endeavors with AI, perhaps we&apos;re looking at a chance for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini</a> to impact the Buds Pro 2.</p><p>It remains to be seen what Google is preparing to bring for I/O 2024. It was rumored that the company&apos;s fall event could be packed as the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-fold-successor-name-change-rumors">upcoming Fold successor</a> could shift toward that later section of the year. If Google does delay its Buds Pro 2 launch until the fall, then we might see even more excitement.</p>
<ul><li> <strong>Earbuds deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/promo/headphone-and-speaker-deals"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/browse/electronics/shop-headphones-by-type/3944_133251_1095191_1230614?sort=best_match&cat_id=3944_133251_1095191_1230614_1230476&stores=3081&ps=40"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=earbuds&crid=2RWE1G9N1EIF&sprefix=earbuds%2Caps%2C161&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/mobile/audio/all-audio/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.dell.com/en-us/search/earbuds"><u><strong>Dell</strong></u></a></li></ul>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="5601f5fd-9319-4272-9e50-ed2eed5f9ceb">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/haAckTqwxXmrT7eboVRVj.jpg' alt='Google Pixel Buds Pro wireless earbuds render.'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel Buds Pro</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Clearer sound, only a touch of bass</strong></em></p>
<p>The Google Pixel Buds Pro launched in July 2022 and came with notable advancements over the base Buds model. The Pro variant features rich, clear sound with decent performance from its ANC (active noise cancelation). The Buds Pro contain stable and responsive touch controls so users can control their music and take calls with ease.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/earbuds/pixel-buds-pro-2-charging-case-spotted</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Pixel Buds Pro 2 reportedly appeared on two databases to receive its case certification. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">wyfSjQEJrxevjHhiTobZQH</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ydbwSu8TmKhyPfTyX3qSqg.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 18:45:12 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Earbuds]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ydbwSu8TmKhyPfTyX3qSqg.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Ted Kritsonis / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Holding the Google Pixel Buds Pro.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Holding the Google Pixel Buds Pro.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Android's satellite SOS UI might look like this, a leak spills beans ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Digging through Android's code seemingly unearthed Google's work at implementing a new satellite SOS UI.</li><li>The UI will guide users through a setup process as they must align their phones with a satellite to begin communicating with emergency services.</li><li>Google is preparing to bring satellite connectivity capabilities with Android 15 and with its upcoming Tensor G4 chip for the Pixel 9.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Some digging into Google&apos;s code seems to have unearthed an alleged first look at how users will get its Android satellite connectivity to work.</p><p>According to Google News <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://t.me/google_nws/4004">on Telegram</a>, users will have to keep their phones in line with satellites floating in low orbit (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.gsmarena.com/pixel_9s_satellite_sos_interface_is_in_the_works_heres_what_it_looks_like_now-news-62447.php">GSMArena</a>). During setup, the code shows that users will be prompted to "get a clear view of the sky" by avoiding obstructions like buildings, trees, and mountains. </p><p>Once done, users will be given a UI page with a large circle in its center. Its purpose is to aid users in locating a satellite in their vicinity. A stronger connection will be obtained by ensuring you&apos;re facing the satellite straight on, meaning it&apos;s in the center of the radius.</p><p>The post adds that users can minimize this SOS page when connected to continue texting emergency services or family members. Android will turn the page into a floating display on a device&apos;s homepage, similar to a widget. If minimized, users will continue to ensure the satellite is properly aligned with their phone.</p><p>Google News states the new SOS UI was spotted in Android&apos;s Adaptive Connectivity Services app. Currently, it&apos;s not a page users can access, as it&apos;s still in the works.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Here's a first look at the Android Satellite Pointing UITo connect via satellite you need to "move your phone to center the satellite in the circle". This UI can be minimized into a floating window which can be useful to stay connected while you texting with emergency services pic.twitter.com/V0cKY8BJ5c<a href="https://twitter.com/Nail_Sadykov/status/1779810347186073636">April 15, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>We&apos;ve known for a while that Google is preparing to bring satellite connectivity via Android 15, and the software&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-second-developer-preview">second developer preview</a> shared more. The preview highlighted the company&apos;s continued work at implementing such connectivity for the next major OS launch later this year. Apps in Android 15 will have the ability to state whether or not a user is connected to a satellite.</p><p>Additionally, Google is adding support for SMS/MMS and RCS chats when connected to a satellite.</p><p>More importantly, it <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-likely-to-bring-satellite-connectivity-to-pixel-9-series">was spotted yesterday</a> (Apr. 15) that Google&apos;s upcoming Tensor G4 chip for the Pixel 9 will utilize a new Samsung modem. The modem was stated to support 5G non-terrestrial networks (NTN) for satellite connectivity capabilities with the new flagship series.</p><p>Android 15 recently achieved its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-first-beta-milestone-rolls-out">first beta milestone</a>, meaning we&apos;re right on schedule regarding Google&apos;s timeframe for its launch, likely this fall.</p>
<ul><li> <strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-satellite-sos-ui-spotted</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google's code seemingly spilled what users can expect from Android's satellite SOS UI. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">enazSYjniXQcoNUEEUbg6G</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zHAkdeQq3P5TrA2YK9FedL.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 17:56:14 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zHAkdeQq3P5TrA2YK9FedL.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The mint colorway of the Google Pixel 8]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The mint colorway of the Google Pixel 8]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ WhatsApp's new chat filters give you no more excuses for missing chats ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>WhatsApp introduces chat filters to allow users to quickly view unread messages or group chats without scrolling through numerous conversations.</li><li>These filters will appear at the top of the chat list, offering options like All, Unread, and Groups.</li><li>The filters will be gradually rolled out to users, with availability expected within the next few weeks.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>WhatsApp has introduced <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/whatsapp-beta-tests-chat-filtersagain">new chat filters</a> meant to help you see just unread messages or all your groups in a snap, removing the need to scroll through tons of chats to find them.</p><p>The new filters will pop up right at the top of your chat list, with options like <em>All</em>, <em>Unread</em>, and <em>Groups</em>. When you open the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-messaging-apps">messaging app</a>, you&apos;ll start with the "All" filter, which gives you a view of all your messages. Switch to "Unread" to see only those messages you haven&apos;t checked out yet or marked as unread.</p><p>These filters are even easier to use than the hidden search bar filter for unread messages. If you&apos;re unaware, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/whatsapp">WhatsApp</a> lets you peek at unread messages through a filter in the search bar. But these new filters make it even easier to find that option when you need it.</p><p>Meanwhile, the "Groups" filter has been a hot request, as per WhatsApp. This feature gathers up all your group chats in one spot, so you can sift through your group messages without any hassle. Plus, it&apos;ll display subgroups of communities for you.</p><p>Before, low-activity groups could easily get lost in the sea of chats. But now, with the Groups filter, you&apos;ll have a much better shot at finding them in the crowd.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="ZdadtUFCKLreTQfnBycbbi" name="Whatsapp-chat-filters.png" alt="WhatsApp chat filters" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZdadtUFCKLreTQfnBycbbi.png" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1600" height="900" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: WhatsApp)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>"We believe filters will make it easier for people to stay organized and find their most important conversations and help navigate through messages more efficiently," WhatsApp said in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.whatsapp.com/find-messages-faster-with-chat-filters" target="_blank">blog post</a>. "We’ll continue to build more options to help you focus on what matters most."</p><p>The filters are hitting your chats starting today, and everyone will get them over the next few weeks.</p><p>WhatsApp&apos;s been on a roll with new features. In addition to the filters coming to your chat list, the service added <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/whatsapp-adds-search-by-date-feature-for-android">another search feature last month for Android users</a>: searching by date. Now, you can finally pinpoint messages effortlessly based on when they were sent instead of endlessly scrolling for that one message.</p><p>And here&apos;s a fun fact: this feature is already up and running on iOS, Mac desktop, and WhatsApp Web.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/whatsapps-new-chat-filters-give-you-no-more-excuses-for-missing-chats</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Now you can filter your chats to see only unread messages or all your groups. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">6TDW4FyQtCTKynzRAUEeL8</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BHF9cLjVHveBwNxp2uvaXU.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 17:14:29 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BHF9cLjVHveBwNxp2uvaXU.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Whatsapp community tab]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Whatsapp community tab]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ OnePlus' next foldable could bring the heat to the Galaxy Z Flip in a whole new way ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>OnePlus might be gearing up to release a new foldable phone that could rival the Samsung Galaxy Z Flip, boasting a zoom lens and macro camera.</li><li>A leaker says camera upgrades expected in OPPO's upcoming foldable may carry over to OnePlus, hinting at a similar model with a telephoto camera.</li><li>While flip phones excel in portability, their camera capabilities are usually lacking, but the rumored inclusion of a telephoto lens in the OnePlus Flip could change the game.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>OnePlus already has a book-style foldable phone, but a new rumor says its next one might be a Galaxy Z Flip contender, and this one could even have a zoom lens, which is rare for foldable phones.</p><p>A leaker who goes by the handle Smart Pikachu on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://weibo.com/5888095979/O9GOwe7lS" target="_blank">Weibo</a> says that OnePlus might drop a second foldable phone this year. But it will supposedly be different from the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-open-review">OnePlus Open</a> and will instead flip open like Motorola&apos;s Razr models and Samsung&apos;s Galaxy Z Flip line. The tipster adds that it will pack a telephoto and macro rear camera (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/oneplus-flip-foldable-leak-3434110/" target="_blank">Android Authority</a>).</p><p>Foldables are seriously turning heads in the smartphone world these days, even though there aren&apos;t heaps to pick from just yet. It&apos;s no wonder every phone maker wants a piece of the action.</p><p>Flip phones fold in half for ultimate portability, unlike those giant slabs everyone else uses. Plus, they are usually more affordable than book-style foldables, putting them right up there with other <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">top Android phones</a> in terms of price.</p><p>But their cameras often leave something to be desired. Usually, they&apos;re rocking a dual-camera setup, but the telephoto lens is often the one that&apos;s missing. However, if this rumor about the OnePlus Flip is true, it could be a game-changer for flip phones by bringing a telephoto lens to the game.</p><p>The tipster is hinting that these camera upgrades will debut on OPPO&apos;s upcoming compact foldable, and it&apos;s likely they&apos;ll trickle down to a similar OnePlus model, maybe with a slight tweak or rebranding.</p><p>Even though it&apos;s not official yet, it&apos;s not exactly a wild guess. The OnePlus Open was basically a twin of the OPPO Find N3. If OnePlus rolls out a flip phone resembling the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oppo-find-n3-flip-review">Find N3 Flip</a>, it wouldn&apos;t be a shocker.</p><p>Plus, having a flip phone with a telephoto camera would be pretty unique since hardly any flip foldables offer this feature right now. In fact, the only one you can actually buy right now with a telephoto camera is the Find N3 Flip. So, if this rumor is accurate, the OnePlus Flip could be a real standout.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-next-foldable-could-bring-the-heat-to-the-galaxy-z-flip-in-a-whole-new-way</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ OnePlus' upcoming foldable phone might have what the Samsung Galaxy Z Flip lacks. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">XVhviV4xABfNg4aatHY8fk</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GqkAUT7bE9vz989UH5uihD.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 16:12:16 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GqkAUT7bE9vz989UH5uihD.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus Open review]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus Open review]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Wallet explained: Licenses, banks, new features, and the Google Pay shutdown ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Google Wallet is the default payment, ID, and transit pass app for most Android phones, supplanting Google Pay. The term "Google Pay" still exists for making contactless NFC payments in stores, but you use the Google Wallet app for those transactions.</p><p>Now that the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-pay-changes-june-shutdown-announced">Google Pay app is shutting down</a> later this year, you&apos;re probably curious which Pay features will transfer over to Wallet. You may also have heard that Google Wallet supports features like driver&apos;s licenses, tickets, and medical info, and you may want to know how to access these.</p><p>Our in-depth Google Wallet guide will break down its history, list of key features, recent news and updates, and everything else you need to know!</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-google-wallet-summarized"><span>Google Wallet, summarized</span></h2>
<p>The original Google Wallet launched in 2011 as a Nexus phone exclusive for contactless credit card payments at specific locations. A lack of NFC-enabled phones, insufficient retail partnerships, and little consumer interest sunk the initiative.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/android-pay-rolling-out-starting-today">Android Pay</a> took Wallet&apos;s place in 2015 as a payment system with much more business support and infrastructure, while Wallet scaled down into a peer-to-peer payment system. </p><p>By 2018, both services had <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/android-pay-and-google-wallet-join-together-form-google-pay">consolidated</a> into the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-pay">Google Pay</a> brand, a single app for both tap-to-pay and sending money to friends, and Google Wallet ceased to be. Over time, Google Pay added boarding passes, event confirmations, transit balances, and other tools that weren&apos;t strictly "payments."</p><p>Google&apos;s love of renaming services for a marketing boost came full circle in July 2022, when it <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet-launch">rebranded its payment service to Google Wallet</a> once again. Google Pay persisted as a peer-to-peer payment app with its wallet-like features removed, but it will shut down on June 4, 2024.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.30%;"><img id="kqEepFZJn662Vo6h4xJVVN" name="Google-Wallet-screenshot-3.jpeg" alt="Google Wallet example animation" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kqEepFZJn662Vo6h4xJVVN.jpeg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1153" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google Wallet will continue to support "Google Pay" payments in stores worldwide. It <strong>won&apos;t</strong> enable P2P payments like the original Pay app, however, and your current Google Pay balance will only be transferrable through the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://pay.google.com/pay/u/0/home" target="_blank">website</a> once the Pay mobile app shuts down.</p><p>Google Wallet supports a variety of banks and credit cards across over 80 countries. It also supports a variety of other passes, IDs, and stored information that we&apos;ll break down in the next section.</p><p>Generally speaking, Google Wallet pulls information from other Google apps on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phones</a>. So, for example, if you receive an email on Gmail with a delayed flight time, it&apos;ll notify you and change the stored boarding pass information.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-what-can-you-store-in-google-wallet"><span>What can you store in Google Wallet?</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2171px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="GcryGVh4qBqev2QRstYGgg" name="Google-Wallet-app-examples.jpg" alt="Google Wallet" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GcryGVh4qBqev2QRstYGgg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="2171" height="1221" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>First and foremost, you can deposit <strong>credit</strong> and <strong>debit cards</strong> in Google Wallet. Most banks and cards are compatible, and Google <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/the-google-wallet-push-continues-as-30-new-banks-are-added-in-the-us">has added</a> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet-supports-42-additional-banks">dozens of new banks</a> in 2024 to fill out the list before Google Pay&apos;s shutdown. You can ensure your bank is included by checking the list of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/pay/answer/7454247?hl=en&ref_topic=7625138" target="_blank">supported contactless payments</a> sorted by country.</p><p>As a sidenote, we have a guide on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-lock-down-google-wallet-cards">how to lock down your Google Wallet cards</a> if your phone is stolen, so that the thief can&apos;t use tap-to-pay with those stored cards.</p><p>You can add your <strong>loyalty </strong>or <strong>membership cards</strong>, then tap your phone or watch to apply discounts or balances, or even pay directly for items. Check if your loyalty card is eligible by tapping <strong>Add to Wallet > Loyalty card </strong>and entering the program name.</p><p>Plus, you can keep your <strong>boarding passes</strong> and <strong>event tickets</strong> in Google Wallet, so entering a plane or stadium is as simple as pulling them up and tapping your phone. In March 2024, Google updated Wallet so that Gmail confirmation emails <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet-gains-movie-boarding-pass-support-from-gmail">automatically export passes to Wallet</a>, saving you the trouble.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="ePCQ8DDxq2B53qYgv6ZSyC" name="Google-Wallet-Add-Transit-Card.jpeg" alt="Adding public transit card to Google Wallet" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ePCQ8DDxq2B53qYgv6ZSyC.jpeg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google Wallet also hosts <strong>transit cards</strong> and <strong>parking passes</strong>, though once again, there is no guarantee that your local public transit or parking system will support Google Wallet without checking. Currently, San Francisco, Washington, D.C., and Toronto are the only cities to support Google Wallet transit passes or payments.</p><p>You may add <strong>COVID-19 vaccine passports</strong> or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-add-covid-vaccine-cards-google-wallet">other medical info</a> to Google Wallet as well.</p><p>Other Google Wallet functions include <strong>digital car keys</strong>, <strong>corporate office passes</strong>, and <strong>hotel keys</strong>. Digital car keys require a relatively recent phone running Android 12 or later, and not all cars will support them. As for corporate badges, only <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/wallet/answer/14085932?hl=en&ref_topic=11925097&sjid=11940236237620777137-NA" target="_blank">10 countries</a> support corporate passes today, and your employer must buy into the program.</p><p>Google&apos;s biggest challenge, however, will be to enable <strong>digital driver&apos;s licenses</strong> or <strong>student IDs</strong>. Certain American states have begun to support digital IDs, but it&apos;s extremely limited at the moment.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-can-i-store-my-driver-s-license-in-google-wallet"><span>Can I store my driver's license in Google Wallet?</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="ZVy8MWzXVKBSjhv5khk5Ph" name="Google-IO-2022-digital-driver's-license-graphic.png" alt="Digital Driver's license graphic" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZVy8MWzXVKBSjhv5khk5Ph.png" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>During Google I/O 2022, VP of Product Management Sameer Samat announced on stage that "we&apos;re working with states here in the U.S. and governments around the world to bring digital IDs to wallet later this year, starting with driver&apos;s licenses."</p><p>That statement turned out to be a bit optimistic: The ID program did launch in Maryland by the end of 2022, but Google took until October 2023 to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet-adds-digital-ids-for-three-more-us-states">add digital ID support for Arizona, Colorado, and Georgia residents</a>.</p><p>Dong Min Kim, Google&apos;s director of product management for Google Wallet, did <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet-to-expand-digital-drivers-license-support">promise in January</a> that "Digital ID will be a cornerstone for us in the next year" and that more states&apos; IDs will come to Wallet in the coming months. But we&apos;ve yet to hear anything since, and there are regulatory hurdles to making this happen.</p><p>To add a driver&apos;s license to Google Wallet, you&apos;ll need an Android phone (version 8 or higher) with Bluetooth and Nearby Devices active and a screen lock protecting it.</p><p>With all of those prerequisites fulfilled, you can simply open the Wallet app and tap <strong>Add to Wallet > ID card</strong>. You&apos;ll then have to take photos of the front and back of your ID, then record a short video of yourself to submit for verification. At that point, you should be able to use your ID in lieu of a physical card at participating airports.</p><p>As for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-add-student-id-google-wallet">adding a student ID to Google Wallet</a>, we have a guide for that as well, but it will once again depend on whether or not your school supports the feature.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-google-wallet-banks"><span>Google Wallet: Banks</span></h2>
<p>We can&apos;t possibly include the full list of Google Wallet banks here, so we&apos;ll link you to this <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/wallet/answer/12059326?hl=en&co=GENIE.CountryCode%3DUS&sjid=13323444051548168082-NA" target="_blank"><strong>Google Support page</strong></a><strong> </strong>that has a dropdown menu linking to each country&apos;s list of banks.</p><p>Just for the United States alone, the list of "other participating banks" appears to have <strong>thousands of options</strong>. Once you&apos;ve selected a bank in Google Wallet, you&apos;ll most likely need to log into the bank&apos;s website, or enter a PIN or authorization code.</p><p>You can also choose to make Paypal a payment method in Google Wallet, though only in the United States and Germany.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-which-countries-support-google-wallet"><span>Which countries support Google Wallet?</span></h2>
<p>Currently, Google Wallet has replaced Google Pay in the following 80 countries, listed below:</p>
<ul><li>Albania</li><li>American Samoa</li><li>Argentina</li><li>Armenia</li><li>Australia</li><li>Austria</li><li>Azerbaijan</li><li>Belgium</li><li>Bermuda</li><li>Bosnia and Herzegovina</li><li>Brazil</li><li>Bulgaria</li><li>Canada</li><li>Cayman Islands</li><li>Chile</li><li>Columbia</li><li>Costa Rica</li><li>Croatia</li><li>Cyprus</li><li>Czech Republic</li><li>Denmark</li><li>Dominican Republic</li><li>Ecuador</li><li>Estonia</li><li>Faroe Islands</li><li>Finland</li><li>France</li><li>Georgia</li><li>Germany</li><li>Greece</li><li>Greenland</li><li>Guam</li><li>Guernsey</li><li>Hong Kong</li><li>Hungary</li><li>Iceland</li><li>Ireland</li><li>Isle of Man</li><li>Israel</li><li>Italy</li><li>Japan</li><li>Kazakhstan</li><li>Kyrgyzstan</li><li>Kuwait</li><li>Latvia</li><li>Liechtenstein</li><li>Lithuania</li><li>Luxembourg</li><li>Malaysia</li><li>Malta</li><li>Mexico</li><li>Moldova</li><li>Monaco</li><li>Montenegro</li><li>Morocco</li><li>Netherlands</li><li>New Zealand</li><li>North Macedonia</li><li>Northern Mariana Islands</li><li>Norway</li><li>Peru</li><li>Poland</li><li>Portugal</li><li>Puerto Rico</li><li>Qatar</li><li>Romania</li><li>San Marino</li><li>Serbia</li><li>Singapore</li><li>Slovakia</li><li>Slovenia</li><li>South Africa</li><li>Spain</li><li>Sweden</li><li>Switzerland</li><li>Taiwan</li><li>Thailand</li><li>Ukraine</li><li>United Arab Emirates</li><li>United Kingdom</li><li>United States</li><li>U.S. Virgin Islands</li><li>Vietnam</li></ul>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-google-wallet-vs-competing-payment-apps"><span>Google Wallet vs. competing payment apps</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="uc9HaLqrS6RYZYUsj5aJqQ" name="Samsung-Wallet-close-up.jpg" alt="Samsung Wallet" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uc9HaLqrS6RYZYUsj5aJqQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4080" height="2295" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Android users, specifically Samsung phone owners, have two main choices for their payment app: <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-wallet-vs-google-wallet">Google Wallet or Samsung Wallet</a>. The latter launched around the same time as Google Wallet, combining Samsung Pay and Samsung Pass into one service. Sound familiar?</p><p>Like Google Wallet, Samsung Wallet collects your digital payment cards, boarding passes, vaccination cards, and digital car keys, with the eventual goal of adding IDs and licenses.</p><p><em>Unlike</em> Google Wallet, Samsung Wallet stores passwords, a remnant of the feature on Samsung Pass. Plus, anyone invested in crypto can "monitor their digital asset portfolio by checking the value of their cryptocurrencies across various exchanges" within Wallet.</p><p>Samsung Wallet is available now, but only on Samsung phones via the Galaxy Store — whereas Google Wallet is available on all Android phones via the Play Store — and only 21 countries, well short of Google&apos;s list.</p><p>Looking beyond the Android phone ecosystem, we also have a general guide on how the five main payment systems — <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/meta-pay-vs-amazon-pay-vs-google-pay-vs-samsung-pay">Google Pay, Samsung Pay, Apple Pay, Meta Pay, and Amazon Pay</a> — compare to one another. </p><p>To briefly summarize, Google and Apple have the most robust features and widespread presence for both mobile and web payments. Amazon Pay is more limited but takes very little setup if you have a Prime account, while Meta Pay is most useful for frequent Facebook Marketplace users.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-what-s-new-with-google-wallet"><span>What's new with Google Wallet?</span></h2>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xJxzdqcGJQk?start=1010" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>The biggest recent change to Google Wallet was a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet-qr-barcode-pass-rollout">photo function</a>, which lets you take a photo of a physical pass and have that data auto-transcribed into Wallet, rather than making you type it out yourself.</p><p>Google Wallet <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet-apple-pass-more-user-support">added support for Apple Wallet files</a> in early 2024, though the rollout is still ongoing. People have noticed glitches, since ".pkpass" file expect you to be using an iPhone, but those glitches should be fixed over time.</p><p>Another controversy arose when Google Wallet began <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet-verification-change">requiring you to verify your identity</a> before making contactless payments in certain countries. While some countries already required this, others let you make payments indefinitely so long as they weren&apos;t above a certain threshold.</p><p>Google later created <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet-adds-verification-settings-to-balance-security-and-convenience">"Verification Settings"</a> for Wallet, letting you decide in advance whether to require authentication before certain actions, such as using Wallet as a transit pass.</p><p>In late 2023, there was a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet-vulnerability-exposes-card-information">Google Wallet vulnerability</a> that exposed credit card information via a standard NFC reader. This glitch was eventually fixed.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-which-smartwatches-support-google-wallet"><span>Which smartwatches support Google Wallet?</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="MqR97nhWDLouM2SmndZgF3" name="add-card-to-google-wallet-pixel-watch.jpg" alt="Add new card to Google Wallet on Pixel Watch" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MqR97nhWDLouM2SmndZgF3.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="4080" height="2294" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The list of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/these-are-watches-support-android-pay">smartwatches that support Google Pay</a> is exceedingly long. Basically, any Wear OS watch is going to support the feature, since it&apos;s a Google operating system. Even the latest Galaxy Watches let you choose between Google Pay and Samsung Pay, now that Google and Samsung have partnered for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/wear-os-3">Wear OS 3</a>.</p><p>In terms of the latest devices to add Google Wallet, both the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/how-to-use-google-wallet-fitbit-sense-2-versa-4">Fitbit Sense 2 and Versa 4 have Wallet support</a> thanks to Google&apos;s Fitbit acquisition. And of course, Google&apos;s own <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-review">Pixel Watch</a> will be the first to receive any new Wallet features and updates.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="0cda0ea1-13ae-484b-b224-4ceea14b7b6e">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BKUkcu7TXZRvd6bhvyv5D.jpg' alt='Polished Silver Pixel Watch 2 with Bay Active band square render'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel Watch 2</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The best watch for Google apps</strong></em></p>
<p>The Pixel Watch 2 is one of our favorite watches for Android phone owners. Its attractive soft-edge design and speedy UI make it stand out from other smartwatches, and you get all the latest Wear OS tech (like Google Wallet) before any other brand.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google Wallet replaced Google Pay, which will shut down soon. Here's all the latest news and added features you need to know. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">23DfMEDxprhgqVZmLdWzwW</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/iSNZtYCjj8zGf6UCJZgbrC.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 14:58:57 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/iSNZtYCjj8zGf6UCJZgbrC.jpeg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Menu to add a payment card, transit pass, loyalty card, or gift card to Google Wallet on an Android phone]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Menu to add a payment card, transit pass, loyalty card, or gift card to Google Wallet on an Android phone]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ How to download YouTube videos to watch offline ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>You can still watch your favorite YouTube videos when your Wi-Fi or mobile data fails simply by downloading them. Sometimes, internet connection can be spotty or fail altogether, and saving them for offline viewing will give you a library of content to pass the time.</p><p>Whether you&apos;re watching videos on one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-samsung-tablets">best Samsung tablets</a> or not, downloading YouTube videos is quick and easy. Even though <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/streaming-platforms-prioritize-content-over-ui">streaming services aren&apos;t getting better</a>, they still want you to pay for more content. But finding something to watch when your internet isn&apos;t working can be frustrating, so it&apos;s always a good idea to have a backup plan and videos to watch.</p><p><strong>Note:</strong> To download YouTube videos, you must have a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/youtube-premium">YouTube Premium</a> subscription.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-download-youtube-videos-to-watch-offline-2">How to download YouTube videos to watch offline</h2>
<p>1. Open the <strong>YouTube app </strong>on your device.</p><p>2. Find and <strong>open the video</strong> you want to download.</p><p>3. Tap <strong>Download </strong>in the menu that appears below the video.</p><p>4. If you don&apos;t have YouTube Premium, you&apos;ll see a <strong>prompt to get it</strong>, which is required to download videos. You can start the free trial or select<strong> Not now </strong>if you don&apos;t wish to proceed. If you give the Premium version a chance, you&apos;ll see a Subscribe button with information letting you know the day the free trial ends and how much you&apos;ll be charged after. YouTube will remind you that your free trial is ending seven days before the deadline.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="86KjjzLv8Q3eisWVbJjuu8" name="download youtube videos 1-3.jpg" alt="youtube" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/86KjjzLv8Q3eisWVbJjuu8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Christine Persaud / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>5. If you have YouTube Premium, you’ll be given <strong>options for the resolution to download the video</strong>. Naturally, the higher the resolution, the more space the download will take up on your device and the potentially longer the video will take to download (though with good Wi-Fi or a solid cellular connection, this likely won’t be an issue). Choose the desired resolution and select <strong>Download</strong>.</p><p>6. Once selected, the <strong>video will automatically begin downloading,</strong> and you’ll see the download process as the arrow lights up.</p><p>7. Once downloaded, the download button will show <strong>Downloaded</strong> with a white checkmark beside it.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="Ju4bAk2ZJCyxK9d6nyhJ69" name="download youtube videos 4-6.jpg" alt="youtube" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Ju4bAk2ZJCyxK9d6nyhJ69.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Christine Persaud / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>As noted, to download YouTube videos for offline viewing, like the top trending videos to watch during your commutes or a walk down memory lane with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-music-2023-recap">YouTube Music 2023</a>, you need a YouTube Premium subscription, which is $13.99 a month. However, you can try it out for one month for free before committing.</p><p>Once downloaded, you have up to 29 days to watch the downloaded video. If you haven’t gotten around to watching yet after the timeframe expires, you can reconnect to a mobile or Wi-Fi network and download the video again (if it’s still available for offline viewing). If it is no longer available, it will automatically be removed from your device the next time you sync it. If any changes have been made to the video, they will be applied when you&apos;re online.</p><p>Once a YouTube video is downloaded, it resides locally on your device. That means it’s taking up valuable space, so it’s a good idea to delete it once you are done watching and no longer need it.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-delete-downloaded-youtube-videos-2">How to delete downloaded YouTube videos</h2>
<p>Deleting the video is simple:</p><p>1. Tap your <strong>profile picture</strong>.</p><p>2. Swipe up and choose <strong>Downloads</strong>.</p><p>3. Tap the <strong>dots to the side</strong> of the video.</p><p>4. Tap <strong>Delete</strong> from downloads at the bottom.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:74.07%;"><img id="5tShocr2fd5GviZ2ngErXH" name="Download-YouTube-Video-Delete.jpg" alt="Steps to erase a downloaded YouTube video on an Android phone" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5tShocr2fd5GviZ2ngErXH.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="3240" height="2400" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Judy Sanhz / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<h2 id="what-are-smart-downloads-on-youtube-2">What are Smart Downloads on YouTube?</h2>
<p>Smart Downloads are recommended videos that YouTube automatically downloads so you always have something to watch. The downloads will stop when you&apos;re low on storage or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://forums.androidcentral.com/threads/wifi-keeps-disconnecting-and-reconnecting.1064087/">disconnected from Wi-Fi</a>. Based on your viewing habits, YouTube will automatically download videos you might like.</p>
<h2 id="how-does-youtube-smart-downloads-work-2">How does YouTube Smart Downloads work?</h2>
<p>If the videos are not downloading, you can enable the feature by:</p><p>1. Tapping your <strong>profile picture</strong>.</p><p>2. Tap the <strong>cogwheel</strong> at the top right.</p><p>3. Go to <strong>Backgrounds & downloads</strong>.</p><p>4. Look for and <strong>toggle on</strong> the <strong>Smart downloads</strong> option.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:74.07%;"><img id="TLRLvy4DHhN7jyBnGcgHvU" name="Turn-off-smart-download-YouTube.jpg" alt="Steps to turn on or off Smart Downloads on YouTube" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TLRLvy4DHhN7jyBnGcgHvU.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="3240" height="2400" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Judy Sanhz / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>As long as you&apos;re here, you can also make other adjustments, such as only downloading over Wi-Fi, adjusting how Playback works, and adjusting how much storage Smart downloads takes up and the quality of Smart downloads. You&apos;ll also see options for Delete all downloads and how much storage you have left. When you adjust the storage space the feature takes up by using the slider; you&apos;ll also see how much video time that is. For example, you set the storage limit to 1.5GB, and besides it, you&apos;ll see that that equals 11 hours of videos.</p>
<h2 id="keep-downloading-2">Keep downloading</h2>
<p>It&apos;s easy to take the Internet for granted and think it&apos;ll always be there, but it&apos;s best to be prepared and have some YouTube videos to watch. If you&apos;re going to watch YouTube on your computer, get ready for a change since YouTube is testing a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-might-change-the-location-of-video-titles-and-comments">redesigned video player on the web</a>.</p><p>Since YouTube Music is also part of the package, remember that it&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-music-for-android-and-ios-gain-activity-feed">rolling out a new Activity feed for Android and iOS</a>. Thanks to this new feature, you&apos;ll know what your favorite artists are up to. YouTube Music has more to offer by teasing users with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-music-team-highlights-current-upcoming-podcast-improvements">improvements to the podcast experience</a> too.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="6e9c5cfc-ad0b-46c6-8921-c2f963f8540c" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="From $13.99/month at YouTube" data-dimension48="From $13.99/month at YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/premium" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:512px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="EQoPfCLCA2UxjrdedEQwc5" name="YouTube-app-logo-2023.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/EQoPfCLCA2UxjrdedEQwc5.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="512" height="512" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>YouTube Premium</strong></p>
<p>With a YouTube Premium subscription, you can watch videos anytime, whether you have an active Internet connection or not, by downloading them for offline viewing.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/premium" data-dimension112="6e9c5cfc-ad0b-46c6-8921-c2f963f8540c" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="From $13.99/month at YouTube" data-dimension48="From $13.99/month at YouTube"><strong>From $13.99/month at YouTube</strong></a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.youtube.com/premium" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="6e9c5cfc-ad0b-46c6-8921-c2f963f8540c" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="From $13.99/month at YouTube" data-dimension48="From $13.99/month at YouTube">View Deal</a></p></div>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-download-youtube-videos-to-watch-offline</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Download YouTube videos to always have access to them by following these easy steps. These are the steps to follow. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">ftby2aXGAXbexCrGDvNu9b</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2R2acB7NEodKgVoVZegGD9.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 14:42:16 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ christinep2424@gmail.com (Christine Persaud) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2R2acB7NEodKgVoVZegGD9.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Christine Persaud / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[youtube]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[youtube]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Best Buy is shaving 50% off the Google Pixel 7a with activation — no, I'm not kidding ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Google Pixel deals are here, with some retailers currently offering great limited-time Spring sales. If you&apos;re just looking for a basic smartphone with some surprising flagship-level features, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-7a-5g-128gb-unlocked-charcoal/6539915.p"><strong>Best Buy is shaving up to $250 OFF the Google Pixel 7a</strong></a>, a midrange device that features 128GB of storage for the base model, the efficiency of the Tensor G2 chipset, and excellent cameras with 4K video recording. The $250 discount is applied when you activate the phone through a carrier on Best Buy&apos;s site, but you can also score a $150 discount when you buy unlocked. That&apos;s the biggest straight discount that the phone has ever received. </p><p>Along with its good-looking 6.1-inch AMOLED display and its great cameras, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-7a-review">Google Pixel 7a</a> comes with five years of Pixel updates, and it includes many of the same useful features as last year&apos;s more-expensive Pixel 7 Pro. </p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="223eeb51-3ace-435e-894e-b1706c310fa1" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$499" data-dimension48="$499" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-7a-5g-128gb-unlocked-charcoal/6539915.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="7CZFaCFuph3tCjQGbGvKmD" name="Google-Pixel-7a-white-space.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7CZFaCFuph3tCjQGbGvKmD.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Google Pixel 7a 128GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-7a-5g-128gb-unlocked-charcoal/6539915.p" data-dimension112="223eeb51-3ace-435e-894e-b1706c310fa1" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$499" data-dimension48="$499"><del>$499</del> <strong>$249 with activation, $349 unlocked at Best Buy</strong></a></p>
<p>If you're not looking for the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phone</a> out there and you'd rather prioritize a low sticker price, this may be the perfect deal for you. For a limited time, you can get a straight $150 off the unlocked Google Pixel 7a at Best Buy, representing 30% off the normal price. Alternatively, you can activate the phone through a carrier and get $250 off, which amounts to a 50% discount! </p>
<p>This simple smartphone includes a bright 6.1-inch AMOLED display, a slick chipset, and capable cameras for both photos and video. Plus, get five years of Android OS updates at an even cheaper price than this phone normal comes with.</p>
<p><strong>Price comparison:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-7a-Unlocked-Smartphone/dp/B0BZ9XNBRB">Amazon - $349.99</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-7a-5g-128gb-unlocked-charcoal/6539915.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="223eeb51-3ace-435e-894e-b1706c310fa1" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$499" data-dimension48="$499">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>you&apos;re looking for a phone with an especially bright, vibrant display of around 6.1 inches; you want an affordable smartphone that still has a good camera for photo and video; you prioritize a phone with several years of OS updates.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if:</strong> you&apos;re looking for a smartphone with great battery life; you plan to use your phone for gaming and don&apos;t mind paying extra for top-notch performance; you don&apos;t like a phone with a plastic exterior.</p><p>With the release of the Pixel 8a likely just around the corner, the Pixel 7a is no longer groundbreaking, but it has all the basic features that Pixel fans are looking for, and this deal makes the already affordable phone even cheaper. With a 6.1-inch AMOLED display and powerful cameras with 4K video recording, it&apos;s not hard to appreciate this phone&apos;s offerings—especially at this extra low price.</p><p>Some of the downsides of this phone include its basic plastic structural design, the lack of a telephoto lens, and some pretty subpar battery life. Still, it remains a great <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-android-phones">cheap Android phone</a>, and for those looking for a deal on something reliable, this is honestly a pretty great pick at this price — <em>especially </em>if you decide to activate today.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/best-buy-is-shaving-50-off-the-google-pixel-7a-with-activation-no-im-not-kidding</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Get the Google Pixel 7a for just $249 when you activate with a carrier through Best Buy or $349 when you buy unlocked. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">bqZ49pCCLRMtbdEfdEtQen</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/imgvxRR8FUb2cmw5XGDHNL.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 14:25:11 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/imgvxRR8FUb2cmw5XGDHNL.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[null]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The back of the Charcoal Google Pixel 7a]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The back of the Charcoal Google Pixel 7a]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Amazon Fire Tablet: Which storage size should I buy? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <section class="article__schema-question"><h3>Amazon Fire Tablet: Which storage size should I buy?</h3><article class="article__schema-answer"><p><strong>Best answer: </strong>Your storage choice will depend on your needs, but remember that 32GB of storage will leave the users with 25GB and a 64GB choice with 54GB in actuality. It's always best to have more storage space than you think you might need just in case your needs change and you're not stuck with a tablet you can't even update due to lack of storage space.</p></article></section>
<h2 id="which-fire-tablet-storage-size-should-you-buy-2">Which Fire Tablet storage size should you buy?</h2>
<p>The first thing you need to know about buying an Amazon Fire tablet (or any modern mobile gadget, for that matter!) is that the listed (or advertised) storage capacity is different from the usable storage space you&apos;ll end up with. Amazon&apos;s tablets use a Fire OS layered on top of the Android operating system, which requires a decent chunk of storage for core system functions and all of Amazon&apos;s apps and services that come preinstalled on these devices.</p><p>Now, you can look at your options, especially when considering a tablet that offers 16GB, 32GB, and 64GB storage sizes. That low-end 16GB tablet will only give you about 12GB of usable storage. Depending on your plans for downloading games, movies, and other media, you&apos;ll want as much storage as possible.</p>
<p>The Fire HD 10 tablet comes in 32GB and 64GB variants, so spending a little extra to double the storage size is a no-brainer. It&apos;s also worth pointing out that Amazon recently updated its line of kid-friendly Amazon Fire devices. While the previous 16GB Fire 7 Kids Edition may have offered enough storage for your tiny tech wizard, Amazon now offers the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/amazon-fire-hd-10-kids-vs-kids-pro" target="_blank">Fire HD 10 Kids and Fire HD 10 Kids Pro</a> tablets, both of which double the storage space to 32GB.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="ok7osy6uGAKYpCWdVURe3G" name="amazon-fire-hd-8-2022-on-table.jpg" alt="Amazon Fire HD 8 (2022) laying face down on table" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ok7osy6uGAKYpCWdVURe3G.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Things get trickier (and pricier) when you consider the newer Fire HD tablets. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/amazon-fire-hd-8-2022-review" target="_blank">Fire HD 8</a> model, which is still our pick for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-kindle-fire-tablet" target="_blank">best Amazon Fire Tablet</a> on the market right now, is available in 32GB and 64GB options, as are the Fire HD 8 Plus, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/amazon-fire-hd-10-2023-launch">Fire HD 10</a>, and Fire HD 10 Plus. The 32GB size is quite a reasonable choice here, and depending on how you plan to use the tablet and the prevalence of media streaming services these days, you might not even need to opt for the 64GB variant.</p>
<p>Then there&apos;s the recently launched <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/amazon-fire-max-11-review" target="_blank">Fire Max 11</a>, which comes in 64GB and 128GB storage sizes, the latter being the largest storage size ever offered in a Fire tablet. Apart from the usual things like media consumption, the Fire Max 11 is also intended for productivity-centric workflows. Even then, the 64GB option will be more than sufficient for basic needs.</p>
<h2 id="expand-your-fire-tablet-apos-s-storage-with-a-microsd-card-2">Expand your Fire Tablet&apos;s storage with a microSD card</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1200px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="4u4mvimzVmhokVAsQbZGFj" name="Amazon-Fire-HD-10-2021-lifestyle-16x9-01.jpg" alt="Amazon Fire HD 10" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4u4mvimzVmhokVAsQbZGFj.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1200" height="675" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>When it comes to storage space, the price tends to increase with the capacity. However, if you opt for a device with less storage to save, don&apos;t worry—thanks to the versatile microSD slot, you always have the option to increase in size with a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-micro-sd-card-android">decent memory card</a>. Thanks to the extra space, you can modify your device&apos;s storage to fit your needs.</p><p>A microSD slot is a reliable feature that you&apos;ve always seen on the Fire tablets and still do in the newer models. With this slot, you can expand the capacity as much as you need. The slot can be a real lifesaver when you unexpectedly need extra storage space.</p><p>When it comes to great deals on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-microsd-cards-amazon-fire-tablet">microSD cards for Fire Tablets</a>, we&apos;ve got you covered with these great options. You can choose from options as little as 64GB or as much as 1TB. If you&apos;re an average user and want to have enough space, you can always go with the 256GB version. They usually go for about $25, but you never know when one of them might be on sale.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="9bc7d3dc-b591-49f6-9dee-bac50ceacd07">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ES99v2WSEXxKrnykTCQ6WD.jpg' alt='SanDisk Made for Amazon 256GB microSD Memory Card'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">SanDisk 256GB microSD (Made for Amazon)</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The ultimate storage upgrade</strong></em></p>
<p>Made for your Amazon Fire tablet, this microSD card comes in six different storage capacities, ranging from 32GB-512GB. So, whether you're going on a long trip or need space for work, feel free to download all your games, music, images, videos, and a lot more on this hardcore memory card.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/amazon-fire-tablet-which-storage-size-should-i-buy</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Spoiler: You're going to want as much storage as possible, so always spring for the extra space model when you can, but it's not a bad idea to just get a microSD card for expansion either. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">sPJpt1MNPbaPs2MftUgLr7</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Maif3htz4EW4c8VF2sVgdV.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 14:08:22 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ sharmarajat@zoho.com (Rajat Sharma) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Maif3htz4EW4c8VF2sVgdV.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Amazon]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Amazon Fire 7 Kids Edition]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Amazon Fire 7 Kids Edition]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ How to shop more sustainably on Amazon ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>As residents of planet Earth, we all need to do our part to help our home thrive. This means adopting a more eco-friendly attitude in all aspects of our lives, be it as consumers, manufacturers, or sellers. Amazon shoppers looking to go green will be pleased to know that there are many ways to make your shopping experience more sustainable. Here&apos;s what you can do to purchase products sustainably on Amazon.</p>
<h2 id="your-guide-to-shopping-more-sustainably-on-amazon-2">Your guide to shopping more sustainably on Amazon</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1366px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.22%;"><img id="ZSTGQyn7JtiSX6Pw9qBsMg" name="amazon-sustainability-1.jpg" alt="Amazon logo" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZSTGQyn7JtiSX6Pw9qBsMg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1366" height="768" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Amazon)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Before plunging into the details, here are a couple of facts about Amazon that&apos;ll help you understand the company&apos;s outlook on sustainability. A few years ago, the e-commerce goliath joined other popular brands like Microsoft, Best Buy, and Verizon in signing the Climate Pledge. In line with the aims of the non-profit organization, Amazon aims to achieve net-zero carbon emissions by the year 2040. Billions of dollars worth of investments have already gone into this initiative, giving birth to projects like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/amazon-promoting-eco-friendly-shopping-its-new-climate-pledge-friendly-program">Climate Pledge Friendly program</a>, green operations and logistics decisions, and the use of renewable energy across many Amazon buildings and warehouses.</p><p>There&apos;s the Amazon Aware store that sells various household and lifestyle products that have been certified by third parties for their use of organic, recycled, and bio-based materials. For sellers, entities like Amazon Launchpad exist to help them implement sustainability across their brands.</p><p>If you own one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-alexa-speaker">best Alexa-enabled speakers</a> and live in the U.S., Amazon has made it even more accessible to contribute to an eco-friendly cause. All you need to do is say <strong>"Alexa, grow a tree”</strong> and you can donate a dollar towards the One Tree Planted initiative. All your contributions are used to plant trees, converting every $1 into one tree planted on your behalf, combatting climate change and pollution one tree at a time.</p><p>Clearly, Amazon is committed to offsetting the negative environmental impacts of its business operations. The tech giant has taken many steps towards achieving a more sustainable existence and enables you, the consumer, to also participate in the same cause. Now, let&apos;s look at the many options available to you to shop more sustainably on Amazon.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-climate-pledge-friendly"><span>Climate Pledge Friendly</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1437px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.30%;"><img id="etZLzcWyrm6VLAAHG5azuG" name="amazon-climate-friendly-pledge.jpg" alt="Amazon Climate Pledge Friendly" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/etZLzcWyrm6VLAAHG5azuG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1437" height="809" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Amazon)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>This is one of the first things to do when shopping in a more sustainable way on Amazon. All you have to do is look for the little green <strong>Climate Pledge Friendly</strong> badge under the product listing. No matter what you&apos;re buying, if it has been certified as environmentally friendly under The Climate Pledge requirements, Amazon will print that little green logo under the item&apos;s name.</p>
<p>1. Go to <strong>amazon.com/climatepledgefriendly</strong>.</p><p>2. Search for the product of your choice. You can also use the Climage Pledge Friendly filter on the left to narrow down the results.</p><p>3. Look for a listing with the <strong>green Climate Pledge Friendly badge </strong>or that lists a sustainability feature (or more than one). If you tap on <strong>sustainability feature,</strong> you&apos;ll see a pop-up on the right side that outlines what they are. It could be that the item was made with a certain percentage of recycled materials or that it is Certified Climate neutral by a third-party organization.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:891px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.34%;"><img id="LvA2CH83pyU6Rf8XjXWogN" name="amazon-climate-pledge-friendly-product.jpg" alt="Amazon Climate Pledge Friendly product listing" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LvA2CH83pyU6Rf8XjXWogN.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="891" height="502" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>4. Click on the <strong>Climate Pledge Friendly product listing</strong>.</p><p>5. Add the product to your cart and check out.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="067d8502-a6f0-433a-828b-6bcc4b83ea77" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Shop Climate Pledge Friendly at Amazon" data-dimension48="Shop Climate Pledge Friendly at Amazon" href="https://www.amazon.com/climatepledgefriendly" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:317px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="e77NGFz46iHK4Twn5X2wzG" name="amazon-climate-friendly-pledge-square-logo.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/e77NGFz46iHK4Twn5X2wzG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="317" height="317" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/climatepledgefriendly" data-dimension112="067d8502-a6f0-433a-828b-6bcc4b83ea77" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Shop Climate Pledge Friendly at Amazon" data-dimension48="Shop Climate Pledge Friendly at Amazon"><strong>Shop Climate Pledge Friendly at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>Easily identify sustainable, environmentally products that have been verified by Amazon. You can do so by spotting the Climate Pledge Friendly product badge under Amazon product listings.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/climatepledgefriendly" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="067d8502-a6f0-433a-828b-6bcc4b83ea77" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Shop Climate Pledge Friendly at Amazon" data-dimension48="Shop Climate Pledge Friendly at Amazon">View Deal</a></p></div>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-amazon-aware"><span>Amazon Aware</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:562px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="6megwKmf8FdNCVepejbWPM" name="Amazon-Aware.jpg" alt="Amazon Aware" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6megwKmf8FdNCVepejbWPM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="562" height="316" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Amazon)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Another excellent option for a greener buying experience is <strong>Amazon Aware</strong>. All you have to do is go to the Amazon Aware online store. There are plenty of household and lifestyle items on offer, including bed sheets, clothes, and beauty products. All the things you see under the Amazon Aware store are Climate Pledge Friendly certified in addition to being carbon neutral.</p><p>Amazon Aware products are made of organic, natural ingredients. Many of these options are recycled or constructed with recycled materials. They also likely come in recycled packaging. Here&apos;s how you can purchase your desired products from Amazon Aware.</p>
<p>1. Go to <strong>amazon.com/amazonaware</strong>.</p><p>2. Go through the product departments.</p><p>3. Browse through the items on sale and select whatever you need.</p><p>4. Add the items you want to your cart and check out.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="7cec975c-55c4-4336-af71-913c8caafdac" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Shop at Amazon Aware" data-dimension48="Shop at Amazon Aware" href="https://www.amazon.com/amazonaware" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:237px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.42%;"><img id="ugFfcWHBrkhcL8fbMsvfTM" name="Amazon-Aware-square-logo.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ugFfcWHBrkhcL8fbMsvfTM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="237" height="238" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/amazonaware" data-dimension112="7cec975c-55c4-4336-af71-913c8caafdac" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Shop at Amazon Aware" data-dimension48="Shop at Amazon Aware"><strong>Shop at Amazon Aware</strong></a></p>
<p>Amazon Aware is a dedicated store within the Amazon platform. All items on sale are Climate Pledge Friendly and carbon neutral. Pick and peruse at ease knowing that they are made of organic and recycled materials.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/amazonaware" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="7cec975c-55c4-4336-af71-913c8caafdac" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Shop at Amazon Aware" data-dimension48="Shop at Amazon Aware">View Deal</a></p></div>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-amazon-renewed"><span>Amazon Renewed</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1366px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.22%;"><img id="wsz8CuhvkRkyqZGxndDjiG" name="Amazon-renewed.jpg" alt="Amazon Renewed" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wsz8CuhvkRkyqZGxndDjiG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1366" height="768" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Amazon)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Going green can mean many things. Instead of purchasing new products, you can get used ones that have been refurbished so that the materials do not go to waste. Buying refurbished or renewed goods is a sustainable way of living as you prolong the lifespan of an item instead of dumping it in the trash. This is especially true when it comes to renewed electronics as your purchase reduces electronic waste. If you have your doubts, remember that the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-sustainable-repairable-phones">best refurbished phones</a> are in such excellent condition, you won&apos;t even notice the difference between old and new. </p><p>Amazon ensures that each <strong>Amazon Renewed</strong> product meets stringent requirements and doesn&apos;t take anything away from your user experience. As a bonus point, refurbished electronics are much cheaper than brand new ones, saving you some cash while also helping to preserve the environment. For your mental assurance, all Amazon Renewed electrical gadgets come with a 90-day Amazon Renewed Guarantee. Here&apos;s how you can buy Amazon Renewed electronics.</p>
<p>1. Go to <strong>amazon.com/renewed</strong>.</p><p>2. Look for whatever electronic item you need to buy.</p><p>3. Add the electronics of your choice to your cart and check out.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="80c46616-beb0-43bc-a3db-005133614c10" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Shop at Amazon Renewed" data-dimension48="Shop at Amazon Renewed" href="https://www.amazon.com/renewed" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:883px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.11%;"><img id="BrwViyDdWzjM42y2qYeMfC" name="Amazon-renewed-square-logo.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BrwViyDdWzjM42y2qYeMfC.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="883" height="884" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/renewed" data-dimension112="80c46616-beb0-43bc-a3db-005133614c10" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Shop at Amazon Renewed" data-dimension48="Shop at Amazon Renewed"><strong>Shop at Amazon Renewed</strong></a></p>
<p>Save the planet and some pocket money while shopping for refurbished items. Amazon Renewed offers refurbished electronic products in every category. You get a 90-day guarantee for reassurance.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/renewed" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="80c46616-beb0-43bc-a3db-005133614c10" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Shop at Amazon Renewed" data-dimension48="Shop at Amazon Renewed">View Deal</a></p></div>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-amazon-warehouse"><span>Amazon Warehouse</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1206px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.14%;"><img id="A57RaZJtGHjESK2cPVyXWP" name="Amazon-Warehouse-lifestyle.jpg" alt="Amazon Warehouse" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/A57RaZJtGHjESK2cPVyXWP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1206" height="677" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Amazon)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>When looking for preloved items that aren&apos;t electronic, the best place on Amazon is the <strong>Amazon Warehouse</strong> store. Starting from pet supplies to baby products, from kitchen items to video games, Amazon Warehouse has it all. The items on sale under this category include pre-owned, used, and open-box products.</p><p>For your safety, Amazon inspects all Amazon Warehouse goods for quality assurance. If you aren&apos;t satisfied with your purchase despite Amazon&apos;s 20-point quality inspection, know that you are covered by a 30-day return policy. Let&apos;s look at how you go about shopping from Amazon Warehouse.</p>
<p>1. Go to <strong>amazon.com/amazonwarehouse</strong>.</p><p>2. Browse through the product categories.</p><p>3. Select the products you want by adding them to your cart.</p><p>4. Check out once you have all you need.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="2085415f-bf54-45c9-b04b-62884986ac10" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Shop at Amazon Warehouse" data-dimension48="Shop at Amazon Warehouse" href="https://www.amazon.com/amazonwarehouse" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:377px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="o9bTnQoCSQeWLXHWPTzfcP" name="Amazon-Warehouse-square-logo.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/o9bTnQoCSQeWLXHWPTzfcP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="377" height="377" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/amazonwarehouse" data-dimension112="2085415f-bf54-45c9-b04b-62884986ac10" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Shop at Amazon Warehouse" data-dimension48="Shop at Amazon Warehouse"><strong>Shop at Amazon Warehouse</strong></a></p>
<p>Buy pre-loved items to reduce unnecessary waste. Amazon Warehouse stocks high-quality used goods under almost every category. You get a 30-day return policy for safety.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/amazonwarehouse" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="2085415f-bf54-45c9-b04b-62884986ac10" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Shop at Amazon Warehouse" data-dimension48="Shop at Amazon Warehouse">View Deal</a></p></div>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-amazon-trade-in"><span>Amazon Trade-in</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1962px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.22%;"><img id="wuHQBTXaEf7r2Vm3mw2i9L" name="amazon-trade-in.jpg" alt="Amazon Trade-in" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wuHQBTXaEf7r2Vm3mw2i9L.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1962" height="1103" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Amazon)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>If you&apos;re the sort of person who doesn&apos;t want to purchase used or refurbished products, there is another option. Shopping sustainably on Amazon doesn&apos;t always lead to preloved or renewed items. Under the <strong>Amazon Trade-in</strong> program, you can trade-in your own used electronics for Amazon gift cards and/or promotional discounts. The Amazon Trade-in procedure varies depending on what it is that you want to trade-in.</p><p>After you have selected your device under the Amazon Trade-in section on the Amazon website, you&apos;ll have to answer some questions about it to confirm its condition and value. The answers to your questions determine the value you will get and how fast you will get it. For instance, certain items qualify for instant payment, while others may not yield you any monetary gain until you&apos;ve sent them in for appraisal.</p><p>What&apos;s really great is that shipping your used electronic gadgets to Amazon doesn&apos;t cost you anything. Even if the item is worth nothing, Amazon will ship it back to you free of charge. All you have to do is print the shipping label and send it in. Here&apos;s how you can initiate the Amazon Trade-in process.</p>
<p>1. Go to <strong>amazon.com/tradein</strong>.</p><p>2. Select the device category that matches your item.</p><p>3. Read and <strong>follow the Amazon Trade-in instructions</strong> for your specific device.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="ccf21a48-6a70-4b3b-ab34-10deacb9f478" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Trade-in at Amazon" data-dimension48="Trade-in at Amazon" href="https://www.amazon.com/tradein" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:376px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="C54wu7Z3ebkCoYcvQrVhfH" name="amazon-trade-in-square-logo.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/C54wu7Z3ebkCoYcvQrVhfH.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="376" height="376" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/tradein" data-dimension112="ccf21a48-6a70-4b3b-ab34-10deacb9f478" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Trade-in at Amazon" data-dimension48="Trade-in at Amazon"><strong>Trade-in at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>Be environmentally responsible by trading-in your used electrical devices and gadgets on Amazon. The Amazon Trade-in program helps you repurpose your old possessions while making a few extra bucks. If you're lucky, Amazon might give you promo offers too.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/tradein" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="ccf21a48-6a70-4b3b-ab34-10deacb9f478" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Trade-in at Amazon" data-dimension48="Trade-in at Amazon">View Deal</a></p></div>
<ul><li><a href="#main"><strong>Back to the top ^</strong></a></li></ul>
<h2 id="do-your-part-2">Do your part!</h2>
<p>There are plenty of ways you can do your part for the Earth, including many options when shopping on Amazon. In most cases, these methods also help you save money, which is a win-win in the end. Plus, you get fabulous new products, from electronics to appliances, bedding to baby gear, that&apos;s new, or in like-new, condition. But most important, you can feel at ease that you are helping the environment and shopping more sustainably.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/amazon/how-to-shop-sustainably-amazon</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Looking to implement an environmentally friendly lifestyle? Here's how you can shop more sustainably on Amazon. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">vepN2Y73DPrNyKwKY2AvtY</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NXx5e25Rxtwc4NHC3qGcWR.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 13:54:53 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NXx5e25Rxtwc4NHC3qGcWR.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Amazon]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Amazon logo]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Amazon logo]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Nothing Phone 2a gets April security patch and camera improvements ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Nothing OS 2.5.5 update brings camera optimizations for the Phone 2a.</li><li>It brings the April security patch and optimizations to Google Assistant as well.</li><li>It is the fourth major update ever since its launch on March 5, 2024.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Nothing appears serious in making its Phone 2a have a smoother and bug-free experience. Despite being the first budget phone from the company, it has been seeing significant updates since its March 5, 2024 launch. The company is rolling out its fourth notable Nothing OS update this week.</p><p>Nothing has announced the update to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/nothing-phone-2a-review">Phone 2a</a> on X (formerly Twitter) bearing <strong>Nothing OS 2.5.5</strong>, while the last one was <strong>Nothing OS 2.5.4.a</strong> from the previous month.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Nothing OS 2.5.5 is now on Phone (2a). Camera:📸 Improved camera colour saturation.👤 Optimised blur accuracy in Portrait Mode, as well as overall clarity.⚡ Enhanced camera loading speed.General improvements:🛡️ Updated to April Security Patch.🗣️ Optimised the Google… pic.twitter.com/A6TTB7iZXU<a href="https://twitter.com/nothing/status/1779905065727263046">April 15, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>The latest release brings notable camera enhancements, including improvements to camera color saturation, optimization for blur accuracy for photos shot in Portrait mode, and overall clarity. Users may also see enhancements in camera loading speeds.</p><p>The update also includes the April 2024 security patch next to increase overall smoothness across the interface for the Phone 2a users. Nothing further notes that Google Assistant wake-up experience and pop-up view animations will appear more fluid with new optimizations included in the latest release.</p><p>The improvements to Google Assistant follow the issue where “Hey Google” wasn’t accessible before and was fixed with the nifty <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/nothing-phone-2a-2-5-4-a-update">Nothing OS 2.5.4.a update</a>.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="X7X6THbcYQFLijMSTZRhrV" name="nothing-phone-2a-24.jpg" alt="Nothing Phone 2a review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/X7X6THbcYQFLijMSTZRhrV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Additionally, the overall gaming experience and performance should significantly improve after users install the update.</p><p>Phone 2a users can navigate to their device’s <strong>Settings> System> System Update</strong> to check for OTA release.</p><p>The other bug fixes per the Nothing OS 2.5.5 update include:</p>
<ul><li>Resolved compatibility issues with some third-party launchers.</li><li>Fixed stability issues with WiFi and Bluetooth connections.</li><li>Fixed an issue where the Night Light feature was ineffective on the lock screen.</li><li>Optimized the overall stability of the system.</li></ul>
<p>Previous updates from Nothing also fixed some minor issues, such as malfunctioning fingerprint sensors, static noise in the receiver during calls, and flickering issues while launching the app lock screen. Likewise, the updates added some new features and improved gaming and overall performance.</p><p>Meanwhile, the company has also rolled out the much-awaited <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/nothing-os-2-dot-5-dot-3-update-to-phone-2">Nothing OS 2.5.3 update</a> to its flagship <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/nothing-phone-2-review">Phone 2</a> early this month. The company is also gearing up for a new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/earbuds/nothing-ear-ear-a-confirmation">Ear and Ear a launch</a> later this month, the specs and pricing of which were recently <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/earbuds/nothing-ear-ear-a-pricing-spec-leak">leaked</a>.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/nothing-phone-2a-receives-april-2024-security-patch</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Nothing has rolled out a slew of updates for Phone 2a ever since its launch. This week, it is getting yet another update with security patches and improvements. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">svFxMgB8QzvzuvZ8gLfMJi</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vrsjpASZ785GN6nzaKVWJW.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 12:52:52 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vrsjpASZ785GN6nzaKVWJW.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Nothing Phone 2a review]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Nothing Phone 2a review]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>