<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 20:49:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Pixel Watch 3 has a new life-saving feature, and Google explains how it works ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google launched the Pixel Watch 3 today (August 13) and is detailing a new emergency feature: Loss of Pulse.</li><li>The device leans on its heart rate sensors and AI software to detect and confirm if a person's heartbeat and movement are non-existent.</li><li>The watch will automatically call emergency services with an audible message explaining the situation.</li><li>Google's Pixel Watch 3 will arrive late in September, starting at $349.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>With the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/made-by-google-event-2024-live-blog-pixel-9-pro-fold-watch-3-gemini-and-everything-else-we-expect-to-see">Made by Google event</a> now concluded, the company revealed a crucial emergency feature on its watch for loss of pulse.</p><p>According to a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.google/products/pixel/pixel-watch-3-loss-of-pulse-detection/">Keyword post</a>, the Pixel Watch 3 features Google&apos;s first "Loss of Pulse" detection feature for unresponsive users. The post states that this feature relies on heart rate sensors and algorithms alongside AI software. If your <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-3-hands-on">Pixel Watch 3</a> does not detect your heart rate with its standard green light, it will activate its red-hued infrared sensors for an additional scan.</p><p>The watch&apos;s motion sensor will join soon after. Google states that it will initiate a check-in after the device confirms that your pulse and movement are absent. Users will see a "Checking for pulse..." display on their Watch 3. Beneath will be an "I&apos;m OK" button to deter it from automatically calling emergency services.</p><p>Afterward, the Pixel Watch 3 will call emergency services within 20 seconds with its automated message in tow to detail the situation.</p><p>If you&apos;ve purchased the LTE variant of the Watch 3, the device will handle all communications. However, the Bluetooth/Wi-Fi variant will lean on your phone to handle the call.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="AM58k4uyAjAsNjDAzKe5tG" name="google-pixel-watch-3-41mm-45mm-with-pixel-buds-pro-2-4.jpg" alt="Pixel Watch 3 41mm and 45mm" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AM58k4uyAjAsNjDAzKe5tG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2500" height="1406" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google states that it leveraged user research to limit "false positives" during the device&apos;s monitoring. Moreover, the company has also worked with cardiologists to train its AI algorithm. This was put through the wringer as live tests were conducted. The Pixel Watch 3 was then strapped to stunt actors who simulated a loss of pulse using a tourniquet. That was paired with simulated falls, producing an impact strong enough to stop one&apos;s heart.</p><p>Loss of Pulse detection is an opt-in feature for all Pixel Watch 3 owners. Users in the U.K., France, Austria, Denmark, Ireland, the Netherlands, Norway, Sweden, and Switzerland are among the first to receive it this September. There&apos;s no word yet on U.S. availability, but Google states it will continue to work to gain the appropriate regulatory permissions for additional areas.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qhfq-P2G_1I" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-3-series-goes-official">Pixel Watch 3 launched today</a> (August 13) during the Made by Google event and has two sizes: 41mm and 45mm. Consumers can find the device in various colors and several band styles. Google improved its viewing experience by widening the display with 16% fewer bezels than the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-2-review">Pixel Watch 2</a>.</p><p>Thanks to its deep Fitbit integration, this year&apos;s model offers a host of health and fitness features for runners, sports enthusiasts, and others.</p><p>The Pixel Watch 3&apos;s Loss of Pulse detection should fit comfortably beside <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-explains-fall-detection">Google&apos;s fall detection</a> software. The watch&apos;s motion sensors carry the bulk of weight, sensing any "hard fall" before leaning on its software to check in on a person. Similar to Loss of Pulse, the company trained its algorithms on stunt doubles who threw themselves (repeatedly) so it could understand a true, life-threatening fall.</p><p>Fall detection is an opt-in feature, but it&apos;s relatively easy to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/how-to-enable-fall-detection-pixel-watch">navigate the settings to enable it</a>. The Pixel Watch 3 arrives in late September, bringing Loss of Pulse with it.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/pixel-watch-3-loss-of-pulse-detection-explained</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google explained its Loss of Pulse detection feature for the Pixel Watch 3 and how it came to be. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Ju2EgLa6pR4wtuQvXeGNyC</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/U89JsJt5Bp2E3WzGdLGuzQ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 20:47:05 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/U89JsJt5Bp2E3WzGdLGuzQ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google / YouTube]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Pixel Watch 3 is the first Google device to feature the Loss of Pulse feature.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Pixel Watch 3 is the first Google device to feature the Loss of Pulse feature.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Should you upgrade to the Pixel 9 or Pixel 9 Pro? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Traditionally, Pixel phones haven&apos;t offered a ton of choice. Mainline models launch in a standard and Pro variant, and Google typically launches a budget Pixel A-series model half a year later. This year, however, the Pixel 9 series is offering <em>a lot</em> more choice than usual, doubling the number of options available in previous years.</p><p>You can choose to keep the price lower by picking the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-series-hands-on">Google Pixel 9</a> or, for the first time ever, upgrade the hardware and cameras with a Google Pixel 9 Pro without being forced to use a larger phone. However, Google <em>also</em> offers the Pixel 9 Pro XL, a larger phone with the same Pro-level cameras and features as the Pixel 9 Pro but with a larger display and battery.</p><p>Plus, Pixel fans can choose to upgrade further to the Pixel 9 Pro Fold, offering a foldable form factor with the same features and Tensor G4 processor as the rest of the Pixel 9 series.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/best-google-pixel-9-preorder-deals">best Google Pixel 9 preorder deals</a> will get you the phone for less than MRSP, but does it make sense to upgrade at all? Let&apos;s cover all the bases.</p>

<h2 id="bold-new-hardware-2">Bold new hardware</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="NAqPF5ycTaqGD5unn6nx56" name="google-pixel-9-pro-and-pro-xl-hazel-01.jpg" alt="Comparing the Hazel Google Pixel 9 Pro to the Pixel 9 Pro XL" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NAqPF5ycTaqGD5unn6nx56.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>There&apos;s no denying just how different this year&apos;s Pixels look, yet they still retain some of that unique Pixel flavor by keeping the centered camera visor on the back. There&apos;s also no denying the iPhone&apos;s influence on these phones with the flat sides and flat glass all around, though.</p><p>If you love flat phones that look a whole lot like an iPhone, this is about as good as it gets. If that&apos;s not your thing, though, maybe a Pixel 9 case or Pixel 9 Pro XL case will help. After all, most phones only truly look different from the back, anyway.</p><p>At the very least, Google says this new design is twice as durable as previous Pixels, which is a good thing given some of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-7-pro-volume-rocker-falling-off">quality control issues</a> we&apos;ve seen in the past.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.30%;"><img id="aDihrFF7G9RXFehfH9nJhg" name="google-pixel-9-pro-vs-pixel-8-pro-porcelain-03-camera-bars.jpg" alt="Comparing the Google Pixel 8 Pro to the Google Pixel 9 Pro XL" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/aDihrFF7G9RXFehfH9nJhg.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1153" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="548bAmXmYXau2FSmft9evg" name="google-pixel-9-pro-vs-pixel-8-pro-porcelain-04-camera-bars.jpg" alt="Comparing the Google Pixel 8 Pro to the Google Pixel 9 Pro XL" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/548bAmXmYXau2FSmft9evg.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="dnfZyRQictSRsHsu9DsuSg" name="google-pixel-9-pro-vs-pixel-8-pro-porcelain-02.jpg" alt="Comparing the Google Pixel 8 Pro to the Google Pixel 9 Pro XL" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dnfZyRQictSRsHsu9DsuSg.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 4 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="scfUdVxyWnHitQpX3n7tQh" name="google-pixel-9-pro-vs-pixel-8-pro-porcelain-06-display.jpg" alt="Comparing the Google Pixel 8 Pro to the Google Pixel 9 Pro XL" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/scfUdVxyWnHitQpX3n7tQh.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Compared to the Pixel 8 Pro, the Pixel 9 series feels a bit sterile and industrial. There&apos;s no denying how fun some of the new colors are, though — especially Wintergreen, Peony, and Rose Quartz — and the shiny side rails on the Pro models give it that extra premium look and feel.</p><p>But there are some pretty exciting hardware improvements to consider. While <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qi2-wireless-charging-standard">Qi2</a> is nowhere to be seen, satellite SOS is making an appearance for the first time on a U.S. phone, and the quirky temperature sensor is now on both Pro models regardless of the size.</p><p>Plus, all Pixel 9 models <em>finally</em> charge faster this year! With the new 45W Pixel charger, you&apos;ll go from 0-50% in 30 minutes on a Pixel 9 or Pixel 9 Pro, while the Pixel 9 Pro XL will jump up to an impressive 70% in 30 minutes. That&apos;s not as fast as my favorite phone, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12-review">OnePlus 12</a>, but it&apos;s still a monumental improvement over anything Samsung offers and better than past Pixels.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="okKNJikSRnW23VRyV2AngF" name="google-pixel-9-45w-charger-04.jpg" alt="Charging the Google Pixel 9 Pro XL with Google's 45W Pixel charger" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/okKNJikSRnW23VRyV2AngF.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>A lot of the things Google is doing with new Pixel 9 features heavily rely on the Tensor G4 processor inside. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-tensor-g4-rumors">As rumors hinted at</a>, the Tensor G4 isn&apos;t a big upgrade in the traditional sense. Gamers likely won&apos;t notice any real differences, and we&apos;re not yet sure if Google has improved the overheating situation of past Tensor processors until we get to test them longer.</p><p>So, while you&apos;re not getting much in the way of daily performance upgrades, all of Google&apos;s new apps and features revolve around the processor&apos;s considerable AI-processing muscle. The Tensor G4 is able to process AI-based tasks 2.25x faster than the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-3">Qualcomm Snapdragon 8 Gen 3</a> processor inside every other major Android flagship in 2024. That&apos;s a pretty unbelievable number.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="nQQVtS85orDKfD5Gc7LP24" name="google-pixel-9-pro-gemini-live-02.jpg" alt="Using Gemini Live on the Google Pixel 9 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nQQVtS85orDKfD5Gc7LP24.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>To translate that into real-world usage, that means images you edit, the stickers you create, the emojis Gemini crafts, the calls recorded and transcribed, the screenshots searched and cataloged, and the friends added to photos stay private and on-device despite featuring the detail and speed of something processed in the cloud.</p><p>There&apos;s no denying just how fascinating <em>and</em> useful Google&apos;s new AI features are, especially when compared to some of the things Samsung launched alongside <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-galaxy-ai">Galaxy AI</a> on its phones this year.</p>
<h2 id="the-pixel-9-pixel-9-pro-and-pixel-9-pro-xl-which-is-right-for-you-2">The Pixel 9, Pixel 9 Pro, and Pixel 9 Pro XL: Which is right for you?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="844XanGJPoQJp8fEAcLZRW" name="google-pixel-9-pro-9-and-xl-rose-pink-02.jpg" alt="Comparing all three Google Pixel 9 models in pink" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/844XanGJPoQJp8fEAcLZRW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>If you&apos;re set on upgrading to a Google Pixel 9 this year, you&apos;ll be able to choose from four different models for the first time ever. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-fold-hands-on">Pixel 9 Pro Fold</a> is the largest, most expensive model available. It&apos;s best for folks who want a tablet and a phone all in one device.</p><p>Down from that is the Pixel 9 Pro XL which is roughly the same size as the Pixel 8 Pro. It features a 6.8-inch display and three cameras on the back, including a 48MP telephoto camera with a 5x optical zoom lens. It&apos;s also the fastest charging of the bunch, as I covered above.</p><p>But if you don&apos;t like large phones, never fear, for the Pixel 9 Pro is here! It sports the same 16GB of RAM and triple rear camera system as the Pixel 9 Pro XL. It even has the 42MP selfie camera from that phone, although it won&apos;t charge quite as fast up to 100% as the Pro XL model.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="9GBqiPDZrHE7q4fvoj92gW" name="google-pixel-9-pro-and-pro-xl-rose-pink-01.jpg" alt="Comparing all three Google Pixel 9 models in pink" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9GBqiPDZrHE7q4fvoj92gW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Google Pixel 9 is the same size as the Pixel 9 Pro — it even fits in the same cases — but it cuts out some features to debut at $200 cheaper.</p><p>First off, it doesn&apos;t include a telephoto camera on the back, and the selfie camera is reduced from 42MP to 10.5MP. There&apos;s no Ultra-Wideband chip inside so device tracker tiles <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/testing-new-google-find-my-device-trackers">won&apos;t work as well</a> as they will on the Pro models. The regular Pixel 9 also doesn&apos;t have the cool <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/how-use-google-pixel-8-pro-temperature-sensor">temperature sensor</a> that&apos;s on the back of both Pro models.</p><p>On the software side of things, most features are identical between all Pixel 9 models but the cheaper Pixel 9 is missing a few camera feature found on the Pro models. The Pixel 9 is missing Video Boost, Zoom Enhance (since there&apos;s no telephoto camera), Video Boost, Night Sight Video, and Super Res Zoom Video.</p><p>If you&apos;re good to go without all those features, the cheapest Pixel 9 model is a pretty great way to get the best of Google without the added cost.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/should-you-upgrade-to-the-pixel-9-or-pixel-9-pro</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Google Pixel 9 series comes in four sizes and shapes this year, but are they worth the upgrade, and which do you pick? We have your answer. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">D6TKkhPwBff3e3tmuHnjaf</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/T3YUpgQw73oDrsWPRXvk8g.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 20:30:16 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/T3YUpgQw73oDrsWPRXvk8g.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Comparing the Google Pixel 8 Pro to the Google Pixel 9 Pro and Pixel 9 Pro XL]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Comparing the Google Pixel 8 Pro to the Google Pixel 9 Pro and Pixel 9 Pro XL]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ What color Google Pixel 9 should you buy? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The fun-sized Google Pixel 9 comes in a diverse squad of colors, with shades ranging from black and white hues to bold and splashy tints. Four colors are a lot to take in, which probably makes it very difficult to settle down on a single variant to take home forever. Three of them aren&apos;t new to the roster, but there&apos;s a blushing new entrant to Pixel&apos;s portfolio of colors.</p><p>Are you pondering over what color <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-series-hands-on">Google Pixel 9</a> should you buy? Stop fretting and take an in-depth look at each colorway first. We&apos;ve listed them all below, followed by useful advice to help you make your choice.</p>
<h2 id="meet-the-pixel-9-in-all-its-forms-2">Meet the Pixel 9 in all its forms</h2>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="91c6144d-028e-45d4-93dd-f265afb4cc39">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SscSR9vZNQyzy98Jr4bwpi.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 official render front and back - Peony"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 - Peony</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Pretty in pink</strong></em></p>
<p>This sweet candy pink is the newest, splashiest, and most attractive colorway of the Google Pixel 9. Everything from the frame to the buttons and the camera bar matches the pink hues of the body.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="799956d1-8e98-4ae1-9e49-f66fdcc01ca8">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CRjLfoDu9MyH4Mc9xa3uCj.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 official render front and back - Wintergreen"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 - Wintergreen</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Sorta minty</strong></em></p>
<p>Wintergreen is this year's green shade for the Pixel 9. It's like a mix of the mint-colored Pixel 8 and the Hazel variant of the Pixel 7 Pro. We love this natural hue because of its freshness.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="1dd7758b-8a3d-4695-8fd4-b7ed71bd05e8">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GPVtH4seobgPnhFZDYKAbi.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 official render front and back - Obsidian"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 - Obsidian</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Black beauty</strong></em></p>
<p>It's common knowledge that you can never go wrong with black, be it clothes, shoes, or possessions like a Pixel 9. Obsidian comes and goes with the Pixel family, but luckily the baby Pixel 9 comes in it this time around.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="681bec46-d9ea-401c-a251-9b7765f501b4">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hE4rXqJRVjM5oX3PLgC7xi.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 official render Porcelain front and back"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 - Porcelain</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Bougie beige</strong></em></p>
<p>The Google Pixel 9 in Porcelain channels champagne and the finer things in life. If you like that "old money" vibe, this color is spot-on. And if you get bored of it eventually, a case can give it a makeover.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<ul><li><a href="#main"><strong>Back to the top ^</strong></a></li></ul>
<h2 id="it-apos-s-a-battle-of-bold-vs-safe-hues-when-choosing-a-pixel-9-color-2">It&apos;s a battle of bold vs. safe hues when choosing a Pixel 9 color</h2>
<p>The itsy bitsy 6.3-inch Google Pixel 9 comes in four shades, two of which are basic while the others are eye-catchingly colorful. Neutrals like Obsidian and Porcelain are safe choices, but they don&apos;t embody the spirit of a Pixel in my opinion.</p><p>Google&apos;s phones are full of cutting-edge features that are both insanely good fun and also mind-blowingly useful. Nothing embodies the spirit of such <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">fine Android phones</a> better than bold hues. The Pixel 9 has so many great features and that signature Pixel UI. You want to match that with a boisterous shade like Peony or Wintergreen.</p><p>Since Google has launched matching Pixel Buds Pro 2 and Pixel Watch 3 options, you can achieve a seamless look regardless of which color Pixel 9 you buy. Don&apos;t be afraid to take a risk; go with your gut. And hey, if you feel like you made a mistake for whatever reason later on, you can always fix it up by getting a good-looking case for your Pixel 9.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-color-google-pixel-9-should-you-buy</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Google Pixel 9 comes in four contrasting shades, so it's a tough call when deciding what color you should buy. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">SfqNQVjwX5czfVLt9kUU8k</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5rGfcgtX2rxwXsh6vh5XLJ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 20:00:15 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5rGfcgtX2rxwXsh6vh5XLJ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[All the Google Pixel 9 colors]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[All the Google Pixel 9 colors]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Best Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold screen protectors 2024 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The mighty successor to the Pixel Fold is here and it is a big one. You need the best Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold screen protectors to keep such a large foldable intact and unscathed. Everyday use can cause scratches, nicks, and even bumps on the screen. Only a decent screen guard can thwart such wear and tear.</p><p>Lucky for you, we have gathered all the best screen protectors for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-fold-hands-on">Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold</a> right here. There aren&apos;t internal screen protectors available just yet, but stay tuned because we update this list regularly. As soon as some good options hit the market, we&apos;ll add them here.</p>
<h2 id="protect-and-preserve-your-google-pixel-9-pro-fold-2">Protect and preserve your Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold</h2>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="2d00e32f-c37e-42af-be62-99611cb74d4d">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rs8FWZCvnREpV5vgJY6AnM.jpg' alt="Supershieldz 3 Pack Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold Tempered Glass Screen Protector"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Supershieldz 3 Pack Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold Tempered Glass Screen Protector</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best overall</strong></em></p>
<p>The Supershieldz 3 Pack Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold Tempered Glass Screen Protector is cheap and trustworthy, a great combination. You get three tempered glass screen protectors for the 9 Pro Fold's external screen, each one being hydrophobic, oleophobic, and scratch-proof.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="4f32b258-7120-4677-bf8c-893b50bfb08f">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/S3kT2ZpnDq6H6mGWB28BPn.jpg' alt="IQShield Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold 2-Pack Clear Film"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">IQShield Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold 2-Pack Clear Film</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best film</strong></em></p>
<p>IQShield's Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold 2-Pack Clear Film includes two pieces of high-grade, anti-bubble films that can self-heal from minor scratches and bumps. IQShield gives you a reassuring lifetime replacement warranty, which is fantastic for the price.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="6d5f57fb-3b57-47a3-8336-9c312e195982">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VBGktfab4mascx9Uz2YCTS.jpg' alt="Skinomi Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold 2-Pack Anti-Glare Matte Film"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Skinomi Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold 2-Pack Anti-Glare Matte Film</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best matte</strong></em></p>
<p>Not a fan of glossy screen guards? You'll love the Skinomi Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold 2-Pack Anti-Glare Matte Film. This matte TPU film deflects glare, thwarts fingerprint smudges, and self-heals from tiny abrasions. It's made of a tough military-grade elastic polymer.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="c3d048c6-9e58-4b6c-8ba8-a62bdfbbbb3c">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TLH9ButR5QUxGmEWMEiHd7.jpg' alt="Caseology Snap Fit for Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Caseology Snap Fit for Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best installation frame</strong></em></p>
<p>Caseology's Snap Fit kit for the Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold includes two very high-quality tempered glass units and a comprehensive self-installation frame. You don't have to worry about positioning or bubbles getting under the screen protector thanks to the frame.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="24600578-5cf4-4d69-877b-16ff4b55dfc1">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KQK7AYQ3Q2vjdp4dbCXnwY.jpg' alt="Spigen GlasTR EZ FIT for Pixel 9 Pro Fold - 2 Pack"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Spigen GlasTR EZ FIT for Pixel 9 Pro Fold - 2 Pack</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best case-friendly</strong></em></p>
<p>Spigen makes the best phone cases, so it only makes sense that the brand makes the most case-friendly screen protector for the Pixel 9 Pro Fold. The GlasTR EZ FIT two-pack gives you a duo of durable tempered glass protectors with 9H hardness and an oleophobic coating on top to repel solids and liquids.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="99d08d54-f0f9-445f-b5c9-f903464049fb">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xcPti4BppGrLM8RarNFypH.jpg' alt="DeltaShield Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold Military-Grade Clear TPU Film"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">DeltaShield Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold Military-Grade Clear TPU Film</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best alternative film</strong></em></p>
<p>DeltaShield isn't as well known as some of the other brands in this roundup, but it has great reviews from customers. The Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold Military-Grade Clear TPU Film promises anti-yellowing technology, self-healing capabilities, high clarity, and a fingerprint-repelling coat on top.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<ul><li><a href="#main"><strong>Back to the top ^</strong></a></li></ul>
<h2 id="screen-protecting-is-serious-business-2">Screen protecting is serious business</h2>
<p>The behemoth Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold has two large screens. While you do get factory-installed screen protectors out of the box, the external one isn&apos;t good enough for everyday use. It&apos;s best to replace that with a durable screen guard of your choosing, be it glass or plastic. If you&apos;re not a fan of the thickness of glass, TPU films are excellent alternatives.</p><p>That being said, nothing can beat the durability and toughness of glass, which is why the Supershieldz 3 Pack Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold Tempered Glass Screen Protector is your best bet overall. This three-pack is extremely affordable, but it doesn&apos;t skimp out on quality. You get scratch-proofing and both hydrophobic as well as oleophobic coatings to repel solid and liquid particles. This keeps your Pixel 9 Pro Fold&apos;s display neat and clean.</p><p>Once you&apos;ve picked the right from the best Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold screen protectors, the next step of protecting your device involves more coverage. Invest in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-google-pixel-9-pro-fold-cases">good phone case for your Pixel 9 Pro Fold</a> to prevent dirt from getting in the hinge or scratching up its body.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-google-pixel-9-pro-fold-screen-protectors</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Good news! The best Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold screen protectors are cheap as chips and readily available. Here are the best ones. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">rYA6nriv3dBwCUDJyKzb7a</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FGpDTKpipC2U464JTXWyCb.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 19:30:52 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FGpDTKpipC2U464JTXWyCb.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Split-screen prompt on Pixel 9 Pro Fold]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Split-screen prompt on Pixel 9 Pro Fold]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Best Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold cases 2024 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The best Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold cases elevate the look of the foldable that only comes in two shades, namely Porcelain and Obsidian. It also makes perfect sense to want to protect your nearly two thousand dollar investment with a sturdy protective cover.</p><p>Most of the cases for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-fold-hands-on">Pixel 9 Pro Fold</a> are expensive because crafting a phone cover for a foldable is tricky. It requires a lot of clever engineering and design, and the case also needs to be made of high-quality materials. Fortunately, you can manage to get a very good Pixel 9 Pro Fold case for about $40 if you&apos;re super tight on budget. Let&apos;s look at all your best options, from the high-end options to the budget-friendly picks.</p>
<h2 id="check-out-all-the-best-pixel-9-pro-fold-cases-2">Check out all the best Pixel 9 Pro Fold cases</h2>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="161678fa-d87c-4523-ac21-464f27a842fe">
            <a href="https://www.mous.co/collections/google-pixel-cases" data-model-name="null"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oF7mGG24RMBgdpZfpMCk56.jpg' alt="MOUS Super Thin for Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold"></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">MOUS Super Thin for Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best overall</strong></em></p>
<p>MOUS is a high-end British smartphone accessory maker. We've tested several of their cases over the years and the quality is always top-notch. MOUS worked with Google to make the Super Thin series even thinner for the Pixel 9 Pro Fold and to ensure the case's colors compliment the phone's colorways. The durable material and raised edges add impact absorption to the device.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="105b5220-a1d5-468f-8155-7f99e9b46480">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CoNZ8LK5Gv7vn9RRRf9VQ7.jpg' alt="Spigen Ultra Hybrid for Pixel 9 Pro Fold"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Spigen Ultra Hybrid for Pixel 9 Pro Fold</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best clear</strong></em></p>
<p>Spigen releases the Ultra Hybrid case with every launch, and the Pixel 9 Pro Fold was not left out. This basic clear case employs anti-yellowing technology, showcases the design of your foldable without endangering the device, and promises robust scratch and drop-proofing.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="06b9d245-3a56-483b-9961-a5070b9aa807">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gs9gKZqjjxMAhgZq2nK8nL.jpg' alt="Poetic Spartan Case for Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Poetic Spartan Case for Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best rugged</strong></em></p>
<p>Forget about bumps and scrapes, you could drop your Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold directly on the pavement and it still wouldn't break with the Poetic Spartan Case on. Apart from boasting military-grade drop protection, it also adds a sturdy stand and a built-in screen guard.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="01518d15-c6aa-4595-adbf-3c3866b35033">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xzPnqRoByYJDHzNfyaag7f.jpg' alt="Thinborne Pixel 9 Pro Fold Case"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Thinborne Pixel 9 Pro Fold Case</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best thin</strong></em></p>
<p>Don't add even more weight to the already-hefty Pixel foldable. With the ultra-slim Thinborne Pixel 9 Pro Fold Case, you get MagSafe support, decent shock absorption, and raised edges for drop protection. Despite being light and slim, the case is durable since it's made of robust 600D aramid fiber.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="f3781d38-ae38-4d15-ac57-a9b56ff9be42">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JCYedpLBEHJVFEpxkEzRUC.jpg' alt="TORRO Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold Leather Wallet Case"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">TORRO Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold Leather Wallet Case</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best wallet</strong></em></p>
<p>Nobody does premium wallets like TORRO. The brand's Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold Leather Wallet Case is made of top-grain genuine leather which ages over time. You don't need me to tell you how classy aged leather looks. The wallet folio has plenty of slots and it can also prop up the phone to act as a stand.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="2d1abdfe-c818-4ab3-9b6b-9313cfc1d0b3">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sWH5qs9jQFFGsBr8y3VkHR.jpg' alt="TUDIA MergeGrip Magsafe Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold Case"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">TUDIA MergeGrip Magsafe Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold Case</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best non-slip</strong></em></p>
<p>TUDIA's MergeGrip Magsafe Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold Case comes in just the one matte black hue. It has a dotted matrix-like texture on the back that adds a good amount of friction, preventing slips and falls. The bezels are raised to prevent damage from drops and it has MagSafe support baked in.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<ul><li><a href="#main"><strong>Back to the top ^</strong></a></li></ul>
<h2 id="it-apos-s-hard-to-choose-just-one-pixel-9-pro-fold-case-with-so-many-great-options-around-2">It&apos;s hard to choose just one Pixel 9 Pro Fold case with so many great options around</h2>
<p>Choosing only one of the best Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold cases to take home with you can be challenging. Identify your needs first and then match the right case to them. This will help you find the perfect protective case for your Pixel 9 Pro Fold.</p><p>If you value drop protection, aesthetics, and a narrow waistline, MOUS is the all-around champion. The British case maker has brought its popular Super Thin lineup to the latest Pixel foldable. You get two shades to choose from, both of which correspond with the Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold&apos;s own color variants. This was intentional and curated in collaboration with Google, so you just know that the shade match will be phenomenal. The MOUS Super Thin for Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold is protective, stylish, and priced under $50, making it our best overall recommendation.</p><p>If you don&apos;t mind splurging a bit more to be able to use <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-magsafe-accessories-for-android-phones">cool MagSafe accessories for Android</a> with your Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold, check out the Thinborne Pixel 9 Pro Fold Case. It&apos;s pricey, but the quality of materials used is unmatched, especially in such a sleek form factor.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-google-pixel-9-pro-fold-cases</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Take care of your foldable the right way with the best Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold cases. We've rounded up all your best bets right here in this guide. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">WZuGk8mJFbgPY34tsNZPg</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LWRsKw7Bx2b9Y5iKr6ox6f.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 19:00:07 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LWRsKw7Bx2b9Y5iKr6ox6f.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Pixel 9 Pro Fold with Pixel Watch 3 and Pixel Buds Pro 2]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Pixel 9 Pro Fold with Pixel Watch 3 and Pixel Buds Pro 2]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Best Google Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro cases 2024 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>All the best Google Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro cases are one and the same. How come, you ask? Well, that&apos;s because these devices sport the exact same shells despite having different innards. While the Pixel 9 Pro has superior hardware, its body dimensions are exactly the same as the Pixel 9. This makes the business of choosing a good phone cover for your Google Pixel 9 or Pixel 9 Pro a lot easier.</p><p>Here is a versatile collection of all the best cases that will fit your 6.3-inch <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-series-hands-on">Pixel 9 or 9 Pro</a> like a glove. Small phones like these are lightweight, and these cases keep it that way. Even if you&apos;re mega clumsy and suffer from an incurable case of butterfingers, even the thinnest of these cases will protect your Pixel from bumps, drops, nicks, and scrapes.</p>
<h2 id="get-the-right-case-for-your-pixel-9-or-pixel-9-pro-2">Get the right case for your Pixel 9 or Pixel 9 Pro</h2>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="53d1388a-44ae-40a1-a033-dfdabfef935d">
            <a href="https://www.quadlockcase.net/pixel9" data-model-name="Quad Lock MAG Case for Google Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AHr77tcedoK9oD5ygRTY7i.jpg' alt="Quad Lock MAG Case for Google Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro"></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Quad Lock MAG Case for Google Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best overall</strong></em></p>
<p>Google didn't give us Qi2 with the Pixel 9, so it's time to take matters into our own hands. The spectacular <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/magsafe-phone-case-with-bottle-opener">Quad Lock MAG Case</a> is magnetic on the back and supports a host of cool modular accessories to go with it, including a bottle opener slash phone grip. The non-slip matte black texture looks and feels epic and you get great impact absorption.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="cdde61d9-9e44-4b3d-afbf-c1e9984e0fdb">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mwaUnsTR4jgmcpPx64ZKaM.jpg' alt="Caseology Nano Pop for Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Caseology Nano Pop for Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best matte</strong></em></p>
<p>True to its name, the Caseology Nano Pop case for the Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro offers a pop of color with its monochrome back and contrastingly bright accents. This military-grade drop-proof case barely adds anything to your phone and bears an amicable under-$20 price tag.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="c3c53e02-4154-42bf-b49b-d695398c6005">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/R5PgVJDHW6nrVhDG8FHq7T.jpg' alt="Thinborne Pixel 9 Pro and Pixel 9 Case"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Thinborne Pixel 9 Pro and Pixel 9 Case</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best thin</strong></em></p>
<p>Thinborne's signature 600D aramid fiber case boasts MagSafe compatibility for all your magnetic stands and grips. At 0.04 inches thin, it is impossibly slim, almost like a coat of paint. You also get a 6.3-inch tempered glass screen protector for your Pixel 9 or 9 Pro in the box.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="89d93a50-7b10-42c1-80f1-1dd40d106c36">
            <a href="dbrand.com/pixel-9-series-cases" data-model-name="null"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vVkxCc2biGsu5QDzDGUPhJ.jpg' alt="Dbrand Grip Case for Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro"></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Dbrand Grip Case for Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best grippy sides</strong></em></p>
<p>Dbrand's Grip Case for the Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro comes in all of its amazing patterns and colors. You get grippy scored sides, raised edges for drop protection, and an enhanced camera bump to protect it even more. This slim case allows for uninterrupted wireless charging.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="14b4d6a9-3edb-4b4d-9bc5-5d18359649a3">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/K85eD3Cz9k3U8mAjSHAWnm.jpg' alt="JETech Magnetic Case for Google Pixel 9/9 Pro"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">JETech Magnetic Case for Google Pixel 9/9 Pro</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best cheap</strong></em></p>
<p>You won't believe how cheap this case is judging by its features and appearance. The JETech Magnetic Case for Google's Pixel 9 and 9 Pro devices costs just $15 and yet it brings you MagSafe support, lanyard holes, a smokey translucent back, and a highly shockproof polycarbonate build.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="48ecee5e-5f96-4b6f-a754-cf4df3e54916">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BF72oH2FBtSCaEKZP5YwZ4.jpg' alt="Spigen Rugged Armor for Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Spigen Rugged Armor for Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best rugged</strong></em></p>
<p>Looking for something tough and unbreaking? The Spigen Rugged Armor is the best rugged cover for the Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro. It's quite sleek for a tough case, but you still get military-grade impact protection. Spigen's the most trustable name in the biz, so you don't have to worry one bit about that claim.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="0d1e99d0-410e-456e-9466-214243ed8743">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fX4dWuwFx9wy7pJsrN2Edf.jpg' alt="TUDIA MergeGrip Magsafe Google Pixel 9 / Pixel 9 Pro Case"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">TUDIA MergeGrip Magsafe Google Pixel 9 / Pixel 9 Pro Case</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best non-slip texture</strong></em></p>
<p>TUDIA makes two versions of this case, a magnetic and non-magnetic one, but the MergeGrip Magsafe Google Pixel 9 / Pixel 9 Pro Case is the better pick. It comes in five colors and sports a dotted anti-slip texture. The robust case itself is designed to absorb impacts well.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="223ca502-2bab-4501-b67c-a262bdefd46c">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Z8aUM3V8ppBmkgLvgeV5Kh.jpg' alt="Poetic Guardian MagPro Case for Google Pixel 9/9 Pro"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Poetic Guardian MagPro Case for Google Pixel 9/9 Pro</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best MagSafe</strong></em></p>
<p>Poetic's Guardian MagPro Case comes with a resilient bumper frame, a built-in screen guard on the front, a MagSafe ring baked into the back, and a see-through backside that shows off the colorway of your Google Pixel 9 or Pixel 9 Pro.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="2e7a1fae-07ab-4c87-8c37-183f27ed27ae">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/o4QLt8jiHhfM7gobFWP6vF.jpg' alt="TORRAS Magnetic & Stand Google Pixel 9 / 9 Pro Case"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">TORRAS Magnetic & Stand Google Pixel 9 / 9 Pro Case</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best with stand</strong></em></p>
<p>TORRAS keeps 'em coming, relentlessly pushing out fantastic clear cases one after another. The TORRAS Magnetic & Stand Google Pixel 9 / 9 Pro Case is just as good as the rest, promising up to 12-feet drop protection adhering to military standards, an in-built MagSafe ring, and a nifty little clip on the rear that's actually a stand.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<ul><li><a href="#main"><strong>Back to the top ^</strong></a></li></ul>
<h2 id="how-to-choose-the-best-google-pixel-9-and-pixel-9-pro-case-2">How to choose the best Google Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro case</h2>
<p>Small phones like the Google Pixel 9 and 9 Pro are easier to carry around, use one-handed, and store in pockets. To match that, the best Google Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro cases offer a blend of durability, style, thinness, and practicality. You maintain the small and lightweight footprint of your Pixel while adding protection as well as functionality.</p><p>The best overall case for the Google Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro is the Quad Lock MAG Case. It doesn&apos;t cost as much as some other high-quality branded phone cases, but you get superb build quality and unique features. I <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/magsafe-phone-case-with-bottle-opener">tested it out for my Pixel 8</a> and was pleasantly surprised with the matte body of the cover. It both feels and looks phenomenal, plus you get MagSafe compatibility and support for Quad Lock&apos;s other modular add-ons. This includes bike mounts, kickstands, tripods, phone grips, and more. The raised bezels add a comforting amount of drop protection, and the magnetic back lets you use almost any <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-magsafe-accessories-for-android-phones" target="_blank">great MagSafe accessory</a>.</p><p>If you want something even more lightweight and slimmer, almost half of the other cases on this list will suffice. However, Thinborne knocks the competition out of the park when it comes to thinness. The MagSafe case doesn&apos;t even compromise drop protection thanks to the high-grade 600D aramid fiber build. And you don&apos;t have to worry about buying a screen protector for your Pixel 9 or 9 Pro either because Thinborne gives you a tempered glass screen protector in the box.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-google-pixel-9-and-pixel-9-pro-cases</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Get the best Google Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro cases to personalize your Pixel, boost its defenses, and enhance its functionality. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">cbFsBRLvUmTVtZ3p8Rn5iN</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6AcWY7myxfTHBsUvqiE7qL.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 18:30:38 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6AcWY7myxfTHBsUvqiE7qL.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Hazel Google Pixel 9 Pro with an official Google case next to the Hazel Google Pixel Buds Pro 2]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Hazel Google Pixel 9 Pro with an official Google case next to the Hazel Google Pixel Buds Pro 2]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ What color Google Pixel 9 Pro or 9 Pro XL should you buy? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The Pixel 9 Pro is basically a beefed-up version of the Pixel 9, sharing nearly identical specs. On the other hand, the Pixel 9 Pro XL brings slightly more significant upgrades over its younger siblings such as a bigger screen and a larger battery. All three Pixel phones share the same Tensor G4 in-house processor.</p><p>Physically speaking, though, the only difference between the 9 Pro and the 9 Pro XL is the size. Since the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-series-hands-on">Google Pixel 9 Pro and Pixel 9 Pro XL</a> are identical in appearance and share the same shades, the colors below are applicable to both models. This guide should help you decide what color Google Pixel 9 Pro or 9 Pro XL you should buy.</p>
<h2 id="twin-siblings-google-pixel-9-pro-and-9-pro-xl-share-the-exact-same-color-options-2">Twin siblings Google Pixel 9 Pro and 9 Pro XL share the exact same color options</h2>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="2e6889b1-b84d-47f8-bb47-a3bb9f7e3f0d">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/B22jKfVHKzg8nbRGgwTHSP.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro official render - Rose Quartz - Front and Back"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Rose Quartz</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Flushed pink</strong></em></p>
<p>Whether you choose the Pixel 9 Pro or Pixel 9 Pro XL, this strawberry milk pink is a stunner. The rosy color instantaneously identifies your Pixel 9 series phone as the Pro or Pro XL model.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="61a6f4fd-4e98-4b38-b254-eb791a155441">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bES27Em9ivhDZB88WYAtKk.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL official render - Hazel - front and back"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Hazel</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Gray-green tones</strong></em></p>
<p>Hazel is a classic Pixel color and it looks just as charming on the Pixel 9 Pro and 9 Pro XL as it did on earlier models. The muted green tint isn't as prominent as the Pixel 9's minty Wintergreen variant.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="2df42cb6-d6d0-4895-a745-869529e0d125">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/UD8dzz6ZtqsbyAGYpz4DtN.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro official render - Obsidian - Front and back"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Obsidian</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Timeless classic</strong></em></p>
<p>Black is black, enough said. You can't go wrong with Obsidian, an ashy black shade with shiny dark gray accents. If nothing pleases you, this color will suffice.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="bd3821e2-9bae-423f-a8f7-ec534b16ef05">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/T8WTnYRAhZw6DGua2jptsk.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL official render - Porcelain - front and back"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Porcelain</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>So fancy</strong></em></p>
<p>This luxurious hue of beige always looks more expensive for some reason. If you like to flaunt, get a Pixel 9 Pro or Pixel 9 Pro XL in this fancy cream color called Porcelain.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<ul><li><a href="#main"><strong>Back to the top ^</strong></a></li></ul>
<h2 id="picking-the-right-color-of-the-google-pixel-9-pro-or-9-pro-xl-2">Picking the right color of the Google Pixel 9 Pro or 9 Pro XL</h2>
<p>When wondering what color Google Pixel 9 Pro or 9 Pro XL you should buy, the first thing you should think about is your favorite color. If you don&apos;t immediately take a liking to any of the four shades, you can consider your existing devices such as your earbuds and smartwatch.</p><p>Google refreshed two more lineups along with the Pixel 9 family of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phones</a>. If you&apos;re upgrading your companion devices or purchasing them for the first time, consider the color of the Pixel Watch 3 and the Pixel Buds Pro 2 as well as the Pixel 9 Pro or 9 Pro XL. Depending on the aesthetics of the entire ecosystem, you could go for a unified color palette across the board.</p><p>For instance, I&apos;d pick the pink hues for all my Pixel gear because it&apos;s splashy and unique to this launch. Thus, I&apos;d choose the Google Pixel 9 Pro or 9 Pro XL in Rose Quartz, the Pixel Watch 3 in Polished Silver Aluminum with a Rose Quartz Active Band, and the Pixel Buds Pro 2 in Peony.</p><p>Lastly, you should also consider the aftercare when choosing the color of your tech. Lighter shades like Porcelain will get dirty faster, thus requiring more frequent cleaning.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-color-google-pixel-9-pro-or-9-pro-xl-should-you-buy</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Both the Google Pixel 9 Pro and Pixel 9 Pro XL come in the exact same colors. Let's mull over which color you should pick. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">UqmESXxomrQHnUhUnEG5a6</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Jeb8Uj55phdW5L57spGKJU.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 18:05:37 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Jeb8Uj55phdW5L57spGKJU.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9 Pro and Google Pixel 9 Pro XL colors]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9 Pro and Google Pixel 9 Pro XL colors]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Best Google Pixel 9 Pro XL cases 2024 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>It&apos;s large, it&apos;s in charge, and it&apos;s anything but subpar. The fabulous new Google flagship deserves only the best Pixel 9 Pro XL cases and we have rounded up all of them right here for your perusal.</p><p>A phone as big as this doesn&apos;t need any more bulk layered on top, which is why the best <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-series-hands-on">Google Pixel 9 Pro XL</a> cases are lightweight yet robust. You can choose a transparent one that showcases the sleek back of your super-sized Pixel, or you can get a fashionable number that adds more pizzazz to the device. The choice is yours, embrace your style and add a ton of cool features to your <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9">Pixel 9 Pro XL</a> with these cases.</p>
<h2 id="all-the-best-pixel-9-pro-xl-cases-for-every-type-of-user-2">All the best Pixel 9 Pro XL cases for every type of user</h2>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="286e4d60-d524-43d7-8a96-c401dcadd164">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kavQ3g6ZWFfV5inZnnkfGU.jpg' alt="TORRAS 360 Spin Magnetic Stand Case for Google Pixel 9 Pro XL"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">TORRAS 360° Spin Magnetic Stand Case for Google Pixel 9 Pro XL</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best overall</strong></em></p>
<p>TORRAS managed to upgrade a perfectly good clear case and made it even better. You get a 360° Spin Magnetic Stand that rotates, propping up the Pixel 9 Pro XL at various angles. This case adds military-grade drop protection and the stand acts as a grip and MagSafe ring.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="6fc42bcc-0fd0-4019-a868-3991335ce40a">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vkvkFj7JgdLXU3eHH3gE6j.jpg' alt="Spigen Slim Armor CS for Pixel 9 Pro XL"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Spigen Slim Armor CS for Pixel 9 Pro XL</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best wallet</strong></em></p>
<p>Eliminate the need to carry your wallet with the Spigen Slim Armor CS for the Pixel 9 Pro XL. This non-traditional wallet cover has a sleek slot on the back that accommodates one or two cards and some cash. You also get rugged impact absorption from this case.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="ed629e5f-8804-4bf0-bf91-291a6627a0e6">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RPXmzNzZdanfuFn7q5mq7T.jpg' alt="Thinborne Pixel 9 Pro XL Case"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Thinborne Pixel 9 Pro XL Case</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best thin case</strong></em></p>
<p>Without a doubt, Thinborne makes the best thin case for the Google Pixel 9 Pro XL. This impossibly slim phone case is made of highly durable 600D aramid fiber and it somehow manages to add MagSafe compatibility to your Pixel. You get a free tempered glass screen protector in the box.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="a970c9a1-a3a7-4cc2-9577-2c06e2105264">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4jK2AJQozC88pYqnyCqyCM.jpg' alt="Poetic Guardian Case for Google Pixel 9 Pro XL"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Poetic Guardian Case for Google Pixel 9 Pro XL</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best bumper cover</strong></em></p>
<p>Poetic promises full frontal protection and robust impact resistance from its military-grade Guardian Case for the Google Pixel 9 Pro XL. Available in several bi-colored frames, this bumper cover shows off the seemingly-naked backside of your Pixel 9 Pro XL without really exposing it.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="7f7373d1-9aa2-4e6f-99b3-4aa334dc1dec">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MQMnRpPKxsUCjJUdr4TZWm.jpg' alt="Nillkin Magnetic Google Pixel 9 Pro XL Case"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Nillkin Magnetic Google Pixel 9 Pro XL Case</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best grip</strong></em></p>
<p>Nillkin's cases are super affordable, but they don't look cheap. The brand's Magnetic Google Pixel 9 Pro XL Case is a slim outfit with a textured back, adding more grip. It's made of dual TPU and PC layers for drop protection, you get lanyard holes on the side to add straps, and there's a MagSafe ring built into it.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="697aaea1-566e-4f3c-bc95-9db038240213">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7YcJKhw5Fi4NTSfGRWzMsW.jpg' alt="Mous Intralock Phone Case for Google Pixel 9 Pro XL"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Mous Intralock Phone Case for Google Pixel 9 Pro XL</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best customizable</strong></em></p>
<p>The Mous Intralock Phone Case is a modular accessory for your Google Pixel 9 Pro XL. The case itself is fabulous and supports MagSafe, but you can turn it up a notch and buy the brand's Intralock add-ons like a bike mount or selfie stick to get the most use out of it.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<ul><li><a href="#main"><strong>Back to the top ^</strong></a></li></ul>
<h2 id="a-device-of-the-pixel-9-pro-xl-apos-s-proportions-needs-low-profile-protection-2">A device of the Pixel 9 Pro XL&apos;s proportions needs low-profile protection</h2>
<p>The gigantic 6.8-inch Pixel 9 Pro XL needs 360-degree protection, but you can&apos;t get a case that bulks it up. A large device such as this is heavier than average, so any thicker phone case will just make it more difficult to carry. This is why the best Pixel 9 Pro XL maintain a narrow waistline.</p><p>Just because a phone cover is thin doesn&apos;t mean that it can&apos;t be protective or highly practical. TORRAS presents a prime example of this with its 360° Spin Magnetic Stand Case for the Google Pixel 9 Pro XL. This slender, smokey, and translucent Pixel case adds a dark tint to your phone. It&apos;s a very thin case that boasts military-grade drop protection. The magnetic ring on the back can act as both a stand as well as a grip for your phone. And, of course, you can use all the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-magsafe-accessories-for-android-phones">coolest MagSafe accessories for Android</a> with it.</p><p>TORRAS offers various versions of its case for the Pixel 9 Pro XL, but this is the ideal model for the 9 Pro XL. It&apos;s not pricey, adds MagSafe compatibility, looks sleek, and has a reliable, spinning kickstand that can serve many purposes, therefore making it the best Pixel 9 Pro XL case overall.</p><p>Once you&apos;re done picking the most suitable Pixel 9 Pro XL cover for your needs, be sure to grab a screen protector for it as well.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-google-pixel-9-pro-xl-cases</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The best Pixel 9 Pro XL cases don't play around. They're lean, mean, handy machines with both form and function. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">qnW2whz3ysxGdBbovujjjf</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yspK7pv8BEg6duoL6rWwaN.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 17:40:15 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yspK7pv8BEg6duoL6rWwaN.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[TORRAS]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[TORRAS 360° Spin Magnetic Stand Case for Google Pixel 9 Pro XL]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[TORRAS 360° Spin Magnetic Stand Case for Google Pixel 9 Pro XL]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The best Google Pixel Watch 3 preorder deals — how to buy and what to expect ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>It&apos;s been less than a year since Google&apos;s last smartwatch hit store shelves, and yet we&apos;re already witnessing the arrival of the new Google Pixel Watch 3. Whether you want to buy the new wearable or you simply have a question about its specs, this guide has everything you need to know about preordering the Google Pixel Watch 3 ahead of its September 10th release date. </p><p>We can already tell that the Google Pixel Watch 3 is going to earn a spot in our list of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch">best Android smartwatches</a> released this year. The versatile wearable boasts butter-smooth Wear OS software with a sleek, water droplet-inspired design and all of the intelligent health and fitness tracking technology you could ever need. The Pixel Watch 3 is also available in two sizes, 41mm and 45mm (with an accompanying increase in battery size for the larger model).</p><p>There aren&apos;t too many preorder offers on the Pixel Watch 3 just yet, but I&apos;ll keep adding new deals throughout the day. If you don&apos;t see anything enticing right now, check back in a few hours to see what&apos;s new. </p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-quick-links"><span>Quick links</span></h3>
<ul><li><strong>Google Store: </strong><a href="https://store.google.com/us/product/pixel_watch_3"><strong>up to $350 off with eligible smartwatch trade-in</strong></a><strong> </strong></li><li><strong>Verizon: </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/connected-smartwatches/google-pixel-watch-3/"><strong>save $270 with select smartphone purchase</strong></a><strong><br>
</strong><br>
<em>(More preorder deals will be added shortly) <br>
</em><br>
<strong>Made by Google 2024 coverage</strong></li><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-3-hands-on"><strong>Google Pixel Watch 3 hands-on review</strong></a></li><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-series-hands-on"><strong>Google Pixel 9 hands-on review</strong></a></li><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-series-hands-on"><strong>Google Pixel 9 Pro hands-on review</strong></a></li><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-fold-hands-on"><strong>Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold hands-on review</strong></a></li></ul>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-google-pixel-watch-3-deals"><span>Google Pixel Watch 3 deals</span></h3>
<p><em><strong>Note:</strong></em><em> Preorder deals will continue to go live throughout the day, so check back later if your retailer-of-choice isn&apos;t advertising its offer yet.</em></p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="c8ba5c01-3989-4b80-a9d0-6b7822b68d44" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Store: up to $350 off with trade-in" data-dimension48="Google Store: up to $350 off with trade-in" href="https://store.google.com/us/product/pixel_watch_3" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="YhuEfbCAEWusKVmLh7X3vh" name="google-store.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YhuEfbCAEWusKVmLh7X3vh.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="500" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Google Store: </strong><a href="https://store.google.com/us/product/pixel_watch_3" data-dimension112="c8ba5c01-3989-4b80-a9d0-6b7822b68d44" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Store: up to $350 off with trade-in" data-dimension48="Google Store: up to $350 off with trade-in"><strong>up to $350 off with trade-in</strong></a></p>
<p>Dig up an old smartwatch and send it to Google and the company will give you up to $350 of trade-in credit when you buy the Pixel Watch 3. That could make the 41mm watch free if you play your cards right! Like all Pixel watches, you'll also get six months of Fitbit Premium for free with your purchase. </p>
<p>In addition to the trade-in discount, Google is stating that they will also cover your data for two years when you buy the LTE version of the watch (via Google Fi Wireless).<a class="view-deal button" href="https://store.google.com/us/product/pixel_watch_3" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="c8ba5c01-3989-4b80-a9d0-6b7822b68d44" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Store: up to $350 off with trade-in" data-dimension48="Google Store: up to $350 off with trade-in">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="d3bcf410-f7ea-468d-b2e8-c02cdd2a437f" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Verizon: save $270 with select smartphone purchase" data-dimension48="Verizon: save $270 with select smartphone purchase" href="https://www.verizon.com/connected-smartwatches/google-pixel-watch-3/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3321px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:40.98%;"><img id="HBqRvBgPimq99uDCsr2Mgj" name="Verizon-2024-logo.png" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HBqRvBgPimq99uDCsr2Mgj.png" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3321" height="1361" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Verizon: </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/connected-smartwatches/google-pixel-watch-3/" data-dimension112="d3bcf410-f7ea-468d-b2e8-c02cdd2a437f" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Verizon: save $270 with select smartphone purchase" data-dimension48="Verizon: save $270 with select smartphone purchase"><strong>save $270 with select smartphone purchase</strong></a></p>
<p>Bundle your Pixel Watch 3 preorder with the purchase of an eligible 5G smartphone at Verizon and the carrier will hook you up with $270 off, no trade-in required. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.verizon.com/connected-smartwatches/google-pixel-watch-3/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="d3bcf410-f7ea-468d-b2e8-c02cdd2a437f" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Verizon: save $270 with select smartphone purchase" data-dimension48="Verizon: save $270 with select smartphone purchase">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="37522eb9-6645-49b3-8d74-cabff81e8a5c" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Amazon: 90 days of Amazon Music Unlimited" data-dimension48="Amazon: 90 days of Amazon Music Unlimited" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D912SM96/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="BtHJYArVipn2USEACJFFAC" name="Amazon-Logo.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BtHJYArVipn2USEACJFFAC.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="500" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Amazon: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D912SM96/" data-dimension112="37522eb9-6645-49b3-8d74-cabff81e8a5c" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Amazon: 90 days of Amazon Music Unlimited" data-dimension48="Amazon: 90 days of Amazon Music Unlimited"><strong>90 days of Amazon Music Unlimited</strong></a></p>
<p>Amazon isn't exactly offering a preorder deal at this time, but the retailer <em>will </em>give you a free three-month subscription to Amazon Music Unlimited when you buy the smartwatch through its site (a $33 value). It's not much, but it's something!<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D912SM96/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="37522eb9-6645-49b3-8d74-cabff81e8a5c" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Amazon: 90 days of Amazon Music Unlimited" data-dimension48="Amazon: 90 days of Amazon Music Unlimited">View Deal</a></p></div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/the-best-google-pixel-watch-3-preorder-deals-how-to-buy-and-what-to-expect</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google just unveiled the Pixel Watch 3, a versatile wearable that's sure to rank among the best Android smartwatches of the year. Here's how to buy.   ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">uPsNBRVN3GaTfhKuQKncF8</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mGLzjZMRguzt5mXNtbL5EY.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 17:37:09 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mGLzjZMRguzt5mXNtbL5EY.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Exercise days in Morning Brief on Pixel Watch 3]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Exercise days in Morning Brief on Pixel Watch 3]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ What color Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold should you buy? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Google has rebranded its Fold moniker and merged it into the regular flagship family of Pixels with the 9 series. The Pixel 9 Pro Fold looks sleek and modern, but the made-by-Google foldable only comes in two unimaginative color options. Can&apos;t make up your mind about the Pixel 9 Pro Fold&apos;s colorways? Here&apos;s a look at both variants and factors you should weigh before making your choice.</p>
<h2 id="check-out-the-noir-look-of-the-pixel-9-pro-fold-2">Check out the noir look of the Pixel 9 Pro Fold</h2>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="84607041-6875-457f-9bfc-2ebe6ca488de">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4SRrae3JE5zTqDJQU2qtne.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold Official Render - Obsidian - Unfolded"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold - Obsidian</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The dark side</strong></em></p>
<p>Google packed some mighty specs into the Pixel 9 Pro Fold, but the color options leave you wanting more. Getting the black Obsidian variant is a no-brainer. It looks cool and stays clean.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="ce83fcc8-6adb-41e9-831d-78ac80413663">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7nEJ4MLpp4jMPGiG3yvSmf.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold Official Render - Porcelain - Unfolded"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold - Porcelain</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The light side</strong></em></p>
<p>Is your heart set on this creamy, luxurious shade of beige? Porcelain isn't for the weak of heart, because it will get dirty faster than Obsidian. But if you're okay with that, go ahead and choose this colorway.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<ul><li><a href="#main"><strong>Back to the top ^</strong></a></li></ul>
<h2 id="there-are-only-two-google-pixel-9-pro-fold-colorways-so-the-decision-is-easy-to-make-2">There are only two Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold colorways, so the decision is easy to make</h2>
<p>Porcelain and Obsidian have been neutrals color staples across the board for Google&apos;s physical products. You can get earbuds, smartwatches, and tablets in said colors from Google to match your foldable. Other devices usually have a third and sometimes a fourth option, but the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-fold-hands-on">Pixel Fold successor</a> only comes in these B&W hues. So when it comes to the Pixel 9 Pro Fold, which color should you buy?</p><p>Black is the safest option in my opinion, and also the easiest to take care of in the long run. Can you imagine all the dust, dirt, fingerprints, scratches, and scrapes that are caused by everyday use on a light-colored phone? The marks will definitely show, which is why Porcelain isn&apos;t the best hue to consider. Unless you&apos;re sure you understand the effort that goes into taking care of such a color variant, get the dark Obsidian shade of the Pixel 9 Pro Fold.</p><p>If you&apos;re bent on getting the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">excellent foldable</a> from Google in the light beige option, get a good Pixel 9 Pro Fold case, preferably something with a microfiber lining inside to protect the body of the device.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-color-google-pixel-9-pro-fold-should-you-buy</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Pixel 9 Pro Fold only comes in two colors. Let us help you decide which one to buy. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">d3YT7CV7WeDkifNJpNp8GB</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dPHS7ToxXWxjAPZJAXRNTm.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 17:25:14 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dPHS7ToxXWxjAPZJAXRNTm.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>