<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 16:23:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Spotify is testing personalized AI playlists you can make with text prompts ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Spotify has introduced AI Playlist, which is currently in beta, allowing users to build playlists by typing a few words.</li><li>Users can use pre-made prompts provided by Spotify or create their own unique prompts to generate playlists.</li><li>The feature is initially accessible in the UK and Australia on Android and iOS devices, with plans for expansion to other countries.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Spotify is joining the AI trend like many other companies, introducing AI Playlist, which helps you make playlists with just a few text prompts to capture the vibe you&apos;re after.</p><p>The new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/spotify">Spotify</a> feature, currently in beta, allows you to build a playlist by typing a few words, similar to how you&apos;d interact with a large language model like ChatGPT or Gemini. It&apos;s still in the testing phase, so expect some rough patches along the way, as per Spotify&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://newsroom.spotify.com/2024-04-07/spotify-premium-users-can-now-turn-any-idea-into-a-personalized-playlist-with-ai-playlist-in-beta/" target="_blank">announcement</a>.</p><p>Spotify gives you some fun ideas to get started with AI Playlist, like "an indie folk playlist to give my brain a big warm hug" and "relaxing music to tide me over during allergy season." But feel free to get creative and come up with your own unique prompts.</p><p>Spotify has safeguards in place to prevent offensive prompts, although the specific details of these measures are not yet clear.</p><p>Once you enter a text prompt, Spotify&apos;s advanced AI model will search through its vast music library to curate the ideal tracks for you. This feature is exclusively for Premium users and initially accessible in the UK and Australia on both Android and iOS devices. However, it&apos;s expected to roll out to more countries in the next few months.</p><p>To get started, tap the "+" button located in the top-right corner of your library. From there, select "AI Playlist" and pick from existing prompts or make your own. Spotify will whip up the playlist, and you can take a peek or remove tracks. When you&apos;re satisfied, hit "Create," and your playlist will be saved to your library.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:768px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:50.00%;"><img id="SXFDbQ5bUVi3ZkfLtysMYC" name="spotify-AI-playlist.jpg" alt="Spotify AI playlist" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SXFDbQ5bUVi3ZkfLtysMYC.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="768" height="384" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Spotify)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>This builds upon <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/spotify-ai-dj-curated-music">Spotify&apos;s beloved AI-powered DJ feature</a>, which curates music just for you. This new feature is like that DJ voice that chats between songs, but instead of a pre-made playlist, you tell it what kind of music you want with a quick message.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-streaming-music-apps-android">music streaming service</a> mentions that the AI playlist can handle prompts related to animals, movie characters, colors, places, activities, and emojis. The platform suggests blending different elements in your prompt to craft the perfect playlist for your mood. If the playlist doesn&apos;t hit the mark, you can fine-tune it by adding more prompts.</p><p>Building playlists can swing from a fun time to a tedious task, depending on why you&apos;re doing it. Sometimes, you might even miss out on the perfect songs simply because you haven&apos;t heard them yet. But with Spotify&apos;s AI Playlist, your choices just got a whole lot wider.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/spotify-launches-personalized-ai-playlists</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Spotify now lets you make playlists by just telling it what kind of vibe you're looking for. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">QFzYk4MKuS9VPVdjv9fEET</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nS4bjbyKmiSYtyq4VFAYJF.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 16:16:44 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nS4bjbyKmiSYtyq4VFAYJF.jpeg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Spotify Premium on an Android phone.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Spotify Premium on an Android phone.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Best phone tripod 2024 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The best phone tripod isn&apos;t just for DSLR and mirrorless cameras. Tripods can also play a pivotal role in mobile photography. Some of the best tripods will even help you better capture scenes in the brightest or darkest conditions for any phone you attach to them. This guide will help you find the right fit for you so you can compose the most stunning images.</p><p>Sensyne&apos;s 10&apos;&apos; Ring Light with 50&apos;&apos; Extendable Tripod Stand offers the best traditional tripod functionality made for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-camera">phones to shoot pictures with</a>. if you&apos;re looking for smaller, more portable form factors, there are loads of excellent alternatives and they all are reasonably priced. You can even score a phone tripod with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-magsafe-accessories-for-android-phones">MagSafe compatibility</a>.</p>
<h2 id="add-a-level-of-finesse-to-your-mobile-photography-with-these-tripods-2">Add a level of finesse to your mobile photography with these tripods</h2>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="680f3053-c6e6-4998-89f7-7fecaf588c29">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FjAURmm5QCmbyCXgXhdtBE.jpg' alt='Sensyne 10'' Ring Light with 50'' Extendable Tripod Stand'><span class='featured__label hero__label'>Staff pick</span></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Sensyne 10'' Ring Light with 50'' Extendable Tripod Stand</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best overall</strong></em></p>
<p>Sensyne offers an extremely versatile range of budget-friendly tripods. The 10'' Ring Light with 50'' Extendable Tripod Stand is ideal for mobile phone users as it comes with a ring light, remote control, and adjustable stand that goes from 10 inches to 50 inches in a jiffy. For a few more dollars, you can get the RGB light version.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="9cae7fd2-0c16-4c30-9d81-5beb9445106a">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uF65dbXBpBMeAkrDDNNwjF.jpg' alt='UBeesize 67inch Phone Tripod Selfie Stick'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">UBeesize 67" Phone Tripod & Selfie Stick</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best extra-long</strong></em></p>
<p>If you need a really tall tripod for your photography, try the extra-long UBeesize 67" Phone Tripod & Selfie Stick for size. This 67-inch accessory doubles as a selfie stick, has a remote, has an adjustable height, and has a very stable clamp for your phone.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="5c880451-0e24-4b10-854c-430705f8b491">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PQbw4ijMaLeuRNRUfbh7Zj.jpg' alt='JOBY GorillaPod Starter Kit'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">JOBY GorillaPod Starter Kit</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best flexible</strong></em></p>
<p>JOBY is a really famous name in the photography world. The brand makes superb camera accessories. You'll enjoy your experience with the GorillaPod Starter Kit, which comes with a flexible mini tripod and a handful of mounting accessories. The legs are so malleable, you can twist them around a tree branch and still get stable shots.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="1794d263-6ca7-4739-953a-cc50b92075cd">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/beVWRrESFtoBvk3PukTYuN.jpg' alt='TODI 63" Portable Selfie Stick Tripod'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">TODI 63" Portable Selfie Stick Tripod</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best portable</strong></em></p>
<p>This highly-rated selfie stick can be extended up to 63 inches long. It's a very compact tripod with a tiny remote. You can easily adjust the height. For such a tall phone tripod, it is extremely compact when folded up so it packs light and is ideal for vacations and trips.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="8224f38a-de1b-4c79-b69a-723eb56a8d0e">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TNYytZMJFz7J3nC9U5RiNc.jpg' alt='andobil MagStick Selfie Stick Tripod'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">andobil MagStick Selfie Stick Tripod</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best MagSafe</strong></em></p>
<p>It's expensive, but the andobil MagStick Selfie Stick Tripod is the ideal tripod for MagSafe lovers. All you need is a MagSafe phone case or adapter ring for Android and you can use this compact and convenient magnetic tripod cum selfie stick anywhere you go. Plus, it has a remote built-in.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="fccaeba1-76fa-4788-af9a-448c02d57370">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BUh8rS5DXAKYwfdGZXT3QG.jpg' alt='Aureday Flexible Tripod'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Aureday Flexible Tripod</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best budget</strong></em></p>
<p>On a very tight budget? No problem! The tiny yet mighty Aureday Flexible Tripod is super affordable, coming in well below the $20 mark. You get flexible legs, a clamp, a remote control for long-distance shots, and three colors to choose from.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<ul><li><a href="#main"><strong>Back to the top ^</strong></a></li></ul>
<h2 id="make-your-phone-apos-s-photos-and-videos-look-professional-2">Make your phone&apos;s photos and videos look professional</h2>
<p>Finding the right phone tripod really boils down to what it is you&apos;re trying to achieve. More seasoned mobile photographers will probably have figured that out going in, but sometimes, creative opportunity knocks when you least expect it. That&apos;s why this list is varied. The Sensyne 10&apos;&apos; Ring Light with 50&apos;&apos; Extendable Tripod Stand is the best option for most situations and with a wide range of phones.</p>
<p>And if you don&apos;t want the clamp anymore, you can always attach another. Even when closed, the tripod acts as a decent handheld stabilizer. It doesn&apos;t have flexible legs, or a Frankenstein-like rig to attach supporting gear, but it&apos;s well-made, dependable, and can work with many DSLR and mirrorless cameras in addition to your phone.</p>
<p>Good and supportive gear can always help take better photos, but you should look into learning some of the fundamentals of using your phone&apos;s camera first. You can level up your mobile photography game with a few simple tips and tricks, which we have compiled in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/gadget-weekly-mobile-photography-tips-and-tricks">handy guide</a> of sorts for beginners. It also helps to have the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-third-party-camera-app-android" data-original-url="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-third-party-camera-app-android">best camera app</a> on your Android phone so you have all the right tools to capture world-class images.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/best-phone-tripod</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The best phone tripods are made to help you capture scenes in the brightest or darkest conditions. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">ce4NPUBuR2KTnxQgdJwN4Z</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YMvVgUU88VjBjiHjNK8NYE.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 14:29:02 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YMvVgUU88VjBjiHjNK8NYE.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Ubeesize]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Ubeesize S]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Ubeesize S]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ How to view your Android notification history ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Having a notification history on your Android device is very helpful. If you accidentally dismiss a notification, you can always go to the notification list to get a recap. The good news is that enabling and accessing this list is quick and easy regardless of your phone model.</p><p>In the steps below, we&apos;ll show you how to view your Android notification history, even after you&apos;ve silenced, dismissed, or deleted them. These steps should work on any relatively recent device, whether one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones" data-original-url="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a> or a dependable budget device.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-view-your-android-notification-history-on-non-galaxy-phones-2">How to view your Android notification history on non-Galaxy phones</h2>
<p>The exact steps in Settings may vary slightly depending on your Android phone, its version, and its skin. That said, the flow should be largely similar, and all Android devices should have this feature built-in right out of the box. </p><p><strong>Note:</strong> I tested the following steps on a Motorola G14.</p>
<p>1. Open the <strong>Settings </strong>app or pull down twice on the notification shade and tap on the <strong>Settings icon (gear-shaped</strong>).</p><p>2. Scroll down and tap on <strong>Notifications</strong>. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1440px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:111.11%;"><img id="PEq5FFRmo5SNz8FwwvgqaE" name="Notification-history-Moto-G14.jpg" alt="Steps to access notification history on Motorola G14" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PEq5FFRmo5SNz8FwwvgqaE.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1440" height="1600" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Judy Sanhz / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>3. Tap on <strong>Notification history</strong>.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1440px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:111.11%;"><img id="XYnjbWsJi3SMardbG8FC2S" name="Notification-history-List.jpg" alt="Notification list for Motorola G14 Android phone" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XYnjbWsJi3SMardbG8FC2S.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1440" height="1600" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Judy Sanhz / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>4. Toggle the switch at the top of the screen to <strong>Use notification history</strong>. You will also see a list of your recently dismissed notifications and a reverse chronological list of notifications.</p>
<p>5. Now, <strong>pull down the notification shade</strong> from any screen.</p><p>6. You should see a link/button called <strong>History</strong> at the bottom of the shade. Tap on that. This will take you back to the notification history view we were just looking at in the previous step. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:338px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:221.89%;"><img id="nWbmXXa8PPWuS6zTCWWR3N" name="History-option-notification-bar.jpg" alt="History option showing after swiping down twice from notification bar" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nWbmXXa8PPWuS6zTCWWR3N.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="338" height="750" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Judy Sanhz / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>That&apos;s all you need to do to enable and access your notifications history on your Android phone. If you ever want to turn the notification history off, follow the same steps and toggle off the option.</p><p>The notification history divides the notifications by time. For example, at the top, you&apos;ll see recently dismissed notifications, and below, the notifications you received in the last 24 hours. If you try to swipe to the sides, the notifications won&apos;t go away. By long-pressing on one of the notifications, you&apos;ll see the notifications page for that app. For example, if you long-press on Gmail notifications, you&apos;ll see an option to manage them.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-view-your-android-notification-history-on-a-samsung-galaxy-phone-2">How to view your Android notification history on a Samsung Galaxy phone</h2>
<p>The steps to do just about everything on a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-samsung-phones">Samsung phone</a> are different. So, here are the steps to access the notification history on that specific model.</p><p>1. Open the <strong>Settings </strong>app or pull down on the notification shade and tap on the <strong>Settings icon (gear-shaped)</strong>.</p><p>2. Tap on <strong>Notifications</strong>.</p><p>3. Tap on <strong>Advanced settings</strong>.</p><p>4. Choose <strong>Notification history</strong>.</p><p>5. Toggle the switch at the top of the screen to <strong>Use notification history</strong>. You will also see a list of your recently dismissed notifications, as well as a reverse-chronological list of notifications.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2214px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:72.27%;"><img id="xXedJqjsGdv33f9cwisnhZ" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Notification-History.jpg" alt="Steps to access notification history on a Galaxy phone" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xXedJqjsGdv33f9cwisnhZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="2214" height="1600" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Judy Sanhz / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Unlike other Android phones, you won&apos;t see a history option to access all your notifications on the Samsung Galaxy model. You can follow the steps previously mentioned or use a third-party app such as <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.myd.android.nhistory2">Notification History</a> or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.libin.notification">Recent Notification</a> and keep the app on the first page of your home screen.</p><p>In notification history, you can&apos;t remove them by swiping, but if you long-press, you can access the option to change how you get notifications for that app.</p>
<h2 id="what-is-notification-history-on-android-2">What is notification history on Android?</h2>
<p>In notification history, you can see all the notifications you received for all your apps, including those you accidentally dismissed, snoozed, or missed. You can also see if an app sent you a notification, but your phone did not show it.</p><p>Notification history started with Android 11 and later, so you can access those important notifications, and hopefully, they won&apos;t go away any time soon. There is always something to manage, whether it&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-password-managers-android">passwords</a> or an app. It&apos;s a good thing there is usually an app for almost everything.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="eb6b15bf-6ce5-4692-94b3-d4607be0e06e">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/us5uBzbMSjqWPB8urvEEEf.jpg' alt='Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="90" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Simply the best</strong></em></p>
<p>Get your notifications with style with the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review">Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra</a>. It has a fantastic 5,000mAh battery, so you won't miss out on important notifications and view them on the tremendous 6.8-inch AMOLED display. You can't forget the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 process that powers this beast.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/how-view-your-android-notification-history</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Discover how to access the notification history to view those dismissed notifications easily. Here are the quick and easy steps that don't require the help of third-party apps. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">wiSEnHhjceyckNgkd2B7Yh</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PBmwMsjbNdFktUNPBgfmAf.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 13:12:42 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ judysanhz30@gmail.com (Judy Sanhz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PBmwMsjbNdFktUNPBgfmAf.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central ]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[How To View Notification History Android 11 Op 1]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[How To View Notification History Android 11 Op 1]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Moto G 5G 2024 vs. Moto G 5G 2023: Should you upgrade? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[         <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="3f20a1ae-269e-4095-bbbd-d9a4277914ea">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9Xuqub5CvqPZfjvpgZW73d.jpg' alt='moto g 5g 2024 square render'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Moto G 5G 2024</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="90" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>New and improved</strong></em></p>
<p>Featuring a gorgeous vegan leather back panel, the Moto G 5G 2024 belies its modest price tag. The smartphone includes dual SIM support and 5G connectivity, and even has NFC for contactless payments.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Stunning design with vegan leather back panel</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Eligible for Android 15</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>NFC for contactless payments</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Still comes with 4GB of RAM</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Useless 2MP macro camera</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="97c75e63-b267-4188-ab22-ebd869522d15">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zZ5Pj7ePZtsWZjA8CoK3qh.jpg' alt='moto g 5g 2023 square render'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Moto G 5G 2023</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="80" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Value for money</strong></em></p>
<p>It may be old, but the Moto G 5G 2023 still has everything you could want in a budget Android phone. It includes 5G support, stereo speakers with Dolby Atmos, and much more, all at a price that's too good to resist.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>More affordable than ever</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>All-day battery life</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Stereo speakers sound great</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Won't get any OS updates after Android 14</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No eSIM support</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<p>Motorola&apos;s Moto G series smartphones are (and have always been) renowned for offering incredible value for money, and the brand-new Moto G 5G 2024 is no different. From a minimal software experience to amazing battery life, the newest Motorola phone brings a lot to the table. It even includes some features that are usually found in much more expensive smartphones, while costing just a penny shy of $200.</p><p>As great as that price is, the previous-gen Moto G 5G 2023 — which is still available for purchase — can now be had for just under $150. So, the question is, should you go for the latest and greatest thing in town, or just get the previous-gen model and save even more of your money? Let&apos;s compare the Moto G 5G 2024 vs. Moto G 5G 2023 and find out.</p>
<h2 id="moto-g-5g-2024-vs-moto-g-5g-2023-design-and-display-2">Moto G 5G 2024 vs. Moto G 5G 2023: Design and display</h2>
<p>Although the newer model is a tad heavier, both the Moto G 5G 2024 and Moto G 5G 2023 have a virtually identical physical footprint and overall design. The two also have an all-plastic frame, as well as similarly placed ports and buttons. However, the moment you flip over the two phones, the biggest visual difference between them immediately becomes apparent.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="nfCxcrWtsgRsZFH9MroFsY" name="Moto-G-5G-2024-back-holding-02.jpg" alt="The back of the vegan leather Moto G 5G 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nfCxcrWtsgRsZFH9MroFsY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Moto G 5G 2024 features a vegan leather back, which is a massive improvement over the plastic rear of the previous-gen model. Sure, vegan leather is technically a form of plastic, but it looks and feels much more premium, while also keeping away dust and fingerprints. As noted by Android Central&apos;s Nicholas Sutrich in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/moto-g-5g-2024-review" target="_blank">his review</a>, this design choice makes the Moto G 5G 2024 stand out in a sea of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones-under-200" target="_blank">Android phones priced under $200</a>, at least as far as looks are concerned.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2989px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="2nTkK4HpAy2gRAbS65eWmS" name="Moto-G-5G-2023-review-hero-wide.jpg" alt="Holding the Moto G 5G (2023)" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2nTkK4HpAy2gRAbS65eWmS.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2989" height="1681" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The 6.6-inch display of the newer model is slightly larger than the 6.5-inch screen that you&apos;d find on the Moto G 5G 2023, but that&apos;s the only difference between them. They are both IPS LCD panels (if you prefer the deep blacks and rich colors offered by AMOLED screens, we suggest checking out the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-a15-5g-review" target="_blank">Samsung Galaxy A15 5G</a>) perfect for everyday use, and even though the display resolution is a little low (720p), you do get a 120Hz refresh rate for a better experience.</p>
<h2 id="moto-g-5g-2024-vs-moto-g-5g-2023-hardware-and-cameras-2">Moto G 5G 2024 vs. Moto G 5G 2023: Hardware and cameras</h2>

<p>The Moto G 5G 2024 is powered by the Snapdragon 4 Gen 1, a newer and moderately better SoC than the Snapdragon 480+ 5G used by its predecessor. Disappointingly though, the RAM is still limited to 4GB. Although the chipsets are capable of handling daily-usage tasks like web browsing and light gaming, the paltry amount of RAM means you won&apos;t be able to multi-task or run resource-intensive apps particularly well on either of these phones. That said, both devices do come with 128GB of internal storage, along with support for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-micro-sd-card-android">microSD cards</a> of up to 1TB.</p><p>Like its predecessor, the Moto G 5G 2024 packs in all the basics like Wi-Fi, multi-band 5G, stereo speakers, and a 3.5mm audio port. However, there&apos;s one extra addition that gives the newer model an edge over the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/moto-g-5g-2023-review" target="_blank">Moto G 5G 2023</a>, and that&apos;s NFC. Yep, you read that right! With the Moto G 5G 2024, you can make hassle-free contactless payments and leave your wallet at home.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="bBGTbKxfiT9RD7LXhEQvzV" name="Moto-G-5G-2024-back-camera-island-02.jpg" alt="The vegan leather back of the Moto G 5G 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bBGTbKxfiT9RD7LXhEQvzV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Moto G 5G 2024 features a dual-lens rear camera setup with a 50MP primary sensor. In comparison, the Moto G 5G 2023 sports a 48MP primary sensor. The 50MP primary lens is the only one you should care about anyway because, like the last-gen model, the secondary sensor is a useless 2MP macro unit that doesn&apos;t do much.</p><p>The camera quality, as expected, is just about average, but you do get features such as dual capture, auto HDR, and more. Video recording is limited to 1080p (at 30fps), and the 8MP front-facing camera (same as that on the last-gen model) works well for selfies and video calls.</p>
<h2 id="moto-g-5g-2024-vs-moto-g-5g-2023-software-and-battery-life-2">Moto G 5G 2024 vs. Moto G 5G 2023: Software and battery life</h2>
<p>Budget phones usually don&apos;t offer much in terms of software support, and the same is true for the Moto G 5G 2024 and Moto G 5G 2023 as well, with both devices being eligible for just one major OS update and up to three years of security updates. That said, since the Moto G 5G 2024 is the newer phone, it already comes with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review" target="_blank">Android 14</a> and will get Android 15 eventually. On the other hand, the Moto G 5G 2023 will stay on Android 14, since it launched with Android 13. If you like using your devices for a long time, this is definitely something worth taking into consideration.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3814px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="dntm8jFqeTsHXbyDXeBftM" name="Moto-G-5G-2023-review-4.jpg" alt="Moto G 5G (2023) outdoors" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dntm8jFqeTsHXbyDXeBftM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3814" height="2145" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The software itself is fairly stock-like, although it&apos;s spruced up with a diverse array of Motorola-exclusive improvements (e.g., quick gestures) that we&apos;ve come to love over the past few years.</p><p>Just like the last-gen model, the Moto G 5G 2024 comes with a big 5,000mAh battery. However, the charging speed has gone up to 18W (in comparison, the Moto G 5G 2023 charges at 15W) for even faster top-ups. Combine that with the power-efficient hardware, and the phone should easily last you a full day with moderately heavy use.</p>
<h2 id="moto-g-5g-2024-vs-moto-g-5g-2023-should-you-upgrade-2">Moto G 5G 2024 vs. Moto G 5G 2023: Should you upgrade?</h2>
<p>With the Moto G 5G 2024, Motorola has hit yet another home run. It not only has all the essentials (e.g., 5G connectivity, awesome battery life), but also packs in goodies like NFC (for contactless payments via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet" target="_blank">Google Wallet</a>), while still costing less than what the Moto G 5G 2023 did at the time of its launch.</p><p>Speaking of the Moto G 5G 2023, the last-gen model can now be had for just $150, and that price is likely to drop even further during festive season sales. It&apos;s no doubt still a good phone, but is it really worth considering, now that the successor is here?</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="CvqPXMRFKhjf7ht7pHM3kW" name="Moto-G-5G-2024-display.jpg" alt="The display of the Moto G 5G 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CvqPXMRFKhjf7ht7pHM3kW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In our opinion, not really. The newer model comes with a much more premium design, NFC, faster wired charging, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-dual-sim-android-phone" target="_blank">dual SIM</a> (and eSIM) support, and an extra year of OS and security updates, all for just a few dollars more. So, unless you really need those extra savings and don&apos;t care about contactless payments, fancy rear panels, and things like that, getting the Moto G 5G 2023 makes little to no sense.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="5f022c55-9901-457f-a59b-a76d194f8fee">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9Xuqub5CvqPZfjvpgZW73d.jpg' alt='moto g 5g 2024 square render'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Moto G 5G 2024</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Thoughtful additions</strong></em></p>
<p>The Moto G 5G 2024 improves upon the last-gen model by including useful features like NFC, dual SIM (with eSIM) support, and 18W fast charging. It runs the latest version of Android and will get three years of security updates.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="d66c1931-dc96-4aa3-ba96-b1a3420bc710">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zZ5Pj7ePZtsWZjA8CoK3qh.jpg' alt='moto g 5g 2023 square render'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Moto G 5G 2023</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>All the essentials</strong></em></p>
<p>The Moto G 5G 2023 may not have all the bells and whistles offered by its successor, but it gets the basics right. The phone packs a 120Hz display, stereo speakers, and a battery that can easily go a full day on a single charge.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/moto-g-5g-2024-vs-moto-g-5g-2023</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Check out our detailed Moto G 5G 2024 vs. Moto G 5G 2023 comparison to find out which one of these affordable Android phones would be right for you. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">nYnrULbKxQkbxbKBFQKPb7</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XYukReiY6pPhKjzgtkYkeY.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 12:05:39 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ sharmarajat@zoho.com (Rajat Sharma) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XYukReiY6pPhKjzgtkYkeY.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The back of the vegan leather Moto G 5G 2024]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The back of the vegan leather Moto G 5G 2024]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google app's experimental bottom search bar on Android is slowly taking shape ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google is known for constantly changing its Android app's interface and is considering relocating the search bar to the bottom, a concept tested since 2021.</li><li>A new experiment involves a Material 3 redesign for the bottom bar, incorporating a pill-shaped search field.</li><li>The updated design introduces a default blue tint, replacing the Dynamic Color, to enhance visual appeal and modernize the app's appearance.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google&apos;s Android app loves to shake things up, especially with its interface, and it&apos;s back at it with the idea of putting the search bar at the bottom. This experiment has been kicking around for a while, starting way back in 2021 and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-app-testing-bottom-search-bar">popping up again in late 2023</a>.</p><p>As spotted by a user on X (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/04/06/google-bottom-search-redesign/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a>), there&apos;s a new test going on. Google is apparently playing around with a Material 3 redesign for the bottom bar, where it&apos;s putting a pill-shaped search field right into the bar itself.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">New Google UI pic.twitter.com/HGGVpw8ER9<a href="https://twitter.com/Cookie_lolll/status/1776355764338073656">April 5, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>The big visual change is perhaps with the search bar. Currently, it&apos;s situated at the top of the app, but the redesign moves it down just above the bottom bar. This might seem like a small move, but it actually makes the bar way easier to reach, no matter what kind of phone you have.</p><p>This move might be Google&apos;s way of admitting our phones are getting huge. The search giant may be thinking that having a UX element up at the top might not be getting as many clicks as it likes. So, bringing the search down to the bottom could make it way easier to tap on and make your search experience a whole lot smoother.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:355px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:211.27%;"><img id="ivUi6gwBmyRkZmfZzjFwo5" name="Google-app-bottom-bar-redesign.jpg" alt="Google app's redesigned bottom bar" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ivUi6gwBmyRkZmfZzjFwo5.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="355" height="750" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: @Cookie_lolll / X)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In the old version, the search bar shrank when you actually started searching. Now, it stays big and bold, no matter what you&apos;re looking for.</p><p>In the updated design, Google swaps out the <em>Dynamic Color</em> for a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-plays-store-turns-blue">default blue tint</a>, which really pops against the Search results page. This redesign of the bottom search bar gives the Google app a much more modern vibe compared to how it looks right now.</p><p>One big change you&apos;ll notice is that in this redesign, the "Google" logo isn&apos;t up there at the top anymore. Instead, you&apos;ll see search filters like <em>Images</em>, <em>Videos</em>, <em>News</em>, and more right off the bat.</p><p>However, this shift means more space is taken up, which could have been used to show search results instead.</p><p>Sure, the new design might cut into how many search results you see at first, but hopefully it makes searching way easier and faster to use overall. We&apos;ll have to see if it works out when they roll it out to everyone.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-app-bottom-search-bar-redesign-on-android</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google is playing with moving the search bar to the bottom of the Android app, and giving it a modern makeover. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">yxHFQXr7Xx4anajCADjBNo</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nWMvZs2495PgsrWCpg8Uib.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 09:52:05 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nWMvZs2495PgsrWCpg8Uib.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google app bottom navigation bar]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google app bottom navigation bar]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Fiio JT1 review: These entry-level headphones are a fantastic value ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Fiio only started making over-ear headphones a year ago, but as is usually the case when the brand enters a new category, it rolled out a wave of new products. While the initial offerings catered to the mid-range segment, Fiio is now focusing on the entry-level segment with the introduction of the JT1.</p><p>I liked what Fiio did with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-ft3-review">FT3</a>, but it was the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-ft5-reviewhttps://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-ft5-review">FT5</a> that allowed the brand to distinguish itself in the mid-range segment. And while there is a decent amount of momentum in the category, it&apos;s the budget segment that sees a bulk of the activity — and sales.</p>
<p>That&apos;s why it&apos;s interesting to see that the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/FiiO-JT1-Professional-Headphones-Microphone/dp/B0CLZRWF8H">JT1 retail for just $57 on Amazon</a>. They&apos;re out of stock as of writing, but you can pick them up via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.aliexpress.com/item/3256805990654609.html?gatewayAdapt=4itemAdapt">Fiio&apos;s official store for $69</a>, or wait until they&apos;re available on Amazon once again. Like other entry-level Fiio products, the JT1 are branded under the Jade Audio label.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="sSyucmNm2jGYxAxJWbgVDW" name="fiio-jt1-16.jpg" alt="Fiio JT1 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sSyucmNm2jGYxAxJWbgVDW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Fiio says it focused on the sound quality instead of outward aesthetics, and that is evident. The JT1 don&apos;t really have a distinct design ethos, and they don&apos;t share any resemblances to the FT3 or FT5. That isn&apos;t a big issue considering just how affordable these headphones, and to its credit, Fiio continues to offer exquisite build quality on all of its products — the JT1 included.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="RiaEa8jQHvgyD9Pj2dH58V" name="fiio-jt1-9.jpg" alt="Fiio JT1 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RiaEa8jQHvgyD9Pj2dH58V.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The earcups on the JT1 are made out of plastic, but the headband and the yokes connecting the earcups to the headband use aluminum, and it gives the headphones good structural rigidity. There isn&apos;t much in the way of swivel, and you miss out on the hard shell case that&apos;s bundled with the FT3 and FT5; you just get a basic carrying pouch.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="FZ2kydHTCyXUg3ZkgzLBVV" name="fiio-jt1-11.jpg" alt="Fiio JT1 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FZ2kydHTCyXUg3ZkgzLBVV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>That said, the JT1 nails the basics. The headband uses a suspension design and distributes the weight of the headphones evenly across your head, and the leatherette material offers adequate cushioning. The best part is that the JT1 don&apos;t weigh as much; at just 301g, they&apos;re much more comfortable than either the FT3 or FT5.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="cPeEhubQSPRpnBp6zWbomU" name="fiio-jt1-7.jpg" alt="Fiio JT1 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/cPeEhubQSPRpnBp6zWbomU.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Although the design is a bit plain, it looks good in its own right, and the visible screws and aluminum exterior gives the JT1 an industrial look. The leatherette ear pads are large and very comfortable, and they can be easily switched out if you want to use aftermarket options.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="ytJ3msG857fp4GFhpz34EU" name="fiio-jt1-4.jpg" alt="Fiio JT1 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ytJ3msG857fp4GFhpz34EU.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>As someone who regularly uses the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/audeze-mm-500-review">Audeze MM-500</a> and FT5, the lighter size of the JT1 made a big difference in daily use. The ear pads are just the right size, and they&apos;re incredibly soft and offer excellent comfort. I used a <em>lot </em>of budget headphones over the last two years, and the JT1 may just be the most comfortable yet.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="K76cXhXxQ3GBYJt2s68XRU" name="fiio-jt1-5.jpg" alt="Fiio JT1 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/K76cXhXxQ3GBYJt2s68XRU.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>There are plenty of other tweaks to the JT1 that make the headphones stand out; they feature a detachable cable with 3.5mm plugs that connect to each earcup, and the cable that you get in the box is similar to that of the FT5. It has a 3.5mm plug, and you get a 3.5mm to 6.35mm connector in the box if you want to use it with a source that has a 6.35mm out. Interestingly, the cable has an inline mic and controls, but the quality of the mic isn&apos;t good. </p><p>The JT1 has a closed-back design, but there are vents on the outside of each earcup that does a good job relieving pressure, and the clamping force is light; if anything, I wanted the headphones to have a slightly tighter seal.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="i6vzbWFYsH4TMMJdq8iBhT" name="fiio-jt1-1.jpg" alt="Fiio JT1 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/i6vzbWFYsH4TMMJdq8iBhT.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>With a sensitivity of 103dB and impedance of just 32Ω, you can drive the JT1 with just about any source. I used the headphones with Fiio&apos;s KA5 dongle DAC and the M15S audio player, and you can use any budget dongle DAC to get the most out of the audio.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="yzczSGMU664bBsFTRADPcU" name="fiio-jt1-6.jpg" alt="Fiio JT1 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yzczSGMU664bBsFTRADPcU.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>On that subject, the JT1 sound great — particularly when you consider what they cost. The low-end has plenty of vibrancy and is highly engaging, and mid-bass is exaggerated, delivering a satisfying rumble. The mid-range is clean and detailed, and vocals come through with a lot of clarity. The treble has good definition, but it doesn&apos;t have much in the way of extension, so you miss out on some detail.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="ke4DberEoHoTEq3XsuhX5W" name="fiio-jt1-15.jpg" alt="Fiio JT1 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ke4DberEoHoTEq3XsuhX5W.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The soundstage is wide given the JT1 feature 50mm closed-back dynamic drivers, and on the whole, the sound signature is clearly aimed at casual listening. It has a smooth quality to it that delivers good detail and clarity, and while you miss out on some nuance, it pairs well with a variety of genres.</p><p>Ultimately, the JT1 are a good choice if you want budget headphones with a comfortable fit and great sound quality. Fiio didn&apos;t go overboard with the features, instead focusing on areas that truly matter. As a result, the JT1 sound better than most other budget headphones I used.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="77c96351-9b2d-451f-aaaa-42caec6bd1da">
            <a href="https://www.amazon.com/FiiO-JT1-Professional-Headphones-Microphone/dp/B0CLZRWF8H" data-model-name="Fiio JT1"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:116.43%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Csc677hpSQFUHpL8gSv7vX.jpg' alt='Fiio JT1'></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Fiio JT1</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>The JT1 feature a lightweight design and sturdy build quality, but it's the sound where they truly stand out. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-jt1-review</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Fiio's JT1 are aimed at the entry-level segment, but these headphones still deliver a fantastic sound, and they're built to last.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">uc4qPnyEi8yJhtv7EiZJjE</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sXCYTsQwrLmidXgZQ9YT4U.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 07:38:38 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sXCYTsQwrLmidXgZQ9YT4U.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Fiio JT1 review]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Fiio JT1 review]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Fiio SP3 review: These powered speakers pack a sizeable punch ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Fiio switched its focus to the desktop segment 18 months ago, and it led to a wave of products that unlocked new use cases while still retaining the brand&apos;s value-driven ethos. One product I was keen on looking at was the SP3, so when the audio manufacturer introduced the active speakers back in May 2023, I immediately had to take a look.</p><p>The SP3 is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/FiiO-SP3-Powered-Desktop-Speakers/dp/B0C69FXB9N">available for just $299 on Amazon</a>, and that makes it an enticing choice if you want powered speakers to use in a desktop setting. As is the case with most of its products, Fiio bundles a decent number of accessories in the box, including a 3.5mm to RCA cable, and two sets of rubber pads — a standard set and one with a 7-degree elevation.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="DPfviZDFAmAG566WGDXreP" name="fiio-sp3-12.jpg" alt="Fiio SP3 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DPfviZDFAmAG566WGDXreP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Unboxing the SP3, my initial thought was that the speakers look smaller than I imagined them to be. With a volume of just 2.35 liters, they don&apos;t take up much room at all, and if you have limited space on your desk, the SP3 may just be a great choice. I paired the active speakers with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-r7-review">outstanding R7 all-in-one streamer</a>, and it&apos;s clear that these two products were designed together.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="9KxoBviq6WHcNyuyszt8GP" name="fiio-sp3-11.jpg" alt="Fiio SP3 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9KxoBviq6WHcNyuyszt8GP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The SP3 cabinet is machined out of metal, and it has outstanding build quality; while the size is on the smaller size, each speaker unit is considerably heavy, with a total weight of 7.4lb (3.4kg). The SP3 has a grooved design that looks good, and it looks much more upmarket than its price tag would suggest.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="TsHSekAzMG4Xo3ycLaeeJN" name="fiio-sp3-6.jpg" alt="Fiio SP3 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TsHSekAzMG4Xo3ycLaeeJN.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Of course, the fact that there&apos;s RGB lighting at the bottom means the SP3 ticks all the right boxes in my book; the lighting is subtle and doesn&apos;t distract from the design, but I like it just the same. I used the SP3 with the elevated rubber pads, and that gave the unit slightly better presence.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="KWTr83Xpkrg7QKDFhyGMKM" name="fiio-sp3-1.jpg" alt="Fiio SP3 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KWTr83Xpkrg7QKDFhyGMKM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>On that note, if you like the look of the SP3 and are considering buying the speakers, I&apos;d suggest getting the white model. Fiio sent the regular black version of the SP3 and R7 for review, and while they both look good, they definitely do not stand out anywhere as much as the white models.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="fxEJG5xK6zJtsAnvLL3HxP" name="fiio-sp3-18.jpg" alt="Fiio SP3 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fxEJG5xK6zJtsAnvLL3HxP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The right side of the SP3 houses all the controls and connectors, with the left acting as just a speaker. While Fiio usually does a great job with connectivity, the SP3 doesn&apos;t get all that much in terms of ports: you get a 3.5mm in and line in, and that&apos;s about it. There&apos;s no optical connectivity, and the speaker misses out on Bluetooth connectivity. There&apos;s no remote either, so you&apos;ll need to use the volume and bass dials at the back of the unit to change volume and adjust bass.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="XJss73TMiyzRYAqrE65jBQ" name="fiio-sp3-15.jpg" alt="Fiio SP3 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XJss73TMiyzRYAqrE65jBQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Another omission is the lack of a subwoofer out. While the SP3 produces great sound in its own right, it&apos;s clear that the ability to connect to a subwoofer would have made the speakers that much more inviting. As it stands, the speakers produce 80W of power in total: there are two 3.5-inch subwoofer units that put out 30W each, and there&apos;s a 1-inch silk dome tweeter on each unit that goes up to 10W.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="2TF2RCLZVLRm5cxvAvZpkQ" name="fiio-sp3-17.jpg" alt="Fiio SP3 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2TF2RCLZVLRm5cxvAvZpkQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Fiio says it is using a double-diffused porting tube to maximize the sound potential of the SP3, and that is indeed the case. I was pleasantly astonished by the sound coming out of the SP3, and while the speaker has a diminutive stature, it is able to produce room-filling sound with relative ease.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="AdXbWRgCdoNJfqqQy8hfdN" name="fiio-sp3-8.jpg" alt="Fiio SP3 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AdXbWRgCdoNJfqqQy8hfdN.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>A big part of that is the use of the 3.5-inch subwoofer; Fiio says it went with a carbon composite material to save weight while offering a rigid structure, and combined with the 1-inch dome tweeter, you get a detailed sound with no distortion even at high volume.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="nSAVoTxHxg4CczvBoreGwN" name="fiio-sp3-9.jpg" alt="Fiio SP3 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nSAVoTxHxg4CczvBoreGwN.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Coming to the sound, the bass is limited because of the inherent size of the speakers, but you get a clean articulation, and some vibrancy. Of course, having a dedicated subwoofer would have made all the difference, but in its own right, the SP3 is decent enough considering its size.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="z2QrUk7DgPAFJ3prPe8PVP" name="fiio-sp3-13.jpg" alt="Fiio SP3 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/z2QrUk7DgPAFJ3prPe8PVP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The mid-range is where the SP3 comes into its own, delivering a clean sound with plenty of clarity and definition. You get full-bodied vocals that sound terrific, and they definitely punch above their segment in this area. The treble is energetic and airy, and you get a balanced sound without any harshness whatsoever — Fiio nailed the tuning in this regard.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="Gh3ZmLgu3znw4RAyMg84aQ" name="fiio-sp3-19.jpg" alt="Fiio SP3 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Gh3ZmLgu3znw4RAyMg84aQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Obviously, there are a lot of great choices if you&apos;re looking to get powered speakers in this category, and most products have Bluetooth connectivity and digital ports as standard. While the Fiio is in the backfoot when it comes to connectivity, the sound quality ultimately redeems the SP3; you just don&apos;t get such a refined sound in this segment.</p><p>So if you want a pair of powered speakers that don&apos;t take up too much room and deliver a powerful sound that belies their size, the SP3 may just be the ideal choice for your use case.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="243054a7-6bb4-4277-bf92-856435cdafd9">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:62.07%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GiXPqugXGogJ8uVjg242QT.jpg' alt='Fiio SP3'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Fiio SP3</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>Fiio's powered speakers don't take up much room and still manage to deliver a great sound. You don't get Bluetooth or a remote, but if you just need great sound and want something with a sturdy build quality, the SP3 is a good option in this category. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-sp3-review</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Fiio's powered speakers have a small stature and still deliver a big sound.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">8Ebj4ia99xWwSqRP6wubfF</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uvWXuGvtw2zLTwdX2mTTVM.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 05:29:55 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uvWXuGvtw2zLTwdX2mTTVM.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Fiio SP3 review]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Fiio SP3 review]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Gmail's 'summarize this email' feature could arrive on Android soon ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Gmail for Android is potentially getting a smart upgrade utilizing AI to provide summaries of long emails.</li><li>The feature is powered by Gemini and is already available in the web version of Gmail, primarily aimed at users of the Gemini for Workspace suite.</li><li>A dedicated option for Gemini has also been spotted within the three-dot menu in email threads, although it currently doesn't display any content.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Gmail on Android might soon pick up a smart upgrade to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-workspace-generative-ai">give you the lowdown on long emails using AI</a>, saving you time digging for the important bits.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://piunikaweb.com/2024/04/05/gmail-summarize-this-email-android/" target="_blank">PiunikaWeb</a>, in collaboration with AssembleDebug, uncovered a <em>Summarize this email</em> button in the Gmail app for Android. Clues pointing to this feature were hidden in version 2024.03.31.621006929 of the app.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Gmail app readying 'Summarize this email' feature powered by Gemini AI on AndroidRead - https://t.co/clWBLuQs1p#Gmail #Android pic.twitter.com/TVtylD37ZH<a href="https://twitter.com/AssembleDebug/status/1776197309560463477">April 5, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>Take a look at the screenshot below, where you can see the button, although it&apos;s not yet active.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:80.28%;"><img id="4TmuyM4r7iGDeMRegzeRfe" name="AI-summaries-gmail.jpg" alt="Gemini-powered AI summaries in Gmail for Android" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4TmuyM4r7iGDeMRegzeRfe.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1080" height="867" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit:  AssembleDebug / X)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>This summarize button makes sense for long emails. It&apos;s powered by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini</a> and is already <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-bard-can-now-summarize-multiple-emails-at-once-for-you">present in the web version of Gmail</a>, which is accessible to users of the Gemini for Workspace suite. So, it&apos;s not a huge surprise that it&apos;s making its way to the Android app.</p><p>But according to Google&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/mail/answer/14199860?hl=en#zippy=%2Csummarize-an-email-thread" target="_blank">support page</a>, this feature is only applicable to email threads with more than two replies. Additionally, it&apos;s clear that the Workspace feature is primarily intended for enterprise use.</p><p>On the other hand, this new button on the mobile app seems like it might be for everyone. As shown in the screenshot above, the button pops up just under the subject line. However, since this feature is still in its infancy, tapping this button doesn&apos;t currently trigger any action.</p><p>Nevertheless, it&apos;s likely that the experience will mirror the same feature found in the web version of Gmail, where users with access to Gemini for Workspace can click on the <em>Ask Gemini</em> button within an email thread. This opens up a sidebar offering suggestions for the next action.</p><p>Besides the <em>Summarize this email</em> button, AssembleDebug has found a separate option specifically for Gemini within the three-dot menu inside email threads. However, tapping this button currently leads to an empty panel with no content.</p><p>Gemini has already showcased its versatility and is continuously growing, especially within other Google services, notably Workspace apps. We&apos;ve recently caught wind of Gemini&apos;s influence in Gmail for Android <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wants-gemini-to-help-you-respond-to-emails-in-gmail-for-android">with its reply suggestions feature</a>. It&apos;s just a waiting game before intelligent summaries also become a part of the service.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/summarize-this-email-button-coming-to-the-gmail-app</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Gmail on Android might soon match its desktop counterpart with smart email summaries. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">8BKFPxeTfdFYFHkkmqpSJ8</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tX2oBaZPRugXdmgGbvUuJ7.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 04:31:52 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tX2oBaZPRugXdmgGbvUuJ7.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nick Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Gmail logo on a Pixel 6 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Gmail logo on a Pixel 6 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Canada is making a big AI push with billions in investments ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Canada's planned $2.4 billion investment in AI will focus on bolstering computing power for AI research, startups, and scaleups.</li><li>Prime Minister Justin Trudeau emphasized the potential of this investment to drive job creation and boost research and business productivity in the AI sector.</li><li>A significant portion of the investment, around CA$2 billion, will be dedicated to enhancing compute capabilities and infrastructure.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Canada&apos;s Liberal government has revealed a $2.4 billion package aimed at boosting the country&apos;s artificial intelligence (AI) capabilities.</p><p>According to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/federal-government-ai-investment-1.7166234" target="_blank">CBC</a>, Canada&apos;s government intends to use its 2024 budget to funnel the money into ramping up computing power for the nation&apos;s AI researchers, startups, and scaleups.</p><p>Prime Minister Justin Trudeau stated that this investment will tap into AI&apos;s full potential by speeding up job creation in Canada&apos;s AI sector, as well as enhancing research and business productivity through its adoption.</p><p>The bulk of the investment (CA$2 billion) will go towards boosting compute capabilities and infrastructure. This support will benefit Canada&apos;s leading AI researchers and startups, leading to the establishment of the Canadian AI Sovereign Compute Strategy.</p><p>Currently, Canada relies heavily on privately owned computing systems, likely referring to cloud services offered by companies based outside the country. This raises security concerns, as the data stored on these systems could be vulnerable to foreign access.</p><p>Deputy Prime Minister Chrystia Freeland suggested at a Sunday press conference that the fund would allow Canada to store and process data within its own borders, potentially improving national security, according to a report from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.thestar.com/news/canada/federal-government-announces-2-billion-investment-to-support-ai-research-growth/article_eeb133b8-f4e8-11ee-a557-ab828d4f2cf1.html" target="_blank">Toronto Star</a>.</p><p>Freeland believes Canada has the resources to build its own supercomputing infrastructure. This includes access to clean electricity for powering the systems, skilled engineers to design and maintain them, a cold climate that can help with cooling, and ample space to house large facilities.</p><p>Additionally, CA$200 million will be distributed by Canada&apos;s Regional Development Agencies to incentivize AI startups and enhance AI integration across pivotal sectors like agriculture, healthcare, clean technology, and manufacturing.</p><p>Generative AI models, propelled by pioneers such as OpenAI with its ChatGPT and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Google&apos;s Gemini</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/un-global-ai-resolution">are rapidly advancing</a>. Canada appears eager to foster its own contender in this field.</p><p>The Canadian government is also establishing a $50 million AI safety institute. This institute will likely research and develop safeguards to mitigate risks posed by "advanced or nefarious AI systems."</p><p>An additional $5.1 million will be directed towards an office of the AI and Data Commissioner, whose role would likely be to enforce the proposed Artificial Intelligence and Data Act. This act would set guidelines and regulations around the development, use, and oversight of AI in Canada.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/canada-allocates-dollar24-billion-for-ai-related-investments</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Canada plans to drop CA$2.4 billion in its next budget to boost artificial intelligence capabilities. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">MLRkwffW5tevFgwR4i3aCf</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hsthSTPq6sF6tiAdDoCWR7.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:22:48 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hsthSTPq6sF6tiAdDoCWR7.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[AI at Google IO 2023]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[AI at Google IO 2023]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Daaaang! The Galaxy Watch 5 Pro just scored a 38% discount at Amazon ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>If you&apos;re looking for a great smartwatch deal, this might be the one for you! The black Bespoke Edition of the Samsung Galaxy Watch 5 Pro is now <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Bluetooth-Smartwatch-Sapphire-Titanium/dp/B0BVGS4FM2"><strong>selling at Amazon with an outstanding 38% discount</strong></a>, offering buyers a powerful smartwatch with excellent battery life at just $278. Similarly, the black ridge band version of the Galaxy Watch 5 Pro is 37% off at a sale price of $281.99. The exact Amazon discount keeps fluctuating for the watch, so don&apos;t wait too long if this price sounds good to you.  </p><p>The Galaxy Watch 5 Pro was rated the "best premium pick" on our list of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch#section-best-premium-pick">best Android watches</a>, and there&apos;s more than one reason why. The battery life, for instance, can last up to 80 hours if you aren&apos;t using power-draining features like the always-on display (AOD) or the constantly-listening Google Assistant. Even with these on, the Watch 5 Pro performs pretty well, and it comes with impressively fast 10W charging, along with several other features that users love.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="fe439bc2-6d0c-4bc1-aaf5-31904868cd1a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$449.99" data-dimension48="$449.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BVGS4FM2" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1398px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:107.30%;"><img id="kHhRSrgm3S9sPcPVJVaUaS" name="samsung-galaxy-watch-5-pro-black-ridge-band.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kHhRSrgm3S9sPcPVJVaUaS.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1398" height="1500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy Watch 5 Pro:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BVGS4FM2" data-dimension112="fe439bc2-6d0c-4bc1-aaf5-31904868cd1a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$449.99" data-dimension48="$449.99"><del>$449.99</del> <strong>$281.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-5-pro-review">Galaxy Watch 5 Pro</a> is an excellent pick as far as smartwatches go, and at over $170 off the purchase price, this is a certifiably good deal. Get up to three days of battery life, super-quick 10W charging, and a number of userful fitness and health sensors. Even though this isn't Samsung's latest Galaxy Watch generation, it still holds up to the hype of the newer models, especially since it's been updated with the user-friendly Wear OS 4.</p>
<p><strong>Price comparison: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-watch5-pro-titanium-smartwatch-45mm-bt-black/6510873.p">Best Buy - $449.99</a><strong> |</strong> <a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Samsung-Galaxy-Watch5-Pro-45mm-Smart-Watch-Bluetooth-Black-Titanium/1401202059">Walmart - $449.00</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BVGS4FM2" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="fe439bc2-6d0c-4bc1-aaf5-31904868cd1a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$449.99" data-dimension48="$449.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if:</strong> you want a watch that has superior battery life; you liked the Wear OS software on other Samsung Galaxy Watch generations; you&apos;re looking for a sleek, black smartwatch that&apos;s durable enough to take with you on outdoor excursions.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if:</strong> you prefer a slightly less wide band and think you might like the 40mm better than the 45mm band; you&apos;re hoping to save even more money on a less premium smartwatch; you want something small and easy to sleep with.</p><p>The Samsung Galaxy Watch 5 Pro holds up well to the newer generation <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-6-review">Galaxy Watch 6</a>, still offering even better battery life and plenty of health monitoring tools for the average user. Without using active battery-draining features, the Galaxy Watch 5 Pro can get access to as many as 80 hours of battery life per charge, while charging up super quickly with the 10W charging.</p><p>Like any watch, the Galaxy Watch 5 Pro does come with a few caveats that could be deal-breakers for some. As one example, some found it too thick and heavy to sleep with, despite including easy-to-use sleep monitoring tools. It&apos;s also pretty pricey when compared with the non-Pro option, though this deal makes it a little more doable.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/daaaang-the-galaxy-watch-5-pro-just-scored-a-38-discount-at-amazon</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Amazon has slashed the price of the Samsung Galaxy Watch 5 Pro by between 36% and 38%, bringing the premium watch down to just under $280.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">GzrN9BfNR8QmfJVx5TkbMb</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NjwVRbEazSjdnAbecJVg7n.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 17:21:16 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NjwVRbEazSjdnAbecJVg7n.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[3 Samsung Galaxy Watch 5 Pros]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[3 Samsung Galaxy Watch 5 Pros]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>