<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 17:20:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung Galaxy Watch FE vs. Samsung Galaxy Watch 4 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[         <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="db75423e-620f-413e-b83e-f88e2c19aa79">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/x9JGqueEAEUp2XRSuW8FC5.jpg' alt='Samsung Galaxy Watch FE'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy Watch FE</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>A new entry into fitness tracking </strong></em></p>
<p>The Samsung Galaxy Watch FE is the first entry-level model in the line-up. It’s designed for those who are new to the world of health and fitness tracking as well as notifications on your wrist. It’s stylish, durable, and has many of the same features you’d find in the more advanced models, with some concessions, of course.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Many of the same features as Galaxy Watch 6</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Detailed sleep tracking and analysis</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Affordable</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Only one size</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Same processor as older model</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="0c82a4da-4441-4b0f-82bb-d3573bfa8264">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fUrX3zn34WS4NhtdgLo3yY.jpg' alt='Samsung Galaxy Watch 4'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy Watch 4</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>An oldie and (sort of) goodie </strong></em></p>
<p>The Samsung Galaxy Watch 4 is coming up on being three years old, which is ancient in the tech space. However, for entry-level users who don’t need all the bells and whistles of the most premium models, it’s a viable option. But you’d most likely be better off with something newer, even if it costs a bit more.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Comes in two sizes</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Lots of health tracking features</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Access to Google services</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Comfortable band</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No Samsung Wallet</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Same older processor</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Very outdated</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<p>If you’re new to the world of fitness and health tracking via wearables and you have a Samsung Galaxy phone, you might be considering getting an affordable smartwatch first to test the waters before diving into a more premium option. It might also be something for a teen or tween that they can use to keep on top of schedules, chores, and health.</p><p>Two good models to consider are the Samsung Galaxy Watch FE vs. Galaxy Watch 4. The former is the newer of the two, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-fe-launch">released in summer 2024</a> and designed for new users. The latter is an older model but was premium at the time of its launch. Which should you choose? Let’s take a look.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-watch-fe-vs-samsung-galaxy-watch-4-the-basics-2">Samsung Galaxy Watch FE vs. Samsung Galaxy Watch 4: The basics</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="z7S7D2XFiNZcDPhqXFHTLi" name="Galaxy-Watch-FE-renders.jpg" alt="Galaxy Watch FE renders" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/z7S7D2XFiNZcDPhqXFHTLi.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Sudhanshu Ambhore)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Samsung Galaxy Watch FE might be an entry model, but it’s no slouch in the style department. It’s available in a 40mm size and employs a design based on the other, more premium models in the line with a circular face and two side buttons.</p><p>The 1.2-inch Super AMOLED screen is made of sapphire crystal glass, so it’s durable, and protected against scratches and scuffs. The screen is a full color always on display offering 396 x 396 pixel resolution.</p><p>Available in Black, Pink Gold, or Silver with new watch bands that have blue and orange stitching, you can customize the watch face to make it your own. The band is one-click style so it’s easy to swap out for other colors and styles. The watch meets 5ATM and IP68 ratings for both water and dust resistance, along with MIL-STD-810H standards so you can be confident that it’s well made.</p><p>Like all other Samsung Galaxy smartwatches, the Galaxy Watch FE can seamlessly connect with Samsung Galaxy devices, like smartphones, tablets, and earbuds. Use features like Find My Phone from the watch to locate a misplaced device, remotely control a Samsung smartphone camera, and pay for items on the go with Samsung Wallet. You can also store ID cards, like a driver’s license and student ID from Samsung Wallet as well. You can use it with other Android phones, too, but you won’t get as seamless an experience.</p><p>With Bluetooth 5.3, NFC, and built-in GPS, there’s an LTE option if you want to get a separate cellular plan for this watch to remain connected wherever you are, even without your phone (think morning run, in a meeting while your phone is at your desk, or at the gym). It also comes loaded with apps like Google Maps and YouTube Music thanks to WearOS.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="xW2LVmcVmpS2trBX3dKLtD" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Watch-6-watchface-big-numbers-02.jpg" alt="One of the new watchfaces on the Samsung Galaxy Watch 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xW2LVmcVmpS2trBX3dKLtD.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>By comparison, the Samsung Galaxy Watch 4 is made from armor aluminum and comes in a 40mm or larger 44mm (stainless steel) size, great for those who have larger wrists or want something less dainty. It’s available in Black, Green, and Silver (44mm version) or Black, Pink Gold, and Silver (40mm version) and has the same two side keys for home and back. The interchangeable bands are made of comfortable fluoroelastomer that doesn’t irritate the skin, as we found in our <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/samsung-galaxy-watch-4-review">review of the smartwatch a few years ago</a>.</p><p>Equipped with either a 1.4-inch or 1.2-inch circular Super AMOLED full-color, always-on screen, the smaller version offers 396 x 396 resolution and it’s 450 x 450 for the larger 44mm edition. The screen is made of Corning Gorilla Glass DX+, so it’s durable as well. You can enjoy plenty of custom watch faces with this model as well, and even a full QWERTY keyboard if you’re adventurous enough to attempt composing a message from the tiny screen.</p><p>The larger model has a bigger 316mAh battery but if you opt for the smaller one, it’s the same 247mAh battery as the Galaxy Watch FE. Our reviewer found that it lasted about a day and a half with typical usage. The Galaxy Watch 4 meets the same 5ATM and IP68 rating as well as MIL-STD-810G, a step down from MIL-STD-810H. The latter is the latest revision of the specification which involves some additional testing, but you can rest assured that both smartwatches are pretty durable.</p><p>With the older Bluetooth 5.0 spec, there’s an LTE option for this watch as well. The Samsung Galaxy Watch 4 also comes with NFC and built-in GPS. But there’s no access to the new Samsung Wallet (though you can presumably use the Samsung Pay).</p><p>As with every <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-samsung-smartwatch">Samsung Galaxy Watch</a>, you can connect this one seamlessly to your Samsung Galaxy smartphone and other devices within the Galaxy ecosystem. This watch also has Google Assistant built-in, which some users might find handy.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-watch-fe-vs-samsung-galaxy-watch-4-specs-2">Samsung Galaxy Watch FE vs. Samsung Galaxy Watch 4: Specs</h2>
<p>When it comes down to the bare bones specs, these two smartwatches are pretty similar in many ways.</p>

<p>When comparing the 40mm size of the Samsung Galaxy Watch 4 to the same-sized Samsung Galaxy Watch FE, are a lot of similarities between these two devices.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-watch-fe-vs-samsung-galaxy-watch-4-features-2">Samsung Galaxy Watch FE vs. Samsung Galaxy Watch 4: Features</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="CdHNrSTxNmyxe2sNirB7v5" name="golfpad-galaxy-watch-4-on-green.jpg" alt="GolfPad on the Galaxy Watch 4" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CdHNrSTxNmyxe2sNirB7v5.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Source: Ara Wagoner / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Now comes the question, what can these watches do and how do they operate? </p><p>The Samsung Galaxy Watch FE runs an Exynos W920 dual core 1.18GHz processor, an older version of what you’ll find in the newer <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-6-review">Galaxy Watch 6</a> and the same processor from the Galaxy Watch 4 as well as the Galaxy Watch 5. It is powered by WearOS with Samsung’s One UI 5 Watch.</p><p>Despite its affordable price and entry-level target, the Galaxy Watch FE has plenty of sensors. At its heart is Samsung’s advanced BioActive Sensor, which is designed to not only track your activity but also provide personalized and actionable tips to help you improve.</p><p>Like the latest Samsung smartwatches, the focus is on sleep and helping you get the best rest possible. There are advanced sleep features like the ability to monitor sleep patterns, sleep coaching, and assistance in creating a sleep-friendly environment.</p><p>For heart health, there are loads of monitoring features. Along with tracking 24/7 heart rate, the watch can deliver HR Alerts when it detects abnormally high or low heart rates. It also has an Irregular Heart Rhythm Notification (IHRN) feature that monitors heart rhythms and advises if atrial fibrillation (Afib) is suspected. The Watch also measures blood pressure and ECG, adding more data to the holistic picture of your health and wellness.</p><p>For exercise, the Samsung Galaxy Watch FE can track more than 100 different workouts and show progress right on your wrist. There’s advanced running analysis for runners, which tracks overall performance to help you maximize efficiency and provide guidance and insights. Runners will also appreciate the ability to use personalized heart rate zones to set their own custom goals based on physical capabilities.</p><p>Additionally, the Watch offers Body Composition tracking, which provides body and fitness data to help you track progress. As a bonus, it even sends motivational messages to guide and encourage you along the way.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="ieLLop8DCY6LEfbzoKAzUC" name="galaxy-watch-4-notification-with-picture.jpg" alt="Galaxy Watch 4 Notification With Picture" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ieLLop8DCY6LEfbzoKAzUC.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Source: Ara Wagoner / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>As noted, the Samsung Galaxy Watch 4 runs on the same Exynos W920 dual core 1.18GHz processor, so you won’t get a snappier experience from this watch than you would with the newer Galaxy Watch FE, despite the latter being an entry model while the Watch 4 was a premium model when it launched in August 2021. However, our Galaxy Watch 4 reviewer found that everything ran really well on the smartwatch when he tested it way back when, saying the device did everything asked of it almost instantaneously.</p><p>The Samsung Galaxy Watch 4 operates with Wear OS powered by Samsung as well. You can access various Google apps thanks to Wear OS, like Google Maps as well as third-party ones like Spotify and Calm.</p><p>This watch has a Samsung BioActive sensor, too, which can track activities and metrics like heart rate, bioelectrical impedance analysis (though you need to manually input your weight each time to get the data), ECG, and more.</p><p>You won’t get the same deep sleep tracking and insights but our reviewer found that the Galaxy Watch 4 did a pretty good job tracking sleep, including stages, and providing a sleep score. You can also access sleep coaching through the Samsung Health app. Nonetheless, if sleep tracking is important to you, this might be a deciding factor between the two. You do, however, get features like body composition, which leverages the BIA analysis.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-watch-fe-vs-samsung-galaxy-watch-4-which-should-you-buy-2">Samsung Galaxy Watch FE vs. Samsung Galaxy Watch 4: Which should you buy?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="EFkoNx3CAyESZgp3JFHZPB" name="galaxy-watch-4-facer-watchface.jpg" alt="Galaxy Watch 4 Facer Watchface" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/EFkoNx3CAyESZgp3JFHZPB.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Source: Ara Wagoner / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>If you’re on a tight budget, the Samsung Galaxy Watch FE provides an almost identical experience to the Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 yet it’s about $100 cheaper. That makes it a pretty good value option that will be considered outdated long after the Galaxy Watch 4 reaches that point (it arguably already has).</p><p>With both watches, you get a slower, outdated processor and shorter battery life compared to more premium models, which are arguably two pretty big concessions. Considering that the Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 is just $100 more than both, you might be better off just going with that model, even if you have to wait longer to save up a bit more.</p><p>There isn’t really a compelling reason to go for the Samsung Galaxy Watch 4 when comparing these two, beyond the larger size option with a slightly higher resolution screen and longer battery life. When comparing apples to apples with the 40mm version of both, the Galaxy Watch FE will provide enough and then some to justify choosing it instead.</p><p>It’s also important to keep in mind that the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-7">Samsung Galaxy Watch 7</a> is likely to launch soon. When it does, you will probably be able to find even better deals on the Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 models. By that time, the Galaxy Watch 4 will be even farther in the rear-view mirror, making it a less appealing option, even for new users.</p><p>Between these two, if you’re dead set on the Samsung Galaxy Watch FE vs. Samsung Galaxy Watch 4, go with the Galaxy FE. Newer is almost always better, and that watch has similar specs to the Galaxy Watch 4 with other new features you won’t find. It will also future-proof your purchase a little longer until you save up for something better. Then, you can choose from among <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch">the best Android smartwatches</a> which, coincidentally, includes the Samsung Galaxy Watch 6.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="1051f1ea-0369-4611-bbc3-8af59ffe1c79">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/x9JGqueEAEUp2XRSuW8FC5.jpg' alt='Samsung Galaxy Watch FE'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy Watch FE</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Save a few bucks </strong></em></p>
<p>You’ll get a nearly premium experience with the Samsung Galaxy Watch FE without spending a fortune and be confident that you have the latest and greatest. But given that it’s not significantly less than the step-up Galaxy Watch 6, you might be better off getting that model, or waiting for the Galaxy Watch 7 to launch and that one to come down further in price.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="53ad922c-ca21-4bf0-a6d7-8397daa309e4">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fUrX3zn34WS4NhtdgLo3yY.jpg' alt='Samsung Galaxy Watch 4'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy Watch 4</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Its time is up </strong></em></p>
<p>The Samsung Galaxy Watch 4 was a fabulous watch when it launched, and it’s still not far behind the Samsung Galaxy Watch FE in terms of specs. In fact, it’s fairly on par with it. But it’s older, outdated, and not the type of product you want to buy right now. If you’re getting similar features, stick with the latest, especially since it’s offered at the same price.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-fe-vs-samsung-galaxy-watch-4</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Samsung Galaxy Watch FE is designed for new smartwatch users, but there's also the option to get an older premium model, like the Galaxy Watch 4. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Ns5MnPjn5sSNMjHJMbLcCk</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Cp7tUGUGxi4JnAhnWLAe4R.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 16:51:43 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ christinep2424@gmail.com (Christine Persaud) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Cp7tUGUGxi4JnAhnWLAe4R.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Samsung]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Samsung Galaxy Watch FE.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Samsung Galaxy Watch FE.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Best cheap smartwatch for Android 2024 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Quick Menu</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="3HrbTVXFdtSXytnoKKuhYH" name="fitbit-versa-4-steps-tile.jpg" caption="" alt="Step tracking tile on Fitbit Versa 4" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3HrbTVXFdtSXytnoKKuhYH.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text"><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="#section-at-a-glance">At a glance</a><br>
<strong>1. </strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-smartwatch-android#section-best-overall">Best overall</a><br>
<strong>2. </strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-smartwatch-android#section-best-runner-up">Best runner-up</a><br>
<strong>3. </strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-smartwatch-android#section-best-value">Best value</a><br>
<strong>4. </strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-smartwatch-android#section-best-cheap-fitness-watch">Best cheap fitness watch</a><br>
<strong>5. </strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-smartwatch-android#section-best-hybrid-watch">Best hybrid watch</a><br>
<strong>6.</strong> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-smartwatch-android#section-best-rugged-watch">Best rugged watch</a><br>
<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-smartwatch-android#section-how-to-choose">How to choose</a></p></div></div>
<p>If you&apos;re stuck on a strict budget, there are plenty of cheap Android smartwatches we&apos;d recommend. Which you choose will depend on how you define "cheap," but also whether you need a proper Wear OS watch with Android phone integration or more of a fitness tracker for health data and basic notifications.</p><p>Most of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch">best Android smartwatches</a> cost between $300 and $500, so we&apos;ve tried to keep this list in the $200-and-under range as much as possible. The Samsung Galaxy Watch FE is a solid budget option for affordable smarts, but we&apos;ll also point you to even cheaper options, or ones focused more on fashion or athletics.</p><p>Depending on where you&apos;re willing to compromise — whether it&apos;s on price, apps, fitness features, or design — you&apos;ll be happy with at least one of the best cheap Android smartwatches available.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-at-a-glance"><span>At a glance</span></h3>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="f54b1c24-71f6-4bd4-8a9a-a11cf52c93e9">
            <a href="#section-best-overall" data-model-name="Samsung Galaxy Watch FE"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nhFiH6CyTxMxNBSkjarybH.jpg' alt='Samsung Galaxy Watch FE render'><span class='featured__label hero__label'>Best overall</span></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">1. Samsung Galaxy Watch FE</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="90" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best overall</strong></em></p>
<p>A rebuilt Galaxy Watch 4 with a revamped display, cool design tweaks, and years of new software support, the Galaxy Watch FE is a cheap variant of our favorite Android watch.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-smartwatch-android#section-best-runner-up"><em>Read more below.</em></a></p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="162253fd-f8ea-4883-9ca3-95872adf8e59">
            <a href="#section-best-runner-up" data-model-name="TicWatch E3"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/u88xXKty8VkJWNXPPwxUGa.jpg' alt='Mobvoi TicWatch E3'><span class='featured__label hero__label'>Best runner up</span></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">2. Mobvoi TicWatch E3</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="80" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best runner up</strong></em></p>
<p>The Mobvoi TicWatch E3 uses an ultra-efficient Snapdragon processor to deliver premium Wear OS 3 performance for less than a Galaxy or Pixel Watch. Keep an eye out for discounts.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-smartwatch-android#section-best-runner-up"><em>Read more below.</em></a></p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="9499f8a5-efdd-435a-9371-7d4889af6711">
            <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-smartwatch-android#section-best-value" data-model-name="Amazfit GTS 4"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/p6XqzUxQoGqiaG3WKSBAQd.jpg' alt='Product render of Amazfit GTS 4 Mini'><span class='featured__label hero__label'>Best value</span></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">3. Amazfit GTS 4</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="80" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best value</strong></em></p>
<p>Amazfit is one of our favorite budget brands. This cheap fitness watch has a mic and speaker, eight-day battery life, dual-band GPS, Alexa commands, and other smarts.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-smartwatch-android#section-best-value"><em>Read more below.</em></a></p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="927c8b0f-b2cd-473a-8b57-01c7baed5876">
            <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-smartwatch-android#section-best-cheap-fitness-watch" data-model-name="Fitbit Versa 4"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mTABksE3NBYFCWuXnYZmbg.jpg' alt='Fitbit Versa 4 render'><span class='featured__label hero__label'>Best cheap fitness</span></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">4. Fitbit Versa 4</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="60" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best cheap fitness</strong></em></p>
<p>Fitbit gives you a ton of health and fitness data, with the Versa 4 as its cheapest squircle option. Its gorgeous AMOLED display and Google apps make it a fair compromise to the Sense 2.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-smartwatch-android#section-best-cheap-fitness-watch"><em>Read more below.</em></a></p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="d5be39da-472d-430b-ba03-2296057c89e3">
            <a href="#section-best-hybrid-watch" data-model-name="Garmin Vivomove Sport"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KN3QqBVmTtznEQTKB8jCfb.jpg' alt='Garmin Vivomove Sport'><span class='featured__label hero__label'>Best hybrid watch</span></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">5. Garmin Vivomove Sport</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="80" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best hybrid watch</strong></em></p>
<p>Pairing the look of a traditional timepiece with fitness tools and smarts, the Vivomove Sport hybrid has a 5-day battery and useful Garmin health data behind the scenes.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-smartwatch-android#section-best-hybrid-watch"><em>Read more below.</em></a></p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="22946278-a096-44ba-bf96-fb5059c5e9e0">
            <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-smartwatch-android#section-best-rugged-watch" data-model-name="Amazfit T-Rex 2"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/37tk7UJVSRDX35xr49jYJF.jpg' alt='Amazfit T-Rex 2 render'><span class='featured__label hero__label'>Best rugged watch</span></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">6. Amazfit T-Rex 2</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="90" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best rugged</strong></em></p>
<p>Most cheap watches use cheap materials. The T-Rex 2 prioritizes ruggedness, with a design built to withstand any damage and plenty of useful health and fitness tools.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-smartwatch-android#section-best-rugged-watch"><em>Read more below.</em></a></p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-best-overall"><span>Best overall</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:908px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.28%;"><img id="N627yqjsmPa4gr54wEYxLi" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Watch-FE-press-photo-running.jpeg" alt="A photo of a woman running while wearing the Samsung Galaxy Watch FE" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/N627yqjsmPa4gr54wEYxLi.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="908" height="511" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Samsung)</span></figcaption></figure>
<div class="buying-guide-block"><h3 id="1-samsung-galaxy-watch-fe-2"><span class="title__text">1. Samsung Galaxy Watch FE</span><span class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span></span></h3><div class="_hawk subtitle"><p>Best overall</p></div><p class="specs__container"><strong>Display: </strong>1.2-inch (396×396) AMOLED | <strong>CPU: </strong>Exynos W920 (1.18GHz) | <strong>Memory: </strong>1.5GB + 16GB | <strong>OS: </strong>Wear OS 4 | <strong>Battery life: </strong>~40 hours | <strong>Protection: </strong>5ATM + IP68, MIL-STD-810H, Sapphire Crystal | <strong>LTE: </strong>✔️ (late 2024) | <strong>GPS: </strong>✔️ | <strong>NFC: </strong>✔️ | <strong>Health sensors: </strong>HRM, ECG, BIA, SpO2</p><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Fast performance</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Wear OS apps and UI</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Years of upcoming updates</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Samsung Health and fitness tools</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Durable design</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">Uses old Galaxy Watch 4/5 specs</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">Only one display size</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">Relatively short battery life</div></div>
<p>Samsung makes our favorite Android watches, but the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-6-review">Galaxy Watch 6</a> is too expensive for this list, and our old favorites like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-5-review">Galaxy Watch 5</a> or Watch 4 are mostly out of stock and sold by shady resellers. Plus, they&apos;ll lose software support from Samsung fairly soon. However, Samsung just launched the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-fe-launch">Galaxy Watch FE</a>, a slightly redesigned Galaxy Watch 4 due to receive years of software support.</p><p>Like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/samsung-galaxy-watch-4-review">Galaxy Watch 4</a>, the Galaxy Watch FE offers heart rate with passive AFib data, blood oxygen, ECG readings, and body composition scans for body fat percentage. It has IP68 dust and water resistance, plus military-grade protection against shock. Plus, it has tap-to-pay and support for both Google Assistant and Bixby.</p><p>What&apos;s different about it? Samsung added fun stitching to the default watch bands for a signature look and a Sapphire Crystal layer to the 1.2-inch display. And this new release resets the clock on software support, so even though it has an older Exynos chip than the latest Galaxy Watch, it should still get Wear OS updates for years. Still, this is essentially a watch with tech from 2021 and 2022, repurposed for 2024. That&apos;s what you have to accept for the discount!</p><p><strong>Cheap alternative:</strong> With the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-7">Galaxy Watch 7</a> arriving soon, you may find discounted <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-6-review"><strong>Galaxy Watch 6</strong></a> models available for not much higher than the Watch FE. Our <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-fe-vs-galaxy-watch-6">Samsung Galaxy Watch FE vs. Galaxy Watch 6</a> guide runs through the differences. Otherwise, Samsung watches are in a class of their own.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-best-runner-up"><span>Best runner-up</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="pijN8QWdPijHNrru7JhWLg" name="ticwatch-e3-lifestyle-landscape-crop.jpg" alt="TicWatch E3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pijN8QWdPijHNrru7JhWLg.jpg" mos="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bm284TUoDgCnscT8xGSn7m.jpg" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Chris Wedel / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<div class="buying-guide-block"><h3 id="2-mobvoi-ticwatch-e3-2"><span class="title__text"><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/mobvoi-ticwatch-e3-review">2. Mobvoi TicWatch E3</a></span><span class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span></span></h3><div class="_hawk subtitle"><p>Best runner up</p></div><p class="specs__container"><strong>Display: </strong>1.3-inch (360x360) LCD | <strong>CPU: </strong>Snapdragon Wear 4100 + Mobvoi MCU | <strong>Memory: </strong>1GB + 8GB | <strong>OS: </strong>Wear OS 3 | <strong>Battery life: </strong>2–3 days | <strong>Protection: </strong>IP68 | <strong>LTE: </strong>🚫 | <strong>GPS: </strong>✔️ | <strong>NFC: </strong>✔️ | <strong>Health sensors: </strong>HRM, SpO2</p><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Wear OS 3 with proper apps</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Long battery life</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Strong performance</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Useful fitness tools</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">No Google Assistant</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">Dim LCD with huge bezel</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">No crown or digital bezel</div></div>
<p>Most <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wear-os-watch" data-original-url="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wear-os-watch">Wear OS watches</a> today are on the pricey side. But the TicWatch E3, which originally launched with Wear OS 2 and received Wear OS 3 recently, is the rare option that&apos;s quite affordable, especially since it frequently goes on sale. You&apos;ll simply have to accept some downsides for the low price.</p><p>First, the positives. Most of our other cheap Android smartwatch picks are fitness watches with proprietary OSs and no app support. The TicWatch E3 gives you all the apps you could want, and it has a stronger battery life than the Galaxy Watch FE—especially in Essential mode. </p><p>Our <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/mobvoi-ticwatch-e3-review">TicWatch E3</a> reviewer had a laundry list of positives when describing it. He noted "little to no delay in opening apps or loading up the Play Store on the watch," something you can&apos;t say for many fitness watches. And on that note, it has heart rate and blood oxygen monitoring for workout and sleep tracking, with the results on par with those he measured on Samsung and Amazfit watches. </p><p>In exchange for the low price, you&apos;re getting an LCD with a thick bezel that our reviewer called "a bit excessive." You also have to rely on the touchscreen, which may bother you if you&apos;re used to a digital crown. The TicWatch E3 has less RAM and storage than the Galaxy Watch FE, as well. But since we&apos;ve seen it discounted for half the price of Samsung&apos;s cheapest watch, these are fair compromises.</p><p><strong>Cheap alternatives:</strong> We&apos;ve also seen the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/mobvoi-ticwatch-pro-3-gps-review"><strong>TicWatch Pro 3</strong></a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/ticwatch-pro-3-ultra-gps-review"><strong>TicWatch Pro 3 Ultra</strong></a> discounted into the $150 range. They have the same software and performance, but far stronger battery life, AMOLED displays, and better materials. We just can&apos;t guarantee they&apos;ll be as cheap as the E3 at any given moment.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-best-value"><span>Best value</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1449px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="auNZ9QHyL4hFr6C3Kd6Msg" name="amazfit-gts-4-lifestyle-3.jpg" alt="Amazfit GTS 4 worn on a wrist" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/auNZ9QHyL4hFr6C3Kd6Msg.jpg" mos="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xyH6ogKRXpf7FDVt3wLnQ3.jpg" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1449" height="815" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Amazfit)</span></figcaption></figure>
<div class="buying-guide-block"><h3 id="3-amazfit-gts-4-2"><span class="title__text">3. Amazfit GTS 4</span><span class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span></span></h3><div class="_hawk subtitle"><p>Best value</p></div><p class="specs__container"><strong>Display: </strong>1.75-inch (390x450) AMOLED | <strong>CPU: </strong>Unknown | <strong>Storage: </strong>2.3GB | <strong>OS: </strong>Zepp OS 2.0 | <strong>Battery life: </strong>8 days (4 days heavy use) | <strong>Protection: </strong>5ATM, tempered glass | <strong>LTE: </strong>🚫 | <strong>GPS: </strong>✔️ (dual-band) | <strong>NFC: </strong>🚫 | <strong>Sensors: </strong>HRM, SpO2</p><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Dual-band GPS</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Activity/sleep tracking</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">PeakBeats and PAI Health</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Up to 8 days of battery life</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Bluetooth calling and Alexa commands</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">No NFC payments</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">No third-party app support</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">No Zepp Coach</div></div>
<p>When it comes to cheap Android smartwatches, Amazfit is one of the first brands we think of. It sells a dozen or more watches at any time, most of which cost $230 or less. Our <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-amazfit-smartwatch">best Amazfit smartwatch</a> guide runs through several great options, but we&apos;re highlighting our top pick here: the Amazfit GTS 4.</p><p>Like our previous pick for this spot—the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/amazfit-gts-3-review">Amazfit GTS 3</a>—the GTS 4 has all of the essentials, from continuous heart, blood oxygen, stress, and breathing data to hundreds of sports modes (with 8 auto-recognized activities like running or cycling). They both have Alexa commands and simple apps like weather and alarms. You also get a gorgeous 1.75-inch AMOLED display with 1,000 nits of brightness and 341 pixels per inch.</p><p>With the GTS 4, Amazfit added a speaker so you can make Bluetooth calls and hear Alexa&apos;s responses instead of reading them. It also added dual-band GPS for more accurate tracking results. Unfortunately, it still lacks NFC for contactless payments, and the revamped "BioTracker 4.0" cuts the battery life down compared to the GTS 3. But it&apos;s still just as long-lived as most other fitness watches, and longer than a Wear OS watch.</p><p>We appreciate how Amazfit takes your workout data and judges your fitness level, training load, and other data via its PeakBeats algorithm. You don&apos;t get the Zepp Coach AI of some of the newer watches, but it&apos;ll still help guide you to get fitter, without the subscription that our next pick charges.</p><p><strong>Cheap alternatives:</strong> As we said, Amazfit has plenty of cheaper options that cut specific features like the mic and speaker. Look at the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/amazfit-gtr-mini-review"><strong>Amazfit GTR Mini</strong></a> for a more circular design, or the <strong>Amazfit Active</strong> for a cheaper squircle. You may also want to look at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-fitness-trackers">fitness trackers</a>, which aren&apos;t proper "watches" but are often significantly cheaper.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-best-cheap-fitness-watch"><span>Best cheap fitness watch</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:5472px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="5eqkWcvEmsEych7MRa4UoJ" name="fitbit-versa-4-review-hero-16x9.jpg" alt="Fitbit Versa 4 review hero 16x9" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5eqkWcvEmsEych7MRa4UoJ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="5472" height="3078" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<div class="buying-guide-block"><h3 id="4-fitbit-versa-4-2"><span class="title__text"><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fitbit-versa-4-review">4. Fitbit Versa 4</a></span><span class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span></span></h3><div class="_hawk subtitle"><p>Best cheap fitness watch</p></div><p class="specs__container"><strong>Display: </strong>1.58-inch (336x336) AMOLED | <strong>CPU: </strong>Unknown | <strong>Storage: </strong>N/A | <strong>OS: </strong>Fitbit OS | <strong>Battery life: </strong>6 days | <strong>Protection: </strong>WR50, Gorilla Glass 3 | <strong>LTE: </strong>🚫 | <strong>GPS: </strong>✔️ | <strong>NFC: </strong>✔️ | <strong>Health sensors: </strong>HR, SpO2</p><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Onboard GPS, HRM, and SpO2</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Built-in mic & speaker</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Google Wallet payments</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Google Maps support</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">6 months of Fitbit Premium</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">No music playback controls, 3rd-party apps, Wi-Fi, or voice assistant like Versa 3</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">Fitbit Premium sub required</div></div>
<p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fitbit-versa-4-review">Fitbit Versa 4</a> is a bit of an odd fitness watch. After Google acquired Fitbit, it made the company change some of its design and hardware strategy, and that played out in the Versa 4. Our reviewer wasn&apos;t a big fan of its cutbacks, but it still gives you Fitbit&apos;s respected health and fitness insights for $100 less than the Sense 2, making it a lock for this list.</p><p>Compared to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/fitbit-versa-3-review">Fitbit Versa 3</a>, the Versa 4 lost the old Fitbit OS&apos; third-party apps, replaced by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/how-to-use-google-maps-fitbit-sense-2-versa-4">Google Maps</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/how-to-use-google-wallet-fitbit-sense-2-versa-4">Google Wallet</a>—arguably more useful. More frustratingly, it no longer supports Google Assistant, nor music storage or playback controls like the Versa 3 did. That makes it less of a "smart" watch than its predecessor. You still have Alexa commands, but the Wi-Fi antenna is disabled, making responses slower than they should be.</p><p>Still, you get a 6-day watch with a gorgeously bright AMOLED display, built-in GPS with an altimeter for judging elevation, Bluetooth calling, continuous heart rate, blood oxygen, heart rate variance (HRV), and breathing rate. It&apos;s enough for Fitbit to give you a ton of insights into your <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/what-fitbit-daily-readiness-score-and-how-do-i-use-it">Daily Readiness</a> and your overall wellness, so long as you keep subscribing to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/fitbit-premium-worth-annual-subscription">Fitbit Premium</a> after the free 6-month trial ends.</p><p><em><strong>Cheap alternatives:</strong></em> We&apos;ve seen the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fitbit-sense-2-review"><strong>Fitbit Sense 2</strong></a> dip to $199 during various deal events in the past couple of years; if you spot it at that price, you can upgrade to get an ECG and stress sensors, among other perks. You may also want the cheaper <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fitbit-charge-6-review"><strong>Fitbit Charge 6</strong></a>; you lose the pretty squircle display and altimeter but gain YouTube Music controls, the ECG, an upgraded HR sensor for accuracy, and a lighter fit.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-best-hybrid-watch"><span>Best hybrid watch</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1200px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="zKtrL8Sc943C8or6VfpNoL" name="Garmin-Vivomove-Sport-outside.jpeg" alt="Garmin Vivomove Sport" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zKtrL8Sc943C8or6VfpNoL.jpeg" mos="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/aTdRiCbq795aVf6vTodvyi.jpg" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1200" height="675" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Courtney Lynch / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<div class="buying-guide-block"><h3 id="5-garmin-vivomove-sport-2"><span class="title__text"><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/garmin-vivomove-sport-review">5. Garmin Vivomove Sport</a></span><span class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span></span></h3><div class="_hawk subtitle"><p>Best hybrid watch</p></div><p class="specs__container"><strong>Display: </strong>0.34" x 0.73" mono OLED | <strong>CPU: </strong>Unknown | <strong>Storage: </strong>14 days of data | <strong>OS: </strong>Garmin OS | <strong>Battery life: </strong>5 days | <strong>Protection: </strong>5ATM, chemically strengthened glass | <strong>LTE: </strong>🚫 | <strong>GPS: </strong>🚫 | <strong>NFC: </strong>🚫 | <strong>Health sensors: </strong>HRM, SpO2</p><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Heart-rate monitoring</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Pulse Ox & Body Battery</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Activity/sleep tracking</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Stress monitoring</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Stylish design</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">Lacks onboard GPS</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">No NFC payments</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">Sunlight visibility isn't great</div></div>
<p>Most cheap Android smartwatches have cheap, toy-like appearances, whether you choose a squircle or circular display. That&apos;s why many gravitate towards <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-hybrid-smartwatches">hybrid smartwatches</a> that pick style over substance. But since most of our favorite hybrids are expensive, we&apos;re picking the reasonable <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/garmin-vivomove-sport-review">Garmin Vivomove Sport</a> for this spot.</p><p>Shipping in Ivory, Cocoa, Cool Mint, or Black, the Vivomove Sport looks like a traditional watch, with actual watch hands and a subtle monocolor OLED touchscreen on the bottom half of the watch. It&apos;s designed to passively track your heart rate, stress, blood oxygen, Body Battery, and other data for you to check in the Garmin Connect app.</p><p>Compared to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-garmin-smartwatch">best Garmin watches</a>, the Vivomove Sport is pretty limited. You won&apos;t find Garmin Pay, built-in GPS, or robust training tools like Garmin Coach. This is much more of a subtle tool for basic stats like Intensity Minutes, steps, calories burned, and sleep insights. But we think plenty of people will prefer a simplified, stylish experience.</p><p><strong>Cheap alternatives:</strong> Most Garmin watches cost $400 and up, with a few hitting $1,000! So even though they&apos;re too expensive for this list, the $250 <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-forerunner-165-review"><strong>Garmin Forerunner 165</strong></a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-venu-sq-2-review"><strong>Garmin Venu Sq 2</strong></a> are <em>relatively</em> cheap for the brand. The Forerunner is a fantastic training tool for runners with workout suggestions and post-run recovery time; the Venu gives you the squircle look and a solid 11-day battery life.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-best-rugged-watch"><span>Best rugged watch</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4032px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="P9KXPSQeBh83tyMEpq9PrU" name="Amazfit-TRex-2-lifestyle-16x9-07.jpg" alt="Amazfit T-Rex 2" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/P9KXPSQeBh83tyMEpq9PrU.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4032" height="2268" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Chris Wedel/Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<div class="buying-guide-block"><h3 id="6-amazfit-t-rex-2-2"><span class="title__text"><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/amazfit-t-rex-2-review">6. Amazfit T-Rex 2</a></span><span class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span></span></h3><div class="_hawk subtitle"><p>Best rugged watch</p></div><p class="specs__container"><strong>Display: </strong>1.39-inch (454x454) AMOLED | <strong>CPU: </strong>Unknown | <strong>Storage: </strong>N/A | <strong>OS: </strong>Zepp OS 2.0 | <strong>Battery life: </strong>10 days (heavy), 24 days (typical) | <strong>Protection: </strong>15 MIL-STD-810G certifications, 10 ATM | <strong>LTE: </strong>🚫 | <strong>GPS: </strong>✔️ (dual-band) | <strong>NFC: </strong>🚫 | <strong>Health sensors: </strong>HRM, SpO2</p><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Large, bright AMOLED display</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Can survive anything</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">One-tap health measurements</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">150 sports modes</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Epic battery life</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">No tap-to-pay, apps, or music storage</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">Heavy design</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">Older health sensors than GTS 4</div></div>
<p>As we mentioned with the GTS 4, Amazfit makes a variety of cheap Android smartwatches. The Amazfit T-Rex 2 is basically the opposite of the GTS 4, which is much daintier and focused on a traditional smartwatch experience. Our <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/amazfit-t-rex-2-review">T-Rex 2 reviewer</a> said that this watch "will likely outsurvive you" thanks to its rugged durability, and that&apos;s a nice reassurance when most cheap watches aren&apos;t built to last long.</p><p>The T-Rex 2 weighs a hefty 66.5g, making it noticeable on your wrist compared to most of the thin, shorter-lived entries on this list—but significantly lighter than the stainless steel <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/amazfit-t-rex-ultra-review">T-Rex Ultra</a>. It survived over a dozen MIL-STD-810G certifications and has a 10ATM water resistance rating, twice as deep as most smartwatches can handle. Plus, it can last for weeks per charge under normal conditions.</p><p>Otherwise, this watch and the GTS 4 aren&apos;t that different. You get a ridiculous number of sports modes and eight automatic exercises, plus data on your heart rate, blood oxygen, stress, and breathing. It even has the Zepp Coach AI, though not the GTS 4&apos;s mic/speaker combo or its newer HR sensor LEDs that are supposed to be 33% more accurate.</p><p><strong>Cheap alternatives:</strong> We&apos;ve already brought up other cheap Amazfit watches to consider, and other rugged watches like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-instinct-2-solar-review">Garmin Instinct 2</a> are too expensive for this list. We also like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/amazfit-t-rex-pro-review">T-Rex Pro</a>, though it has an even older health sensor suite, a smaller display, and other downsides. If you don&apos;t need ruggedness and just want a cheap fitness watch, consider the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/polar-pacer-review">Polar Pacer</a> or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/coros-pace-3-review">Coros Pace 3</a>.</p>
<ul><li><a href="#main"><strong>Back to the top ^</strong></a></li></ul>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-how-to-choose"><span>How to choose</span></h3>
<h2 id="choosing-between-the-best-cheap-android-smartwatches-2">Choosing between the best cheap Android smartwatches</h2>
<p>Hopefully, this list will make it clear that you can find a cheap Android smartwatch that doesn&apos;t feel like a complete downgrade. Most of them have a baseline of features that you&apos;ll want: health and sleep tracking, notifications, and solid battery life. But in other ways, you&apos;ll have to accept compromises.</p><p>Your first big decision is whether to choose Wear OS or a secondary option like Fitbit or Garmin OS. We appreciate the Galaxy Watch FE and TicWatch series for giving you access to Play Store apps and the ability to respond to notifications on your wrist. But in exchange, you&apos;ll have to charge them every one to two days, while other picks on this list will last a week or more.</p><p>Some <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-smartwatches-fitness">fitness watches</a> are smarter than others, and most of our picks sacrificed features that you may really want. You&apos;ll want the Versa 4 for Bluetooth calling, but not for music playback. Amazfit watches don&apos;t have tap-to-pay. Hybrid watches typically don&apos;t have built-in GPS. Make sure to do your research before you buy, so you don&apos;t end up regretting your choice.</p><p>The Galaxy Watch FE looks smart and superior next to our other picks, but do remember that it&apos;s a downgrade compared to other full-priced smartwatches. Specifically, it has less RAM, an older CPU, and a thicker border around its display than the Galaxy Watch 6. You may want to hunt for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/prime-day-smartwatch-deals-2024">Prime Day smartwatch deals</a> instead of compromising.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Smartwatch deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/searchpage.jsp?st=smartwatch&_dyncharset=UTF-8&_dynSessConf=&id=pcat17071&type=page&sc=Global&cp=1&nrp=&sp=&qp=&list=n&af=true&iht=y&usc=All+Categories&ks=960&keys=keys"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/search?q=smartwatch"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=smartwatch&crid=19YAPQ38561AK&sprefix=smartwatch%2Caps%2C138&ref=nb_sb_ss_ts-doa-p_1_10"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/watches-audio-accessories-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.dell.com/en-us/search/smartwatch"><u><strong>Dell</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-smartwatch-android</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ If you want to own a smartwatch to pair with your Android phone without breaking the bank, be sure to check out these affordable options! ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">qebuVQx9SsXoUoNjDsf3hy</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3HrbTVXFdtSXytnoKKuhYH.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 16:43:37 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3HrbTVXFdtSXytnoKKuhYH.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Samsung]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Galaxy Watch Active 2 (40mm)]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Galaxy Watch Active 2 (40mm)]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Is the Motorola Razr Plus 2024 waterproof? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <section class="article__schema-question"><h3>Is the Motorola Razr Plus 2024 waterproof?</h3><article class="article__schema-answer"><p><strong>Best answer:</strong> Yes, but there are some limitations. It has an IPX8 rating, meaning it can withstand submersion in 1.5 meters of water for up to 30 minutes. The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 has not been tested against solid particles like dust.</p></article></section>
<h2 id="wait-this-is-what-the-razr-plus-2024-apos-s-ip-rating-means-2">Wait! This is what the Razr Plus 2024&apos;s IP rating means</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="rGwGHzDny625oebApQjdCk" name="Motorola-Razr-Plus-2024-and-Razr-2024-2.jpg" alt="The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 and Razr 2024 next to each other" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rGwGHzDny625oebApQjdCk.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The International Electrotechnical Commission (IEC) uses an IP (ingress protection) rating system to grade an enclosure&apos;s dust and liquid entry resistance. The first digital (or X) indicates protection against solids, while the second digital indicates protection against liquids. </p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2024-hands-on">Motorola Razr Plus 2024</a> has an IPX8 rating, meaning it has not been tested for dust resistance but can withstand 30 minutes of submersion in 1.5 meters of water. If there were a zero instead of an X, that would indicate that it underwent testing and is not dust-resistant.</p><p>While the phone&apos;s water resistance was tested in a lab with fresh water, it&apos;s advisable to avoid exposing it to salt water, chlorinated pools, or other liquids like soft drinks and juices, as these could potentially damage the phone.</p><p>The Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 5, which features on our <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-waterproof-phone">best waterproof phone</a> list, shares the same IPX8 rating as the Motorola Razr Plus 2024. However, like the Flip 5, it&apos;s wise not to take the Razr Plus 2024 swimming or expose it to excessive dust, particularly in environments where fine particles can easily get inside the phone. While keeping dust out of a folding phone can be challenging, using a dustproof bag or case can offer significant protection.</p><p>It&apos;s important to note that the IPX8 rating can deteriorate over time due to drops, impacts, and rough handling. The seals and gaskets can crack, become loose, or compress. Extreme temperatures and areas with high humidity can also contribute to the rating decreasing over time.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-clean-and-disinfect-your-android-smartphone">Properly cleaning your Android phone</a> will also help keep the rating at its highest as long as possible and prevent any damage from occurring. Also, avoid trying to replace any hardware on your waterproof Razr Plus 2024 since any unauthorized modifications can affect the rating over time. </p><p>The highest rating you will see on a phone is IP69K, meaning it&apos;s completely dustproof (6), and nine means it can withstand high-pressure hot water from different angles. When you want to know how much water a device can withstand, the IP rating will give you a more precise indication than words. While a phone might be able to withstand slightly more water than its IP rating suggests, it&apos;s best not to risk it. It&apos;s not a common rating you would see on phones, but some phones have that rating, such as the Nokia XR21.</p><p>If you don&apos;t want that much protection, you can go with flagship phones such as the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review">Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra</a>, which has an IP rating of IP68, meaning it&apos;s completely dustproof and waterproof for up to 1.5 meters for 30 minutes.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="4b700e72-363f-478d-a9c5-964c326f41bc">
            <a href="https://www.motorola.com/us/smartphones-razr-gen-4" data-model-name="Motorola Razr Plus 2024"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fqVbP4FnC2UkrwDdrYtwBR.jpg' alt='The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 in Midnight Blue'></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Motorola Razr Plus 2024</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="90" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The improved Razr model</strong></em></p>
<p>The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 has an improved 4,000mAh battery, 256GB storage, 12GB RAM, and a Snapdragon 8s Gen 3 processor for more power for everyday tasks.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/is-the-motorola-razr-plus-2024-waterproof</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Discover how much water can land on the Motorola Razr Plus 2024 without damaging it. Get the information you need and what the phone's IP rating means. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">fRHTXx5Q6DvAEJVpetBFd6</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zzttxnWvHBCcqEyapM7rs4.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 16:35:42 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ judysanhz30@gmail.com (Judy Sanhz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zzttxnWvHBCcqEyapM7rs4.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 cover screen]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 cover screen]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Motorola Razr Plus 2024 vs. Razr Plus 2023 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[         <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="44ed6b8a-297f-456b-8239-e4f1f7511b2c">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QYAFTS6Yd3th4KVUFQcqY8.jpg' alt='Motorola Razr Plus 2024'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Motorola Razr Plus 2024</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>A massive improvement</strong></em></p>
<p>The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 is a massive improvement over the Motorola Razr Plus 2023, with a better overall design that includes a larger external display and an easier-to-use hinge, along with more favorable cameras, a more powerful processor with more RAM, bigger battery and faster charging, plus deep Google Gemini AI and moto ai integration. It’s worth the upgrade or the better option of the two to choose.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Improved hinge design</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Larger external screen</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Google Gemini AI integration</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Better cameras</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Improved battery life</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>More expensive</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No dust resistance rating</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Cameras protrude more</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="f530958f-43ad-4e3c-b16d-80c3131fd77d">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Jc85GVTAkFfiMQ4UeXdmXP.jpg' alt='Motorola Razr Plus 2023'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Motorola Razr Plus 2023</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>A good start </strong></em></p>
<p>The Motorola Razr Plus 2023 was a great entry into the growing foldables market. But you get a vastly improved experience with the Motorola Razr Plus 2024 that leaves this one in the dust. If you still own the Motorola Razr Plus 2023 and you’re happy with it, you don’t need to rush to upgrade. But if you want a better overall experience, go for it. You won’t be disappointed.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Supports three OS upgrades</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Panels and apps on external display work well</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Handles gaming well</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Easy and fun to use</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Cameras aren't great</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Battery barely lasts a day</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Older OS, processor</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Peak brightness not sufficient for direct sunlight</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No advanced AI integration</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<p>Motorola has improved greatly on its popular Razr Plus foldable phone with a new version that boasts tons of enhancements in AI, design, specs, and more. If you’re considering buying the new phone as an upgrade or looking to compare both to decide which one to buy, we’re here to help. Looking at the Motorola Razr Plus 2024 vs. Razr Plus 2023, here’s what you need to know.</p>
<h2 id="motorola-razr-plus-2024-vs-razr-plus-2023-the-design-and-basics-2">Motorola Razr Plus 2024 vs. Razr Plus 2023: The design and basics</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="78tE4SHLAESmQ2jbu5zXTe" name="Motorola-Razr-Plus-2024-hands-on-06.jpg" alt="The back of a Motorola Razr Plus 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/78tE4SHLAESmQ2jbu5zXTe.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>First, let’s consider the design and basics of these two phones. </p><p>The Motorola Razr Plus 2024, which will be available starting July 10, 2024, has a 6.9-inch FHD+ pOLED 2,640 x 1,080 main foldable screen with HDR 10+. In his hands-on, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2024-hands-on">Android Central’s Derrek Lee</a> said the screen is brighter and more vibrant. The smaller external display once folded is the largest you’ll find in a foldable device to date at 4 inches, boasting 1,272 x 1,080 resolution, and covering almost the entire front of the phone once folded. The larger inner screen offers a 165Hz refresh rate and 3,000 nits brightness while the smaller external display offers the same refresh rate at 2,400 nits peak brightness.</p><p>Available in Midnight Blue, Spring Green, Peach Fuzz (the Pantone Color of the Year), and a Hot Pink throwback to the original Razr, the phone has a soft vegan leather back with contoured edges. Lee said that beyond the bigger external screen and new colors, the phone looks nearly identical to its predecessor, with the same curvaceous frame. The cameras, however, do protrude more from the bottom corner.</p><p>The screen is made of Corning Gorilla Glass Victus and the phone is submersible in up to 1.5 meters of water for up to 30 minutes, making it quite durable. However, it does not have a dust resistance rating, which you’ll want to keep in mind when using it while out and about.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="mc9H6pcxQdLgW4mCZYcbDg" name="Motorola-Razr-Plus-2024-hands-on-03.jpg" alt="The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 main display" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mc9H6pcxQdLgW4mCZYcbDg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The hinge has been improved with a simplified design that not only offers good dust protection for this part of the device, but it’s also easier to flick open or snap shut with one hand. Lee said it feels smaller but sturdier, holding the phone nicely in place at various angles. It offers a wide range of Flex View positions, allowing for hands-free photo capture along with a shake-free camcorder mode that’s optimized for social media.</p><p>With a 4,000mAh battery, the Motorola Razr Plus 2024 supports 45W TurboPower charging (charger sold separately), 15W wireless charging (charger sold separately), as well as 5W reverse charging. It has 256GB built-in storage, dual stereo speakers with Dolby Atmos and Spatial Sound (along with Qualcomm Snapdragon Sound 4), and three microphones.</p><p>Offering USB-C charging, it also includes Bluetooth 5.4, Wi-Fi, 5G, NFC, a fingerprint reader, lock screen, and more.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="uqQYR7pWJuZMVHSVcYaiNn" name="Motorola-Razr-Plus-2023-how-its-going-9.jpg" alt="Motorola Razr Plus 2023 hinge and back panel" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uqQYR7pWJuZMVHSVcYaiNn.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Comparatively, the Motorola Razr Plus 2023, which launched in summer 2023, has the same 6.9-inch internal pOLED screen with the same 2,640 x 1,080 resolution and 165Hz refresh rate. But it taps out at 1,400 nits brightness. The external screen is smaller at 3.6 inches in size and offers a lesser 1,066 x 1,056 resolution with a 144Hz refresh rate and 1,100 nits brightness.</p><p>If you’re going to be using the external screen a lot, you’ll find it much more pleasurable with the new phone versus this older one. In <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-review">his review last year</a>, Lee said the 1,400 nits isn’t enough in direct sunlight, and he’d often find himself struggling to see the display.</p><p>The Motorola Razr Plus 2023 comes in Infinite Black, Glacier Blue, and Viva Magenta with the same faux leather back on the latter option that Lee said adds a nice texture to the phone. The Gorilla Glass Victus screen is just as durable but this phone only meets an IP52 rating. You won’t get the same level of intelligent personalization, but there are lots of wallpapers from which to choose, along with lock screens and clock styles.</p><p>The flex mode adjusts the angle of some apps, like YouTube, to take advantage of the phone if it’s sitting at a different angle. With Ready For support, you can connect the phone to a compatible PC to cast the display to the bigger screen without the need for wires.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="uUghf2sg5tnb7i42XbVDfj" name="Motorola-Razr-Plus-2023-how-its-going-7.jpg" alt="Motorola Razr Plus 2023 internal display" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uUghf2sg5tnb7i42XbVDfj.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The hinge is a big difference here since it was difficult to open and close the phone with one hand with the Motorola Razr Plus 2023. “It’s not as easy as I’d like” one-handed, said Lee, “but it’s not impossible.” He did find closing the phone, however, to be quite smooth. Considering that’s one of the big draws with a foldable phone, it’s a major upgrade that Motorola has improved on one-handed opening and closing with the Motorola Razr Plus 2024.</p><p>The older phone has a smaller battery as well at 3,800mAh and supports slower charging at 30W wired or 5W wireless. For power users, this is a significant upgrade with the new phone. Lee said battery life isn’t great with the Motorola Razr Plus 2023, with the phone struggling to get through a full day on a charge. With stereo speakers with Dolby Atmos and three mics, you will get a favorable audio experience with this phone. It also has the same 256GB storage. </p><p>Along with USB-C charging, you get the older (but still good) Bluetooth 5.3 spec, Wi-Fi, 5G, fingerprint sensor, face unlock, and other similar features. Motorola promised three OS updates with the Motorola Razr Plus 2023 and four years of bi-monthly security updates. The new Motorola Razr Plus 2024, it should be noted, offers the same.</p>
<h2 id="motorola-razr-plus-2024-vs-razr-plus-2023-the-specs-2">Motorola Razr Plus 2024 vs. Razr Plus 2023: The specs</h2>
<p>Let’s see how the core specs break down for these two phones.</p>

<p>There are some notable differences between these phones, mostly in the exterior screen size, resolution, and refresh rate, cameras, RAM, and processor as well as durability.</p>
<h2 id="motorola-razr-plus-2024-vs-razr-plus-2023-features-and-functions-2">Motorola Razr Plus 2024 vs. Razr Plus 2023: Features and functions</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="p6g6MdZHdoD4AXBhrpWUAh" name="Motorola-Razr-Plus-2024-hands-on-04.jpg" alt="The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 cover screen panels" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/p6g6MdZHdoD4AXBhrpWUAh.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Now, let’s get down to the nitty-gritty. What is it about the Motorola Razr Plus 2024 that makes it a worthwhile upgrade from the Razr Plus 2023, or the better option to buy between the two, if that is what you’re pondering?</p><p>First off, the new phone adds access to the Google Gemini app right from the external display: all you need to do is press and hold the power button. A Gemini Advanced subscription is included for three months, which includes access to Google Gemini in apps like Gmail and Docs along with 2TB of cloud storage. You can also access Google Photos right from the external display.</p><p>The panels are improved: they’re more fluid to use with animations as you swipe. There’s also the option to pinch to zoom out and view all at once, and more app choices, like Google Messages that can take up the entire cover screen. </p><p>You can change the Desk Display to show your own selection of text and images, effectively creating your own modern screensaver. With moto ai, you can use Style Sync, a neat feature that develops wallpaper options based on your outfit. With Magic Canvas, meanwhile, you can generate images based on simple and descriptive text prompts.</p><p>Equipped with a powerful Snapdragon 8S Gen 3 mobile processor and Hello UX software along with 12GB RAM, the phone comes with Android 14. Moto ai offers enhanced experience features leveraging generative AI. While not available out of the gate, there are some new features coming to the phone in a few months. </p><p>Catch me up will provide a prioritized summary of your personal communications so you don’t have to sift through notifications. Pay attention enables instant recordings of conversations or speakers, then transcribes and summarizes them. Remember this, meanwhile, can capture live moments or on-screen information so you can easily recall it later. You can also access moto ai with virtually any app or function on the phone, getting suggestions, answers to questions, guidance on how to use the phone, and more, all powered by Gemini from Google Cloud.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="nb99u8YSDN3JzrJyMF9KhV" name="Motorola-Razr-Plus-2023-how-its-going-4.jpg" alt="YouTube Music on a rotated Motorola Razr Plus 2023 cover screen" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nb99u8YSDN3JzrJyMF9KhV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While you won’t find all the same Google Gemini integration and features with the Motorola Razr Plus 2023, it does have some interesting features. There are panels you can arrange for the external screen as well, including apps for things like weather, a calendar, contacts, games, news, music, and more. But you won’t find as many and they don’t work as fluidly.</p><p>Nonetheless, you can still easily access a selection of apps and even use them without having to open the phone. Lee said he absolutely loved using the outer display and access to the apps, finding it very responsive. But the experience is presumably much better with the Motorola Razr Plus 2024, not only with more app options and better navigation through them, but also because of the larger screen size.</p><p>The apps aren’t optimized for the smaller display, but most are relatively easy to use. Although you’ll run into a few, like Instagram, that are a bit more challenging since it’s so scaled down. Lee does, however, love the app continuity such that if you find an app too difficult to use on the external screen, you can open the phone and it will automatically open on the full screen. Presumably, this works the same way in the Motorola Razr Plus 2024.</p><p>With 8GB RAM and running the Snapdragon 8+ Gen 1 processor, the Motorola Razr Plus 2023 did pretty well at running games in Lee’s testing. The built-in gaming mode provides an extra boost as well, though Lee noticed that the phone can get warm if you’re playing very graphics-heavy games.</p><p>The Motorola Razr Plus 2023 comes with Android 13. Though it can be upgraded to Android 14 and likely beyond, it won’t be supported for as long as the newer Motorola Razr Plus 2024, which would go up to Android 17 versus 16. So, this is something you should factor into your decision.</p>
<h2 id="motorola-razr-plus-2024-vs-razr-plus-2023-the-cameras-2">Motorola Razr Plus 2024 vs. Razr Plus 2023: The cameras</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="S8xDDjsbgjzBr33xC4myiV" name="Motorola-Razr-Plus-2024-hands-on-02.jpg" alt="The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 cameras" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/S8xDDjsbgjzBr33xC4myiV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The cameras have been vastly improved with the Motorola Razr Plus 2024. There’s a 50MP main camera or 12.6MP camera with optical image stabilization. The 50MP secondary camera, while much higher resolution than what was found in the Motorola Razr Plus 2023, is strangely a telephoto camera with 2x optical zoom instead. Lee interviewed an executive at the company who said the decision was made since consumers tend to use portrait mode more often than ultrawide. The front camera is 32MP.</p><p>You get all the usual suspects you’d expect from a Motorola device when it comes to photo modes, like portrait, Face Beauty, night vision, panorama, Auto Smile Capture, and more. Plus, there are moto ai enhancements. </p><p>The Photo Enhancement Engine uses AI to apply settings from multiple shooting modes so you get the best possible pictures every time. It fine-tunes images for detail, clarity, highlights, shadows, color, and even bokeh effects. Adaptive Stabilization automatically determines the speed of movement and dynamically adjusts stabilization to provide the best results as well while you’re recording moving videos, like a sporting event or riding a bike.</p><p>Action Shot automatically increases and adjusts the shutter speed and illumination to account for the lighting condition; while Long Exposure helps you capture content like artistic light trails or waterfalls with a single tap. Super Zoom is also available, helping you take crisp photos from further away. It uses AI-based machine learning to help capture fine details.</p><p>Lee hasn’t had the chance to put these features and the cameras through their paces just yet: stay tuned for more details.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4089px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="3S8QFTpRzPa8aQLkLC4FqX" name="Motorola-Razr-Plus-2023-how-its-going-3.jpg" alt="The Motorola Razr Plus 2023 cover screen" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3S8QFTpRzPa8aQLkLC4FqX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4089" height="2300" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Nonetheless, with the Motorola Razr Plus 2023, the cameras leave much to be desired so you can be certain that they’re better in the Motorola Razr Plus 2024. There’s a decent 12MP wide camera and a 13MP ultrawide and macro camera that can take acceptable photos. The same goes for the 32MP front “selfie” camera. But these are nothing to write home about.</p><p>There are some interesting photo features beyond the usual in the Motorola Razr Plus 2023, like photo booth mode for taking a series of photos in a row, just like if you were in a photo booth. But there’s nothing particularly compelling about the camera experience with this phone.</p><p>Lee said photos taken with these cameras are “okay” and “fairly balanced,” but feel slightly muted: there’s something missing he just can’t put his finger on. Low light and night shots are decent, however, as are portrait and macro shots. So, you’ll get good results, just nothing jaw-droppingly great when it comes to photos you take with the Motorola Razr Plus 2023.</p>
<h2 id="motorola-razr-plus-2024-vs-razr-plus-2023-which-should-you-buy-2">Motorola Razr Plus 2024 vs. Razr Plus 2023: Which should you buy?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4027px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="uLCGmMeES929A7PKut7VnF" name="Motorola-Razr-Plus-2024-and-Razr-Plus-2023-1.jpg" alt="The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 next to the Razr Plus 2023" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uLCGmMeES929A7PKut7VnF.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4027" height="2265" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The decision between the Motorola Razr Plus 2024 vs. Razr Plus 2023 seems pretty obvious: go with the newer phone. It offers notable upgrades over the older model and comes in at the same starting price point that one did. Though you can find the Motorola Razr Plus 2023 for much cheaper now, it’s not worth getting, especially since Motorola doesn’t promise as many years of software and security updates as other brands.</p><p>If you’re concerned about cost, you can also consider the new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2024-launch">Motorola Razr 2024</a>,  which offers pared-down specs for a more affordable price. But comparing the Razr Plus 2024 to the Razr Plus 2023, you get plenty more AI features, much better cameras, a larger external screen on which you can do (and see) more, and a hinge that has been drastically improved.</p><p>We named the Motorola Razr Plus 2023 among <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">the best foldable phones</a>, but this model will likely be replaced by the Motorola Razr Plus 2024 in the ranking. If you’re considering a foldable phone, this model is a great option to consider that will be a solid upgrade or a first great device in this growing space.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="7b5ee585-4b28-48eb-af6f-3f436f9f119f">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QYAFTS6Yd3th4KVUFQcqY8.jpg' alt='Motorola Razr Plus 2024'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Motorola Razr Plus 2024</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The new flagship foldable </strong></em></p>
<p>If you’re considering a foldable phone and want to stick with Motorola, the Motorola Razr Plus 2024 is the one to go with. It incorporates all the latest AI features, some coming within the next few months, and boasts impressive specs that are worlds above the previous generation phone. You’ll appreciate the improved peak brightness, especially if you are outdoors a lot, the better cameras, more powerful processor, longer battery life, and more. Plus, there are funky new colors from which to choose.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="af4c944f-d6e3-48a2-b81c-5a40010482e2">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Jc85GVTAkFfiMQ4UeXdmXP.jpg' alt='Motorola Razr Plus 2023'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Motorola Razr Plus 2023</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>There was work to be done </strong></em></p>
<p>The Motorola Razr Plus 2023 was a great phone when it launched and it still is among the best foldable phones you can buy. But it will likely be replaced by the more powerful, better-designed Motorola Razr Plus 2024. If you’re buying new, you’re best to save up for this newer version. If you have the Razr Plus 2023, keep it until the upgrade cycle is here, and then look into enjoying the benefits of this new phone.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2024-vs-razr-plus-2023</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ If you're looking for a foldable phone, the Motorola Razr Plus 2024 is the latest version, a worthy step up from the Motorola Razr Plus 2023. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Tn6TaueFmfA5CyiRjriRzg</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uLCGmMeES929A7PKut7VnF.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 16:29:56 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ christinep2424@gmail.com (Christine Persaud) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uLCGmMeES929A7PKut7VnF.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 next to the Razr Plus 2023]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 next to the Razr Plus 2023]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Open AI holds off on releasing voice mode on Chat GPT ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>OpenAI took to X to announce that it will delay the launch of the advanced Voice Mode, which was slated for release this spring. </li><li>The company is testing the new voice model on a small group of people for feedback and learning before rolling it out to all Plus users.</li><li>If all goes as anticipated, the other Plus users will get access to the advanced voice model in the fall. </li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Open AI quickly tweeted on Tuesday (June 26) that it will be holding off on launching the advanced Voice Mode that was <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/openai-gpt-4o-launch-demo">demoed last month</a>. It planned to roll out this feature widely in the software&apos;s spring update; however, it looks like people who were looking to experiment with it need to wait a bit more.</p><p>The new voice assistant is said to have "human-like" conversations that users can interrupt, emoting and bringing life-like interactions like laughter, sarcasm, and humor that come as a relief from the usual robotic prompts we expect from an assistant. However, despite promising a quick rollout to subscribed users, OpenAI has now announced a delay in releasing the upgraded "Voice Mode" (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidpolice.com/openai-delays-chatgpts-new-voice-mode-by-a-month/">Android Police)</a>.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">We're sharing an update on the advanced Voice Mode we demoed during our Spring Update, which we remain very excited about:We had planned to start rolling this out in alpha to a small group of ChatGPT Plus users in late June, but need one more month to reach our bar to launch.…<a href="https://twitter.com/OpenAI/status/1805716393524183136">June 25, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>While it continues to test this new voice mode, the company says it will be giving access to it to a small group of ChatGPT Plus users in late June, and some of them have already received an update on their phones. One such user who got access took to X to share an invite she received. The invite stated, "advanced voice is in limited Alpha, it may make mistakes, and access (to it)  is subject to change."</p><p>Open AI stated that its systems will use the audio and video content that the user shares via Chat GPT to train the model better. Users can also opt out of sharing their data and training the model by hitting " improve the model for everyone" in settings.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">👀 pic.twitter.com/6RfCMkanN4<a href="https://twitter.com/wongmjane/status/1805863101637722167">June 26, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>The user also posted a tweet with the new voice of "Sky" that appears to be different from the one we heard at the Chat GPT- 4o announcement. Initially, users on social media pointed out the similarities between the voice of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/openai-trying-to-steal-scarlett-johanssons-voice-to-make-ai-feel-comfortable-is-the-reason-why-its-so-worrying">assistant and Scarlett Johansson</a>, the award-winning actress. However, OpenAI denied that Sky&apos;s voice was based on Johansson and even released a blog post explaining how the voices were chosen. The actress countered those claims with a statement about how OpenAI approached her about officially voicing GPT-4o, which she declined, and then the company quickly removed the Sky voice option from its platform.</p><p>The new voice has a more "cheery tone," the user states, as the voice model describes the weather in San Francisco. Other users on the same tweet thread seemed unhappy with the new voice. One user said, "It&apos;s horrifying; someone helps it," while others were particularly "cringed" by it, listen in below.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">GPT-4o talking about SF summer but in a very cheery tone pic.twitter.com/6taoPeVLdh<a href="https://twitter.com/wongmjane/status/1805873170957635795">June 26, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>OpenAI added in its tweet, that based on the feedback they recieved from this small group of testers, they will be planning to roll out the model to Plus users in the fall. </p><p>"Exact timelines depend on meeting our high safety and reliability bar. We are also working on rolling out the new video and screen sharing capabilities we demoed separately, and will keep you posted on that timeline."</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/open-ai-holds-off-on-releasing-voice-mode-on-chat-gpt</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Open AI showed off its Chat GPT-4o about a month ago in all its glory; however, now, the company says it needs more time to launch its Voice mode.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">aBzMzr7axHEY9oMXofw56d</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/UGgG32iy2pmgymUqdtABh8.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 15:57:18 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nandika.iyerravi@futurenet.com (Nandika Ravi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/UGgG32iy2pmgymUqdtABh8.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[OpenAI]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The announcement of GPT-4o.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The announcement of GPT-4o.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Our favorite Android smartwatch (for now) just got hit with an $82 discount at Walmart — but how long will it last? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Good Samsung watch deals are often few and far between, so if you&apos;re in the market, this might be your chance. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Samsung-Galaxy-Watch6-Smart-Watch-40mm-Small-Bluetooth-Graphite/3074183240"><strong>Walmart has temporarily cut $82 off the price of the Samsung Galaxy Watch 6</strong></a>, our favorite Android smartwatch that&apos;s available today. The Galaxy Watch 6 comes with user-friendly Wear OS performance, blazingly fast charging speeds, and a bright, beautiful display that users love. The Watch 6 also has an improved capacitive bezel, personalized HR zones, and useful health features like passive AFib detection.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="8e0ae724-c598-4c8e-9477-c66676e60102" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy Watch 6: $299.99" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy Watch 6: $299.99" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Samsung-Galaxy-Watch6-Smart-Watch-40mm-Small-Bluetooth-Graphite/3074183240" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="MEqKzmeq6vKueYbJ3R3ajF" name="Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 render bg.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MEqKzmeq6vKueYbJ3R3ajF.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy Watch 6: </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Samsung-Galaxy-Watch6-Smart-Watch-40mm-Small-Bluetooth-Graphite/3074183240" data-dimension112="8e0ae724-c598-4c8e-9477-c66676e60102" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy Watch 6: $299.99" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy Watch 6: $299.99"><del>$299.99</del> <strong>$217.88 at Walmart</strong></a></p>
<p>Until the Galaxy Watch 7 arrives, the Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 is perhaps the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch#section-best-overall">best Android watch</a> out there, in no small part due to its large, aesthetically pleasing screen and minimal design. Walmart cutting $82 off the price of the Watch 6 almost brings it down to the prices of prior-generation Samsung watches. Going with the Watch 6 instead of past generations will net you better performance, an improved capacitive bezel, and an enlarged display, so it's easy to consider upgrading with this big of a price cut.</p>
<p><strong>Price comparison: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-watch6-aluminum-smartwatch-40mm-bt-cream/6546702.p">Best Buy - $269.99</a> | <a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Bluetooth-Smartwatch-Personalized-Advanced/dp/B0C792QRW6">Amazon - $234.99</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Samsung-Galaxy-Watch6-Smart-Watch-40mm-Small-Bluetooth-Graphite/3074183240" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="8e0ae724-c598-4c8e-9477-c66676e60102" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy Watch 6: $299.99" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy Watch 6: $299.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>battery charging speeds are a major priority for you when it comes to a smartwatch; you want a premium smartwatch at a discount price; you&apos;re looking for a watch with a large, easy-to-read display.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if:</strong> you need a smartwatch that&apos;s especially long-lasting; you want to wait for the arrival of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-7">Galaxy Watch 7</a>; you&apos;d rather get a smartwatch that&apos;s even cheaper than what this deal can offer.</p><p>There&apos;s more than one reason why the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-6-review">Samsung Galaxy Watch 6</a> is the best smartwatch on the market today, but the speedy performance and good-looking display certainly help lead the charge. The Watch 6 also features the easy-to-use Wear OS, and it tends to be compatible with a wide range of smartphone brands.</p><p>If you want industry-leading battery life, you might want to consider the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oneplus-watch-2-review">OnePlus Watch 2</a> instead. The Watch 6 has also been called out for some occasionally inaccurate GPS mapping, so many folks are waiting to see what the Galaxy Watch 7 offers when it&apos;s presumably revealed next month. In any case, if you&apos;re in the market for a great smartwatch at a great price, this is a certifiably good deal. </p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/our-favorite-android-smartwatch-for-now-just-got-hit-with-an-dollar82-discount-at-walmart-but-how-long-will-it-last</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 is the best smartwatch on the market — for now at least — and $82 off the purchase price doesn't hurt its case, either. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">H33mdEXfj6rvUUgwdVMjB6</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/V6e8aVYQq3ppzrzpu2RwHY.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 15:10:19 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/V6e8aVYQq3ppzrzpu2RwHY.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Samsung]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Official lifestyle images of the Samsung Galaxy Watch 6]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Official lifestyle images of the Samsung Galaxy Watch 6]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ What color Motorola Razr Plus 2024 should you buy? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The Motorola Razr Plus 2023 was such a success that Motorola rolled out its successor in even brighter and spunkier shades. If you&apos;re wondering what color Motorola Razr Plus 2024 you should buy, look no further. We&apos;re here to speed up your decision-making process.</p><p>Before you settle down on a single colorway, let&apos;s look at all the variants of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2024-hands-on">Motorola Razr+ 2024</a>, also known as the Motorola Razr 50 Ultra in some markets.</p>
<h2 id="these-are-all-the-colors-of-the-razr-2024-2">These are all the colors of the Razr+ 2024</h2>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="e3b540f8-1bed-4428-9af9-2043ac0de5fa">
            <a href="https://www.motorola.com/us/smartphones-razr-gen-4" data-model-name="Motorola Razr Plus 2024"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ePypxEuu6W83HkCJHHGcDQ.jpg' alt='The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 in Peach Fuzz'></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Motorola Razr Plus 2024 - Peach Fuzz</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Feeling peachy</strong></em></p>
<p>This light orangish coral shade is a delightful look on the Motorola Razr Plus 2024. Peach Fuzz is a joyful, fun shade and it's our favorite colorway for the Razr+ 2024.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="b0ec7418-15bf-4321-b149-3d128bd589d7">
            <a href="https://www.motorola.com/us/smartphones-razr-gen-4" data-model-name="Motorola Razr Plus 2024"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BTfNT9WVYLbwsXmfm9k49M.jpg' alt='The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 in Hot Pink'></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Motorola Razr Plus 2024 - Hot Pink</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Furiously funky</strong></em></p>
<p>Hot Pink is a spiritual successor to last-gen's Viva Magenta colorway. Go for this if you want to embrace a bold look on your Motorola Razr Plus 2024.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="4cf6c9e0-5f49-49ab-add2-85107244254a">
            <a href="https://www.motorola.com/us/smartphones-razr-gen-4" data-model-name="Motorola Razr Plus 2024"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NQq6NGpeAutUsMnKkHE2XT.jpg' alt='The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 in Spring Green'></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Motorola Razr Plus 2024 - Spring</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Leafy and fresh</strong></em></p>
<p>The green Spring shade is a new entry with the Motorola Razr Plus 2024. It's a fresh, leafy hue that reminds one of trees, forests, and everything green.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="26832d5b-9c25-442a-8b50-33d76db463a2">
            <a href="https://www.motorola.com/us/smartphones-razr-gen-4" data-model-name="Motorola Razr Plus 2024"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rt3W2PrRDM8f9QhZvjh9PQ.jpg' alt='The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 in Midnight Blue'></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Motorola Razr Plus 2024 - Midnight Blue</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Classy blue</strong></em></p>
<p>Can you even go wrong with blue? This dark Midnight Blue color is an elegant option. Anyone who loves aqua hues will love this option.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<ul><li><a href="#main"><strong>Back to the top ^</strong></a></li></ul>
<h2 id="there-are-four-motorola-razr-plus-2024-colors-to-choose-from-2">There are four Motorola Razr Plus 2024 colors to choose from</h2>
<p>Wondering what color Motorola Razr Plus 2024 should you buy? There are four stunning variants to choose from, giving you plenty of choice. Naturally, getting a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-motorola-phones">Motorola phone</a> in your favorite color should make the decision making process easy.</p><p>If you&apos;re not aligned with one specific hue outright, we suggest picking the unique colors like Peach Fuzz or Hot Pink. Blues and greens are very commonplace when it comes to phone colors these days, so corals and pinks stand out and make a big statement.</p><p>Even if you know you&apos;ll be putting your Motorola Razr Plus 2024 in a case, be sure to choose a nice color that you&apos;re really in love with. A folding phone is a luxury, so you should go all out when treating yourself to such a delight.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-color-motorola-razr-plus-2024-should-you-buy</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ There are four shades to choose from when buying the Motorola Razr Plus 2024. Here's a look at them all to help you choose which one to buy. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">9wt5x8ncdDS99muNzbVcHR</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QuDchN85zhGGbZHmG7hKM.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 14:38:35 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QuDchN85zhGGbZHmG7hKM.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 and Razr 2024 colors]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 and Razr 2024 colors]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ How many software updates will the Motorola Razr Plus 2024 receive? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <section class="article__schema-question"><h3>How many software updates will the Motorola Razr Plus 2024 receive?</h3><article class="article__schema-answer"><p><strong>Best answer:</strong> Three years of OS updates and four years of bi-monthly security updates. It may not seem like much, but it's better than the Moto G34 that will only get one Android upgrade.</p></article></section>
<h2 id="what-to-expect-when-dealing-with-updates-from-motorola-2">What to expect when dealing with updates from Motorola</h2>
<p>When looking for your next phone, it&apos;s important to see how many software updates it&apos;ll receive. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2024-hands-on">Motorola Razr Plus 2024</a> has fewer updates than other models, such as the Google Pixel 8 Pro, which is promised eight years of software and security updates. This is only one update more than the Galaxy S24 series, which promises seven years of updates. Another <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phone</a> that offers the same number of updates as the Razr Plus 2024 is the Motorola Edge Plus 2023, with the same three Android upgrades and four years of patching.</p><p>While three years of software updates and four years of security patches might not seem extensive, it surpasses the support offered for many other Motorola phones. For example, the Moto G 5G series phone only gets one Android OS update and three years. With only one upgrade, users are shortly left out of the loop regarding the latest features.</p><p>Motorola has a reputation for not being very generous regarding model updates. That&apos;s why it&apos;s best to research before committing to a specific model, especially if the phone you want to buy is a budget model. Budget models usually get one or two years of updates. Even if you&apos;re happy with the number of updates the phone will get, Motorola is slow in rolling out those promised updates.</p><p>If you&apos;re unsure whether your phone will get that update, you can try using <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://en-us.support.motorola.com/app/software-upgrade/g_id/1949/">Motorola&apos;s online tool</a>. It&apos;s an easy-to-use tool where you&apos;ll need to answer some questions, such as where you purchased your phone, and click on some models Motorola will show you. If you don&apos;t see your Moto model in the listed options, your phone will not get any more software updates.</p>
<h2 id="what-do-android-updates-usually-bring-in-the-razr-plus-2024-or-other-models-2">What do Android updates usually bring in the Razr Plus 2024 or other models?</h2>
<p>Software updates fall into two main categories: major and minor. Usually released annually, major updates introduce significant changes like new features, interface redesigns, and enhancements. Minor updates focus on bug fixes and smaller feature additions.</p><p>Major updates involve you going from Android 13 to Android 14. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a> will bring all sorts of new features you won&apos;t want to miss out on—for example, better multitasking, partial screen recording, audio sharing, notification cooldown, and more.</p><p>Minor updates, on the other hand, bring bug fixes or more minor features. These security updates can be so small that you might not even notice your phone received one. You&apos;ll likely get more of these types of updates after a major software update since they usually come with issues. You can quickly check to see if your phone has a software update pending by going to Settings > System updates. The steps may vary depending on your model phone, but they should not differ too much. </p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="8889fb3e-a5f8-48d7-ab5c-239f680caf54">
            <a href="https://www.motorola.com/us/smartphones-razr-gen-4" data-model-name="Motorola Razr Plus 2024"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/znCGGT5zMeoWnypVRNhjQW.jpg' alt='The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 in Spring Green'></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Motorola Razr Plus 2024</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="90" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Flipping the script</strong></em></p>
<p>The new Motorola Razr Plus 2024 comes with the latest Snapdragon 8s Gen 3 processor for access to new AI features, an even larger 6.9-inch screen for a better app experience, and an improved camera system that lets you get up close and personal with its 50MP rear and 32MP front-facing camera.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/how-many-software-updates-will-the-motorola-razr-plus-2024-receive</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ If software updates are important to you, see how many software updates the Motorola Razr Plus 2024 will get to know if it makes it your next smartphone or not. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">gpbXtKnC9WtKp4R3yqkJBk</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/C2YUaSYpySqHXGVJUgu2ob.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 13:44:22 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ judysanhz30@gmail.com (Judy Sanhz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/C2YUaSYpySqHXGVJUgu2ob.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 next to the Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 5]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 next to the Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 5]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Apple's policy changes aren't good enough for the EU — iOS might get closer to Android ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The European Union's Digital Markets Act, which took effect earlier this year, aims to improve competition and interoperability among big tech companies. </li><li>Apple made a few policy changes in the EU to attempt to comply with the DMA. However, the EU started investing Google, Meta, and Apple for possible noncompliance in March.</li><li>Now, a preliminary report explains how the EU wants Apple to change iOS — and it sounds a lot like Android. </li></ul>
<hr>
<p>When the European Union&apos;s long-awaited <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/what-is-digital-markets-act">Digital Markets Act (DMA)</a> took effect earlier this year, it caused an industry-wide shakeup among big tech companies. Since the law is new and has many subjective elements, some companies didn&apos;t appear entirely sure how to comply with the DMA. After reviewing their compliance plans, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/alphabet-apple-and-meta-are-under-investigation-in-europe-for-non-compliance-with-the-digital-markets-act">EU formally announced an investigation</a> into potential noncompliance by Meta, Alphabet (Google), and Apple in March 2024.</p><p>The legislation primarily covers the biggest tech corporations that operate in the EU, dubbed "gatekeepers." These are Alphabet, Amazon, Apple, ByteDance, Meta, and Microsoft for now, but that list could expand in the future. Gatekeepers are bound by certain DMA requirements, including the requirement that their specific "core platform services" must be cross-platform. </p><p>In an attempt to comply with the DMA, Apple made various changes to iOS and the App Store in the EU. Alternative app stores and third-party default browsers were added to the iPhone&apos;s operating system for the first time. Additionally, the App Store rules were overhauled, adding alternative payment processors and allowing steering practices. </p><p>However, the company also added a Core Technology Fee of "€0.50 for each first annual install per year over a 1 million threshold." It also added a 3% fee for using Apple&apos;s own payment processing system. These charges are part of Apple&apos;s "new business terms in the EU." App developers have the choice of sticking with the old terms (which the EU isn&apos;t a fan of) or accepting the new terms with new fees. For what it&apos;s worth, Apple <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2024/01/apple-announces-changes-to-ios-safari-and-the-app-store-in-the-european-union/" target="_blank">estimated</a> that 99% of developers would pay the same or less under the new terms. </p><p>It&apos;s clear that Apple isn&apos;t thrilled about the DMA, though. "The changes we’re announcing today comply with the Digital Markets Act’s requirements in the European Union while helping to protect EU users from the unavoidable increased privacy and security threats this regulation brings," said Apple Fellow and App Store chief Phil Schiller in a January 2024 press release. "Our priority remains creating the best, most secure possible experience for our users in the EU and around the world."</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="oycDpSH3ipPWhnFiY5ziU6" name="iphone-15-pro-max-10.jpg" alt="iPhone 15 Pro Max review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oycDpSH3ipPWhnFiY5ziU6.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The EU disagrees with Apple&apos;s claim that it is compliant with DMA requirements in preliminary statements. In a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/ip_24_3433" target="_blank">press release</a> shared this week, the European Commission provided details on what areas of the DMA it believes Apple may be violating. The EU also announced that it is opening a new investigation into Apple, this time looking into the company&apos;s new business terms, including the Core Technology Fee. </p><p>Here&apos;s a quick summary of the EU&apos;s preliminary opinion of Apple&apos;s shortcomings with regard to DMA compliance:</p>
<ul><li>The EU claims that Apple does not allow app developers to "freely" steer their customers outside the Apple ecosystem. It explains that developers can't provide alternative pricing information in their app directly and can't communicate with users in all ways.</li><li>Separately, the EU says Apple's "link-out" method of steering does not fulfill DMA requirements. It adds that Apple's restrictions on this method, including preventing open communication between the developers and users, could potentially represent noncompliance. </li><li>Finally, the EU argues that the "fees charged by Apple go beyond what is strictly necessary" as compensation for customer acquisition on iOS and through the App Store.</li></ul>
<p>These findings are not finalized, and the EU says that Apple will have the chance to defend its position against the claims. On top of this, there is the new inquiry into Apple&apos;s contract terms with app developers. For that investigation, the EU will presumably have a full 12-month period to look into potential violations. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="yLC3zDH6ZbFVPskxwaDKpg" name="oneplus-12-vs-iphone-15-pro-max-19.jpg" alt="OnePlus 12 vs. iPhone 15 Pro Max" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yLC3zDH6ZbFVPskxwaDKpg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It&apos;s not hard to predict where this saga is heading, though. Based on the EU&apos;s early findings, the Commission wants Apple to open iOS and the App Store more. It wants contract terms and steering permissions that level the playing field, whether a developer wants to go through the App Store directly or use a third party. In other words, the EU wants iOS and the App Store to work a lot like Android already does today. </p>
<h2 id="is-this-really-competition-2">Is this really competition?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="3kgqwSRVz4Up3zNT2YJx6g" name="oneplus-12-vs-iphone-15-pro-max-14.jpg" alt="OnePlus 12 vs. iPhone 15 Pro Max" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3kgqwSRVz4Up3zNT2YJx6g.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Regardless of whether you agree or disagree with the DMA, there are some parts of the EU&apos;s statement that may be alarming. For starters, it seems brazen for the European Commission to claim that Apple charges more than is "strictly necessary" in App Store fees. Sure, the fees are significant, but how is the EU valuing Apple&apos;s platforms and user base? When an app is available on the App Store, it immediately gets in front of over a billion devices. That makes it one of the most lucrative platforms on the planet, and it&apos;s extremely difficult to put a price on that.</p><p>The whole concept that the EU would require companies only to charge what is "strictly necessary" appears to go against the market system we use fundamentally. For example, if it costs a coffee shop about $3 to make my iced latte in materials and overhead, would it be illegal for the shop to charge $10? Of course not. Businesses set their prices, and consumers vote with their wallets on whether the price is reasonable. If it&apos;s overpriced, consumers (or, in this case, developers) just won&apos;t buy it. </p><p>Though I find the EU&apos;s logic above suspect, I&apos;ll leave that debate up to the lawyers. To me, the bigger question is whether <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/everything-ios-18-stole-from-android">requiring iOS to be a carbon copy of Android</a> is <em>really</em> competition. Is fair competition being able to use an open ecosystem on whichever platform you choose, or is it being able to choose an open ecosystem (Android) <em>or</em> a closed one (iOS)? I&apos;ve said this before, and I&apos;ll say it again: the DMA may end up creating less competition, not more. </p><p>Based on the EU&apos;s preliminary findings, it looks like the European Commission wants iOS to work like Android. Only time will tell whether that&apos;s really what the buyers want. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/apples-policy-changes-arent-good-enough-for-the-eu-ios-might-get-closer-to-android</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Apple already made iOS more like Android to comply with the DMA, but the European Commission wants more. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">gpx3VtJx2r5au7o595GrFH</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tQA6wo7Mpgr6aTuXKm7UX7.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 12:56:33 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tQA6wo7Mpgr6aTuXKm7UX7.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[iPhone 15 Pro Max review]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[iPhone 15 Pro Max review]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Honor's latest AI features want to fight deep fake videos and eye strain ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Honor's new AI Defocus Eye Protection combats screen-induced eye strain and myopia by blurring peripheral vision while keeping the center clear.</li><li>The feature is claimed to reduce transient myopia by an average of 13 degrees, with some users seeing up to a 75-degree improvement.</li><li>Meanwhile, Honor also unveiled a new detection tech that uses AI to analyze eye contact, lighting, and image clarity in real time to detect deepfakes.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Honor has introduced two new AI-driven features designed to keep users safe and healthy.</p><p>Honor showcased its new <em>AI Defocus Eye Protection</em> tech at MWC Shanghai. As its name implies, this new on-device feature uses AI to tackle the rising issue of screen-induced eye strain, with a special focus on combating myopia (nearsightedness).</p><p>The rapid increase in computer and mobile phone use in recent years has gone hand in hand with a worrying rise in global cases of myopia. This is largely due to the prolonged strain on our eyes from focusing on screens up close. Over time, this constant close-up viewing can cause the eyeball to elongate, leading to nearsightedness.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:875px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:48.57%;"><img id="PjHzDss3ygbYJ65FoNoTga" name="HONOR-AI-Defocus-Eye-Protection.png" alt="Honor AI Defocus Eye Protection" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PjHzDss3ygbYJ65FoNoTga.png" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="875" height="425" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Honor)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Honor&apos;s new feature is intended to replicate defocus glasses on your smartphone screen. Defocus glasses are great for your eyes because they blur your peripheral vision while keeping the center clear, helping reduce eye elongation.</p><p>While defocus glasses use corrective lenses, the exact workings of Honor&apos;s AI Defocus Eye Protection technology are still under wraps. However, Honor claims that this software solution can significantly reduce transient myopia in users, averaging a 13-degree reduction, with some seeing improvements up to 75 degrees.</p><p>The other feature is pretty intriguing. Honor claims it can detect fake content using AI by analyzing eye contact, lighting, and image clarity. It even works in real time to thwart video impersonation scams before they can do any damage.</p><p>In the AI era, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-and-universal-music-to-tackle-ai-deepfakes-in-music">deepfakes are increasingly problematic</a>. These realistic but fake media are hard to spot and pose a big online threat. Bad actors use them to hide identities, impersonate others, or create fake personas. This issue underscores the need for strong measures to protect against deepfake scams.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1357px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:41.34%;"><img id="34q2UvgchBrobLqszndSTa" name="HONOR-AI-Deepfake-Detection.png" alt="Honor AI Deepfake Detection" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/34q2UvgchBrobLqszndSTa.png" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1357" height="561" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Honor)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Honor says its AI deepfake detection scans video calls in just three seconds. If a fake is spotted, users get an instant on-screen warning, helping them avoid potential scams.</p><p>The company&apos;s deepfake detection runs on a carefully curated dataset of videos and images. This collection helps the AI spot common scam signs and subtle anomalies that reveal deepfakes.</p><p>It&apos;s unclear if these features work entirely on-device, but real-time deepfake detection likely needs an internet connection. The company also hasn&apos;t shared which <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-honor-phones">Honor phones</a> will support these features or when they&apos;ll be available. More details should be coming soon.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/honors-latest-ai-features-want-to-fight-deep-fake-videos-and-eye-strain</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Honor unveils AI eye care and deepfake busting technology at MWC Shanghai. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">x4J6NMojEafeRzXpkQpZ9k</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LhAv9RqTcfVotWTkzNjZYP.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 08:58:21 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LhAv9RqTcfVotWTkzNjZYP.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Honor 200 Pro face down on a corner]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Honor 200 Pro face down on a corner]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>