<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 10:25:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Files by Google has a new PDF viewer, and it's ditching Google Drive ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google is rolling out a new PDF viewer for the Files by Google app, as it shared in a recent update to the app's Play Store listing.</li><li>The old PDF viewer incorporated Google Drive, but now, the new one is specific to Google Files.</li><li>It's easier to share, star, and take actions while viewing a PDF while using the new Files by Google interface.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Files by Google is getting a minor upgrade that could improve your PDF viewing experience. The app is rolling out a new view that leverages a custom PDF viewer, rather than using the integrated one from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-drive">Google Drive</a>. This will make accessing certain options easier, such as starring a PDF or sharing it with others. Alternatively, you can still use the PDF viewer in the Google Drive app if you prefer the previous user-interface.</p><p>Google previewed the change in an update to the "What's new" section of the Files by Google <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.nbu.files&pli=1" target="_blank">app listing on</a> the Google Play Store. "Over the next few weeks, we’re rolling out improvements to your experience with PDF files," the note reads. "Print, find content, or access markup tools whenever you open a PDF in the Files app."</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/12/16/files-by-google-pdf-viewer/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a> first spotted that the change was rolling out to users of version 1.5687 of the Google Files app after a server-side tweak. Android Central confirmed the new PDF viewer on its devices, but notably, one device had to be updated to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a> before the change took effect.</p><p>You can see the new look of the PDF viewer in Files by Google in the screenshots below.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4480px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="JS8osd24PJZhzVjAhtSUdM" name="Files-PDF-Viewer" alt="A PDF opened in the Files by Google app on various versions." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JS8osd24PJZhzVjAhtSUdM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4480" height="2520" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="caption-text">From left to right: Old PDF viewer, new PDF viewer, new PDF viewer + overflow menu. </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Future)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Now, the overflow menu lets you access key options that weren't available using the previous UI. With the old version, some menu buttons were only accessible through the list view of documents in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/files-by-google-gains-receive-floating-action-button">Files by Google app</a>. They weren't there after the PDF was opened using the external Drive viewer, but that has been rectified with the new Files by Google custom PDF viewer.</p><p>The <strong>Find</strong> and <strong>Save to Drive</strong> icons have been replaced with <strong>Star</strong> and <strong>Share </strong>on the new viewer. These can be pressed without opening the overflow menu. The new overflow menu includes more options, including <strong>Use as</strong>, <strong>Open with</strong>, <strong>Move to Trash</strong>, <strong>Move to</strong>, <strong>Copy to</strong>, <strong>Move to Safe folder</strong>, <strong>File info</strong>, <strong>Find in file</strong>, and <strong>Print</strong>.</p><p>Finally, the markup button (floating action button) has been redesigned, and some files will have a <strong>Google Lens</strong> button above it that quickly opens <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-circle-to-search">Circle to Search</a>.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/files-by-google-has-a-new-pdf-viewer-and-its-ditching-google-drive</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google Files previously used Google Drive for PDF viewing, but it now has a native viewer with streamlined sharing options. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">tXM7DsqmceKnhTSU6FjdhS</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DHBUGU9NDPcNNLvihKXmJ5.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 02:54:29 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DHBUGU9NDPcNNLvihKXmJ5.jpeg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Joe Maring / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Files&#039; home screen.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Files&#039; home screen.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Android 15 QPR2 Beta 2 is here with our first look at the working Linux Terminal app ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google today released Android 15 QPR2 Beta 2 for testers enrolled in the Android Beta Program.</li><li>The update includes bug fixes and improvements, as well as an early look at a few work-in-progress features.</li><li>Notably, the Linux Terminal app can be opened after upgrading to Android 15 QPR2 Beta 2.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a> QPR2 Beta 2 update is rolling out to testers on eligible Pixel devices starting today, Dec. 16, Google announced in a Reddit <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/android_beta/comments/1hftm6b/android_15_qpr2_beta_2_now_available/" target="_blank">post</a> on the official Android Beta Program subreddit. The update includes a variety of bug fixes and other improvements; however, the exciting part of Android 15 QPR2 Beta 2 is what wasn't officially announced.</p><p>A few work-in-progress features spotted in earlier versions of Android 15 beta releases now appear to be functional. For starters, the Linux Terminal app for Android is now working in Android 15 QPR2 Beta 2. The new app was first spotted in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-qpr2-beta-1-pixel-test-start">Android 15 QPR2 Beta 1</a>, but didn't work — it would crash after trying to load a new virtual machine. Now, in Android 15 QPR2 Beta 2, the app can download, configure, and run instances of Linux using the Android Virtualization Framework.</p><p>Android 15 QPR2 Beta 2 testers confirmed the Linux Terminal app worked after upgrading, and so did Android expert Mishaal Rahman in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/MishaalRahman/status/1868798147989844270" target="_blank">post</a> on X (formerly Twitter). It isn't the only previously-covered feature to appear as part of the update. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16-has-a-new-trick-to-put-a-damper-on-annoying-app-pings#:~:text=You%20can%20find%20notification%20cooldown,it%20can%20be%20super%20annoying.">Notification cooldowns</a>, which were originally thought to be an Android 16 feature, are also working in Android 15 QPR2 Beta 2.</p>
<blockquote class="reddit-card"  ><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/android_beta/comments/1hftm6b/android_15_qpr2_beta_2_now_available">Android 15 QPR2 Beta 2 now available!</a> from <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/android_beta">r/android_beta</a></blockquote><script async src="//embed.redditmedia.com/widgets/platform.js" charset="UTF-8"></script>
<p>The update is available now for the Pixel 6 series, Pixel 7 series, Pixel 8 series, and Pixel 9 series, and the Pixel Fold and Pixel Tablet. You can enroll in the Android Beta Program to receive beta Android 15 QPR2 updates over the air, or install the update manually. You can join the program via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="http://g.co/androidbeta" target="_blank">this link</a>.</p><p>Google notes that it can take up to 24 hours for the update to appear, and you can manually check for an update by navigating to <strong>Settings > System > System updates</strong>.</p><p>The build number for Android 15 QPR2 Beta 2 is <strong>BP11.241121.010</strong>, and it carries an update size raining from megabytes to a few gigabytes, depending on your device model. It fixes the following bugs, per Google's release notes:</p>
<ul><li>Fixed an issue that prevented the "ANGLE preferences" option from being accessed in developer options. (<a href="https://issuetracker.google.com/issues/379196574" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Issue #379196574</u></a>)</li><li>Fixed an issue that prevented some glucose sensor devices from connecting. (<a href="https://issuetracker.google.com/issues/378816128" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Issue #378816128</u></a>)</li><li>Fixed issues that caused a long delay while selecting options to place a call. (<a href="https://issuetracker.google.com/issues/379266329" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Issue #379266329</u></a>, <a href="https://issuetracker.google.com/issues/378854091" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Issue #378854091</u></a>)</li><li>Fixed an issue that prevented the "Limit to 80%" option in charging optimization settings from being enabled. (<a href="https://issuetracker.google.com/issues/378800194" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Issue #378800194</u></a>)</li><li>Fixed null pointer issues that could cause devices to unexpectedly crash or restart. (<a href="https://issuetracker.google.com/issues/378856187" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Issue #378856187</u></a>, <a href="https://issuetracker.google.com/issues/381894854" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Issue #381894854</u></a>)</li><li>Fixed an issue that sometimes caused Pixel Fold devices to stop responding while unfolded. (<a href="https://issuetracker.google.com/issues/379387626" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Issue #379387626</u></a>)</li><li>Fixed a bug of inconsistent behavior during switch from ASHA to LE Audio and back, ensuring the audio always pauses when switching.</li><li>Fixed a bug that causes L2CAP connection failure with error reason code 3 after a phone reboot due to incorrect security level saving during pairing, leading to a security check failure on Bluetooth reset.</li><li>Fixed a bug that allowed LE links to remain unencrypted on reconnection with bonded devices, potentially exposing sensitive data to attackers.</li><li>Fixing a bug of Bluetooth HAL crashes or gets stuck when Bluetooth LE audio hardware offload is disabled.</li></ul>
<p>To provide feedback, you can submit comments using the Android Beta Feedback app or post comments on the official Android Beta Program subreddit.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-qpr2-beta-2-is-here-with-our-first-look-at-the-working-linux-terminal-app</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Android 15 QPR2 Beta 2 is available now, and with it the March Feature Drop is starting to come into fruition. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">5CLgBntuFMA4AQxwRzn9j9</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/eVc6dkCxz3spdacUidzBUo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 01:33:12 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/eVc6dkCxz3spdacUidzBUo.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android 15 home page on Pixel 9, Pixel 9 Pro XL, and Pixel 9 Pro Fold]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android 15 home page on Pixel 9, Pixel 9 Pro XL, and Pixel 9 Pro Fold]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ A MediaTek modem could make or break the Pixel 10 — Google can’t screw this up ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Before the Google Pixel 9 series was officially revealed, I was <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-tensor-g4-rumors">already looking ahead to the Pixel 10</a>. That’s because the Pixel 10 is expected to gain a major performance boost since the Tensor G5 chip is expected to be fabricated using TSMC’s 3nm process. To my surprise, Google managed to ship a quite compelling product in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9">Pixel 9</a>. Regardless, the Pixel 10 is still something to be excited about — even with this new wild card.</p><p>There’s a part of your smartphone that is absolutely crucial to how you use it to connect with others, access your favorite apps and sites, and more. It’s also one you probably don’t think about often: the modem. According to Android Authority, Google is reportedly <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-tipped-to-bring-mediatek-5g-modem-to-pixel-10-series" target="_blank">exploring a switch from Samsung modems to a MediaTek modem on the Pixel 10</a>, and it could have significant implications.</p><p>High-speed, reliable 5G modems are hard to come by, and only a few companies in the world can make them. Qualcomm dominated the space for years and still dominates to an extent. However, due to cost and other reasons, smartphone manufacturers have been trying to move away from Qualcomm modems.</p><p>That leaves Samsung and MediaTek as the only other companies with the capabilities of producing a modern 5G modem. That is, unless it wanted to make its own. Apple is an example of how difficult it is to take that path to building a new modem. It got a head start by purchasing Intel’s mobile modem business in 2019, and five years later, it is still trying to build one reliable and competitive enough to best the Qualcomm ones it uses in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/apple-iphone-16-pro-max-review" target="_blank">iPhone 16 series</a>.</p><p>That’s why it isn’t all that surprising that Google probably won’t make a modem in-house. Developing a custom system-on-a-chip, like Google’s Tensor series, is a different thing entirely. Modems can make or break the smartphone experience, and every switch carries the risk of potential disaster.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="nA3naoxQorm7Jzh2wwgaZB" name="google-pixel-9-pro-pixel-9-pro-xl-8.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro and Pixel 9 Pro XL in tree" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nA3naoxQorm7Jzh2wwgaZB.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>For years, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-details-pixel-9-modem-security-improvements">Google has used Samsung modems in Pixel phones</a>. The move correlated with the shift to Google’s in-house Tensor processor, which is fabricated by Samsung. The idea is simple — it’s easy to use an Exynos modem with an Exynos chip. The newest <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-review">Google Pixel 9</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-review">Pixel 9 Pro, Pixel 9 Pro XL</a>, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-fold-review">Pixel 9 Pro Fold</a> all use Exynos modems to this day, likely for that reason.</p><p>However, all signs point to the next Tensor G5 chip being fabricated by a company other than Samsung. In fact, it’s nearly a lock that the Tensor G5 will be produced using TSMC’s advanced 3nm process node. Back in July, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-has-reportedly-finished-designing-the-pixel-10s-custom-tensor-g5-soc">Google reportedly gave the green light to manufacture the Tensor G5</a> on TSMC’s 3nm process. If easy integration and cost were reasons for Google using Samsung modems, they wouldn’t be applicable to future Pixels now that Google is moving away from using Samsung Foundry for Tensor chipmaking.</p><p>That means Google is poised to make a switch, and its choice will be an interesting one. After all, only a handful of brands use external modems. Qualcomm integrates its modems with its systems-on-a-chip, so any phone using a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/snapdragon-8-elite">Snapdragon 8 Elite</a> processor will also feature a Qualcomm modem. So, Google could purchase an external modem from either Samsung, Qualcomm, or MediaTek to pair with its Tensor G5 chip.</p><p>Google reportedly settled on MediaTek, specifically on using an unannounced MediaTek T900 modem in the Pixel 10 series. Per the report, it considered a few options, including <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-snapdragon-x75-5g-modem">Qualcomm’s X75 modem</a>, in its upcoming phones. It’s unclear what led Google to decide on MediaTek modems, but efficiency and cost are presumably two large factors. The tight integration between Samsung’s 5G modems and Google’s Tensor processors can be partially attributed to the excellent efficiency and battery life offered by Pixel phones.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="Ppx2XnXUjksHgLDqz4RePJ" name="google-pixel-9-pro-pixel-9-pro-xl-10.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro and Pixel 9 Pro XL angled view" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Ppx2XnXUjksHgLDqz4RePJ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It’s impossible to say how the MediaTek T900 modem will perform compared to the top options from Samsung and Qualcomm, considering it’s not even available yet. Additionally, since MediaTek, Samsung, and Qualcomm all integrate their in-house modems with their SoCs, there isn’t a lot of data covering how they’d perform as external modems.</p><p>With that caveat in mind, there’s still an adage that I think applies in this case: if it ain’t broke, don’t fit it. Google has found a great balance between 5G performance and efficiency with its current Samsung Exynos modems, and disrupting that carries a huge risk. Of course, it was probably inevitable since Google would disrupt the easy integration of Samsung-produced chips and modems when it moved to TSMC on the Tensor G5.</p><p>In that case, why not shoot for the best and use Qualcomm modems? The Qualcomm X75 is still clearly the industry standard for 5G modem technology, and it’s found inside the iPhone 16 series. Crucially, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.qualcomm.com/news/releases/2023/08/qualcomm-achieves-world-s-fastest-5g-downlink-with-sub-6-ghz-ban" target="_blank">the X75 achieved the world record</a> for the fastest 5G downlink. It’s an absolutely fantastic modem that’s reliable, and it beats anything that MediaTek, Samsung, and Apple currently have the ability to make.</p><p>I'll reiterate that while the reasons behind the MediaTek move will probably never be known, it’s likely that cost is a driving factor. In that case, I’m disappointed. Pixel phones are not exactly cheap anymore, and going for the best 5G modem available would’ve given Google even more credibility as a manufacturer of some of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a>.</p><p>Instead, it appears that Google went the cheap route. Only time will tell whether that was the right or wrong decision. The modem is a part of your phone you hope you don’t have to think about. If this move works out in Google’s favor, no one will talk about the new modem on the Pixel 10.</p><p>However, it’s a move Google can’t afford to get wrong. It could completely undermine the real progress it’ll make with Tensor G5 on the Pixel 10.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/mediatek-modem-could-make-or-break-google-pixel-10</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The latest reports indicate that Google could be switching from Samsung to MediaTek modems — here’s what that will mean for the Pixel 10. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">GzeeVtPtov4bFmrYkEv2og</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/e9cmFTHgKTTLrGuFyEfYP4.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 22:52:18 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/e9cmFTHgKTTLrGuFyEfYP4.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9 Pro XL with Pixel 8 Pro and 7 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9 Pro XL with Pixel 8 Pro and 7 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ TECNO is using AI and other tricks to address major photography pain points ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>TECNO recently held its Future Lens 2024 event in China.</li><li>The company unveiled new Image Matrix that will use AI to enhance images using a multi-layered process.</li><li>TECNO also revealed features that will enhance telephoto images and photos of fast-moving subjects.</li><li>These features are expected to appear in a new TECNO smartphone in 2025.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>TECNO <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/tecno-pioneers-ai-imaging-with-unveiling-of-tecno-image-matrix-and-two-ai-powered-imaging-technologies-at-future-lens-2024-302324650.html">unveiled</a> its latest AI efforts during its Future Lens 2024 event in China, which aim to enhance mobile photography and overcome major pain points for users when taking photos.</p><p>At the helm of these is TECNO's new Image Matrix, which will be the backbone of a new imaging process. The Image Matrix will take a multi-layered approach to imaging, working to enhance a photo at each step. This, of course, starts at the hardware level, utilizing the camera hardware, display, chipset, and sensor to capture the image. The image is then deconstructed using as many as 10 different algorithms, focusing on various aspects of the image, such as noise reduction, focus, tone adjustment, detection, and more.</p>
<p>The Image Matrix takes that information and reconstructs the image using the TECNO Algorithm Process Stack (TAPS), which powers several different image processing engines to enhance speed, low-light performance, skin tone, and more. The final layer is the application layer, where the final output is available for use with TECNO's other imaging features for further enhancement.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1276px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.11%;"><img id="FxyZM4ADo5aToQW8n77zUJ" name="TECNO-Image-matrix" alt="TECNO Image Matrix details" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FxyZM4ADo5aToQW8n77zUJ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1276" height="716" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: TECNO)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>TECNO is also introducing some unique methods that aim to improve high-speed image capture and zooming. The first, dubbed EVS Dynamic Snapshot, tracks and records the motion of a subject at a high frequency, then combines static and motion image data to ensure that the resulting image remains sharp at the pixel level. This feature is ideal for capturing fast-moving subjects such as athletes or vehicles in motion, promising a clearer image than you would get using traditional methods with some <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">other premium Android phones</a>.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9SAvEw1CVds" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>Finally, TECNO's Tap Any Zoom feature utilizes a dual prism telephoto design to better frame subjects when zooming in. According to TECNO, a user can double-tap a subject, and the camera will select the appropriate zoom level to keep it in the frame. Additionally, the lens-shift optical image stabilization will let you zoom into virtually any particular section of the frame, keeping the subject in focus with minimal camera shake, even at high magnification levels, to ensure your subject remains in the frame.</p><p>And with telephoto sweep, users can stitch together multiple telephoto images for a high-quality ultrawide-angle image with out the distortion often found in traditional wide-angle cameras. This also makes it possible to easily recompose a shot while retaining a high-quality image.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7SaJOJV46rg" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>In the image below, you can see how the photo utilizes both EVS and Tap Any Zoom by automatically framing the biker in the shot while keeping the fast-moving subject in focus. The result is a stark contrast from the image without these features enabled.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1280px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="E2ap2TjbaDUfonSEZ79LJ3" name="TECNO-EVS -Dynamic-Snapshot" alt="Before and after image with EVS off and on" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/E2ap2TjbaDUfonSEZ79LJ3.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1280" height="720" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: TECNO)</span></figcaption></figure>
<h2 id="coming-soon-2">Coming soon</h2>
<p>Earlier this year, TECNO <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/tecno-ai-foldable-strategy-interview">announced a suite of features</a> that it's bringing to its smartphones as part of its efforts to bring "practical AI" to consumers. This means focusing on features that will make it easy to summarize, translate, and create content for users. These new camera-focused features are the latest approach to using AI to further enhance its devices, which can help bridge the gap between high-end and low-end smartphones.</p><p>TECNO is well-versed in emerging markets by launching impressive <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-android-phones">budget Android phones</a> in regions where consumers may not be able to spend exorbitant amounts of money on tech. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/tecno-phanton-v-flip-2-review">Phantom V Flip 2</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/tecno-phantom-v-fold-2-review">Phantom V Fold 2</a> are just two examples of great phones that undercut the competition by a significant margin, with the latter in particular impressing us with its imaging capabilities. By utilizing AI to enhance camera quality, the company is basically saying you don't need to spend a ton of money to capture a good image. Furthermore, the company hinted that we could see more AI imaging capabilities down the road, although for now, it is focused on bringing these features to market.</p><p>Fortunately, we may not have to wait too long to see these features in action. TECNO says these features will arrive sometime in 2025 on an upcoming smartphone.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/tecno-future-lens-2024-announcements</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ TECNO unveiled new photography capabilities coming to future devices at its Future Lens 2024 event in China. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">3xy7WrdEn7Zi2p45ti4oFc</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bmcaPeGrxC58GkjkMuLybh.png" type="image/png" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 22:23:58 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ derrek.lee@futurenet.com (Derrek Lee) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/png" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bmcaPeGrxC58GkjkMuLybh.png">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[TECNO]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[TECNO Dual Prism Telephoto]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[TECNO Dual Prism Telephoto]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ ChromeOS M131 bolsters user security with 'Back to Safety' alongside Flash alerts ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google highlighted the rollout of its ChromeOS M131 update for Chromebooks, which includes a "Safety Reset" for users.</li><li>Another major inclusion is Flash notifications: a function that will flash a user's screen to ensure they don't miss important alerts.</li><li>Google pushed M130 for Chromebooks and Chromebook Plus models in November with several AI features and OS-level security tools.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google is returning with another update for its Chromebooks with a few new features to shore up its major November patch.</p><p>A Chromebook <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/chromebook/thread/313128087?hl=en&s=31">community post</a> highlighted the update titled ChromeOS M131, which should start hitting devices today (Dec 16). While this update is lighter than the M130, Google is detailing a feature for Chromebooks called <strong>ChromeOS Back to Safety</strong>. As the title implies, the set of tools is intended to give users a clear look at the state of their laptop's security and ways to improve their online/device safety.</p><p>The primary function of this feature is "Safety Reset." Google's on-device description states Safety Reset will "help remove unwanted pop-ups, fix network issues, and address other unexpected issues." Specifically, this safety-focused refresh can reset your Chrome shortcuts, delete cookies, and temporary site data.</p><p>Google adds that Back to Safety will inform users of extensions they should disable and reset settings that could pose a threat to their device. Moreover, Safety Reset will not touch your bookmarks, history, or saved passwords.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:755px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:79.47%;"><img id="FgnwyKXaaDgjystc3cZXGh" name="google-chrome-os-m131-flash-notifications" alt="Google's ChromeOS M131 brings Flash notifications to Chromebooks." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FgnwyKXaaDgjystc3cZXGh.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="755" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>ChromeOS M131 is also adding a tool to help bring more awareness to your alerts via <strong>Flash notifications</strong>. Added into the Audio and Captions page of the Accessibility settings on your Chromebook, Google states Flash notifications will flicker or "flash the screen when you receive notifications." The company states this feature could be useful for those who utilize screen magnification or for the hard of hearing.</p><p>Moreover, it seems these Flash notifications can be colored. The settings option for it indicates a "flash screen color" with a drop down menu. Google didn't deliver specifics; however, we can see that a user's screen could quickly flash yellow to grab your attention.</p><p>Google also states that light-sensitive users should take caution should they enable this feature.</p><p>The final portion of M131 includes a restyling update for ChromeOS' AI-powered Quick Answers. Google reiterates that these responses provide the user with useful information via summaries, interactive outlines, and document Q&A. A separate <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/chrome/a/answer/13616580">support document</a> states Quick Answers is accessible when right-clicking and can provide tools such as spell check, definitions, translations, and unit conversions.</p><p>ChromeOS M131 is rolling out today (Dec 16), so users should keep their eyes open as we go through the week.</p><p>This light M131 update adds a little more to what Chromebook and Chromebook Plus users experienced with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/google-chromeos-130-chromebook-plus-update-rollout">the huge M130 patch</a>. Chromebook Plus devices gained several AI features like "Help me read," which assist users by getting to the core of an article or lengthy passage of text without them needing to read through it. The feature also includes a freeform Q&A function for follow-up questions.</p><p>Additionally, all Chromebook devices picked up OS-level privacy features in Chrome.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Chromebook Deals: </strong><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1943169/565706/9383?subId1=ac-us-2259150687754449799&sharedId=ac-us&u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fbrowse%2Felectronics%2Fgoogle-chromebooks%2F3944_3951_1089430_1230091_1103213" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><strong>Walmart</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://shop-links.co/link?id=pcat17071&st=chromebook&publisher_slug=future&exclusive=1&u1=ac-us-9695703416023711163&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fsearchpage.jsp%3Fid%3Dpcat17071%26st%3Dchromebook&article_name=Best%20back%20to%20school%20tech%20deals%202023%20%E2%80%94%20Chromebooks%2C%20smartphones%2C%20watches%2C%20and%20more&article_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.androidcentral.com%2Fchromebooks-laptops%2Fbest-back-to-school-tech-deals-2023-chromebooks-smartphones-watches-and-more" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><strong>Best Buy</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://lenovo.7eer.net/c/221109/218864/3808?subId1=ac-us-7786208971231987451&sharedId=ac-us&u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.lenovo.com%2Fus%2Fen%2Fd%2Fchromebook-laptop%2F" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><strong>Lenovo</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-100048248-15880090?sid=ac-us-4559891887021430387&url=https://www.hp.com/us-en/shop/mlp/laptops/chromebook-344506--1" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><strong>HP</strong></a><strong>| </strong><a href="https://target.georiot.com/Proxy.ashx?tsid=169923&GR_URL=https%3A%2F%2Famazon.com%2Fstores%2Fpage%2F8667F8E9-10FC-4DCC-AB6A-97566CE718A5%3Fingress%3D0%26visitId%3D46ceb076-1b26-4ec4-8324-90885a489a11%26tag%3Dhawk-future-20%26ascsubtag%3Dac-us-1173286602236132557-20" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><strong>Amazon</strong></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/chromeos-m131-safety-reset-flash-alerts-update</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google has started rolling out ChromeOS M131 for Chromebooks. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">LsXFWEvuyLaGYnLFiaZqxG</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NDdTV4hTgba5iCmS5zqdGH.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 20:31:57 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Chromebooks &amp; Laptops]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NDdTV4hTgba5iCmS5zqdGH.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Chrome logo on a Lenovo Chromebook]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Chrome logo on a Lenovo Chromebook]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ I just found the perfect stocking stuffer for Android users — score 24% OFF the Galaxy Buds 3 Pro (plus a free gift card, because why not?)  ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The Christmas sales have landed, so if you&apos;re looking for some last-minute Samsung Galaxy deals to stick under the tree, it&apos;s time to make your move. Fortunately, there&apos;s no shortage of options to choose from, especially if you&apos;re on the hunt for a quality pair of wireless earbuds. </p><p>Grab the new Samsung Galaxy Buds 3 Pro from Amazon, for instance, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DKM22TSH/"><strong>you&apos;ll score a straight 24% discount</strong></a> — the epic same price drop that we saw during Black Friday. As if that wasn&apos;t enough, Amazon is also throwing in a free $20 gift card, just for kicks. In other words, you&apos;re getting some of the best wireless earbuds on the market along with some free cash. If that&apos;s not a great stocking stuff, I don&apos;t know what is. </p>
<h2 id="get-these-apos-brilliant-apos-earbuds-with-a-black-friday-level-discount-plus-a-free-20-gift-card-2">Get these &apos;brilliant&apos; earbuds with a Black Friday-level discount (plus a free $20 gift card)</h2>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="f70998d1-546b-432e-9a91-696e14512dc7" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$249.99" data-dimension48="$249.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DKM22TSH/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="DusDiixF6E6YsDAu2xXHWL" name="galaxy-buds-3-pro-render-space.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DusDiixF6E6YsDAu2xXHWL.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy Buds 3 Pro:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DKM22TSH/" data-dimension112="f70998d1-546b-432e-9a91-696e14512dc7" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$249.99" data-dimension48="$249.99"><del>$249.99</del><strong> $189.99, plus FREE $20 gift card at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>Pick up a pair of the Samsung Galaxy Buds 3 Pro from Amazon during its holiday sale and you'll score a 24% discount — the same price drop that we saw during Black Friday — plus a free $20 gift card, no strings attached. Throw those into a stocking and you're pretty much guaranteed to be a hero come Christmas morning. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DKM22TSH/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="f70998d1-546b-432e-9a91-696e14512dc7" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$249.99" data-dimension48="$249.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/android-central-holiday-gift-guide-best-deals-2024"><em><strong>Check out Android Central's holiday gift guide! Over 20 deals for Android users</strong></em></a></li></ul>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>you want a cutting-edge pair of wireless earbuds with adaptive noise cancellation and great sound quality; you already use one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-samsung-phones">best Samsung phones</a>; you&apos;re looking for a last-minute holiday gift. </p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>you don&apos;t generally use Samsung devices; you&apos;ve had some issues with earbuds fitting properly (do a bit of research, if so — this has been a problem for some users). </p><p>Released this past July, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/earbuds/samsung-galaxy-buds-3-pro-review">Galaxy Buds 3 Pro</a> are the perfect addition to your existing Samsung ecosystem, with AI support, active noise cancellation, and super-customizable EQ settings via the companion app. You also get a few surprising features, such as wireless charging support and a neat little LED light strip on the stem. </p><p>I wouldn&apos;t necessarily recommend these earbuds at full price (although you could do a lot worse in this price range) but with this 24% discount, they&apos;re a no-brainer. Throw in a $20 Amazon gift card, and it&apos;s truly a holiday deal for the history books. </p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/earbuds/i-just-found-the-perfect-stocking-stuffer-for-android-users-score-24-percent-off-the-galaxy-buds-3-pro-plus-a-free-gift-card-because-why-not</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Amazon is dropping a Black Friday-level discount on the Samsung Galaxy Buds 3 Pro, plus you'll get a free gift card, just for kicks. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">8FAbg9xb9UzmnKUK3wBstG</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sqcAtMQne48WELxTzwmK4U.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 20:21:55 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Earbuds]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sqcAtMQne48WELxTzwmK4U.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Tshaka Armstrong]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Galaxy Buds 3 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Galaxy Buds 3 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ One UI 7 beta 2 arrives for enrolled Galaxy S24 series testers in the US ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung is pushing One UI 7 beta 2 to Galaxy S24 devices in the U.S., packed with loads of bug fixes.</li><li>Among the fixes, beta 2 is correcting malfunctions with the Now Bar, issues with TV product connections over DeX, and more.</li><li>Samsung finally opened its One UI 7 beta program on December 5, which introduced the Now Bar on the lock screen.</li><li>One UI 7 is expected to arrive near or alongside the Galaxy S25 in January.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>It seems enrolled One UI 7 beta testers can begin to expect the next iteration of software today (Dec 16).</p><p>Android Central has started receiving the update today on a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review">Galaxy S24 Ultra</a> bearing software version <strong>ZXL5</strong>. Samsung detailed the rollout of the One UI 7 beta 2 update in its Members app, highlighting improved "system stability." The second beta packs quite a few fixes to bugs that testers have encountered since the program's start.</p><p>According to the changelog, Samsung states it has fixed a Quick Panel operation error alongside a display error regarding the "personal drawer App." Another bug fix rolling in is for the Galaxy S24's wireless connection to TV products through DeX. The company is also fixing an issue where "reminder widget transparency is not applied." However, the company states that an app update is required for that fix to go into effect.</p><p>The One UI 7 beta 2 patch informs users of app updates when the software is available. Tapping "view more" will likely take you to where you can update apps that require it post-download.</p><p>Another bug fix arrives for Samsung's newly unveiled Now Bar. The patch notes state it has corrected a "continuous display error and malfunction" after closing it.</p><p>The remainder of the changelog is as follows:</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:424px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:141.51%;"><img id="JfquUBgVZq4QorwKCExB9N" name="samsung-one-ui-7-beta-2-bug-fixes-alt" alt="The changelog for One UI 7 beta 2 on the Galaxy S24 series." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JfquUBgVZq4QorwKCExB9N.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="424" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>With the update spotted, other users enrolled in the One UI 7 beta program should soon expect it. Additionally, those just getting involved in the second beta can expect a huge 4GB download. However, as noted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/samsung-one-ui-7-beta-2-rollout-3509206/">Android Authority</a>, those who've been enrolled since the beta's beginning will only download a 1GB patch as Samsung progresses its development. The publication also cites <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/MaxJmb/status/1868601315875787203">Max Jambor</a> in stating the update was spotted in Germany, the U.K., and South Korea alongside the U.S.</p><p>Users can head into the <strong>Samsung Members app > One UI 7 Beta Program banner </strong>to view the full changelog or provide testing feedback.</p><p>Samsung dropped <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsungs-first-one-ui-7-beta-is-available-now-public-release-set-for-early-2025">the One UI 7 beta</a> earlier in December after the software faced an insurmountable amount of delays. Based on Android 15, the beta opened access to those with a Galaxy S24 series devices with the possibility of hitting others and a few past-gen phones.</p><p>Galaxy AI is at the core of this beta, with Samsung providing an early glimpse at Writing Tools: a set of AI-based writing and grammar options. The Now Bar was another major addition as users can find it incorporated as a significant feature on the lock screen. Users can view "important notifications dynamically" without opening their phones.</p><p>The stable version of One UI 7 is expected to arrive near or alongside the Galaxy S25's launch in January 2025.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="e1ba05e0-f238-4cb4-82ba-462ca3ccfe7d">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jH2nkHNQPuwBpm8KyQ6u4c.jpg' alt="samsung galaxy s24 ultra square render - 1"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>Samsung's Galaxy S24 Ultra continues the trend of a strong, superb performance phone. The latest Ultra-tier device delivers an eye-friendly display, fantastic cameras, and a completely flat display with thin bezels. Additionally, the phone's 5,000mAh battery can keep you going, whether you're watching videos or playing some games.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/one-ui-7-beta-2-galaxy-s24-rollout</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung has started rolling out One UI 7 beta 2 for the Galaxy S24 series. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">yeWhnDCR3d8Kqr8gG9B8mH</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WGZFcwvp3vUr2yezPByNfN.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 20:05:29 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WGZFcwvp3vUr2yezPByNfN.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The back of the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra in the Titanium Grey colorway]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The back of the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra in the Titanium Grey colorway]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Galaxy S25 Ultra could come these colorways ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Prominent analyst Ross Young has shared all the color variants of the upcoming Galaxy S25 Ultra.</li><li>The device is likely to ship in new Titanium JetBlack, Titanium JadeGreen, and Titanium PinkGold colorways next to conventional color options.</li><li>The new ones are presumably sold as online exclusives, while the traditional ones would be widely available online and in stores.</li><li>The Galaxy S25 series is anticipated to launch sometime in January 2025.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Samsung's flagship Galaxy S25 launch might just be around the corner. It is assumed to be happening on January 22, although the company has yet to confirm the date. Meanwhile, new information reveals all the possible colorways of the Ultra model in the lineup.</p><p>The news comes from the display analyst Ross Young on X, who has shared the alleged color variants of the Galaxy S25 Ultra model. According to Young, we should likely see the Galaxy S25 Ultra in the following color options:</p>
<ul><li>Titanium Black</li><li>Titanium SilverBlue</li><li>Titanium Gray</li><li>Titanium WhiteSilver</li><li>Titanium JetBlack</li><li>Titanium JadeGreen</li><li>Titanium PinkGold</li></ul>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Updated S25U colors in order of volume:Titanium BlackTitanium SilverBlueTitanium GrayTitanium WhiteSilverTitanium JetBlackTitanium JadeGreenTitanium PinkGold<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1868492364270199211">December 16, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>An <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-25-ultra-color-options-leaked">earlier leak</a> and also a new Finland-based <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://suomimobiili.fi/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-muisti-ja-variversiot-suomessa/">carrier listing</a> have revealed some of these color options. While Black, Green, Blue, and Titanium were already expected color variants just like the previous iteration models, the new ones that will likely take the limelight might be the new JetBlack and PinkGold. There are several JetBlack enthusiasts, and it could be on the likes of the Galaxy S23's Phantom Black or maybe even calling back to the iPhone 7.</p><p>The Pink Gold colorway, on the other hand, is not new to Samsung devices; older smartwatches like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/samsung-galaxy-watch-4-review">Galaxy Watch 4</a> featured Pink Gold, and we expect the upcoming Galaxy S25 Ultra to likely incorporate the same or more pinkish to catch up to its counterparts like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-review">Pixel 9</a> series.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1066px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.29%;"><img id="X65GexZdyC98NmHwvCEFNJ" name="Galaxy-S25-Ultra-renders-leak-01.jpg" alt="Galaxy S25 Ultra renders leak" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/X65GexZdyC98NmHwvCEFNJ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1066" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OnLeaks / Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Young has further shared that the aforementioned color options list are ranked by the number of units, which means the first few are likely to be widely available across online and offline stores, and presumably, the new ones at the bottom are more likely to be Samsung's online-exclusive units.</p><p>Aside from these colorways, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-leaked-renders-reveal-flat-design">thanks to the renders</a>, we have an idea of how the Galaxy S25 Ultra would appear. The handset will likely sport a more flatter design than the predecessor model and be slightly lighter to hold in hand than the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review">Galaxy S24 Ultra</a>.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-all-seven-colorways-tipped</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Earlier leaks have hinted at four traditional color options of the Galaxy S25 Ultra. New information adds a few more, including a JetBlack version. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">fqo4v8DKAfkmGn3rBbasyF</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CAuNSXoh8GMudGNmNstKdg.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 19:48:14 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CAuNSXoh8GMudGNmNstKdg.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Future]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Galaxy S24 Ultra in different colors]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Galaxy S24 Ultra in different colors]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Gemini Advanced subscribers can now use Gemini Flash 2.0 Experimental in latest Gemini app beta ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-32">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google announced Gemini 2.0 last week, its newest set of models, including Gemini 2.0 Flash Experimental.</li><li>The experimental version of Gemini 2.0 Flash, a lightweight and fast model, became immediately available in the Gemini web client.</li><li>Now, Google is starting to bring the latest model to the Gemini app, adding support for Gemini 2.0 Flash experimental in the most recent beta update.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/googles-latest-ai-model-gemini-2-0-is-here-to-usher-in-the-agentic-era">debuted Gemini 2.0 last week</a>, and now, the Gemini 2.0 Flash Experimental model is starting to make its way to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-gemini-app-android">mobile Gemini app</a>. The full suite of models is yet to be released, as Google is only making an “experimental” version of Gemini 2.0 Flash. The new, experimental model launched on the Gemini web client immediately, but Google said it would soon come to the official mobile apps.</p><p>Only a few days later, Google is beginning to roll out the Gemini 2.0 Flash Experimental model as part of the latest Gemini app beta, spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/12/16/gemini-2-0-flash-app-android/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a>. Previously, the way to access Gemini Advanced models was to enable an option in settings. Now, with version 15.50 of the Gemini app, there is a new way to switch between models. You can top the model name at the top of the landing page to switch between models and learn more about them.</p><p>Expectedly, Google describes Gemini 2.0 Flash Experimental as its “latest experimental model,” adding that it “might not work as expected.” Conversely, Gemini 1.5 Pro is “for complex tasks” and Gemini 1.5 Flash is a way to “get everyday help.” The company clearly wants users to know that this experimental version of Gemini 1.5 Flash is not a final release.</p><p>“While we’re excited for you to try it, remember it’s an early preview and might not work as expected,” the company warned in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.google/products/gemini/google-gemini-deep-research/" target="_blank">blog post</a>. “Additionally, some Gemini features won't be compatible with this model in its experimental state.”</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="K7orNPM3U8hJfboWTqbwDW" name="google-pixel-9-pro-gemini-advanced.jpg" alt="Running Gemini Advanced on a Google Pixel 9 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/K7orNPM3U8hJfboWTqbwDW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>On top of that, the option will only be available to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini Advanced</a> subscribers. The higher tier is available through the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-one">Google One AI Premium plan</a>, which costs $20 per month. Aside from Gemini 2.0 Flash Experimental, the subscription also unlocks Google’s other top AI models, like Gemini 1.5 Pro.</p><p>You can try Gemini 2.0 Flash Experimental today by enrolling in the Google app beta via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://play.google.com/apps/testing/com.google.android.googlequicksearchbox/join" target="_blank">this link</a>. Otherwise, the option to use this model should become available through the stable channel soon.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/gemini-advanced-subscribers-can-now-use-gemini-flash-2-0-experimental-in-latest-gemini-app-beta</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Gemini 2.0 Flash is one of Google’s newest and smallest AI models, and an experimental version of it is now available in the Gemini app. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">BYNs7YvHvhsfFFryGUBJFR</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QUuejB6p5fokJUFyse3swb.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 18:53:23 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QUuejB6p5fokJUFyse3swb.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Google Gemini app]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Google Gemini app]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Ray-Ban Meta glasses just got their most futuristic AI update yet ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-37">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Early Access program members are getting three key new features for the Ray-Ban Meta smart glasses.</li><li>"Live AI" will record video and offer AI insights based on what you see, a feature originally shown at Meta Connect 2024.</li><li>"Live translate" will let you hear or see people's Spanish, French, or Italian words in English.</li><li>Ray-Ban Metas also added Shazam integration with the v11 update.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Your <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/ray-ban-meta-smart-glasses-review">Ray-Ban Meta smart glasses</a> are about to get a major intelligence update, and you won't have to wait if you're an Early Access program member.</p><p>On Monday, Meta <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.meta.com/blog/quest/ray-ban-meta-v11-software-update-live-ai-translation-shazam/">announced the v11 update</a>, with <strong>Live AI</strong> as the standout feature.  Until now, Meta AI could only respond to "Hey Meta" queries by taking a single photo and analyzing it. Now, "Meta AI can see what you see continuously and converse with you more naturally than ever before."</p><p>During a Live AI session, it'll record video and analyze what it sees in real time. You can ask it questions without the Hey Meta wake word, and the AI will remember things you asked earlier. You can also "interrupt anytime to ask follow-up questions or change topics," and Meta promises that the AI will proactively "give useful suggestions even before you ask."</p><p>If that sounds familiar, it's because Google's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/gemini-live-is-available-for-free-on-android-phones">Gemini Live</a> offers similar conversational AI, with interruptions and remembered queries. But that's tied to your Android phone, whereas Meta's Live AI will let you ask questions without needing to hold anything.</p><p>During Meta Connect 2024 in October, Zuckerberg gave an example of using Live AI to look at your closet and ask which clothes would best fit a Roaring 20s-themed costume party. We'll have to test how well it works in practice, but the concept is intriguing and a big step up for the smart glasses.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/I7JyydkqDeI?start=1717" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>The second v11 update feature is <strong>Live translate</strong>, which Zuckerberg demoed at Meta Connect 2024. As the name suggests, you can speak in English with someone speaking Spanish, French, or Italian and either see their responses on your phone or hear them through the Ray-Ban Meta glasses' speakers.</p><p>Google has offered live translate for years, and in more languages. Meta's version is unique because of its hands-free option, but the translation delay will still make conversations a bit awkward (based on Zuckerberg's Connect demo).</p><p>The final v11 update is <strong>Shazam integration</strong>. You'll simply say, "Hey Meta, Shazam this song," and find out what the music playing around you is.</p><p>If you want to test these features today, you'll need to sign up for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.meta.com/help/smart-glasses/articles/voice-controls/early-access-program-ray-ban-meta-smart-glasses">Early Access program</a>, or else wait for the final release. That link walks you through the steps, but all you really need to do is opt in from the Settings menu of the Meta View app. Otherwise, the stable version should arrive in early 2025.</p><p>Meta has pushed out several <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/ray-ban-meta-smart-glasses-just-got-a-bunch-of-ai-upgrades-and-live-translation">useful AI updates</a> in recent months, such as the ability to ask Meta AI to "remember" something — such as where you parked — and have it photograph the relevant thing and create a reminder for later.</p><p>With <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-orion-hands-on">Meta Orion AR glasses</a> on the horizon, Meta is wisely pushing out iterative AI updates on its display-free smart glasses for now, getting Meta AI ready for the next generation and challenging Google Gemini and its nascent <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/android-xr-is-the-most-exciting-new-version-of-android-in-years">Android XR platform</a>.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="5a095fa3-3fe1-48eb-b985-e7f3cc1b3612">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:56.25%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/iUwAmBXqMRLL5VcApSqbrR.jpg' alt="Ray-Ban Meta smart glasses matte black"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Ray-Ban Meta smart glasses</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Use AI in style</strong></em></p><p>The Ray-Ban Meta smart glasses are our top pick for the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-smart-glasses">best smart glasses</a> available. Even without AI, they're comfortable, stylish, let you stream playlists without needing earbuds, and capture surprisingly good photos with your phone in your pocket. And Meta AI itself is only going to keep getting smarter in 2025.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/ray-ban-meta-glasses-just-got-their-most-futuristic-ai-update-yet</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Your Ray-Ban Meta smart glasses just got the live translate demo Zuckerberg showed off at Connect, plus another major AI trick. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">hVBjkouToxzbo9TEV23w4C</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9Wg6WCfF6F7nr2A7ddcicT.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 18:49:28 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9Wg6WCfF6F7nr2A7ddcicT.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Brady Snyder / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Ray-Ban Meta limited edition transparent smart glasses.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Ray-Ban Meta limited edition transparent smart glasses.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>