<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 12:55:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ YouTube Music is testing letting you build custom radio stations using AI prompts ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>YouTube Music is testing a new AI feature that lets users describe their mood to create custom radio stations.</li><li>This feature seems to be currently in a limited testing phase with only a few users.</li><li>When fully rolled out, expect to see a purple and pink tile in the Home feed labeled "Ask for music any way you like."</li></ul>
<hr>
<p> YouTube Music is apparently trying out a new AI feature where you can whisper song wishes to Google&apos;s AI gods.</p><p>A Reddit user going by the name <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/YoutubeMusic/comments/1dxp3zj/new_ai_generated_radios/" target="_blank">kater_pro</a> stumbled upon a new feature while browsing through the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/youtube-music">YouTube Music</a> app. It looks like this feature is still in its testing phase and is only available to a small group of users at the moment (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/07/07/youtube-music-ai-radio/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a>).</p><p>This experimental feature uses text prompts, letting users describe the kind of music vibe they want. The built-in AI then creates a custom radio station with songs that match the mood.</p><p>When and if it&apos;s rolled out, this feature is expected to have a unique tile in the Home feed, labeled "Ask for music any way you like." This eye-catching tile will likely be in bright purple and pink colors, as shown in the screenshot below.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1008px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:46.92%;"><img id="dpKgYFc2eSvJsHZCJmGRQj" name="youtube-music-prompt-generated-radio-station.jpg" alt="Youtube music prompt-generated radio station" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dpKgYFc2eSvJsHZCJmGRQj.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1008" height="473" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: kater_pro / Reddit)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It’s designed to look like the "Create a radio: Your music tuner" card that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-music-may-allow-you-to-create-custom-radio">you can already find in the Library tab</a>. However, this feature requires you to pick a starting song or artist to get a playlist of similar tunes.</p><p>The interface allows for dynamic station customization with a chat window at the bottom of the screen and a handy list of prompts right above it. This interactive feature invites users to fine-tune their musical experience by speaking or typing in their preferences, from lively pop anthems to exploring the emerging Moscow rock scene.</p><p>Earlier reports hinted at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-wants-record-label-partnerships-but-is-it-a-good-idea">ongoing talks between YouTube and major record labels</a> with the goal of securing licensing rights for copyrighted songs, setting the stage for advanced AI tools in the YouTube Music app.</p><p>This feature is quite similar to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/spotify-ai-dj-curated-music">Spotify&apos;s "AI DJ"</a> and PlaylistAI, a third-party app that works with both Spotify and Apple Music. Although YouTube Music doesn&apos;t yet have an AI DJ that offers musical commentary, this new addition hints at a possible direction for future updates.</p><p>The Reddit user&apos;s subscription status is unknown, making it unclear who can access this feature. Previously, AI-powered tools on YouTube have been limited to paying subscribers, which might suggest that this new music exploration tool could also be part of a premium offering.</p><p>The feature seems to be in its early stages. 9to5Google mentioned just one Reddit user discovering it, with no other reports confirming this. This lack of evidence hints at a possible delay in making the feature widely available.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-music-is-testing-letting-you-build-custom-radio-stations-using-ai-prompts</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ YouTube Music is apparently trying out a new way to pick your tunes: just tell it what kind of music you want to hear. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">G55x9SJdUEjmUHUgnJ3EtD</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GzQNJ8Q6j77Rdsyt2oQSP8.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 12:15:16 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GzQNJ8Q6j77Rdsyt2oQSP8.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Create a radio section in Youtube Music]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Create a radio section in Youtube Music]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google's passkey update focuses on the 'high-risk' for improved data protection ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google details a simplified enrollment process for "high-risk" users interested in passkeys through its Advanced Protection Program (APP).</li><li>Additionally, Google has partnered with Internews to protect other high-risk users like journalists and human rights workers from online attacks.</li><li>Google brought passkeys to its APP earlier this year after making the security measure an alternative to passwords for accounts in 2023.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>As Google looks to help users combat online attacks, the company is detailing a new update for passkeys to help the "high-risk."</p><p>Today&apos;s update (July 10) aims to simplify the enrollment process for high-risk users of passkey through the Advanced Protection Program (APP). Google informed a press release that users enrolling in the app must ensure their device and browser are compatible. After that, visiting the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://landing.google.com/advancedprotection/?utm_source=Google&utm_medium=Marketing&utm_campaign=Content">program&apos;s official page</a> and hitting "Get Started" will produce a set of instructions.</p><p>Users can enroll with a passkey or physical security key, however, Google still recommends adding a recovery method. The options include your phone number, email, or another passkey/security key.</p><p>Aside from a revamped enrollment process, Google announces its partnership with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://internews.org/">Internews</a>. Journalists and human rights workers fall within the scope of a "high-risk" user as Google looks to help protect their sensitive data. The post adds that the partnership helps expand the APP&apos;s work by bringing free security keys.</p><p>Work with Internews will reach 10 countries, including Brazil, Mexico, and Poland.</p><p>Google started <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-next-major-phase-of-passkey">rolling out passkeys</a> as an alternate method to signing into its accounts a year ago. While users can forget their passwords, they are also quite susceptible to heinous attacks. Passkeys require a user&apos;s biometric data, which isn&apos;t an easy item for attackers to crack and gain access to your information.</p><p>More importantly, Google states that passkeys are usable across any device. This means folks who&apos;ve enrolled through the APP on one phone can utilize their passkeys on another without issue.</p><p>The simplification of its APP enrollment process comes a few months <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-is-expanding-passkeys-to-its-advanced-protection-program-as-us-election-nears">after the program gained passkeys</a> in the first place. Google started rolling out passkeys in its Advanced Protection Program in May, which was announced during the World Password Day celebrations. Several other big names in tech have joined <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/upgrade-to-passkeys-on-pixel-with-google-password-manager">the passkey movement</a> such as Amazon, 1Password, Dashlane, Docusign, Kayak, Mercari, and Shopify.</p><p>These passkeys were also stated to bring "security notifications" regarding your Google account and other services you&apos;ve used. The company hopes security measures such as this will help restrict the abilities of online attackers.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-passkey-high-risk-user-update</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google detailed a new update for its passkeys through the APP for "high-risk" users. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">pZwMTgC2W9oDV5JkHMBzQ8</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/o2in9iK6eDrPYA6kUdTRtN.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/o2in9iK6eDrPYA6kUdTRtN.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Passkey on a Windows 11 PC]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Passkey on a Windows 11 PC]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung Galaxy Unpacked 2024: LIVE blog and everything you need to know about the Z Fold 6, Flip 6, and Galaxy Ring ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>It’s hotter than all get out, which means we’re right in the middle of summer. This also means that we’re gearing up for the latest Galaxy Unpacked event. We’re expecting it to be jam-packed, complete with phones, wearables, and possibly more. Samsung is hosting its Galaxy Unpacked event in Paris, but you don’t have to jump on a flight. Instead, you can watch from the comfort of your own home, so hit the link below to learn more about the event. </p>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-unpacked-july-2024-how-to-watch-what-to-expect"><strong>Samsung Unpacked 2024: how to watch and what to expect from the event</strong></a></li></ul>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="2DCyL78nL8tV6P3bMq3CgD" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Watch-6-watchface-silly.jpg" alt="One of the new watchfaces on the Samsung Galaxy Watch 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2DCyL78nL8tV6P3bMq3CgD.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>From the way that everything appears to be shaking out, Samsung’s next lineup of foldables are taking a backseat this year. Instead, the focus is expected to be on the company’s wearables. Not only are we expecting the Galaxy Watch 7, but rumors suggest Samsung is set to announce two new products, one of which sees Samsung entering an entirely new product segment. </p>
<ul><li><a href="https://howl.link/d4ex1o8mjix8w"><strong>Reserve the Galaxy Watch 7 or Ultra and get $50 off—No payment required</strong></a></li></ul>
<p>Let’s get the party started with arguably the most highly-anticipated product that could finally debut at Unpacked — the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-ring-name-and-release-date-leaked">Galaxy Ring</a>. Until recently, Oura has really been the only player in the smart ring market, as the original Oura Ring was released in 2015 following a successful Kickstarter campaign. Since then, Oura has released two new iterations, with the most recent being in 2023 and the 4th generation is expected sometime this year. </p><p>Other companies have joined the fray, with notable releases from Ultrahuman, RingConn, and Amazfit. Seeing the success and market heating up, Samsung wants to get in on the fun, with rumors of a potential Galaxy Ring beginning in 2023. </p>
<p>Galaxy Ring<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-smart-ring-teaser"> rumors sporadically</a> popped up as we went into 2024, and was surprisingly announced at the end of the first Galaxy Unpacked of the year. Not much was actually shared, as Samsung only showed off a teaser video, confirming the name, and that it would be released “later this year.” </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="VZV5nxvJyY5oJdrhnP6gML" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Ring-MWC-silver-03.jpg" alt="Eyes on with the Samsung Galaxy Ring at MWC 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VZV5nxvJyY5oJdrhnP6gML.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p> We had to wait about a month and a half to learn more, as Samsung showcased the Galaxy Ring at MWC 2024 in Barcelona. It was here that the company began revealing and confirming what this new wearable would be capable of. This includes things such as the smallest version weighing just 2.3 grams, while the heaviest one weighs 2.9 grams. In comparison, the Oura Ring “tips the scales between 4 and 6 grams.” </p><p>Besides that, Samsung stopped short of revealing much more about the Galaxy Ring, besides that “it’s a wellness-focused gadget taking on the likes of Oura, packed with a bunch of sensors.” </p>
<p>Our very own Nick Sutrich was on the ground at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-ring-eyes-on-mwc-2024">MWC 2024</a>, and was able to get a “close-up look” at the Galaxy Ring. Unfortunately, this wasn’t a hands-on session, but Nick provided us with his own opinions while snapping a bunch of photos showing off the array of sensors on the inside of the different rings. NIck came away feeling “particularly impressed by how much the Samsung Galaxy Ring looks like a proper piece of jewelry rather than a geeky gadget.” </p>
<p>From there, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-ring-may-last-almost-ten-days">bits and pieces of information</a> about the Galaxy Ring has been rumored and/or leaked. In March, Dr. Hon Pak, head of the digital health team at Samsung, confirmed that this new wearable “lasts for about five to nine days.” The battery life is dependent on the size that you get, as the smallest Galaxy Ring is equipped with a 14.5mAh cell, with the largest coming with a 21.5mAh battery.</p>
<p>Shortly after the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/galaxy-ring-release-unit-production-rumor">battery life</a> was seemingly confirmed, a report surfaced suggesting that Samsung was gearing up “to produce 400,000 units for its launch.” The same report also confirmed that the Galaxy Ring would not be labeled as a “medical device,” as the company was “still going through the required certification loops.” Instead, Samsung is expected to market the Galaxy Ring as a “wellness wearable” at launch, but that could change if the medical certification is acquired.</p>
<p>At this point, there were still a lot of questions left unanswered, but some of that changed after nine models of the Galaxy Ring <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/galaxy-ring-fcc-listing-cradle-specs-confirmed"><u>appeared at the FCC</u></a>. This confirmed that Samsung will offer the Ring in sizes ranging from Size 5 to Size 12. The FCC appearance also gave us our first look at the “charging cradle” for the Galaxy Ring, but the filing only showed a drawing of the bottom of the cradle. </p><p>It wouldn’t be<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/galaxy-ring-charging-case-rendering-leak"> until June</a> before more information was leaked regarding the cradle, this time coming courtesy of Ice Universe. An official-looking render showed that the Galaxy Ring will likely reside in what looks to be a ring box when it needs to be charged. When the box is opened, there’s a “raised portion with the expected contact pins for charging purposes.”</p>
<p>A little over a month ahead of the expected launch date, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-sues-oura-to-prevent-galaxy-ring-patent-challenge">Samsung filed a lawsuit</a> against Oura Health Oy, the parent company of Oura Ring. It might seem like an odd thing to do considering that the Galaxy Ring was not yet released. However, the documents stated Samsung’s reasoning was due to “Oura&apos;s pattern of indiscriminate assertion of patent infringement against any and all competitors in the smart ring market" is an "actual, imminent risk to Samsung.” </p><p>The move makes sense from Samsung’s point of view considering that Oura pointed out that it holds “100 granted patents, 270 pending patent applications, and 130+ registered trademarks.” At the time of this writing, there has yet to be an outcome rendered in the lawsuit, which was to be expected. </p><p>By filing the lawsuit, Samsung also revealed that the Galaxy Ring was entering “mass production ‘in mid-June 2024’ and will open smart ring sales ‘in or around August 2024.’”<br>
<br>
Following the lawsuit, only a few other bits of information have trickled out regarding the Galaxy Ring. Instead, it’s just been a waiting game until Galaxy Unpacked gets underway. </p>
<p>Much like the Z Fold 6 and Flip 6, we’re not expecting many changes when it comes to the Galaxy Watch 7. However, the big change this year is that it’s unlikely that Samsung will release a Watch 7 Pro or Watch 7 Classic. On the bright side, spec leaks point to the Watch 7 still coming in two sizes; 1.3-inches or 1.5-inches. Besides that, don’t expect much in the form of any major design changes.</p>
<p>Instead, the bigger change will come via the rumored Exynos W940. According to a rumor earlier this year, the W940 is internally known as the Exynos 5535 but will be branded. What makes the W940 so special is that it’s rumored to be built on the 3nm process, and “allegedly ‘improves power consumption by 50%, performance by more than 30%, and reduces area by 35%.’” The Watch 7 is also rumored to now offer 32GB of storage, a big upgrade over the 16GB found in the Watch 6 lineup.</p>
<p>When it comes to software, we’re in for another year of Samsung relying on Wear OS. However, the Watch 7 is said to be released “with One UI Watch 6 before receiving the full <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/wear-os-5"><u>Wear OS 5</u></a> update later this fall.” One UI Watch 6 is currently in beta, but will likely launch alongside the Galaxy Watch 7. With it, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-announces-new-galaxy-ai-health-and-fitness-insights">Samsung is</a> implementing a slew of Galaxy AI features, including things such as “energy score, workout routines, racing past routes, new HR metrics, and enhanced health algorithms.”</p>
<p>In lieu of the Galaxy Watch Pro or Classic, Samsung’s borrowing a trick from Apple’s playbook as all signs point to the Galaxy Watch Ultra arriving at Unpacked. Rumors of an Ultra smartwatch began swirling in late 2023, suggesting that Samsung was working on an Apple Watch Ultra competitor. At the time, one rumor claimed Samsung would opt for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/galaxy-watch-7-ultra-micro-led-rumor">MicroLED</a>, the same technology found in many of the latest Samsung TVs. It would also give Samsung a jump-start on Apple, as the latter has been rumored to implement MicroLED into its high-end smartwatch.</p>
<p>As is the case with most devices, we got our first “look” at the Galaxy Watch Ultra thanks to renders from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-7-ultra-renders-leak"><u>@OnLeaks and SmartPrix</u></a>. These renders also seem to confirm one way that Samsung aims to differentiate the Watch Ultra from its cheaper counterparts. Instead of using the tried-and-true round design, the renders showed off a smartwatch with a “squircle” frame. Yes, it’s the same design as the icons found on Samsung smartphones. </p>
<p>Along with revealing the renders, OnLeaks<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-7-ultra-renders-leak"> stated that the </a>Watch 7 Ultra would feature a 1.5-inch display. Although this is the same screen size as the Galaxy Watch 6 Classic, the overall dimensions would be slightly different, measuring 47 x 47.14 x 16.4mm. Some of the other inclusions mentioned in this leak are a rotating bezel, and a third button, perhaps similar to the Action Button from the Apple Watch Ultra 2.</p>
<p>Although the renders and information from OnLeaks were convincing, some didn’t consider them serious until the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-z-flip-6-watch-7-ultra-specs-fcc-listing">Ultra stopped by the FCC</a>. This didn’t provide too much, besides confirming the model number (SM-L705,) along with LTE, Wi-Fi, Bluetooth, and NFC support. But, this was only the beginning.</p>
<p>As the calendar turned into July, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/galaxy-watch-ultra-watch-7-spec-sheet-leak"><u>biggest leak</u></a> came in the form of supposed spec sheets for both the Galaxy Watch 7 and Galaxy Watch Ultra. This gave us a pretty clear picture of what to expect, seeming to confirm much of what was previously leaked. According to the leaked spec sheet, the Galaxy Watch Ultra is said to be powered by a 3nm SoC named the Exynos W1000, paired with 2GB of RAM and 32GB of storage. </p><p>The leaked spec sheet also taught us that this is about as close as it gets to being a true Apple Watch Ultra competitor. Samsung’s Ultra is said to use a Titanium casing along with Sapphire Glass while offering IPX6 dust resistance and being equipped with a 10 ATM waterproof rating.</p>
<p>From here, the only question remaining is how much Samsung plans to charge for the Galaxy Watch 7 and Watch Ultra. That question was somewhat answered in the same leak that revealed the entire spec sheets. I saw “somewhat,” because the leaked pricing is for what the wearables could retail for in France. With that in mind, the Watch 7 is said to start at €319 (~$342) for the 40mm model, going up to €349 (~$374) for the 44mm version, and the Watch Ultra comes in at €699 (~$750.)</p>
<p>With Samsung’s lineup of wearables out of the way, it’s time to switch gears to the new phones that we’re expecting. It’s admittedly a bit odd knowing that the Galaxy Fold and Flip won’t be taking center stage, but with two brand-new products, it kind of makes sense. Along with that, the leaks and rumors suggest that at least one of these foldable phones won’t be more than an iterative update.</p>
<p>Kicking things off with the smaller of the two, it didn’t take long before we started seeing rumors about the Galaxy Z Flip 6. One of the big complaints regarding Samsung’s foldable phones is that the cameras fall a bit short compared to the company’s flagship slab phones. However, in August 2023, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-6-prototype-camera-rumor"><u>an early rumor</u></a> claimed the Galaxy Z Flip 6 would be upgraded with a 50MP primary lens. </p><p>A subsequent report from Ross Young of DSCC claimed that Samsung was looking to increase the size of the Cover Screen. This would mean moving up from the 3.5-inch panel on the Flip 5 to about 3.9-inches on the Flip 6. At the same time, Young also claimed that both screens on the Fold 6 would be larger, but stopped short of providing specific sizes.</p>
<p>Although battery life has gotten better thanks to improvements made to the Qualcomm’s chips, it’s still not quite on par with traditional phones. Samsung was reportedly testing larger batteries for the Flip 6, potentially resulting in the same battery size as the standard Galaxy S24 at ~4,000mAh. </p>
<p>Fast forward to March, and we got our <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-6-renders-leak"><u>first supposed look</u></a> at the Galaxy Flip 6 courtesy of renders from OnLeaks. This seemed to confirm that the Flip 6 would be a bit thicker, presumably to accommodate a larger battery. However, it also potentially debunked previous rumors of a larger Cover Screen, as the renders portrayed Samsung relying on the same size displays from its predecessor.</p>
<p>There was a bit of a lull in terms of any “major” leaks or rumors regarding Samsung’s smaller foldable phone. However, that all changed in May as the Flip 6 made an appearance at the FCC alongside the Galaxy Watch Ultra. Coming as little surprise, this did nothing more than confirm the model number, in addition to the 5G network support, to go along with Bluetooth, Wi-Fi, NFC, and wireless charging. </p>
<p>Last, but certainly not least, the Galaxy Z Fold 6 is also expected to be announced during Galaxy Unpacked. Samsung hasn’t had much pressure to deal with here in the States, but we were hopeful that the OnePlus Open would push Samsung to innovate its book-style foldable further. However, the company was seemingly looking to take a different approach as rumors earlier this year suggested <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-could-make-a-cheaper-galaxy-z-fold-to-bring-foldables-mainstream-finally"><u>a cheaper Z Fold</u></a> was in the works.</p><p>According to multiple reports, Samsung was “considering developing an entry-level model for the new Galaxy Z Fold 6. The goal with such a move would be to cater more towards the Chinese market, where the foldable competition is much more fierce. This was followed by the appearance of a third device codename appearing alongside Samsung’s component orders for the Z Fold 6 and Flip 6. The codename, Q6A, denotes an alternative version of the Z Fold 6, which carries the Q6 codename. </p>
<p>Surprisingly, not much else was leaked regarding the Galaxy Z Fold 6, until renders appeared courtesy of OnLeaks and SmartPrix. These got us a bit excited, as they showed off a supposed redesign with flatter edges, similar to what we saw with the Galaxy S24 Ultra. As a result of this change, the Cover Screen would sport a 22:9 aspect ratio, slightly wider than the 23:9 ratio of the Z Fold 5. Unfortunately, this also would mean that while the inner screen would be larger, it likely wouldn’t be very noticeable.</p>
<p>Instead of trying to take the fight to OnePlus or Vivo, the next set of rumors seemingly confirmed that while the Fold 6 wasn’t going to be completely overhauled, Samsung was set to at least make it lighter. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/grade-2-titanium-frame-for-samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6"><u>first rumor</u></a> claimed the Galaxy Z Fold 6 would be “the world’s first foldable phone with a titanium frame,” following in the footsteps of the Galaxy S24 Ultra and iPhone 15 Pro Max. This would make it lighter, while also aiming to improve the durability, which in turn, could result in higher sales as there are still concerns about the longevity of foldable phones.</p><p>A few weeks later, Ice Universe claimed the “Galaxy Z Fold6 weighs 239g and finally reaches the first-tier level. It weighs the same as the Voyage Black OnePlus Open.” The comparison to the Open is an obvious one, as OnePlus really won over foldable fans with the release in late 2023. However, it’s worth pointing out that this would offer quite a dramatic decrease in weight as the Galaxy Z Fold 5 weighs 256 grams. </p>
<p>While many of us were enjoying burgers, hotdogs, and fireworks, a surprise leak spilled the beans on the specs for Samsung’s upcoming foldables. According to the leak, both devices would be powered by the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 for Galaxy, paired with 12GB of RAM. Meanwhile, the display on the Z Fold 6 would now be able to reach up to 2,600 nits of brightness, a massive improvement over the 1,750 nits from the Fold 5. </p><p>Despite relying on the same 4,400mAh battery, the leak showed claims of an extra hour of “LTE internet,” and two more hours of video playback. It also revealed that Samsung would not be implementing any upgrades to the triple rear camera setup, marking the third generation of Z Fold devices to use the same camera system.</p>
<p>Given all of the leaks and rumors about what is set to be a somewhat boring release, there was still hope that Samsung would be lowering the cost of its foldable pairing. Unfortunately, a report in June claimed that not only would we not be seeing lower prices, but that the Flip 6 and Fold 6 would actually cost $100 more than their predecessors. What makes matters more frustrating is that the only real explanation could be a rise in cost for the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3, as that’s what’s been attributed to the higher price tag of the Galaxy S24 Ultra.</p>
<p>Samsung’s second major event is set to get underway at any minute, but we’ll keep you posted on what we think about today’s announcements. And remember, you can watch Galaxy Unpacked alongside us, as it’s being live-streamed. Just hit the link below to learn more about how to watch as Samsung unveils its next lineup of flagship products.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/samsung-galaxy-unpacked-2024-live-blog-and-everything-you-need-to-know-about-the-z-fold-6-flip-6-and-galaxy-ring</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung Unpacked is July 10th, but we're already on the ground with live updates and everything you need to know about the historic announcement event.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">vcnepL3Qow2kDqJ5vN2xCQ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tcyq44jCevuwixo5VKx8kg.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 02:12:47 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ shruti.shekar@futurenet.com (Shruti Shekar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tcyq44jCevuwixo5VKx8kg.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Samsung]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung Unpacked 2024 ad]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung Unpacked 2024 ad]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Leaks suggest the Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 Slim might be worth waiting for ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung is reportedly working on a Galaxy Z Fold 6 Slim foldable that could debut at the end of this year.</li><li>The company will reveal its typical foldables, the Galaxy Z Fold 6 and Galaxy Z Flip 6, at a Samsung Unpacked event on July 10.</li><li>The possible Galaxy Z Fold 6 Slim is rumored to offer a few notable advantages over Samsung’s regular foldable, including a larger 8-inch display.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>All eyes are on Samsung, as the company is about to reveal its next-generation foldables at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/samsung-galaxy-unpacked-2024-live-blog-and-everything-you-need-to-know-about-the-z-fold-6-flip-6-and-galaxy-ring">a Galaxy Unpacked event</a> on July 10. That includes the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-galaxy-z-flip-6-full-specs-leak">Galaxy Z Flip 6 and Galaxy Z Fold 6</a>, which are set to offer a few upgrades over their predecessors. We’re expecting to see other cool things, too, like new Galaxy Watch models and the Galaxy Ring. However, the most exciting Samsung foldable of the year might not be released at the summer Galaxy Unpacked event.</p><p>It’s looking increasingly likely that Samsung will introduce a third folding phone at some point this year. Leakers have dubbed it the “Galaxy Z Fold 6 Slim,“ and it is rumored to be a more premium version of the Galaxy Z Fold 6. That could mean a lot of things—this rumored foldable might have more premium features and a higher price tag. Of course, the “slim” moniker would suggest that the Galaxy Z Fold 6 Slim is thinner than the standard model.</p><p>According to prior reports, this ultra-thin version of the Galaxy Z Fold 6 would be looking at a fourth-quarter release. One report indicated that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-slim-rumor-mill">the Galaxy Z Fold 6 Slim could be released in October</a>, right around the time we’d usually see new Pixels debut. Now that Google has moved up its event to an August date, the Galaxy Z Fold 6 Slim could be the lone Android flagship released in that month. </p><p>It feels like Samsung was resting on its laurels as the king of the foldable space for a while. The company was uncontested in the U.S. foldable market for a while, but a lack of significant improvements to the Galaxy Z Fold 5 opened the door for the OnePlus Open to earn the title of best foldable, at least in terms of specs. Similarly, the company’s foldables aren’t even close to matching the devices coming out of China these days. All these factors contributed to Samsung losing the title of global folding phone shipments leader, with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/global-foldable-market-share-q1-2024">Huawei taking Samsung’s top spot in Q1 2024</a>.</p><p>That’s why it’s exciting to see a rumored Galaxy Z Fold 6 Slim in development that could truly rival cutting-edge foldables, especially those from Asia. However, the supposed release timeline for this device certainly complicates things for prospective buyers. If the rumored October release window is accurate, it’s smack in the middle of Samsung’s typical Galaxy Unpacked event. That might make potential Galaxy Z Fold 6 buyers wait a few months to make their purchase or make potential Galaxy S25 customers purchase a Galaxy Z Fold 6 Slim early instead.</p>
<h2 id="why-the-galaxy-z-fold-6-slim-could-be-worth-the-wait-2">Why the Galaxy Z Fold 6 Slim could be worth the wait</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="zSPR5TTR7pDZ5SJ5HSVjYU" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Z-Fold-5-flex-back-02.jpg" alt="Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5 in flex mode" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zSPR5TTR7pDZ5SJ5HSVjYU.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div></figure>
<p>The latest information about the Galaxy Z Fold 6 Slim comes from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="http://www.thelec.kr/news/articleView.html?idxno=28933" target="_blank">The Elec</a>, a South Korean publication with a reliable history of reporting on Samsung’s future plans. The site says that this new folding phone will feature the largest display we’ve ever seen from Samsung on a foldable. It’ll be eight inches diagonally, per the report, which is significantly more screen real estate than the 7.6-inch display on current phones.</p><p>This will mean that the cover screen will also be larger, measuring 6.5 inches diagonally. Samsung is poised to make the cover screen on the standard Galaxy Z Fold 6 slightly wider, matching the trend that the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-fold-review" target="_blank">Pixel Fold</a> and OnePlus Open ushered in. However, the Galaxy Z Fold 6 Slim will reportedly be even bigger. </p><p>The thinner design is intended to keep Samsung competitive with other Asian phone manufacturers, like Huawei and Honor. They have ultra-thin foldables available that are barely larger than a traditional smartphone. As such, Samsung might restrict sales to certain countries or regions, like Asia. The company might only make 500,000 units, according to recent reports, and it’s unknown whether the Galaxy Z Fold 6 Slim will be available in the U.S.</p><p>There are some tradeoffs that will come with the more compact design. For example, Samsung is expected to remove S Pen support for the Slim version of the Galaxy Z Fold 6. It’s unknown what it will cost or where it will be available, so there is a risk to waiting for a foldable that might be out of your price range, be missing core features, or simply be unavailable in your country or region. </p><p>With all that being said, it still might be worth waiting to see what comes of the Galaxy Z Fold 6 Slim before buying a standard Galaxy Z Fold 6. Folding phones are too expensive to purchase, and one could be one-upped by a newer model just a few months later.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/leaks-suggest-the-samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-slim-might-be-worth-waiting-for</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung is reportedly making a third foldable this year, the Galaxy Z Fold 6 Slim, and it is said to have a larger display. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">CdbaLe67BKNwt6U9nVs94A</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Y8u5hR93eZWidEUtmuNL4J.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 21:37:33 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Y8u5hR93eZWidEUtmuNL4J.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[S Pen Fold and Slim S Pen for the Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[S Pen Fold and Slim S Pen for the Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Motorola Razr 2024 vs. Nubia Flip 5G ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[         <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="903c2041-6618-4643-9654-2a2a73f3abd5">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/aQmkmwcXHNYdm3tKYBM5oK.jpg' alt="The Motorola Razr 2024 in Spritz Orange"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Motorola Razr 2024</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Foldable on a budget </strong></em></p>
<p>If you’re looking to test the waters in foldable phones but aren’t quite ready to drop a massive amount on one, the Motorola Razr 2024 is a good option to try out the design. It has decent though not top-notch specs and employs a design similar to many other foldables. With OS updates for three years, you can hand it over to someone else or sell it once you decide if you’re ready for something more premium.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Comes with Gemini Assistant</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Sizable inner and outer screens</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Supports 3 years of OS updates, 4 years of security</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Affordable</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Slower processor</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No charger in the box</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="11a80468-b308-4da4-a754-33f096e7d648">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Yt5NmEfSXrrWzuZDGEEV8B.jpg' alt="A render of the front and back of the Nubia Flip 5G"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Nubia Flip 5G</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>An interesting concept </strong></em></p>
<p>The Nubia Flip 5G employs an interesting design with a small, smartwatch-sized circular external screen to complement the larger inner screen. While its hinge is durable and it opens flat, the phone has some performance issues we just can’t ignore. Plus, you can only perform limited functions from the outer screen. Thus, while it has some better specs, this phone might not be worth the investment.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Lovely and unique design</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Takes decent photos</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>The crease is barely noticeable</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Affordable</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Outdated software</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Doesn't have an IP rating</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Does not support wireless charging</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Limited external screen functionality</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Performance is buggy</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<p>The Motorola Razr 2024 vs. Nubia Flip 5G are both foldable phones that provide an outer screen plus a larger inner screen once unfolded. If you’re considering getting a foldable phone, one of the latest trends of late, these are both good options to consider. But let’s take a look at how they compare to help you decide between the two.</p>
<h2 id="motorola-razr-2024-vs-nubia-flip-5g-their-designs-2">Motorola Razr 2024 vs. Nubia Flip 5G: Their designs</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="xTNhEtXXViTAqcjaUq7nBd" name="motorola razr 2024 in hand.jpg" alt="Motorola Razr 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xTNhEtXXViTAqcjaUq7nBd.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Motorola)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2024-launch">Motorola Razr 2024</a>, introduced in summer 2024, comes in funky color options, including Spritz Orange, Beach Sand, and Koala Grey. It has a 3.6-inch pOLED HDR10+ (1,056 x 1,066) external display. When unfolded, it reveals a 6.9-inch pOLED HDR10+ FHD+ 2,640 x 1,080 foldable display. </p><p>The external screen offers up to 90Hz refresh rate and 1,700 nits of brightness, so it’s decently viewable in direct sunlight while the main screen affords a 120Hz refresh rate and an impressive 3,000 nits peak brightness. The outer screen is great for viewing quick information, like calendar alerts, text messages, weather updates, and more. With Google Gemini and Google Photos access, it’s also a neat way to interact with the phone without opening it up. </p><p>Made with Corning Gorilla Glass Victus, it’s a fairly durable phone with a vegan leather back and high-strength aluminum frame. It meets an IPX8 rating, which makes it resistant against water but not rated for dust, which is typical of foldable phones with a hinge like this one. </p><p>Available with 256GB storage, the 4,200mAh battery is rated to last all day, and the phone supports 30W TurboPower charging, 33W regular charging, and 15W wireless charging. But there’s no charger in the box, so you’ll need to charge it with a USB-C cable you have at home (most of us have many nowadays anyway) or purchase a TurboPower charger separately to keep it running for as long as possible per charge. </p><p>Additional basic features include 5G, USB-C as noted, NFC, fingerprint reader, Bluetooth 5.4, Wi-Fi, lock screen, personalized themes, dual stereo speakers, and quick gestures. It also has a Moto Secure folder for storing personal and sensitive information privately.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3841px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.26%;"><img id="rYVcTPb3ifzSyr9Tm4rPxK" name="Nubia-Flip-5G-review-8.jpg" alt="Holding a closed Nubia Flip 5G with the cover screen on" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rYVcTPb3ifzSyr9Tm4rPxK.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3841" height="2161" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Introduced in February 2024, the Nubia Flip 5G is a foldable phone from a brand you might not know as much about. It comes in Sunshine Golden, Cosmic Black, or Flowing Lilac and is designed to be ultra-pocket-sized, offering a seamless fold and opening without wrinkles. The high-strength hinge has been tested for up to 2,000 folds. While it’s thin when folded up and unfolded, it’s also a heavier phone, so that’s something to keep in mind. </p><p>In his review, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/nubia-flip-5g-review">Android Central’s Derrek Lee</a> says he loves the flat frame, which reminds him of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-5-review">Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 5</a>, but finds this phone softer to the touch. Made with metallic, starlight AG etched glass with a zircon sand sandblasting frame, it has a 6.9-inch 2,790 x 1,188 OLED inner screen and much smaller, circular 1.43-inch 466 x 466 OLED external display. To put this in perspective, the outer screen is comparable in size to the typical screen on a circular smartwatch. </p><p>The circular external screen might not be what you’d expect from a foldable, but Lee loves the golden ring around it that gives it a premium feel. However, it won’t provide the same experience as you’d get with other foldables that have external screens twice the size. You can cycle through eight panels for functions like camera, calendar, and music player and see notifications, but not do anything about them (you can’t reply to a message, for example). </p><p>It comes with either 256GB or 512GB storage depending on the country and availability, and with a 4,310mAh battery that supports 33W charging. Nubia says it can charge up to 50 percent in just 18 minutes. It does not, however, support wireless charging. </p><p>With 5G connectivity, as the name implies, it also has USB-C, the older Bluetooth 5.1 spec, fingerprint reader, NFC, and dual speakers with DTS:X Ultra and Snapdragon Sound. There’s an optional face wake-up or fingerprint sensor and even mobile NFC door unlocking, which varies by country or region. </p><p>Enjoy additional features like all-care eye protection with dark, night, and read modes. With the circular front screen, you can access things like one-click call backs and even a cute interactive 3D pet. The Nubia Flip 5G, however, does not have an IP rating for resistance against dust or water.</p>
<h2 id="motorola-razr-2024-vs-nubia-flip-5g-specs-2">Motorola Razr 2024 vs. Nubia Flip 5G: Specs</h2>
<p>Let’s break down the most notable specs of these two foldable phones.</p>

<p>There are some differences here between the two foldable phones, with the Motorola Razr 2024 having a leg up in some respects and the Nubia Flip 5G in others.</p>
<h2 id="motorola-razr-2024-vs-nubia-flip-5g-operation-2">Motorola Razr 2024 vs. Nubia Flip 5G: Operation</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="LFgJShXezaCaPrAAq9wbJd" name="motorola razr 2024 upright.jpg" alt="Motorola Razr 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LFgJShXezaCaPrAAq9wbJd.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Motorola)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Motorola Razr 2024 comes loaded with Android 14 and supports three years of software and four years of bi-monthly security updates, which is decent. It also features Motorola’s Hello UX overlay for further personalizing the look and feel of the phone. </p><p>With a MediaTek Dimensity 7300x processor, this isn’t the most powerful foldable phone. Considering most people opting for a foldable are power users on the cutting edge of technology, you might find this disappointing. </p><p>However, the phone does come with moto ai and Gemini Assistant so you can enjoy plenty of AI-powered features, both on the main phone as well as the external display. There’s a no-hand mode, for example, for incoming calls so you can answer without even opening the phone. </p><p>Along with the 8GB RAM, the phone also offers RAM Boost, which can temporarily turn storage into 8GB of extra RAM as needed. You might tap into this for more intensive tasks, like gaming. This is complemented by the dual stereo speakers that support Dolby Atmos and Spatial Audio content so you get a favorable audio experience to go along with the bright and beautiful screens.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="xbvS7EPcY8cr5BroM4PLe8" name="Nubia-Flip-5G-review-4.jpg" alt="Notifications showing on the Nubia Flip 5G cover screen" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xbvS7EPcY8cr5BroM4PLe8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Nubia Flip 5G comes with a more powerful albeit mid-range Snapdragon 7 Gen 1 processor and offers up to 12GB RAM, depending on the version and country. Lee says it handles itself well, even when playing games at a high setting. However, the phone can get warm after a long gaming session. The 120Hz refresh rate is great but note that you need to adjust to this in settings as the default is set to 60Hz. </p><p>The phone oddly runs on the older Android 13 OS and it’s unclear how many software updates and how many years of security updates it might support. It’s strange, nonetheless, that a phone released in 2024 would come with an older version of the OS. </p><p>The phone also boasts MyOS 13 with animation speed adjustments, a wallpaper color picker, split screen, and other cool features baked in over and above the stock Android experience. But there’s nothing else worth noting about this phone.</p>
<h2 id="motorola-razr-2024-vs-nubia-flip-5g-cameras-2">Motorola Razr 2024 vs. Nubia Flip 5G: Cameras</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="JDWprQopjTk2DXWe83sw4d" name="motorola razr 2024 selfie.jpg" alt="Motorola Razr 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JDWprQopjTk2DXWe83sw4d.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Motorola)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The cameras in the Motorola Razr 2024 are decent but won’t blow you away. You get a respectable 50MP main camera along with a decent 13MP ultra-wide camera with macro vision and a 32MP front “selfie” camera. </p><p>Motorola adds some neat photo features, like the option to tilt the phone at a 90° angle for video recording to start automatically, holding it just like a traditional video camera. There’s also the cool Photo Booth mode that will snap four consecutive photos as you make different poses, mimicking the shopping mall photo booths of yesteryear. </p><p>Additionally, the phone has a dual preview mode that allows you to view yourself on the external display while taking a selfie so you can fix your make-up or hair or adjust your pose or smile just right before taking the photo.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3582px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="Gs3epnRpnNGJvU2DJbniRj" name="Nubia-Flip-5G-review-hero.jpg" alt="The Nubia Flip 5G outdoors and in hand" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Gs3epnRpnNGJvU2DJbniRj.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3582" height="2015" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Across the board, the Motorola Razr 2024 has better cameras than the Nubia Flip 5G. It does have the same 50MP sensor for its AI dual camera, but there’s no ultra-wide camera, just a 2MP depth camera that’s likely not usable at all. The front camera also leaves something to be desired at a dismal 16MP, a waste for a foldable phone with so many great opportunities to take selfies. </p><p>Nonetheless, Lee says he was pleasantly surprised with the performance of the main camera, which he said took decent images when the lighting conditions were favorable that had lots of detail and vibrancy. He found the images better than ones he had snapped with the previous generation <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-2023-review">Motorola Razr 2023</a>. He did, however, find that the phone’s camera can go overboard with saturation and you’ll lose a lot of detail when zooming in to images you have taken from further away. </p><p>There are some cool usability features when it comes to the cameras in the Nubia Flip 5G, though, including gesture and smile snap, super night camera, and fun real time photo filters so you can turn your images into ones with themes like cyberpunk, mucha, and nostalgic film styles. The circular screen also plays a role here since you can use it as a viewfinder for the camera, set a photo timer, or even swipe up and down to cycle among photo and video modes.</p>
<h2 id="motorola-razr-2024-vs-nubia-flip-5g-which-should-you-buy-2">Motorola Razr 2024 vs. Nubia Flip 5G: Which should you buy?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="qrpiLbhLafNgKi7yZFGFqc" name="motorola razr 2024 video.jpg" alt="Motorola Razr 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qrpiLbhLafNgKi7yZFGFqc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Motorola)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>When it comes to foldable phones, there are only a limited number of them on the market to date. But that’s quickly changing as more brands are entering the category and established ones are refreshing designs and coming out with new options. </p><p>Both the Motorola Razr 2024 vs. Nubia Flip 5G are affordable options in this otherwise expensive category. We ranked the Motorola Razr 2023 as the top affordable flip phone on our list of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">the best foldable phones</a> and we’re confident that once we get our hands on it, the Motorola Razr 2024 will take its place. </p><p>The Motorola Razr 2024 is more of a traditional foldable phone design that gives you a big external display you can make use of when the phone is folded closed. But some of its specs are disappointing, though necessary to bring the cost down. You won’t get an ultra-fast processor, for example, and don’t even get a charger in the box. But overall, it’s a pretty decent foldable phone if you’re looking to get into this category and don’t want to spend in the thousands. </p><p>By contrast, the Nubia Flip 5G is a less traditional foldable, with an outer screen that’s more like a smartwatch screen. It has limited functionality, but still classifies as a foldable for those who might prefer the design. </p><p>Lee found the circular outer screen disappointing overall and he deems only one of the three cameras to be actually useful. The fact that the Nubia Flip 5G comes with an older OS version is odd, and the lack of wireless charging is an unfortunate omission for a phone that employs such a modern design. </p><p>Through his review period, Lee also experienced some issues with things like notifications showing up late or not at all, and found the battery barely lasted a day with mixed use of apps like social media, games, and photos. At least it recharges quickly. </p><p>Bottom line: if you’re looking for something foldable on the cheap, go with the Motorola Razr 2024, which will provide a larger external screen, some cool AI features (includes ones that can be accessed from that screen), and decent cameras. Yes, it has an outdated, slower processor. But you get what you pay for. If you need more, wait it out, save up some money, and consider another foldable that might set you back more dough but will offer much better overall performance and specs.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="022e5863-8ca4-4b78-9e37-07ce5dcc9e96">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yCeQuEhngWq6dtEz8hQUaK.jpg' alt="The Motorola Razr 2024 in Koala Gray"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Motorola Razr 2024</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>A respectable entry option</strong></em> </p>
<p>If you are dying to get your hands on a foldable phone but don’t have a ton of dough to spare, the Motorola Razr 2024 is a decent option worth considering. It doesn’t cost an arm and a leg but has a design that’s a lot like many others that are twice its price. Just keep in mind that there are some concessions to be made when it comes to specs and performance if you go this route.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="57fb8ad3-90b9-4004-802d-ce80c9edcd21">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Yt5NmEfSXrrWzuZDGEEV8B.jpg' alt="A render of the front and back of the Nubia Flip 5G"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Nubia Flip 5G</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Outdated already </strong></em></p>
<p>Despite launching in February 2024, the Nubia Flip 5G comes loaded with the old Android 13 OS, and it’s unclear how many more software updates it will support. It has a solid mid-range processor and a cute smartwatch-sized outer screen that some might love but others may find doesn’t meet expectations for a foldable. With some performance downsides, however, there are better options to consider.  </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-2024-vs-nubia-flip-5g</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ If you're looking for a foldable phone but don't have a large sum to spend, you can consider the affordable Motorola Razr 2024 and Nubia Flip 5G. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">VqanVcmhexjFVfXH3UmACK</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FeE6qpTu7DwUcTQQewxzWM.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 20:38:30 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ christinep2424@gmail.com (Christine Persaud) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FeE6qpTu7DwUcTQQewxzWM.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Motorola]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Motorola Razr 2024 colors]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Motorola Razr 2024 colors]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Walmart has apparently launched its "biggest sale ever" — these are the Android deals I'd buy  ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Prime Day 2024 is a week away, but Walmart is preemptively taking on the competition by launching a massive sitewide sale of its own, complete with a wide assortment of great Android deals. The retailer is calling the event its "biggest sale ever", and while I can&apos;t verify that claim, I <em>have</em> listed many of the best discounts for Android users below. The sale runs today through Thursday, July 11th, so don&apos;t wait if a particular offer catches your eye.</p><p>Wearables, in particular, are receiving major discounts, but there are some good phone deals in there too. Keep reading to see all of my favorites, and if you want to shop beyond the confines of Android-friendly tech, don&apos;t forget to peek at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.walmart.com/shop/deals"><strong>Walmart&apos;s full official list of deals</strong></a> so you can see everything that&apos;s available. </p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-quick-links"><span>Quick links</span></h3>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.walmart.com/plus"><strong>Get 50% off a year of Walmart Plus — just $49 for a limited time</strong></a></li><li><strong>Fitbit Charge 6: </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Fitbit-Charge-6-Black-aluminum-activity-tracker-with-infinity-band-silicone-obsidian-NFC-Bluetooth-1-33-oz/5087333627"><del>$159.95</del> <strong>now $119.95 at Walmart</strong></a></li><li><strong>Sony WH-1000XM5:</strong> <a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Sony-WH-1000XM5-The-Best-Wireless-Noise-Canceling-Headphones-Black/386006068"><del>$399.99</del> <strong>now $314.99 at Walmart</strong></a></li><li><strong>Samsung Galaxy A54 5G: </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/SAMSUNG-Galaxy-A54-5G-A-Series-Cell-Phone-Factory-Unlocked-Android-Smartphone-128GB-w-6-4-Fluid-Display-Screen-Hi-Res-Camera-Long-Battery-Life-Refine/3467193116"><del>$449.99</del> <strong>now $340 at Walmart</strong></a></li><li><strong>Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 40mm:</strong> <a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Samsung-Galaxy-Watch6-40mm-Smart-Watch-w-Bluetooth-Armor-Aluminum-Graphite/3074183240"><del>$299.99</del> <strong>now $204.97 at Walmart</strong></a></li><li><strong>Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 Ultra 256GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Samsung-Galaxy-Tab-S9-Ultra-Rugged-Tablet-14-6-Octa-core-Cortex-X3-Single-core-1-Core-3-36-GHz-Cortex-A715-Dual-core-2-2-80-A710-GHz-12-GB-R/3977383562"><del>$1,199</del><strong> now $769.98 at Walmart</strong></a></li><li><strong>TCL 75" Class Q 4K QLED smart TV: </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/TCL-75-Class-Q-Class-4K-QLED-HDR-Smart-TV-with-Google-TV-75Q650G/2620966245"><del>$899.99</del> <strong>now $498 at Walmart</strong></a></li></ul>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-top-walmart-deals"><span>Top Walmart deals</span></h3>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="04ae1676-ca19-46e5-a185-c32f11f668fa" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$159.95" data-dimension48="$159.95" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Fitbit-Charge-6-Black-aluminum-activity-tracker-with-infinity-band-silicone-obsidian-NFC-Bluetooth-1-33-oz/5087333627" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="KWKMozPtNvwKG537XuSSoB" name="fitbit-charge-6-health-tracker-space.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KWKMozPtNvwKG537XuSSoB.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1000" height="1000" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Fitbit Charge 6:</strong> <a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Fitbit-Charge-6-Black-aluminum-activity-tracker-with-infinity-band-silicone-obsidian-NFC-Bluetooth-1-33-oz/5087333627" data-dimension112="04ae1676-ca19-46e5-a185-c32f11f668fa" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$159.95" data-dimension48="$159.95"><del>$159.95</del><strong> $119.95 at Walmart</strong></a></p>
<p>Our top choice for the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-fitbit">best Fitbit</a> that money can buy today, the Charge 6 has a whopping 7 days of battery life on a single charge, plus you get a ton of health and fitness tracking features and NFC/GPS support. Walmart's sale is carving $40 off the formidable fitness tracker, knocking the price down to only $119.95. </p>
<p><strong>Price check: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CC644KMJ">Amazon - $154.99</a> | <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/fitbit-charge-6-advanced-fitness-health-tracker-obsidian/6559662.p">Best Buy - $159.99</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Fitbit-Charge-6-Black-aluminum-activity-tracker-with-infinity-band-silicone-obsidian-NFC-Bluetooth-1-33-oz/5087333627" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="04ae1676-ca19-46e5-a185-c32f11f668fa" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$159.95" data-dimension48="$159.95">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="c686958b-bb78-45f6-8afb-a6fa5f55e3c2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$399.99" data-dimension48="$399.99" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Sony-WH-1000XM5-The-Best-Wireless-Noise-Canceling-Headphones-Black/386006068" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:830px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="qz9SARuXK2DKN6Amh25Ek9" name="sony-wh-1000xm5-square-render-w-space.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qz9SARuXK2DKN6Amh25Ek9.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="830" height="830" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Sony WH-1000XM5 Headphones:</strong> <a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Sony-WH-1000XM5-The-Best-Wireless-Noise-Canceling-Headphones-Black/386006068" data-dimension112="c686958b-bb78-45f6-8afb-a6fa5f55e3c2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$399.99" data-dimension48="$399.99"><del>$399.99</del> <strong>$314.99 at Walmart</strong></a></p>
<p>The Sony WH-1000XM5 have received the honor of being our favorite <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones">wireless headphones</a> because of their generation-defining ANC (active noise cancellation), superb sound quality, and long battery life, but they aren't exactly cheap. That's why we're excited to see Walmart drop over $80 off the price of these legendary cans for the duration of the sale.</p>
<p><strong>Price check: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WH-1000XM5-Canceling-Headphones-Hands-Free/dp/B09XS7JWHH">Amazon - $379</a> | <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/sony-wh-1000xm5-wireless-noise-canceling-over-the-ear-headphones-silver/6505728.p">Best Buy - $399</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Sony-WH-1000XM5-The-Best-Wireless-Noise-Canceling-Headphones-Black/386006068" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="c686958b-bb78-45f6-8afb-a6fa5f55e3c2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$399.99" data-dimension48="$399.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="d6dd541e-44c5-4479-b584-380d8e529f63" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy A54 5G: $449.99" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy A54 5G: $449.99" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/SAMSUNG-Galaxy-A54-5G-A-Series-Cell-Phone-Factory-Unlocked-Android-Smartphone-128GB-w-6-4-Fluid-Display-Screen-Hi-Res-Camera-Long-Battery-Life-Refine/3467193116" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:403px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:136.48%;"><img id="4ryS4fRqp4s46d83Rx8JnN" name="Samsung-Galaxy-A54.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4ryS4fRqp4s46d83Rx8JnN.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="403" height="550" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy A54 5G: </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/SAMSUNG-Galaxy-A54-5G-A-Series-Cell-Phone-Factory-Unlocked-Android-Smartphone-128GB-w-6-4-Fluid-Display-Screen-Hi-Res-Camera-Long-Battery-Life-Refine/3467193116" data-dimension112="d6dd541e-44c5-4479-b584-380d8e529f63" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy A54 5G: $449.99" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy A54 5G: $449.99"><del>$449.99</del><strong> $340 at Walmart</strong></a></p>
<p>The Galaxy A54 5G may be last-gen, but it's still a solid Android phone if you're looking to save some cash today. Currently selling for just $340 unlocked at Walmart, the midrange device boasts a lovely 120Hz AMOLED display, a huge 5,000mAh battery, and years of OS updates guaranteed straight out of the box. </p>
<p><strong>Price check:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Factory-Unlocked-Android-Smartphone/dp/B0BSLR2L5R/">Amazon - $326.40 (Used)</a> | <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-a54-5g-128gb-unlocked-awesome-graphite/6538053.p">Best Buy - $449.99</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/SAMSUNG-Galaxy-A54-5G-A-Series-Cell-Phone-Factory-Unlocked-Android-Smartphone-128GB-w-6-4-Fluid-Display-Screen-Hi-Res-Camera-Long-Battery-Life-Refine/3467193116" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="d6dd541e-44c5-4479-b584-380d8e529f63" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy A54 5G: $449.99" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy A54 5G: $449.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="135edaa7-523a-407d-aba0-1c48e2bbda8a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$299.99" data-dimension48="$299.99" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Samsung-Galaxy-Watch6-40mm-Smart-Watch-w-Bluetooth-Armor-Aluminum-Graphite/3074183240" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="ZFk8tX7bD9dZBwf8oaBae8" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Watch-6-square-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZFk8tX7bD9dZBwf8oaBae8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="800" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 40mm:</strong> <a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Samsung-Galaxy-Watch6-40mm-Smart-Watch-w-Bluetooth-Armor-Aluminum-Graphite/3074183240" data-dimension112="135edaa7-523a-407d-aba0-1c48e2bbda8a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$299.99" data-dimension48="$299.99"><del>$299.99</del> <strong>$204.97 at Walmart</strong></a></p>
<p>Sure, the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-7">Galaxy Watch 7</a> is probably going to be revealed during Samsung Unpacked tomorrow, but if you don't care about owning the absolute newest wearable on the market, the Galaxy Watch 6 remains an outstanding smartwatch. The prospect of buying this flagship wearable becomes even more tempting when you see that Walmart's big sale has slashed an epic $95 off the price, clobbering the current offers from Amazon and Best Buy. </p>
<p><strong>Price check:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Bluetooth-Smartwatch-Personalized-Advanced/dp/B0C792QRW6">Amazon - $209.99</a> | <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-watch6-aluminum-smartwatch-40mm-bt-cream/6546702.p">Best Buy - $209.99</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Samsung-Galaxy-Watch6-40mm-Smart-Watch-w-Bluetooth-Armor-Aluminum-Graphite/3074183240" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="135edaa7-523a-407d-aba0-1c48e2bbda8a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$299.99" data-dimension48="$299.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="d92b34f0-223a-4f56-8b82-9ded2287e9de" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,199" data-dimension48="$1,199" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Samsung-Galaxy-Tab-S9-Ultra-Rugged-Tablet-14-6-Octa-core-Cortex-X3-Single-core-1-Core-3-36-GHz-Cortex-A715-Dual-core-2-2-80-A710-GHz-12-GB-R/3977383562" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="yLfHKyedVCjhtyaSNpCT67" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Tab-S9-Ultra-with-S-Pen-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yLfHKyedVCjhtyaSNpCT67.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1080" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 Ultra 256GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Samsung-Galaxy-Tab-S9-Ultra-Rugged-Tablet-14-6-Octa-core-Cortex-X3-Single-core-1-Core-3-36-GHz-Cortex-A715-Dual-core-2-2-80-A710-GHz-12-GB-R/3977383562" data-dimension112="d92b34f0-223a-4f56-8b82-9ded2287e9de" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,199" data-dimension48="$1,199"><del>$1,199</del> <strong>$769.98 at Walmart</strong></a></p>
<p>The Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 Ultra is arguably the most powerful <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-tablets">Android tablet</a> ever built, with a huge 120Hz screen, Snapdragon 8 Gen 2 chipset, and reliable 11,200mAh battery. It's also more expensive than some laptops, so we're pleased to see Walmart's sale slash over $420 off the 256GB device. Keep in mind that this is coming from a third-party seller, not Walmart itself, so the discount won't be around for long.</p>
<p><strong>Price check: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Factory-Unlocked-SM-X910NZA-Including/dp/B0C81DWF4B">Amazon - $1,049.99</a> | <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-tab-s9-ultra-14-6-256gb-wi-fi-with-s-pen-graphite/6546675.p">Best Buy - $1,049.99</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Samsung-Galaxy-Tab-S9-Ultra-Rugged-Tablet-14-6-Octa-core-Cortex-X3-Single-core-1-Core-3-36-GHz-Cortex-A715-Dual-core-2-2-80-A710-GHz-12-GB-R/3977383562" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="d92b34f0-223a-4f56-8b82-9ded2287e9de" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,199" data-dimension48="$1,199">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="97bc7bba-42e3-4b3d-a5bb-9c6182ff52eb" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$899.99" data-dimension48="$899.99" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/TCL-75-Class-Q-Class-4K-QLED-HDR-Smart-TV-with-Google-TV-75Q650G/2620966245" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:638px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:71.47%;"><img id="zaqFvQWifFXYnZByHWQaW6" name="tcl-q-class-4k-tv-render.JPG" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zaqFvQWifFXYnZByHWQaW6.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="638" height="456" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>TCL 75" Class Q 4K QLED smart TV:</strong> <a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/TCL-75-Class-Q-Class-4K-QLED-HDR-Smart-TV-with-Google-TV-75Q650G/2620966245" data-dimension112="97bc7bba-42e3-4b3d-a5bb-9c6182ff52eb" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$899.99" data-dimension48="$899.99"><del>$899.99</del> <strong>$498 at Walmart</strong></a></p>
<p>If you're planning to upgrade the home theater this summer, check out this Walmart deal that drops over 400 bucks off this 75-inch smart TV from TCL. This entertainment powerhouse delivers gorgeous 4K picture with TCL's QLED technology, support from an entire suite of HDR enhancement formats, and DTS Virtual:X support for optimized, immersive audio.  </p>
<p><strong>Price check: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TCL-75-Inch-75Q650F-Streaming-Television/dp/B0C1J5BL57">Amazon - $599.99</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/TCL-75-Class-Q-Class-4K-QLED-HDR-Smart-TV-with-Google-TV-75Q650G/2620966245" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="97bc7bba-42e3-4b3d-a5bb-9c6182ff52eb" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$899.99" data-dimension48="$899.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><em>If you didn&apos;t find what you were looking for at Walmart today, don&apos;t forget that Amazon Prime Day 2024 kicks off next Tuesday, July 16th. To learn more about the sale event, check out our </em><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/amazon-prime-day-2024-dates-early-deals-and-what-to-expect-from-the-sale"><em>Prime Day FAQ and shopping guide</em></a><em>. </em></p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/walmart-has-apparently-launched-its-biggest-sale-ever-these-are-the-android-deals-id-buy</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Days before Amazon Prime Day is set to kick off, Walmart has launched a massive limited-time sale of its own. Here are some of my favorite deals.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Pc5LbDGFeDEBhFpraSC63Y</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/r49HbLKRM5AUoKcQha4aTL.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 17:35:44 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/r49HbLKRM5AUoKcQha4aTL.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[null]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Walmart logo with AC logo]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Walmart logo with AC logo]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ OnePlus builds its Summer Launch Event hype with a host of confirmed specs ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>OnePlus confirmed several specifications regarding its device set to debut during its Summer Event in Milan, Italy on July 16 at 9 am EDT.</li><li>The OnePlus Pad 2 will feature a 12.2-inch display with a 7:5 aspect ratio and an "industry-leading" chip.</li><li>The Watch 2R offers a light, aluminum body, a "classic watch" design, and a 100-hour battery life.</li><li>The OnePlus Nord Buds 3 Pro delivers 49dB of noise cancellation, up to 4,000Hz frequency range, and a 12.4mm driver.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>OnePlus is gearing up for its Summer Launch event by confirming some specifications regarding its debuts on deck for July 16.</p><p>In a press release, the Chinese OEM started by detailing its upcoming Watch 2R, categorized as a "follow-up" to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oneplus-watch-2-review">Watch 2</a>. OnePlus has updated the design of the 2R in a couple of colorways (green and black) with light, aluminum bodies. The bezels of the upcoming device look slightly different from the original Watch 2 as the 2R shifts to a "classic watch" approach.</p><p>Additionally, OnePlus adds that the variant wearable continues to feature a 100-hour battery life like its predecessor but includes "ultra-precise" dual-frequency GPS. Of course, the launch of this device follows <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oneplus-watch-2-china-variant-launch">its original China release</a>.</p><p>The OnePlus Nord Buds 3 Pro is next as the company seeks to redefine the midrange earbud space. Boasting a small redesign, the Buds 3 Pro can reach up to 49 dB of noise cancellation with an ultra-wide frequency range of up to 4,000Hz. </p><p>OnePlus states that these upgrades should boost the next-gen Buds over the capabilities of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/oneplus-nord-buds-2-review">Buds 2</a> in terms of low and high frequencies.</p><p>The Buds 3 Pro will feature 12.4mm drivers and an upgraded BassWaveTM 2.0 for deep, shapely bass tones when listening to music. These higher-tier buds are preparing to join the likes of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/headphones/oneplus-buds-3-announcement-date-revealed">the base Buds 3</a> that launched earlier this year.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1077px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="VJVaAM6XzPmZ6Csr7PHSVk" name="oneplus-watch-2-2024-china-launch-hero.jpg" alt="OnePlus Watch 2 China launch brings LTE (eSIM) support." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VJVaAM6XzPmZ6Csr7PHSVk.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1077" height="606" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OnePlus / Weibo)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Rounding out the announcements is the OnePlus Pad 2. The device is said to feature a large 12.1-inch display with a 7:5 aspect ratio. The company teased that the device would contain an "industry-leading" SoC but did not state specifically what consumers should expect. However, it seems confident that it will aid users in their daily tasks.</p><p>There <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/key-specs-for-the-oneplus-pad-2-may-have-surfaced-thanks-to-this-benchmark-listing">were rumors</a> that OnePlus could opt for Qualcomm&apos;s Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 SoC for the Pad 2.</p><p>OnePlus is preparing to launch these products on July 16 in Milan, Italy. Interested parties can head to the OnePlus website or they can view the event live on its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uXHMP2nZFho&ab_channel=OnePlus">YouTube channel</a>. The festivities kick off at 9 am EDT.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oneplus-summer-launch-event-confirmed-specs</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ OnePlus confirmed what consumers can expect from its devices during the Summer Launch Event. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">xVavSf5GXu9A3cnTvZoDLG</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rTc9AqdMCDdw6WJqt8TzoT.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 16:58:59 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rTc9AqdMCDdw6WJqt8TzoT.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus logo on a wall]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus logo on a wall]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Phone 2 gets Nothing OS 2.6 with new features and bug fixes ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Nothing brings new features and experience improvements to the Phone 2.</li><li>The update, dubbed Nothing OS 2.6, brings several enhancements to the Game Mode on the flagship phone.</li><li>Bug fixes are also included in the firmware release for WhatsApp, which previously affected voice and call recording in the app.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>While we await the launch of Phone 3 from Nothing, the predecessor, Phone 2, is getting a new operating system update, dubbed Nothing OS 2.6. It simultaneously brings in many new features, experience improvements, and bug fixes. Phone 2 users will have to bear in mind that it is being rolled out staggered, and the update won&apos;t reflect on the devices right away.</p><p>In the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://nothing.community/d/12446-phone-2-nothing-os-26-changelog">community post</a>, Nothing shared the full changelog of the latest build, which includes features like support for deleting wallpaper history in Wallpaper Studio for the Home Screen. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/nothing-phone-2-review">Phone 2</a> users will now see new user-friendly prompts for their cities during the initial setup of the weather widget or app.</p>
<p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/cmf-watch-pro-2-launch">CMF Watch 2 Pro</a> was just announced this week, and the company is now supporting the CMF Watch battery level display in the Quick Settings Bluetooth tile with the new firmware release on the Phone 2. The Nothing earbuds users will also see optimizations for the Low Lag Mode experience.</p><p>Game Mode on the Phone 2 is seeing a bunch of enhancements with Nothing OS 2.6. One of these is tapping the sidebar to access the Game Dashboard while gaming quickly. To lessen the interruption of the gaming experience, incoming calls will be showcased as a pop-up view.</p>
<p>Besides, there&apos;s new support to reject third-party app calls during gameplay, which can include WhatsApp, for instance. Also, support being added for a one-tap callback after rejecting a regular call while gaming. The light notifications will also see optimizations, which can further showcase more information during gameplay. Besides, there&apos;s new support for blocking notifications while gaming to reduce distractions.</p><p>The other bug fixes with the new firmware release include a fix to an issue "affecting voice and call recording in WhatsApp." Some anomalies caused when making emergency calls in certain cases have also been resolved. Some apps were facing issues while using the Cloned Apps feature on the Phone 2, which was fixed with the new update.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/nothing-phone-2-gets-new-nothing-os-2.6-system-update</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ As we wait for Phone 3, which seems unlikely to happen soon, Phone 2 has a new operating system update. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">TQ4KgSwtoHanaj5atRf97P</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/A4jNceWRzrygtnXSzBpH37.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 16:38:05 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/A4jNceWRzrygtnXSzBpH37.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicolas Sutrich]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Nothing OS 2.0 home screen on the Nothing Phone 2]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Nothing OS 2.0 home screen on the Nothing Phone 2]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ OnePlus 12 and OnePlus Open get the latest security patches ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>OnePlus 12 and OnePlus Open get the June Android security patch this week.</li><li>Additionally, the latest update has several improvements, new features, and bug fixes.</li><li>While the OnePlus 12 receives the latest firmware in multiple regions, including the U.S., the firmware release for the OnePlus Open is currently limited to India.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>OnePlus has started rolling out its June Android security patch update for its premium handsets, including the latest OnePlus 12 and the OnePlus Open. Both phones are getting the <strong>OxygenOS 14.0.0.810</strong> builds. However, they differ significantly when it comes to their change logs.</p><p>The build to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12-review">OnePlus 12</a> is being rolled out extensively with regions including the European Union, India, and North America. It brings several new Touch Control improvements, such as app icons that are promised to respond faster when users tap them on their home screens.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="KP77ktFmGJABimSRhbDnmE" name="oneplus-12-2.jpg" alt="OnePlus 12 back against colorful background" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KP77ktFmGJABimSRhbDnmE.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Similarly, overall touch responsiveness will see improvements when opening/closing apps. The company notes in the accompanying <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://community.oneplus.com/thread/1628541882587938816">community post</a> that the animations are also said to be optimized when opening and closing multiple apps and when dragging them on the home screen.</p><p>Widget showcasing on the Home Screen is likely seeing improvements as well. Besides, there are several animation upgrades with the latest build on the OnePlus 12, which comprise:</p>
<ul><li>Adds Gaussian blur effects when opening and closing app icons on the Home screen.</li><li>Adds a transition animation when opening and closing Home screen widgets.</li><li>Adds a transition animation for clock widgets when the screen is turned off.</li></ul>
<p>The other system-wide improvements on the OnePlus 12 involve Lock Screen Pin/Pattern tracking, which means users can choose to turn off animation tracking while entering their Pin or Pattern while unlocking the device. </p><p>The Fluid Cloud feature, which is popular with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/oneplus-oxygenos-14-android-14-hands-on">OxygenOS 14</a>, will now showcase music controls. There was a bug that would display a volume slider in Quick Settings and another one while hitting the physical volume rockers simultaneously. This is supposedly addressed with the latest firmware on the OnePlus 12. </p><p>The new release incorporates the June Android security patch and improves gaming stability. A fix seems to address the screen turning black in some instances while gaming on the OnePlus 12. These and the volume slider fixes are the common issues shared and addressed with the firmware update released to the company&apos;s first <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">foldable phone</a>, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-open">OnePlus Open</a>.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="htHM4nHEfUMhY7sUAwqhsD" name="oneplus-open-12.jpg" alt="OnePlus Open review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/htHM4nHEfUMhY7sUAwqhsD.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>OnePlus <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://community.oneplus.com/thread/1633009335099457539">notes in the post</a> that security improvements are included on the OnePlus Open with the latest OxygenOS build. These include minimal-level permission grants for the Calendar app to provide maximum information security. The latest firmware release also improves clipboard privacy. It will automatically detect privacy information on the clipboard and prevent unauthorized app access without users&apos; consent to "minimize the risk of privacy leaks."</p><p>Other system-wide changes include music controls displayed in Live Alerts on the foldable phone. The firmware release addresses an issue where system data is taking up more storage space. Issues causing unexpected screen rotation "when switching a video app from the cover screen to the main screen" are also being fixed.</p><p>The OnePlus 12&apos;s builds are rolling out in batches for the aforementioned regions, and the OnePlus Open firmware release is currently confined to the Indian region.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/oneplus-12-and-oneplus-open-gain-june-2024-security-patch</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ It is that time of the month when we expect security patches to roll out to Android devices, and some of the OnePlus devices are getting them this week. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">ZRa8Ky7AmsXQcpukBkspTB</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/eTYvoXTAaPFaaDtW2nksDG.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 15:42:06 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/eTYvoXTAaPFaaDtW2nksDG.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus 12 home page against colorful background]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus 12 home page against colorful background]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ If I buy only one thing this Prime Day, it will be this ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Gadget Weekly</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="DZLQ4jKZk9tEF5A3sqU5Jh" name="inspector-lloyd-square.jpg" caption="" alt="Inspector Lloyd" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DZLQ4jKZk9tEF5A3sqU5Jh.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">Join Namerah Saud Fatmi as she explores the cool, quirky, and sometimes downright odd world of smartphone accessories, gadgets, and other nerdy toys <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/gadget-weekly">every week</a>.</p></div></div>
<p>It is almost that time of the year again folks. Amazon&apos;s annual shopping bonanza is just around the corner and I&apos;m hoping against hope that one thing in particular goes on sale for a spectacular price.</p><p>I&apos;m sure you&apos;ve got a wishlist of all the coolest things you&apos;d like to score this Prime Day because I know I&apos;ve got one too. My list in general could go on and on, but at the top of the stuff that I really ache to possess is the brilliant <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/xgimi-halo-plus-portable-projector-review">XGIMI Halo+</a> smart projector. It&apos;s big expensive buys like this that I save for deal seasons. Heck, if I only buy one thing this Prime Day, it would be this <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-tvs">Android TV</a> projector.</p><p>Big sales like this are what help hard-working people like you and me to get the most bang for our hard-earned buck. Whether you&apos;ve just moved into a new house or are looking to upgrade your current premises, events like Prime Day do wonders for our tight wallets and big dreams.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:869px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="UgdyXT2Fm4yraHvWwZtoVh" name="xgimi-halo-plus-review-lifestyle-1.jpg" alt="XGIMI Halo+" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/UgdyXT2Fm4yraHvWwZtoVh.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="869" height="489" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Why this projector in particular? There are several reasons for that. See, I already own a respectable smart TV from Hisense with a Chromecast with Google TV dongle in my living room. The TV itself used to perform quite poorly, which is why I got the Google dongle to beef it up. The results made me very, very happy, and now I&apos;d like to bring a similar Android TV experience to my bedroom. Only, there&apos;s one major problem.</p><p>Unfortunately, my tiny two-bedroom apartment has very small bedrooms, so there isn&apos;t really much space for another TV. My colleague Harish Jonnalagadda has been banging on about XGIMI and the brand&apos;s fantastic smart projectors for a while here at Android Central, so it&apos;s about darn time I listened to his sound advice. Harish has tested many XGIMI projectors and mentioned again and again that they serve wonderfully as Android TV replacements.</p><p>XGIMI&apos;s projectors are portable and have great automatic keystone correction, so I can place them at weird angles in my bedroom to accommodate the lack of space. I want the Halo+ model specifically because it comes with a built-in battery, so I don&apos;t even have to worry about a wall socket being nearby.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="P6WS8Qm6Miarr7NTgtVTfh" name="xgimi-halo-plus-review-lifestyle-3.jpg" alt="XGIMI Halo+" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/P6WS8Qm6Miarr7NTgtVTfh.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:992px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="GgFbvv74MrCiimzxwj4kzh" name="xgimi-halo-plus-review-lifestyle-4.jpg" alt="XGIMI Halo+" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GgFbvv74MrCiimzxwj4kzh.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="992" height="558" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Just like a smart Android TV, the XGIMI Halo+ comes with an HDMI port with eARC support, a 3.5mm audio jack, and a USB-A port. You get a Bluetooth remote control with a mic along with the XGIMI Halo+ and two 5W Harman Kardon speakers with Dolby Audio. The projector runs Android TV 10 out of the box and you can connect your Google Assitant to it for a hands-free experience.</p><p>As for the picture quality, the Halo+ outputs bright images that get as bright as 700 ISO Lumens. In his review, Harish said that the Halo+ delivers better picture quality than just about any other portable projector. It has HDR10 and a Full HD screen resolution of 1920x1080 pixels. You get a dedicated game mode with a 26.5ms latency.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:902px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.21%;"><img id="EH7eQJix7ydWFiCN2fyArh" name="xgimi-halo-plus-review-lifestyle-2.jpg" alt="XGIMI Halo+" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/EH7eQJix7ydWFiCN2fyArh.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="902" height="507" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The XGIMI Halo+ usually retails at $700. It isn&apos;t the cheapest projector offered by the brand, but the more affordable <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/xgimi-mogo-2-pro-review">MoGo 2 Pro</a> and MoGo 2 models have lower display and brightness specs. Not to mention, the cheaper models lack built-in batteries. All of these factors come into play for me, because I want something portable but also reasonably powerful and affordable.</p><p>Since my budget is about $500 to $600, there&apos;s a high possibility that a decent Prime Day deal can strike down the XGIMI Halo+ into an affordable price bracket for me. How I wish I could consider buying the more premium offerings from XGIMI&apos;s roundup, like the Horizon or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/xgimi-horizon-ultra-4k-projector-review">Horizon Ultra 4K</a> projectors, but there&apos;s no foreseeable discount that could drive down their thousand-dollar-and-over price tags to something I can afford.</p><p>The bottom line is that a smart projector is a clever solution if you&apos;re in a predicament like me. Tight spaces don&apos;t mean you have to forgo a TV. Just get an Android TV projector! If you get one on sale, it might even cost less than the price of a traditional TV.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/if-i-buy-only-one-thing-this-prime-day-it-will-be-this</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Prime Day is nearly upon us. There's only one deal that I'm holding out for and it's from a brand called XGIMI. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">huDtqN55c9xxAZp6KUTnQo</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/B6P9rG3nDi4uVRz6ghFm9B.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 14:48:56 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Smart Home]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/B6P9rG3nDi4uVRz6ghFm9B.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[XGIMI Halo+]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[XGIMI Halo+]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>