<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 18:12:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google calls out the DOJ for its 'extreme' plan to break up its search business ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google is pushing back against the DOJ, calling its plan to break up Google Search an "extreme" move.</li><li>The DOJ’s 23-page proposal came after a court ruled that Alphabet broke antitrust laws by paying Samsung and Apple to keep Google as the default search engine.</li><li>The DOJ wants Google to divest Chrome, arguing it would give other search engines a shot at competing.</li><li>Google’s Kent Walker warns the plan could hurt user privacy, security, and product quality.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google has hit back at the U.S. Department of Justice, accusing it of pushing a "radical interventionist agenda" to break its search business.</p><p>According to a report from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://apnews.com/article/google-search-monopoly-penalty-justice-department-84e07fec51c5c59751d846118cb900a7" target="_blank">Associated Press</a>, the DOJ has made it official—<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-could-be-forced-to-sell-off-chrome-to-level-the-search-playing-field">it’s coming for Google’s search monopoly</a>. After Judge Amit Mehta <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/justice-department-vs-google-ruling-search-dominance">ruled against the tech giant</a>, the DOJ issued a 23-page proposal detailing its plan to force Google to part ways with Chrome and tighten the reins on Android.</p><p>Back in August, a U.S. court called out Alphabet for throwing billions at Samsung and Apple to keep Google as the default search engine. Judge Mehta ruled the tactic straight-up broke antitrust laws.</p><p>The DOJ argues that cutting Chrome loose would strip Google of a key internet gateway, giving rival search engines a fair shot to compete.</p><p>Alphabet isn’t backing down from what it calls the DOJ’s “extreme" proposal. Kent Walker, Google’s global affairs chief, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/public-policy/doj-search-remedies-nov-2024/" target="_blank">argued</a> that splitting off Chrome and Android could hurt user security, privacy, and the overall quality of their products.</p><p>Walker raised concerns that the DOJ’s plan might force Google to share sensitive info—like proprietary tech and even personal search queries from millions of Americans—with unknown entities at home and abroad.</p><p>He also slammed the DOJ’s proposal for adding extra steps for Pixel users, requiring two separate choice screens just to get to Google Search.</p><p>Walker also warned that the DOJ’s plan could leak trade secrets to foreign companies, slow down AI progress, and have major negative effects on the global tech landscape.</p><p>The DOJ’s proposal goes way beyond what the court decided, targeting not just Google Search but a whole range of beloved Google products used around the globe, Walker wrote.</p><p>The DOJ has been taking aim at Alphabet’s habit of pre-installing Google products on Android, suggesting both "behavioral and structural fixes" to stop Google from using its power in Chrome, the Play Store, and Android to unfairly push Google Search.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-calls-out-the-doj-for-its-extreme-plan-to-break-up-its-search-business</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google slams the DOJ's over-the-top proposal. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">c3U3GVayDPFZdTTDVYPLii</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/64gYZMQggHRYve2CH4xdxk.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 14:44:41 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/64gYZMQggHRYve2CH4xdxk.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A statue of the multicolored &quot;G&quot; in Google on the Google campus in Mountain View]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A statue of the multicolored &quot;G&quot; in Google on the Google campus in Mountain View]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ I ditched my Apple and Galaxy watches for a Garmin, and you should too ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>I’ve been a believer in wearable technology since the beginning. Before smartwatches really became mainstream, I used <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-fitbit">Fitbit trackers</a> to track activity, check the time, and see notifications. When the first Apple Watch was announced, I was one of the first to buy one in 2015. That says a lot because the first Apple Watch Sport was terrible. Since then, I’ve owned a ton of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch">top smartwatches</a>, including Apple Watch, Pixel Watch, Galaxy Watch, and Garmin models.</p><p>But recently, I reviewed the most expensive smartwatch ever strapped to my wrist. It’s the Garmin Enduro 3, a long-lasting wearable with a $900 retail price. As I test products throughout the fall release cycle, I’m usually thrilled when I’m finished and can return to my preferred everyday carry. For smartwatches, that typically means adorning my Apple Watch Ultra or Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 Classic.</p>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/early-black-friday-garmin-deals-2024-ditch-your-old-smartwatch-and-save-big-on-forerunner-venu-and-more" target="_blank"><em><strong>Check out the best early Garmin deals of Black Friday 2024</strong></em></a></li></ul>
<p>This time was different. I couldn’t stop wearing the Garmin Enduro 3, and truthfully, I haven’t even thought about switching back to the Apple Watch Ultra or Galaxy Watch 6 Classic. In fact, I don’t even know where my Apple Watch Ultra is at the moment — despite wearing it religiously for two years before giving the Garmin watch a try.</p><p>We're approaching <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/black-friday-2024" target="_blank">Black Friday and Cyber Monday discounts</a>, where smartwatches — including those from Garmin — are sure to go on sale. That's why if you're itching to make a change, next week is probably the best time to do so. Here's why I've left those smartwatches behind, and why you may want to as well.</p>

<h2 id="no-more-compromises-2">No more compromises</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="aKsQ2PKB9YkEFnsyv2WML3" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Watch-6-Classic-and-Apple-Watch-Ultra-2.jpeg" alt="The Apple Watch Ultra 2 (left) and Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 Classic (right) side-by-side" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/aKsQ2PKB9YkEFnsyv2WML3.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It’s true that the Garmin Enduro 3 costs more than the Apple Watch Ultra or the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-6-review">Galaxy Watch 6 Classic</a> (and their newer models, for that matter). However, it’s also true that the Enduro 3 is better in a few key ways, starting with battery life. Garmin advertises the Enduro 3 as potentially offering “unlimited” battery life thanks to its solar charging capabilities, but in smartwatch mode, you can get up to three months of battery on a single charge. A more realistic figure is probably a month of battery life, which I’ve replicated in real-world usage.</p><p>Compare that to the latest <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/apple-watch-ultra-2-review">Apple Watch Ultra 2</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-ultra-review">Galaxy Watch Ultra</a>, and the difference is staggering. I’m lucky to get a day or two of battery life on my Ultra with normal usage, sleep tracking, and activity tracking. The Garmin Enduro 3 helps me forget about charging, and it completely changed the way I use a smartwatch. When the battery gets low, I still have a few days of power left. All I have to do is remember to charge it for a few hours across those couple of days, and I’m set for another month.</p><p>In practice, that results in tangible benefits. I went on an international trip last month, and I didn’t bring a Garmin charger with me. The Enduro 3 was halfway charged when I left and still had a week of battery when I returned. On vacation, where remembering to bring all the right chargers can be a hassle, the Garmin was like a breath of fresh air.</p><p>Of course, this is nothing new for Garmin watches. The Enduro 3 is the longest-lasting smartwatch in the company’s lineup, but all <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-garmin-smartwatch">great Garmin watches</a> have solid battery life. The eye-opening part of using the Garmin Enduro 3 was discovering that you don’t really have to give up features to get this level of outstanding battery life. I’ve used older Vivoactive models, and more recently, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-instinct-2x-solar-review">Garmin Instinct 2 Solar</a>. Those watches had great battery life, too, but lacked in terms of feature set.</p>
<p>The Garmin Enduro 3 doesn’t compromise in the same ways. It has plenty of useful, tactile buttons — plus a responsive touchscreen. There are a handful of GPS bands supported, and a long list of sensors that includes a barometric altimeter, compass, gyroscope, accelerometer, ambient light sensor. In terms of health sensors, you get a heart rate monitor, Pulse Ox monitor, thermometer, and ECG.</p><p>Add it all together with Garmin’s insightful software, and the Enduro 3 was a much more useful fitness and health tool than either Apple or Samsung’s smartwatches. With the Apple Watch, it feels like Apple wants me to <em>feel good</em> about my fitness and health. You aim to close Activity Rings in a way that’s reminiscent of checking off a daily to-do list rather than actually being focused on fitness progress. While watchOS 11 is indeed better at acknowledging rest days, the emphasis on rest and recovery still isn’t comparable to Garmin’s.</p><p>Again, this results in tangible lifestyle benefits. The Garmin Enduro 3 recorded absolutely atrocious sleep and body battery scores in the days preceding myself coming down with a severe sinus infection. It knew I was sick before I did and recommended I pause training. Similarly, when I feel sore and tired after a grueling workout the previous day, Garmin’s training readiness store affirms what my body is telling me — giving me the confidence to take a rest day without feeling guilty.</p><p>Meanwhile, my Apple Watch is sitting in a drawer somewhere, buzzing each hour to remind me to get up and walk it off.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4480px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="horQmYjnYX4GWDWvRZz2zh" name="Garmin-Enduro-3-Hiking-Workout" alt="A hiking workout tracked on the Garmin Enduro 3." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/horQmYjnYX4GWDWvRZz2zh.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4480" height="2520" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Brady Snyder / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4480px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="9wg6YpsmujBV7cVXgAseE4" name="Garmin-Enduro-3-Sleep-Score" alt="The sleep score on a Garmin Enduro 3 watch." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9wg6YpsmujBV7cVXgAseE4.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4480" height="2520" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Brady Snyder / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Part of the reason I’ve loved using the Garmin Enduro 3 is not because the Apple Watch or Galaxy Watch have changed for the worse; it’s that I’ve changed as a user. I’m not interested in using my smartwatch like a phone strapped to my wrist anymore. I want a watch that reliably tells the time, has long-lasting battery life, and has excellent fitness tracking capabilities and insights. Garmin watches are fantastic for that. Purely as a smartwatch, I’d recommend you pick the Apple Watch or Galaxy Watch.</p><p>But for me, I’ve discovered there’s value in wearing a smartwatch that’s a bit less <em>smart</em>.</p>
<h2 id="wait-you-re-saying-i-should-pay-900-for-a-smartwatch-2">Wait, you’re saying I should pay $900 for a smartwatch?</h2>
<p>I know what you’re probably thinking. Sure, the Enduro 3 is cool, but it’s way too expensive to possibly be worth it. It is expensive — I wouldn’t blame you if you’re not willing to pay $900 for a smartwatch — however, it’s also worth it.</p><p>The value proposition starts to make sense when you look at what came before and after the Garmin Enduro 3. This watch’s predecessor was the Enduro 2, which cost $1,100. Garmin added a ton of software features and hardware improvements to the Enduro 3, making the company's longest-lasting watch ever while simultaneously slashing $200 off the sticker price.</p><p>Additionally, the Enduro 3 is quietly a better value than the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-fenix-8-review">Garmin Fenix 8</a>. In our review, we found that the Fenix 8 was simply overpriced. The crazy thing is that the Enduro 3 can do much that the Fenix 8 can do while being lighter, cheaper, and featuring longer battery life and an advanced solar screen with more surface area for charging. Unless you need diving features or a speaker and microphone, the Enduro 3 is a better value — and maybe a better watch, depending on your use case — than the Fenix 8.</p><p>Consider these two watches for comparison, and the $900 Enduro 3 suddenly looks like an awesome deal. Combine that with the fact that the Garmin Enduro 3 very well may go on sale during Black Friday sales, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/black-friday">which are already starting</a>, and it looks like a great time to upgrade to a Garmin watch.</p><p>For budget buyers, there’s good news. Many of the things I’ve mentioned in this review apply to a ton of other Garmin watches, which are available at a fraction of the price of the Enduro 3. The Instinct 2 Solar is a great option for those who can forgo a touchscreen and most smartwatch features in favor of long battery life and excellent activity tracking. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/garmin-vivoactive-4-review">Vivoactive</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-forerunner-165-review">Forerunner</a> lineups are less versatile than the Enduro 3, but they still feature great watches with week-plus battery life at low prices.</p><p>I’m betting that at least a few Garmin watches will go on sale on Black Friday. We already saw killer deals on the brand’s offerings while covering Prime Day, and Black Friday and Cyber Monday might offer even bigger price cuts. If you’re like me and are ready to ditch your Apple or Galaxy watch for a Garmin, you should keep an eye out for Black Friday deals on Garmin smartwatches. We might even luck out and see new models like the Enduro 3 and Fenix 8 get a much-needed price drop.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Smartwatch deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/searchpage.jsp?st=smartwatch&_dyncharset=UTF-8&_dynSessConf=&id=pcat17071&type=page&sc=Global&cp=1&nrp=&sp=&qp=&list=n&af=true&iht=y&usc=All+Categories&ks=960&keys=keys"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/search?q=smartwatch"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=smartwatch&crid=19YAPQ38561AK&sprefix=smartwatch%2Caps%2C138&ref=nb_sb_ss_ts-doa-p_1_10"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/watches-audio-accessories-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.dell.com/en-us/search/smartwatch"><u><strong>Dell</strong></u></a></li><li><strong>Fitness tracker deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/searchpage.jsp?st=fitness+tracker&_dyncharset=UTF-8&_dynSessConf=&id=pcat17071&type=page&sc=Global&cp=1&nrp=&sp=&qp=&list=n&af=true&iht=y&usc=All+Categories&ks=960&keys=keys"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/search?q=fitness+tracker"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=fitness+tracker&crid=1QI27KW7ITF2W&sprefix=fitness+tracker%2Caps%2C160&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.dell.com/en-us/search/fitness%20tracker"><u><strong>Dell</strong></u></a></li></ul>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="cc9628cc-2593-4664-ab1d-92d8836ce220">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/86NvA3JryhDKJEYfBRWTeQ.jpg' alt="Render of the Garmin Enduro 3"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Garmin Enduro 3</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>My new favorite smartwatch</strong></em></p><p>Don't let the price fool you — the Garmin Enduro 3 is an excellent value, with tons of features and battery life packed into a relatively light form factor. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/i-ditched-my-apple-and-galaxy-watches-for-a-garmin-and-you-should-too</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ After switching to one of Garmin’s best smartwatches, I can’t go back to my Apple Watch Ultra or Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 Classic. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">aPpbfC8VEgchNURiQLB7BK</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kEM78AfQ7LiSm935yBkUfC.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kEM78AfQ7LiSm935yBkUfC.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Brady Snyder / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The screen of the Garmin Enduro 3.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The screen of the Garmin Enduro 3.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ OPPO Find X8 Pro review: Samsung should be terrified ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>I thoroughly enjoyed <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oppo-find-x7-ultra-review">using the Find X7 Ultra</a> earlier this year, and the only reason I still don&apos;t use the phone as my daily driver is that the Chinese-flavored ColorOS software is a little too limiting. Ignoring that, the device is terrific; it has arguably the best design of the year, one of the best camera and hardware packages, and industry-leading charging tech.</p><p>So it was annoying to see that OPPO limited the Find X7 Ultra to China, with the brand curtailing a global launch. Thankfully, it&apos;s making amends with the Find X8 and X8 Pro; both models are now available globally, and are on sale in key markets like the U.K. and India.</p><p>That in itself is a big deal, and the fact that these devices are on sale globally makes them much more accessible. There&apos;s plenty to like on the hardware side of things as well; the Find X8 is essentially the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-13">OnePlus 13</a> in all but name, and the X8 Pro contains one of the most versatile camera systems — it has dual telephoto modules.</p><p>Clearly, both phones have a lot to offer, and in this review, I&apos;m focusing my attention on the Find X8 Pro. I used the phone for just over a week now, and while the main camera isn&apos;t quite as good as the Find X7 Ultra, the rest of the device holds up just as well, and that&apos;s great news for OPPO&apos;s global ambitions.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-oppo-find-x8-pro-pricing-and-availability"><span>OPPO Find X8 Pro: Pricing and availability</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="SazHhGurn2ZgmMvRw9vRgU" name="oppo-find-x8-pro-3.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SazHhGurn2ZgmMvRw9vRgU.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>OPPO unveiled the Find X8 and X8 Pro in China on October 24, and both devices made their international debut at a launch event in Bali, Indonesia on November 21. The Find X8 is available in 12GB/256GB and 16GB/512GB variants, and the X8 Pro is sold in a single 16GB/512GB model globally. You can pick up the Find X8 in Star Grey, Space Black, and Shell Pink colors, with the X8 Pro available in Space Black and Pearl White options.</p><p>The Find X8 costs ₹69,999 ($830) in India and 13,999,000 IDR ($878) for the 12GB/256GB model and ₹79,999 ($947) in India and 15,999,000 IDR ($1,003) in Indonesia for the 16GB/512GB edition. The Find X8 Pro, meanwhile, retails at ₹99,999 ($1,185) in India and 19,999,000 IDR ($1,255) for the 16GB/512GB edition, and as always, OPPO is being aggressive in India as it&apos;s still trying to pick up market share in this segment.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-oppo-find-x8-pro-design"><span>OPPO Find X8 Pro: Design</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="CdKEcP3JPjnBwXz5mDS6Va" name="oppo-find-x8-pro-25.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CdKEcP3JPjnBwXz5mDS6Va.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oppo-find-x6-pro-review">Find X6 Pro</a> and X7 Ultra maintained a similar design aesthetic with leather-backed variants, and it made the phones look distinctive. OPPO is switching things up with the Find X8 Pro, and the phone has flatter sides and a glass back with a silky finish. You still get a massive camera island, but the overall design doesn&apos;t stand out anywhere as much.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="Gg9xd2oL2Fp8ry7H86iDpY" name="oppo-find-x8-pro-21.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Gg9xd2oL2Fp8ry7H86iDpY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Having used the Find X7 Ultra extensively, I&apos;m not a fan of the design of the X8 Pro; I think OPPO should have continued its existing design language. That said, the Find X8 Pro is 0.7mm thinner and 6g lighter than the X7 Ultra while featuring a massive 5910mAh battery (910mAh bigger than the unit on the X7 Ultra), so while the design may not be as exciting, it is easier to hold and use the device.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="pFTqLYzHZuCsYZaFSVsUkb" name="oppo-find-x8-pro-24.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pFTqLYzHZuCsYZaFSVsUkb.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While it has flat sides, the beveled edges and subtle curves at the back ensure the Find X8 Pro is comfortable to hold, and I didn&apos;t have any issues in this area. The sides have a coated texture that mimics soft-touch plastic, but the mid-frame itself is made out of metal, and it is resilient against tumbles. The device slid right off a table twice in the week I used it, and thankfully, it came away unscathed both times.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="vCzQRRGaipgrz8kZsUiPKV" name="oppo-find-x8-pro-5.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vCzQRRGaipgrz8kZsUiPKV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The camera island dominates the back of the phone, and like the last two years, there&apos;s a textured ring that sits underneath the housing, differentiating the design. The quartet of cameras is arranged symmetrically within the housing, with a stylized Hasselblad logo located in the middle. The camera housing doesn&apos;t protrude too much from the chassis, and there&apos;s no noticeable wobble when using the phone on a table.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="tNaqUmMtDGWLFWUqitJf7W" name="oppo-find-x8-pro-8.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tNaqUmMtDGWLFWUqitJf7W.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Although you get a massive battery and sizeable cameras at the back, the Find X8 Pro doesn&apos;t feel heavy or unwieldy in the least; weight distribution is ideal, and you get a great in-hand feel. The only usability issue I have with the phone is that the in-screen optical reader sits too low on the screen, making it awkward to unlock the device one-handed. This isn&apos;t a new issue on OPPO devices either, and if anything, the fingerprint sensor is even lower this time around.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="BuXFffgwvTWetKhy76FPcV" name="oppo-find-x8-pro-7.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BuXFffgwvTWetKhy76FPcV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>You only get two color choices of the Find X8 Pro globally — Space Black and Pearl White — and I&apos;d recommend going with the latter. The black model just doesn&apos;t have the same level of excitement, and even if you put the phone in a case, you&apos;ll want a design that stands out in this category.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="ACxAvePyE3ErvRiJGKfr5X" name="oppo-find-x8-pro-10.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ACxAvePyE3ErvRiJGKfr5X.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Mainstays like the alert slider are intact, and you can easily toggle between ring, vibrant, and silent modes. This is a necessary feature on the Find X8 Pro, as the usual DND mode within the software is needlessly convoluted, but more on that later. You still get an IR blaster as well, and the SIM card tray sits at the bottom, and can take in two SIM cards. Yes, eSIM is available globally in addition to the traditional SIM card slots.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="ZAheaD8icEXdYF2j52kaKW" name="oppo-find-x8-pro-9.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZAheaD8icEXdYF2j52kaKW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>What&apos;s new this time is the introduction of a dedicated button to launch the camera and take photos. Similar to Camera Control on the iPhone 16 Pro Max, the button on the Find X8 Pro lets you launch the camera with a double press, and you can use it as a shutter button. It sits flush with the chassis and isn&apos;t noticeable, and you can use swipe actions to adjust the zoom level. It isn&apos;t a button technically as it uses the vibration motor, but you get decent feedback.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="9HdvGbVGHmb8DZevDRQzVW" name="oppo-find-x8-pro-11.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9HdvGbVGHmb8DZevDRQzVW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I found the positioning of this button to be more convenient than Camera Control on the iPhone, and you can adjust the pressure sensitivity so it doesn&apos;t trigger accidentally. If you don&apos;t like the button, you can disable it entirely. Rounding out the design, the Find X8 Pro gets <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-is-an-ip69-rating-and-why-should-you-care">IP69 ingress protection</a>, which is the highest tier available. In addition to submersion in up to 1.5 meters of water, the device is resilient against water jets, making it immune to any weather condition.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-oppo-find-x8-pro-display"><span>OPPO Find X8 Pro: Display</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="bYxGZwm4q8HvUXDa4epyRX" name="oppo-find-x8-pro-12.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bYxGZwm4q8HvUXDa4epyRX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Just like its predecessor, the Find X8 Pro uses a 120Hz AMOLED panel made by BOE, albeit one that&apos;s slightly smaller at 6.78 inches. It has the same brightness figures, going up to 1600 nits in HBM mode and 4500 nits in HDR content, and you get Dolby Vision and HDR10+ integration.</p><p>Colors and contrast levels are excellent, and similar to previous years, you get decent customizability in tweaking the color balance to your preferences. There&apos;s an eye comfort mode that does a decent enough job switching the panel to warmer hues, and you can tailor colors based on ambient light.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="n4t2TGLES8jVSbU9HsJiYZ" name="oppo-find-x8-pro-15.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/n4t2TGLES8jVSbU9HsJiYZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>What&apos;s interesting is that the bezels are uniform, and at just 1.9mm, they&apos;re thinner than previous years. The ultra-thin bezels make using the device that much more immersive when streaming content, and on that note, I didn&apos;t see any issues with HDR content in general.</p><p>Gaming is similarly enjoyable, and but the biggest issue is that games are still restricted to 60fps. This has been a constant annoyance in the past, and while I was holding out for OPPO to change its strategy with ColorOS 15, that hasn&apos;t materialized. Notably, the X8 Pro has 2160Hz PWM dimming, while the regular model gets 3840Hz dimming, so if you&apos;re sensitive to PWM flicker, the standard Find X8 is the way to go.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="TB9TBAfdgCaLP8L7FWWEsW" name="oppo-find-x8-pro-16.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TB9TBAfdgCaLP8L7FWWEsW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Another drawback is that the device doesn&apos;t quite as bright as its rivals. Yes, the touted figures are among the highest, but in actual use, the Find X8 Pro doesn&apos;t get close to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/pixel-9-pro-xl-two-months-later">Pixel 9 Pro XL</a> or the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-6-pro-review">Honor Magic 6 Pro</a>. I didn&apos;t have any issues using the screen under harsh sunlight, but the panel just doesn&apos;t deliver in this area.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-oppo-find-x8-pro-performance"><span>OPPO Find X8 Pro: Performance</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="KuarjS8zd3FMfaSUUCXsTY" name="oppo-find-x8-pro-18.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KuarjS8zd3FMfaSUUCXsTY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In an interesting move, OPPO decided to go with MediaTek&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/mediateks-dimensity-9400-is-the-biggest-challenger-to-qualcomm-yet">Dimensity 9400</a> on the Find X8 and X8 Pro in lieu of the usual Qualcomm hardware, and that&apos;s a big deal. There&apos;s definitely a lot to like with the Dimensity 9400, which once again sees MediaTek use an all big-core design, this time made up of the new Cortex X925, Cortex X4, and A720.</p><p>The Immortalis-G925 GPU is an exciting upgrade as well, and the Find X8 Pro is one of the fastest phones you can buy today. I didn&apos;t see any problems in daily use in the week I used the phone — there wasn&apos;t any errant lag or slowdown, and the phone did a fantastic job in demanding titles, delivering stable framerates.</p>

<p>That said, the device has aggressive thermal management, and throttles early to avoid overheating. In 3DMark&apos;s demanding Steel Nomad Light stress test, it had a stability score of just 52%, which is on the lower side of things. Also, the Immortalis-G925 does a standout job with rasterization, but it doesn&apos;t quite measure up to the Adreno 830 in ray tracing workloads. </p><p>The upside is that I didn&apos;t see the phone cross 42 degrees Celsius, so there were no issues with usability even during extended gaming sessions. Outside of two instances where there was some jitter after 30 minutes of gaming, the phone held up pretty well in this regard.</p><p>Like previous years, the biggest limitation is that you can&apos;t play games at 120fps, with ColorOS enforcing a strict 60fps restriction. It is annoying when the Dimensity 9400 is clearly able to handle demanding titles with ease, but it looks like the brand is once again being conservative in this regard.</p>
<p>Switching to the device from the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/asus-rog-phone-9-pro-review">ROG Phone 9 Pro</a>, what&apos;s evident is just how much ground MediaTek covered in the last year. While I still give the edge to Qualcomm, the Dimensity 9400 is just as good in daily use, and that&apos;s a sizeable achievement. It&apos;s no wonder, then, that both OPPO and Vivo chose to go with MediaTek this time around.</p><p>There are no issues in other areas. I got rock-solid 5G connectivity in Hyderabad, India, and a stable connection in my home network. Calls went through without any issues as well, but weirdly enough, the earpiece isn&apos;t as loud, so I had to turn up the volume.</p><p>The phone has the usual LDAC and LHDC codecs, but you also get Qualcomm&apos;s AptX and AptX HD, allowing you to use a wider range of earbuds and unlock better-quality streaming. The rest of the connectivity is in line with other high-end phones; you get Bluetooth 5.4, NFC, USB-C based on the USB 3.2 standard, and dual-band GPS.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-oppo-find-x8-pro-battery-life"><span>OPPO Find X8 Pro: Battery life</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="fjvn83bWoiLp6Vu5kf4TAZ" name="oppo-find-x8-pro-20.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fjvn83bWoiLp6Vu5kf4TAZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I got a day&apos;s worth of use out of the 5000mAh battery in the Find X7 Ultra, and the Find X8 Pro takes things to a whole new level. The phone has a huge 5910mAh battery, and it uses a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/most-android-flagships-are-getting-an-exciting-battery-upgrade-in-2025">new silicon-carbon tech</a> to deliver better density — that&apos;s the main reason why the phone is thinner while still delivering a bigger battery.</p><p>I&apos;m yet to use some of the other phones that use the same battery tech, but what&apos;s already evident is that 2025 phones deliver heady gains in this area. I got nearly two days of use between charges, and that&apos;s more than any other device I used yet. Even with heavy use, I got a day and a half before needing to plug in the device, and that&apos;s an achievement in and of itself.</p><p>While OPPO has 100W charging, the Find X8 Pro uses 80W as standard, and what&apos;s interesting is that it goes up to 50W over the USB PD standard, so you don&apos;t need to use the bundled power brick — you can use any USB PD charger and get up to 50W. This is a huge deal in my own usage, and while I like the efficiency of the 80W standard, the bundled charger is bulky, and the ability to use any GaN charger to get 50W makes things that much more convenient — you could only get 10W over PD in the past.</p>
<p>Anyway, charging the phone with the bundled 80W charger takes just over 50 minutes. It&apos;s considerably longer than the Find X7 Ultra and other devices I tested in the past, and that&apos;s because the phone now has a single cell instead of the dual batteries that have been standard in the last three years. While it&apos;s not quite as fast at getting to 100% as the OnePlus 12, it is still much better than other mainstream phones.</p><p>In addition to regular charging, you get 50W wireless charging, and there&apos;s a magnetic charging accessory that looks pretty cool. I didn&apos;t get a chance to test it yet, but it is considerably smaller than usual charging mats, and it&apos;s an unknown if it will be sold in all global markets.</p><p>You get the usual safeguards to ensure the battery lasts several years without any degradation. You can set a charge limit to 80% and use optimized charging, and the brand notes that the switch to a silicon anode should deliver greater longevity in general.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-oppo-find-x8-pro-cameras"><span>OPPO Find X8 Pro: Cameras</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="KXqm8dDxA6Xvs2tcpMvAuV" name="oppo-find-x8-pro-6.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KXqm8dDxA6Xvs2tcpMvAuV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The biggest reason to pick up the Find X8 Pro is the cameras, and there&apos;s a lot to like in this area. The phone has a quartet of 50MP cameras at the back; there&apos;s a main 50MP 1/1.4-inch Sony Lytia LYT-808 module with OIS, 50MP ISOCELL JN5 wide-angle lens, 50MP 1/1.95-inch Sony LYT-600 with 3x optical zoom, and a secondary 50MP telephoto that uses the IMX858 and goes up to 6x optical zoom.</p><p>You get OIS modules on all the cameras other than the wide-angle lens, and the inclusion of two telephoto periscope lenses gives the Find X8 Pro a distinct advantage. There&apos;s a new imaging engine, and AI-assisted zoom beyond 10x that delivers usable shots.</p><p>Another notable change is the ability to take photos of fast-moving objects; this is something both the Pixel 9 Pro XL and Magic 6 Pro excel at, and the Find X8 Pro shoots up to six images a second, and it does a better job than its predecessor in this regard. In a similar vein, all four sensors at the back deliver the same color balance, and that&apos;s because all images go through the same processing stack.</p><p>To build on that, you can take up to 200 shots in burst mode, and all photos will have the same quality — that&apos;s another differentiator from last year. The phone uses on-device AI subject detection, and it does a decent job. Live Photo is great, and what&apos;s notable is that the video that&apos;s recorded uses the same quality as the image.</p><p>You get good upgrades on the video side of things as well, with the phone able to shoot 4K60 Dolby Vision footage from all four lenses at the back as well as the front shooter. There&apos;s the ability to shoot HDR video with the Ultra Steady stabilization enabled, and honestly, this is one of the best camera packages you get today.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 14</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="AyEwZ3QE5hGnaz2B9ei8Vd" name="findx8-pro-shots-8.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro images" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AyEwZ3QE5hGnaz2B9ei8Vd.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1536" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 14</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="VSTufGXpvQAcu3k5aNXqpd" name="findx8-pro-shots-9.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro images" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VSTufGXpvQAcu3k5aNXqpd.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1536" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 14</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="J7xDi8cn9mxyignbw3WChb" name="findx8-pro-shots-3.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro images" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/J7xDi8cn9mxyignbw3WChb.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1536" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 4 of 14</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="A5Hc5aZyVKdLBzQcAb5m5c" name="findx8-pro-shots-4.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro images" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/A5Hc5aZyVKdLBzQcAb5m5c.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1536" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 5 of 14</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="hGUaWd5aHfmTWF8S5nRYRc" name="findx8-pro-shots-5.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro images" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hGUaWd5aHfmTWF8S5nRYRc.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1536" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 6 of 14</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="vBcNRbWjhrYGM28x6tPFkc" name="findx8-pro-shots-6.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro images" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vBcNRbWjhrYGM28x6tPFkc.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1536" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 7 of 14</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="fwekHbE2yA5sxN48wDKx5d" name="findx8-pro-shots-7.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro images" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fwekHbE2yA5sxN48wDKx5d.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1536" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 8 of 14</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:133.35%;"><img id="oNRYkFJ9G2HpQScXiD5Sga" name="findx8-pro-shots-1.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro images" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oNRYkFJ9G2HpQScXiD5Sga.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="2731" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 9 of 14</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:133.35%;"><img id="xuHErT2yUuGVfcdENeVrKb" name="findx8-pro-shots-2.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro images" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xuHErT2yUuGVfcdENeVrKb.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="2731" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 10 of 14</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="ZzogLCEvc8SwdH9uNzKVCe" name="findx8-pro-shots-11.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro images" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZzogLCEvc8SwdH9uNzKVCe.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1536" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 11 of 14</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="grkzEwcZ3opGY2ic33b5he" name="findx8-pro-shots-10.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro images" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/grkzEwcZ3opGY2ic33b5he.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1536" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 12 of 14</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="HbdXfhdsa3dEMngZMYHNNf" name="findx8-pro-shots-12.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro images" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HbdXfhdsa3dEMngZMYHNNf.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1536" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 13 of 14</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="AnRYVT4zjbRQJCzrSiFk2f" name="findx8-pro-shots-13.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro images" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AnRYVT4zjbRQJCzrSiFk2f.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1536" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 14 of 14</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="XKndCkYpriX9FbiMLxCG5a" name="findx8-pro-shots-14.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro images" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XKndCkYpriX9FbiMLxCG5a.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1536" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>As you can imagine, the Find X8 Pro takes outstanding photos and videos in just about any situation. Daylight shots have excellent detail and dynamic range, and foliage is rendered accurately without much in the way of artifacts. The wide-angle lens also holds up just as well, producing shots of the same caliber.</p><p>The phone does a fantastic job in low-light situations as well, and I have no problems in this regard. You get good detail and color balance, and there&apos;s no visible noise. The biggest differentiator with the phone is its portrait shots; you can use the 3x and 6x lenses to shoot portraits with gorgeous bokeh, and while the latter may require you to stand back quite a long way, I found the 3x lens to be the ideal choice in this area.</p><p>The portrait shots have good segmentation and tonal balance, and similar to the Find X7 Ultra, I just used this mode most of the time. It does a decent job with inanimate objects as well, and that wasn&apos;t the case in previous years.</p><p>You also get a decent number of AI-assisted utilities, including AI Eraser, AI Clarity Enhance, and AI Unblur. These work as intended and I didn&apos;t have any issues, but the one I liked the most is AI Reflection Remover; the feature does a good job clearing reflections, and as someone who has taken hundreds of images taken at museums and galleries of objects behind glass cases, this was quite useful.</p><p>Overall, the Find X8 Pro is one of the best camera packages available today. The main camera doesn&apos;t quite come up to the standard set by the Find X7 Ultra, and that&apos;s understandable — there&apos;s clearly a Find X8 Ultra coming soon, and it makes sense that the 1-inch module is exclusive to that device. Other than that though, the Find X8 Pro does a fantastic job in all situations, and it easily outshines anything Google and Samsung have to offer.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-oppo-find-x8-pro-software"><span>OPPO Find X8 Pro: Software</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="5mSLJEXAVpkFMeAAQteeiX" name="oppo-find-x8-pro-19.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5mSLJEXAVpkFMeAAQteeiX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Find X8 Pro runs ColorOS 15 based on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a> out of the box, and it looks quite different to ColorOS 14 — and not in a good way. The new design is clean and has a modern aesthetic, but it looks a little too much like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/everything-ios-18-stole-from-android">iOS 18</a> to my liking. After four years of trying to ditch resemblances to iOS, ColorOS is back to leaning heavily into it, and it&apos;s irksome.</p><p>The interface is still fluid, but the styling is a bit heavy-handed, and that gets in the way even in daily use. Thankfully, you can still choose a unified notification shade with the toggles and notifications in the same pane, but it&apos;s clear that OPPO wants to go with a split option. Will this toggle still be available next year? I doubt it.</p><p>While the UI emulates iOS, the resemblance is only skin-deep, as some of the issues in previous versions are still present. DND continues to be flaky on the device. I like to leave DND enabled throughout the day as I don&apos;t want to get disturbed by constant notification messages, but I get a lot of deliveries, so I allow all calls to come through. That isn&apos;t possible on the Find X8 Pro (and any other ColorOS phone) because it clubs calls and messages into a single category. The only choice is to allow both calls and messages to override DND, and that defeats the idea of having the mode enabled.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="w36z4KttSzTcG8cWtJDSrZ" name="oppo-find-x8-pro-17.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/w36z4KttSzTcG8cWtJDSrZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Talking about a source of constant frustration, push notifications continue to be inconsistent, and I missed several Gmail alerts in the time I tested the device. Some notifications come through, but it&apos;s the sporadic nature that&apos;s annoying; at least with MIUI, you don&apos;t get any notifications at all, so you know that going in.</p><p>Another quirk with the software is that when you launch an app from the app drawer and eventually exit, you stay in the app drawer instead of going to the home screen. It takes an additional gesture to go back to the home screen, and that&apos;s just annoying. The one new feature I like is Share with iPhone. There&apos;s a sharing option that allows you to transfer content to an iPhone — provided the iOS app is installed — and it works seamlessly.</p><p>Of course, AI is now a big talking point with all Android skins, and ColorOS 15 is no different. You get AI-backed features to assist you to write messages and mails, summarize documents, transcribe audio notes, and there&apos;s Circle to Search as well. I don&apos;t have much need of AI, so I didn&apos;t use these features beyond the usual testing, but if you want software with at least a modicum of useful AI-assisted tools, you&apos;re covered with ColorOS 15.</p><p>When it comes to software updates, the Find X8 Pro will get five years of Android OS updates and six years of security updates. That&apos;s a sizeable increase from last year, and while Google and Samsung deliver seven years of updates, I don&apos;t have a problem with OPPO&apos;s update guarantee.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-oppo-find-x8-pro-the-competition"><span>OPPO Find X8 Pro: The competition</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="Muu2fJgP6ZUkGdVwvXhpTb" name="oppo-find-x8-pro-22.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Muu2fJgP6ZUkGdVwvXhpTb.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Find X8 Pro is launching globally ahead of its rivals, but Vivo&apos;s X200 Pro isn&apos;t far behind. That phone is also powered by the MediaTek Dimensity 9400, and it has the same AMOLED panel and main 50MP camera at the back. You get an even bigger battery, and I like Vivo&apos;s camera tuning a little better, so it should deliver better photos. The international launch is still a little while away, but the X200 Pro is the closest rival to the Find X8 Pro, and it&apos;s great to see both phones available globally.</p><p>The regular Find X8 is a good choice as well if you don&apos;t need a second zoom lens. As I said at the start, it is basically the same device as the OnePlus 13, and the only difference is the badge at the back.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-oppo-find-x8-pro-should-you-buy-it"><span>OPPO Find X8 Pro: Should you buy it?</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="GmNeBRFgKk2gJUcXmDs76U" name="oppo-find-x8-pro-1.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GmNeBRFgKk2gJUcXmDs76U.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>You should buy this if:</strong></p>
<ul><li>You need a phone that takes stunning photos</li><li>You want the one of the best portrait cameras available today</li><li>You need a powerful hardware package</li><li>You want a phone that lasts two days between charges</li></ul>
<p><strong>You shouldn&apos;t buy this if:</strong></p>
<ul><li>You need 120fps gaming</li><li>You want frustration-free software</li></ul>
<p>While it doesn&apos;t have the absolute best cameras, the Find X8 Pro is still a frontrunner in this area, and it handily beats the Pixel 9 Pro XL, iPhone 16 Pro Max, and Galaxy S24 Ultra without too much trouble. The main camera takes stunning photos and videos, but it&apos;s the portrait shots where the phone truly comes into its own. The dual zoom lenses make a big difference in this area, and with the phone now available globally, the tech is finally becoming accessible to a wider audience outside China.</p><p>I don&apos;t like the new design, and I feel that OPPO shouldn&apos;t have moved away from its distinctive aesthetic. That said, the phone is thinner and lighter than its predecessor while slotting in a massive battery, and that is a sizeable achievement. There are absolutely no issues with the hardware, and the phone should be just as fast as the Qualcomm-powered alternatives debuting in the coming weeks.</p><p>The only point of contention is the software. Similar to the hardware design, OPPO decided to take a different tack with ColorOS 15, and the interface now looks like a poor imitation of iOS 18, which wasn&apos;t the case in the preceding three years. It still has a good amount of customizability and is fluid in regular use, but it has annoyances with DND and notifications, and the design feels backward.</p><p>If you can overlook the software, the Find X8 Pro is a fabulous phone. OPPO did all the right things with the hardware, display, battery, and cameras, and it is a terrific alternative to the Galaxy S24 Ultra and Pixel 9 Pro XL.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oppo-find-x8-pro-review</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Find X8 Pro has made its global debut, and it combines an outstanding camera package with class-leading battery life and the best hardware available today.   ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">iYpDpY6VJUNtp8piP8XDuV</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YaYYPA7iszJeamjmP7KbRU.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 07:31:50 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YaYYPA7iszJeamjmP7KbRU.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OPPO Find X8 Pro review]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OPPO Find X8 Pro review]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ I don't care much for watch apps, but I'm giving them a second chance ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Wear OS Weekly</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="o8KRGSTt4mbFxn3wdtWvtU" name="lloyd-wear-os-weekly.jpg" caption="" alt="Android Central mascot Lloyd wearing a Galaxy Watch and Pixel Watch" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/o8KRGSTt4mbFxn3wdtWvtU.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">My new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/wear-os-weekly">weekly column</a> focuses on the state of Wear OS, from new developments and updates to the latest apps and features we want to highlight.</p></div></div>
<p>My initial bias against both Wear OS watches and Apple Watches was that wrist-based apps felt too limited when my phone was always <em>right there</em>. Why not buy a "dumber" watch that lasts a week or two instead if I don't need apps? I've even spoken to several avid Wear OS users who love having actionable notifications and Google Assistant, but when I asked them what their <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wear-os-apps">favorite Wear OS apps</a> were, they couldn't think of any.</p><p>So I know I'm not alone in this feeling; unless you buy a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/i-used-to-want-lte-smartwatch-but-not-anymore">standalone LTE watch</a> specifically to leave your phone at home, you're probably not going to use the apps all that often — aside from obvious ones like workouts or answering calls.</p><p>But as I've begun to use watches like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-3-review">Pixel Watch 3</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-ultra-review">Galaxy Watch Ultra</a> more extensively, I've surprised myself and found a few Google apps that I rarely use on my phone but <em>love</em> to use on my watch. Most recently, I've had a mini-love affair with the Recorder app — which was added in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/wear-os-5">Wear OS 5</a> — and Google Keep Notes.</p><p>As much as I depend on Gmail, Drive, and Chrome daily, I mainly use them on my laptop unless I'm out and about. Otherwise, I find it hard to get attached to any particular Google app or tool when they're likely to get deprecated (aka Killed by Google™) at any given moment.</p><p>However, my new Wear OS focus and these voice-based apps are rekindling my enthusiasm for Google apps, and now I'm on the hunt to find more Wear OS apps that are actually fun to use.</p>

<h2 id="google-recorder-my-new-audio-diary-reminder-tool-2">Google Recorder: My new audio diary/reminder tool</h2>
<p>I'm not thrilled that, in my mid-30s, I seem to forget a lot these days unless I write it down. I tap out phone notes or add reminders to my to-do app, but it's not always convenient, and I frequently spit out some rapid-fire text that makes sense at the time but is gibberish later.</p><p>Now, I've started using the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/how-use-pixel-watch-recorder-app" target="_blank">Google Recorder app</a> and Tile to take audio notes that sync to my <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-review" target="_blank">Pixel 9.</a> Later, I can generate a transcript to copy to other apps; it also syncs to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://recorder.google.com/">recorder.google.com</a>.</p><p>I wish I could edit its imperfect transcripts or see them on the watch itself, but it's certainly better than having no text at all! Recorder comes in handy for recording meeting notes on the fly without having to awkwardly hold my phone out. And I can't stress enough how useful the Recorder app has turned out for random moments of my day.</p><p>After training runs, I've taken to recording post-run summaries of how it went, any cool things I saw, and goals for future runs; later on, I copy the transcript over to a Google Doc, add my Strava stats and any photos, and just like that, I have a full-on running diary that feels more organic than typing everything out later.</p><p>(I also tried doing this with my <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-fenix-8-review">Garmin Fenix 8</a>, but the lack of phone syncs and transcription makes its recorder app less useful, for now.)</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="YKdacstEhPUGr6vWs5tK7d" name="google-pixel-watch-3-recorder-app-2.jpg" alt="Recorder app on Pixel Watch 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YKdacstEhPUGr6vWs5tK7d.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2500" height="1406" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I used to jot down notes of my weirdest dreams to remember later, but squinting half-awake at my phone screen was annoying, and the notes never made much sense. Seriously, try to understand this one: "Thanksgiving, Jedi/yoda, headless horseman chasing me and cloned itself." That's a real dream note I made.</p><p>Now, I've taken to sneaking into the bathroom and whispering out a quick dream summary with the door closed so I don't wake up my partner. They're still nonsense, but I can describe the nonsense with more context because I'm not restricted by thumb-typing speed. Now, the next time I'm menaced by a headless horseman on Thanksgiving, I'll have more information to go on.</p><p>I'm not going out of my way to use the Recorder app, and it's still sometimes easier to type out things I want to remember. But I love having the option.</p>
<h2 id="google-keep-notes-checking-off-my-day-2">Google Keep Notes: Checking off my day</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="xwkkkefE6xVk6Eh9KyH2ya" name="Google-Keep-Notes-tile-Pixel-Watch-3" alt="The Google Pixel Watch 3 showing the Google Keep Notes tile, with an option to Create note or Create list" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xwkkkefE6xVk6Eh9KyH2ya.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I've been using the Microsoft To Do app to keep myself organized for personal goals, chores, packing lists, and so on since before Microsoft bought it (remember Wunderlist?). So I've never felt the need to use Google Keep.</p><p>But since there's no Wear OS To Do app, I've taken to creating to-do lists in Keep every Monday morning and then checking them off my wrist throughout the work week so I don't lose track of any goals.</p><p>I also use Keep's voice-transcribed note function for the same reason as the Recorder app: to remind myself of things later without having to find and unlock my phone or type things out. I know I could do that just as easily in the mobile app, but I like the way Wear OS feels more <em>casual</em> and <em>immediate</em> for these apps.</p>
<h2 id="limited-with-much-potential-2">Limited, with much potential</h2>
<p>My initial skepticism still applies to a lot of other Wear OS apps. The initial time saved by using Wear OS is usually offset by the small display, the finicky touchscreen for typing things out on a little QWERTY keyboard, and the unreliable transcript when using voice-to-text.</p><p>Now, I'm happy to give Wear OS apps a second shot and acknowledge that I don't have to pull out my phone for everything. But I'm also hoping that the recent focus on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini AI</a> will make its way to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wear-os-watch">Wear OS watches</a> so that apps can benefit from greater smarts when it comes to voice-to-text and commands. I still don't want to spend any time typing on a watch if I can help it.</p><p>Do you have a favorite Wear OS app that you prefer to use over the normal Android mobile version? I'm looking for future apps to highlight in this column and will happily take any recommendations!</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="f4325f3e-f437-4e7a-9f7f-b6135fcaa7f6">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FBXoKSyApdcecWDoiCt5YZ.jpg' alt="Google Pixel Watch Active Band"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel Watch 3</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="90" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Chock-full of apps</strong></em></p><p>The Pixel Watch 3 runs Wear OS 5, which added a ton of new software tricks like Google TV controls, Nest Camera controls, offline Google Maps, and the aforementioned Recorder app, plus old standbys like Fitbit Premium and Google Assistant. If you like using watch apps without needing to rely on your phone as much, this is a fast and attractive option for Android users.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/using-google-keep-and-recorder-app-on-pixel-watch</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Smartwatch apps don't seem much more useful than smartphone apps, but they can sometimes be more convenient. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">3QwxyTiPmCV8E2EfmQseL6</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/p3qGTraPSZmr9Wkcuum2na.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wear Os]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/p3qGTraPSZmr9Wkcuum2na.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Google Pixel Watch 3 showing the Google Recorder tile.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Google Pixel Watch 3 showing the Google Recorder tile.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The OPPO Find X8 series is taking the fight to the iPhone 16 globally ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The Find X8 and X8 Pro launched in Bali with ColorOS 15 and next-gen OPPO AI features.</li><li>Both models have a dedicated camera shutter button and run on the MediaTek Dimensity 9400 chipset, plus an alert slider and solid IP68/IP69K ratings.</li><li>The Find X8 series is compatible with OPPO's Mag accessories, but you'll need a special case for them.</li><li>The regular Find X8 comes in 12GB + 256GB and 16GB + 512GB, while the Pro model is available only with 16GB + 512GB.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>After its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-wait-is-over-oppos-find-x8-and-x8-pro-are-launching-globally">debut in China</a>, the OPPO Find X8 series is now going global, marking a big step in the brand's plan to bring premium flagship experiences to more people.</p><p>The OPPO Find X8 and X8 Pro today made their global debut in Bali, Indonesia, alongside the reveal of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/oppo-coloros-15-advances-device-ai-google">ColorOS 15</a>, packed with next-gen OPPO AI features.</p><p>As expected, OPPO’s latest flagship comes with a dedicated camera shutter button, giving off iPhone 16 vibes with its design. The Find X8 and X8 Pro run on the MediaTek Dimensity 9400 chipset. They also come with an alert slider, IP68 and IP69K water and dust resistance, plus 80W wired and 50W wireless charging support.</p><p>The Find X8 series works with OPPO's Mag accessories, but you'll need to grab a special case for that. The accessory lineup includes a power bank, an 80W 20,000mAh power bank, and a 50W wireless charger with a built-in cooling fan.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:5333px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="JRjcJ3VFsrBiMwS7Y859hT" name="OPPO-Find-X8" alt="OPPO Find X8" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JRjcJ3VFsrBiMwS7Y859hT.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="5333" height="3000" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OPPO)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Pro model, with its new shutter button, packs all the flagship features you'd expect for 2024. It comes with a 6.78-inch display and a massive 5,910mAh battery.</p><p>Meanwhile, the standard Find X8 has a 6.59-inch flat LTPO OLED display with FHD+ resolution and a refresh rate that adjusts between 1Hz and 120Hz. This smart display saves battery by tweaking the refresh rate based on what's on screen, giving you smooth scrolling and responsive performance without draining the battery.</p><p>Both models feature an in-display fingerprint sensor for quick unlocking and a 32MP front camera subtly hidden within the display.</p><p>A big draw of the Find X series has always been its cameras, and the Find X8 models look set to keep that legacy alive. The Find X8 Pro features a Hasselblad-branded camera setup with four 50MP cameras, including two with 6x and 3x optical zoom telephoto lenses.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:5333px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="okMaYbDgRbWrvhhQigiAhT" name="OPPO-Find-X8" alt="OPPO Find X8" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/okMaYbDgRbWrvhhQigiAhT.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="5333" height="3000" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OPPO)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Find X8 series brings a new feature called Shadowless Snapshot, letting you snap clear, blur-free photos with just a hand gesture.</p><p>OPPO is showing off the AI capabilities of the Find X8 series. Along with AI tools that eliminate glare in photos, the Find X8 Pro also has a feature like Google Lens or iPhone's Visual Lookup—just snap a pic of something like a landmark, and the AI will give you a description or some context about it.</p><p>The base model starts at IDR 13,999,000 (about $878) and the Pro variant at IDR 19,999,000 (around $1,255). International prices may vary depending on the region.</p><p>The devices will roll out in parts of Asia and Europe, with other markets to be confirmed soon.</p><p>The regular Find X8 comes in two options: 12GB + 256GB and 16GB + 512GB, while the Find X8 Pro is only available with 16GB + 512GB.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-oppo-find-x8-series-is-taking-the-fight-to-the-iphone-16-globally</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ OPPO's Find X8 series is spreading its wings and taking flight worldwide. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">mp8CzbggtzukY7F9jRqVtg</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SDiwzt2GyAJQZS8G7qkcJ7.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 06:10:11 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SDiwzt2GyAJQZS8G7qkcJ7.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[OPPO]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OPPO Find X8 being held to the ear]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OPPO Find X8 being held to the ear]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ What happens if Google has to sell Chrome? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The worst person you know finally made a great point. Former Google CEO Eric Schmidt was <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.cnbc.com/video/2024/11/19/watch-cnbcs-full-interview-with-the-former-google-ceo-eric-schmidt.html">on CNBC</a> and said the quiet part out loud:</p><p><em>“Breaking up these companies is not going to fundamentally address the annoyance you have with them.”</em></p><p>He was talking about the news that the Justice Department may ask a judge to force<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-could-be-forced-to-sell-off-chrome-to-level-the-search-playing-field"> Google to sell off its Chrome browser</a> and he's absolutely right. Breaking up Google may benefit other tech companies, but nothing will change for you and me.</p>
<p>The reason why isn't hard to figure out; simply look at which companies would be both willing and able to buy Chrome from Google. Do you think Jeff Bezos or Elon Musk is going to treat you and your data any better than Google does? Will either somehow make the web a better place if they suddenly own the world's most popular browser?</p>
<p>I don't think it's going to happen, and after <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/the-pulse-google-is-now-a-monopoly-but-nothing-will-really-change">Google has exhausted every appeal</a> and tried every trick it can think of, it will have plenty of things on its plate that it hates. But selling Chrome (<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-will-die-if-split-from-google">or Android</a>, or its cloud platform, or any other of its "big" products) won't be one of them. Even if selling Chrome would help consumers, it hinges on finding a buyer who can face the regulatory scrutiny that Google is now facing. None of them can, or at least none of them should be able to. Big Tech is equally evil, and Meta is no better than Apple, which is no better than Microsoft.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1389px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="uCyqjgRgv6aNdMgFBZcHE3" name="google-my-ads-center-lifestyle.jpg" alt="Google My Ad Center on a Chromebook" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uCyqjgRgv6aNdMgFBZcHE3.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1389" height="781" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>With no buyer, the only other option would be to force Google to shut down Chrome, and that's downright un-American. Nope. Can't do it, won't do it. Remember, you think tech CEOs are fighting the good fight against Washington, but in reality, they're <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/musk-joined-call-between-trump-google-ceo">calling president-elect Trump to congratulate him</a>. The posturing and feel-good social media posts are to draw your attention away from the donations and camaraderie.</p>
<p>In a perfect world, getting rid of Chrome <em>could</em> be great. It would open the way for a company with no ties to ads or operating systems to lead the charge, and we all could use <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/">Firefox</a> and be treated a little better. In the real world, Firefox is still going to die a slow death without Google's money, while Chrome will still be around, sucking in everything it can in order to manipulate and monetize you regardless of what name is on the company letterhead.</p><p>It's my opinion that forcing Google to stop investing in Chrome actually does plenty of harm to consumers. Google spends so much money and time on Chrome's open codebase — which powers almost every WebKit browser — because <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/does-google-sell-your-data">it makes so much in return</a>. Chrome is an avenue to data, and data is an avenue to effective advertisements. It's just like Android, and to Google, spending money on a free product is an investment in its ad business. No other company will do this, and names like Opera, Brave, Samsung Internet Browser, and even Microsoft Edge will pay the price for it.</p>
<p>People use Chrome for one reason — its integration with Google's other products. You don't (well, shouldn't) use Chrome if you want a fast and resource-friendly web browser that doesn't spy on you like a dirty old man with a pair of binoculars. You use it because it works seamlessly with all the other stuff you use, like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gmail-android-how-to">Gmail</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-docs-new-feature-is-your-go-to-tool-for-wrangling-those-giant-documents">Google Docs</a>, or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/i-used-new-google-pay-over-two-years-heres-why-amazing">Google Pay</a>. This cohesion is something every other tech company dreams about, and only Apple can come close for people who only use an iPhone. For better or worse, the web belongs to Google.</p><p>Selling Chrome or making Google syndicate search results won't change any of that. It will allow other companies to make more money, but for consumers, nothing is going to change no matter how Alphabet gets carved up because all tech companies have the same goals.</p>
<p>For me, it's nice to see Google on the hot seat because the company does so many terrible things. I just think the people who run companies like Google are smarter than the people going after them and will always win in the end.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/what-happens-if-google-has-to-sell-chrome</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A win for Microsoft and Apple, selling Chrome isn't going to make the web better.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">SQeYjWP5gHm9CeuqNvjVbH</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZogmMvXgwJrn6aMHtVxdd5.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZogmMvXgwJrn6aMHtVxdd5.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Chrome logo at 2024 Fall Chromebook Event]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Chrome logo at 2024 Fall Chromebook Event]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Skip Black Friday, the Galaxy S24 Ultra just scored a stunning $350 discount at Best Buy — no trade-in required! ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>If steep price tags have prevented you from buying this year&apos;s greatest Android phones, you&apos;re in luck: Best Buy just dropped <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-256gb-unlocked-titanium-black/6569855.p"><strong>an early Black Friday deal that slashes $350 off</strong></a> the Galaxy S24 Ultra — no strings attached, no trade-in required!</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Black Friday deals</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Black Friday Google Pixel deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Black Friday Motorola deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Black Friday OnePlus deals</a><br>
<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/early-black-friday-garmin-deals-2024-ditch-your-old-smartwatch-and-save-big-on-forerunner-venu-and-more">-Black Friday Garmin deals</a></p></div></div>
<p>For $949.99, you&apos;re getting what is arguably the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-samsung-phones">best Samsung phone</a> ever built, a super-powered device with a stunning 6.8-inch AMOLED display, built-in S Pen stylus, and a powerful 200MP main camera. You also get a reliable two-day battery, a ton of useful Galaxy AI features, and the unrivalled efficiency of the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 chipset. And like all of the phones in the Galaxy S24 lineup, the S24 Ultra comes with seven years of guaranteed OS and security updates. We&apos;ve already seen a ton of outstanding <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024">Black Friday Samsung deals</a> this year, but this offer takes the cake as one of the best. </p>
<h2 id="the-premium-galaxy-s24-ultra-just-got-a-little-less-premium-for-black-friday-2">The premium Galaxy S24 Ultra just got a little less premium for Black Friday</h2>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="a0c2601e-c57c-4fa1-8f44-b1f4e483064d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,299.99" data-dimension48="$1,299.99" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-256gb-unlocked-titanium-black/6569855.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="GgWobTBkWru648FmweBtcg" name="samsung galaxy s24 ultra square render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GgWobTBkWru648FmweBtcg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="800" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra 256GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-256gb-unlocked-titanium-black/6569855.p" data-dimension112="a0c2601e-c57c-4fa1-8f44-b1f4e483064d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,299.99" data-dimension48="$1,299.99"><del>$1,299.99</del> <strong>$949.99 unlocked | $849.99 with activation at Best Buy</strong></a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review"><strong>Android Central review: </strong>★★★★<strong>½</strong></a></p>
<p>If you value power in your devices, look no further than the Galaxy S24 Ultra. This beast of performance features a powerful Snapdragon processor with 12GB of RAM, a glorious QHD+ AMOLED display, and all of the innovative Galaxy AI features you could ever need. </p>
<p>Thanks to Best Buy's Black Friday sale, you can currently grab this super-powered smartphone with a $350 discount, no strings attached. Activate the device through your carrier and Best Buy will throw in an additional $100 off, just for kicks. </p>
<p>👀<strong>Alternate Black Friday deal: </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/smartphones/galaxy-s24-ultra/buy/galaxy-s24-ultra-256gb-unlocked-sm-s928ulbexaa/"><strong>Up to $800 off with trade-in, free storage upgrade at Samsung</strong></a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-256gb-unlocked-titanium-black/6569855.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="a0c2601e-c57c-4fa1-8f44-b1f4e483064d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,299.99" data-dimension48="$1,299.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>you want one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a> ever produced; you prefer to buy your phones unlocked; you want years of software support. </p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>you can wait for the Galaxy S25 to come out next year; you&apos;re looking for a trade-in opportunity. </p><p>Of course, even with this deal, 950 bucks isn&apos;t nothing. If you&apos;re cool with doing a trade-in (or you own something like the Galaxy S23 Ultra), I&apos;d consider skipping this Best Buy offer altogether and heading straight to Samsung.com, where you can <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/smartphones/galaxy-s24-ultra/buy/galaxy-s24-ultra-256gb-unlocked-sm-s928ulbexaa/"><strong>score up to $800 off the S24 Ultra</strong></a> when you send in an old or broken device. </p><p>No matter how you choose to save money this holiday season, you can rest easy knowing that there&apos;s never been a better time to buy the Galaxy S24 Ultra than <em>right now. </em></p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/skip-black-friday-the-galaxy-s24-ultra-just-scored-a-stunning-usd350-discount-at-best-buy-no-trade-in-required</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Days before Black Friday officially kicks off, Best Buy is carving a straight $350 off the super-powered Galaxy S24 Ultra. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">gBaejHPHY8vNgnFTZdwh8N</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7P2ErZCEHSc73umEzHChMN.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 22:57:52 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7P2ErZCEHSc73umEzHChMN.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The back of the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra in the Titanium Grey colorway]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The back of the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra in the Titanium Grey colorway]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Early Black Friday Garmin deals 2024 — ditch your old smartwatch and save big on Forerunner, Venu, and more ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>If you&apos;re planning to buy a new smartwatch this holiday season, you&apos;ll be pleased to learn that many of the best Black Friday Garmin deals have already gone live. Retailers like Best Buy and Amazon are carving up to $250 off Garmin wearables, and I&apos;ve dropped a selection of my favorite offers below. Whether you want something sleek and versatile or rugged enough to withstand ALL the elements, the best Garmin watch deals of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/black-friday-2024">Black Friday 2024</a> can be found in this guide. </p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">More Black Friday deals</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Black Friday Google Pixel deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Black Friday Motorola deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024">Black Friday Samsung deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Black Friday OnePlus deals</a></p></div></div>
<p>Here at Android Central, it&apos;s no secret that we&apos;re big fans of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-garmin-smartwatch">Garmin smartwatches</a>. These wearables are expertly crafted for athletes of all ages and skill levels, whether you&apos;re a marathon runner, long-distance hiker, or simply counting your steps throughout the day. Garmin devices can range from budget models to premium beasts of performance, but whatever you&apos;re searching for today, there&apos;s probably a Black Friday deal just waiting to be uncovered. </p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-quick-links"><span>Quick links</span></h3>
<ul><li><strong>Black Friday Garmin sales: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/Garmin/page/675B188D-FBE3-4FF4-9DD0-E48E4A2C888D"><strong>Amazon</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/searchpage.jsp?st=garmin"><strong>Best Buy</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/browse/0?facet=brand:Garmin"><strong>Walmart</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.garmin.com/en-US/"><strong>Garmin Store</strong></a></li><li><strong>Garmin Venu 3:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/garmin-venu-3-gps-smartwatch-45-mm-fiber-reinforced-polymer-stainless-steel-and-black/6551498.p"><del>was $449.99</del><strong> now $349.99 at Best Buy</strong></a></li><li><strong>Garmin Forerunner 165:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Garmin-Forerunner-Smartwatch-Colorful-Training/dp/B0CT3SGHXL"><del>was $249.99</del> <strong>now $199.99 at Amazon</strong></a></li><li><strong>Garmin Fenix 7 Pro Solar: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/garmin-fenix-7-pro-solar-gps-smartwatch-47-mm-fiber-reinforced-polymer-slate-gray/6545135.p"><del>was $799.99</del> <strong>now $549.99 at Best Buy</strong></a></li><li><strong>Garmin Vivoactive 5: </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Garmin-v-voactive-5-Slate-Aluminim-Bezel-with-Black-Case-and-Silicone-Band/5022920052"><del>was $299.99</del><strong> now $199.99 at Walmart</strong></a></li><li><strong>Garmin Venu Sq 2: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Garmin-Smartwatch-All-Day-Monitoring-Long-Lasting/dp/B0B5VVNJBF/"><del>was $249.99</del><strong> now $149.99 at Amazon</strong></a></li><li><strong>Garmin Forerunner 965: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/garmin-forerunner-965-gps-smartwatch-47-mm-fiber-reinforced-polymer-carbon-gray-tlc-titanium/6544443.p"><del>was $599.99</del><strong> now $499.99 at Best Buy</strong></a></li><li><strong>Garmin Bounce:</strong> <a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Garmin-Bounce-Green-Burst/6659973310"><del>was $149.99</del> <strong>now $129.99 at Walmart</strong></a></li></ul>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-early-black-friday-garmin-deals"><span>Early Black Friday Garmin deals</span></h3>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="7037602c-b3dc-4dfe-9452-ab9e83a5c811" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$449.99" data-dimension48="$449.99" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/garmin-venu-3-gps-smartwatch-45-mm-fiber-reinforced-polymer-stainless-steel-and-black/6551498.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="2WiJoGHqwkgsQeNTwMwDwL" name="garmin venu 3 400x500.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2WiJoGHqwkgsQeNTwMwDwL.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Garmin Venu 3:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/garmin-venu-3-gps-smartwatch-45-mm-fiber-reinforced-polymer-stainless-steel-and-black/6551498.p" data-dimension112="7037602c-b3dc-4dfe-9452-ab9e83a5c811" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$449.99" data-dimension48="$449.99"><del>$449.99</del><strong> $349.99 at Best Buy</strong></a></p>
<p>The watch we'd recommend to most folks is the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-venu-3-review">Garmin Venu 3</a>. This super-balanced wearable boasts a spacious AMOLED display with up to 14 days of battery life and all of the health and fitness tracking features you could ever need. Grab the Venu 3 during Best Buy's Black Friday sale and you'll score a straight $100 off your purchase!   <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/garmin-venu-3-gps-smartwatch-45-mm-fiber-reinforced-polymer-stainless-steel-and-black/6551498.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="7037602c-b3dc-4dfe-9452-ab9e83a5c811" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$449.99" data-dimension48="$449.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="639ee3dc-3ccc-425b-8e20-9dfa0cab752d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$249.99" data-dimension48="$249.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/Garmin-Forerunner-Smartwatch-Colorful-Training/dp/B0CT3SGHXL" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="kes35gCrRe7qtT24rDFeoP" name="garmin-forerunner-165-whitestone-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kes35gCrRe7qtT24rDFeoP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1080" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Garmin Forerunner 165:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Garmin-Forerunner-Smartwatch-Colorful-Training/dp/B0CT3SGHXL" data-dimension112="639ee3dc-3ccc-425b-8e20-9dfa0cab752d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$249.99" data-dimension48="$249.99"><del>$249.99</del> <strong>$199.99 at Amazon</strong></a> </p>
<p>Currently 20% off at Amazon, the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-forerunner-165-review">Forerunner 165</a> is a great starter fitness watch with a lightweight design, up to 11 days of battery life, and some accurate heart rate and sleep tracking capabilities. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/Garmin-Forerunner-Smartwatch-Colorful-Training/dp/B0CT3SGHXL" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="639ee3dc-3ccc-425b-8e20-9dfa0cab752d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$249.99" data-dimension48="$249.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="8f7fbdb8-df87-48b8-bd7b-d4e1c70bac1e" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799.99" data-dimension48="$799.99" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/garmin-fenix-7-pro-solar-gps-smartwatch-47-mm-fiber-reinforced-polymer-slate-gray/6545135.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:967px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:88.52%;"><img id="voY6FBpVwNB4bARsXDbkrn" name="garmin-fenix-7-pro-solar-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/voY6FBpVwNB4bARsXDbkrn.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="967" height="856" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Garmin Fenix 7 Pro Solar:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/garmin-fenix-7-pro-solar-gps-smartwatch-47-mm-fiber-reinforced-polymer-slate-gray/6545135.p" data-dimension112="8f7fbdb8-df87-48b8-bd7b-d4e1c70bac1e" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799.99" data-dimension48="$799.99"><del>$799.99</del> <strong>$549.99 at Best Buy</strong></a></p>
<p>If you're looking for a fitness watch that's built to last, consider the Fenix 7 Pro Solar. This rugged watch harnesses the power of the sun to bring you up to 22 days of battery life, plus you get military-grade durability, a built-in LED flashlight, and 24/7 health and sleep monitoring. Place your order while the Black Friday sale is active and Best Buy will hook you up with a $250 discount. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/garmin-fenix-7-pro-solar-gps-smartwatch-47-mm-fiber-reinforced-polymer-slate-gray/6545135.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="8f7fbdb8-df87-48b8-bd7b-d4e1c70bac1e" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799.99" data-dimension48="$799.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="4dac547e-e8fc-408b-be41-facfd037dbd2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$299.99" data-dimension48="$299.99" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Garmin-v-voactive-5-Slate-Aluminim-Bezel-with-Black-Case-and-Silicone-Band/5022920052" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1125px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:133.33%;"><img id="b7JGFY7Rt6zJq2RBZfSLMA" name="garmin-vivoactive-5-render-black.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/b7JGFY7Rt6zJq2RBZfSLMA.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1125" height="1500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Garmin Vivoactive 5:</strong> <a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Garmin-v-voactive-5-Slate-Aluminim-Bezel-with-Black-Case-and-Silicone-Band/5022920052" data-dimension112="4dac547e-e8fc-408b-be41-facfd037dbd2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$299.99" data-dimension48="$299.99"><del>$299.99</del> <strong>$199.99 at Walmart</strong></a></p>
<p>The Vivoactive 5 is a popular choice for folks who want the Garmin experience without sacrificing sleek smartwatch style. Currently sitting with a $100 discount during Walmart's Black Friday sale, the watch features a 1.2-inch AMOLED display, up to 11 days of battery life, and all of the same health and fitness tracking features that made Garmin famous. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Garmin-v-voactive-5-Slate-Aluminim-Bezel-with-Black-Case-and-Silicone-Band/5022920052" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="4dac547e-e8fc-408b-be41-facfd037dbd2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$299.99" data-dimension48="$299.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="7219b63f-1d43-451d-a7ac-cf2364eb5b82" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$249.99" data-dimension48="$249.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/Garmin-Smartwatch-All-Day-Monitoring-Long-Lasting/dp/B0B5VVNJBF/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1045px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:143.54%;"><img id="JigHsWJiLs4qWEQXnLoRQH" name="garmin-venu-sq-2-gray-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JigHsWJiLs4qWEQXnLoRQH.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1045" height="1500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Garmin Venu Sq 2:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Garmin-Smartwatch-All-Day-Monitoring-Long-Lasting/dp/B0B5VVNJBF/" data-dimension112="7219b63f-1d43-451d-a7ac-cf2364eb5b82" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$249.99" data-dimension48="$249.99"><del>$249.99</del> <strong>$149.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>We called the Garmin Venu Sq 2 the "goldilocks smartwatch" in <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-venu-sq-2-review">our 4/5-star review</a>, and it isn't hard to see why. The balanced smartwatch comes with a bright AMOLED display that would look great next to an Apple Watch or Galaxy wearable, plus you get a long-lasting battery, a ton of health and fitness sensors, and NFC support. Grab the Venu Sq 2 before the Black Friday sales end and you'll receive a whopping 40% discount. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/Garmin-Smartwatch-All-Day-Monitoring-Long-Lasting/dp/B0B5VVNJBF/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="7219b63f-1d43-451d-a7ac-cf2364eb5b82" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$249.99" data-dimension48="$249.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="94b1df88-49ec-4afd-a2f4-33fa104062dd" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$599.99" data-dimension48="$599.99" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/garmin-forerunner-965-gps-smartwatch-47-mm-fiber-reinforced-polymer-carbon-gray-tlc-titanium/6544443.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="x3XC9L6qCL8KL6HswwFq78" name="Garmin Forerunner 965.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/x3XC9L6qCL8KL6HswwFq78.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Garmin Forerunner 965:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/garmin-forerunner-965-gps-smartwatch-47-mm-fiber-reinforced-polymer-carbon-gray-tlc-titanium/6544443.p" data-dimension112="94b1df88-49ec-4afd-a2f4-33fa104062dd" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$599.99" data-dimension48="$599.99"><del>$599.99</del><strong> $499.99 at Best Buy</strong></a></p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-forerunner-965-review">Garmin Forerunner 965</a> might just be the best runner's watch ever built, with impressively-accurate mapping software, multiple days of battery life on a single charge, and a vibrant AMOLED display. As part of its Black Friday sale, Best Buy is dropping a straight $100 off the watch. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/garmin-forerunner-965-gps-smartwatch-47-mm-fiber-reinforced-polymer-carbon-gray-tlc-titanium/6544443.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="94b1df88-49ec-4afd-a2f4-33fa104062dd" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$599.99" data-dimension48="$599.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="fb67f081-9bc0-4d5b-b7c9-47dc61ffef8d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Garmin Bounce: $149.99" data-dimension48="Garmin Bounce: $149.99" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Garmin-Bounce-Green-Burst/6659973310" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="KyVVivBZwsdKbY64XtEDaY" name="Garmin Bounce render bg.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KyVVivBZwsdKbY64XtEDaY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Garmin Bounce: </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Garmin-Bounce-Green-Burst/6659973310" data-dimension112="fb67f081-9bc0-4d5b-b7c9-47dc61ffef8d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Garmin Bounce: $149.99" data-dimension48="Garmin Bounce: $149.99"><del>$149.99</del> <strong>$129.99 at Walmart</strong></a></p>
<p>Is your kid ready for their first-ever smartwatch? The <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-bounce-kids-watch-review-the-fun-smartwatch-for-kids">Garmin Bounce</a> might be the answer. Currently $20 off at Walmart, this kid-friendly wearable comes with activity and sleep tracking, a durable construction, voice  and text support, and a bunch of intuitive, easy-to-use software features.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Garmin-Bounce-Green-Burst/6659973310" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="fb67f081-9bc0-4d5b-b7c9-47dc61ffef8d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Garmin Bounce: $149.99" data-dimension48="Garmin Bounce: $149.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-faq"><span>FAQ</span></h3>
<h2 id="when-is-black-friday-2">When is Black Friday?</h2>
<p>Black Friday is November 29th, the day after Thanksgiving in the United States. Although that&apos;s when sale events have gone live historically, Black Friday sales have been starting earlier and earlier every year, which means you can find excellent Black Friday deals throughout the entire month of November. </p>
<h2 id="which-retailer-has-the-best-garmin-deals-during-black-friday-2">Which retailer has the best Garmin deals during Black Friday?</h2>
<p>Retailers such as Best Buy, Amazon, Walmart, and Garmin itself have all released their Black Friday deals on Garmin watches early, and there are few differences between them. If you&apos;re trying to settle on a particular retailer, look beyond the price tags to see if there are any additional perks in the fine print. Is Amazon Prime going to give you free shipping? Does the Garmin store offer an extended warranty? These are important details to check before choosing an offer. </p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/early-black-friday-garmin-deals-2024-ditch-your-old-smartwatch-and-save-big-on-forerunner-venu-and-more</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Garmin's holiday sale is LIVE, and retailers all over the web are dropping major discounts on some of our favorite smartwatches.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">r2FBm43e4suTnh3KnjtbjR</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/L32utu6sJRhWEgUGUmhh8B.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 20:58:44 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/L32utu6sJRhWEgUGUmhh8B.jpeg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Garmin Forerunner 165 and 965 sitting atop one another on a plant.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Garmin Forerunner 165 and 965 sitting atop one another on a plant.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google's Android 16 release schedule shakeup is all about helping its competitors ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Google is in an interesting position. It's the developer of Android, but it's also the hardware manufacturer of a growing Android phone brand. In years past, being the developer of Android has given it an edge in making hardware and software for Google Pixel phones.</p><p>However, with Android 16, Google is shaking things up. The company is completely changing the Android development and release schedule in a way that'll benefit Google's partner OEMs — and by extension, Pixel competitors.</p><p>Google is such a large tech conglomerate that it naturally has a few competing interests. However, with the release of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16-developer-preview-1-is-here-with-new-features-and-a-snappier-release-timeline">Android 16 Developer Preview 1</a> this week, the company has rightfully and decisively put the Android platform above the Pixel brand. To compete with the iPhone, Google needs all of its Android partner OEMs at their best, shipping thorough and timely version updates each year.</p>

<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="xiQzkBM5cbAGgGccwEM6CB" name="iphone-16-pro-max-30.jpg" alt="Apple iPhone 16 Pro Max next to Pixel 9 Pro XL" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xiQzkBM5cbAGgGccwEM6CB.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>That's something that even the best Android phone manufacturers have struggled with of late. Samsung can't seem to ship its Android 15-based One UI 7 update quickly, as it was delayed until next year. Smaller brands have horrible reputations for delivering fast and reliable Android updates, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/android-14-is-finally-coming-to-the-motorola-razr-and-razr-plus-and-it-only-took-a-year">like Motorola</a>, which brought <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review">Android 14</a> to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2023-how-it-started-how-its-going">Motorola Razr Plus 2023</a> a full year after it was released.</p><p>OnePlus is one of the few companies with a presence in North America, not named Google, that managed to roll out Android 15 to the OnePlus 12 and OnePlus Pad 2 in a timely manner.</p><p>Google appears to have recognized this issue with Android, and it's actively correcting it. Android 16 is set for release in the second quarter of 2025, and it'll reach platform stability in March. That's months ahead of schedule, and the extra time will give partner OEMs — like Samsung, OnePlus, Motorola, and others — the time they need to deliver Android version updates alongside the release of their <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best phones</a>.</p>
<h2 id="what-s-changing-about-the-android-yearly-release-schedule-2">What's changing about the Android yearly release schedule</h2>
<p>The first developer preview for Android 16 is here early, and that's not by accident. Google says that the move is "the start of Android having more frequent API releases as part of our effort to drive faster innovation in apps and devices" in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2024/11/first-developer-preview-android16.html" target="_blank">blog post</a> announcing the launch. What exactly does that look like? For one, there will now be two SDK releases each year, with the major one arriving in Q2 2025.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1357px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:21.00%;"><img id="rHUVhYifwwHNUKQpmEHXUj" name="Android-Release-Timeline" alt="The new release timeline for Android." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rHUVhYifwwHNUKQpmEHXUj.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1357" height="285" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The major SDK release will be the Android version update we're used to, which is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16">Android 16</a> in 2025. However, instead of reaching a final release in the third quarter, it'll come an entire quarter early. This is the update that'll include significant Android behavior changes, APIs, and new features.</p><p>Google says it's pushing the release up a quarter "to better align with the schedule of device launches across our ecosystem, so more devices can get the major release of Android sooner."</p><p>There's more — the company will now issue a <em>second</em> SDK release in the final quarter of 2025. This will be a "minor" SDK release, according to Google, that's bigger an a quarterly feature drop but smaller than an annual version update. The minor SDK release in Q4 2025 will come with new APIs and features but won't bring behavior changes.</p><p>This is intended to "ensure continuous quality" for the Android platform while not adding an extra burden for developers. That final SDK release will have feature updates, optimizations, bug fixes, and new developer APIs but won't include the behavioral changes that could cause compatibility issues for apps. "The Q2 major release [Android 16] will be the only release in 2025 to include planned behavior changes that could affect apps," Google emphasizes.</p><p>There are still quarterly Android updates, too. They'll now come in Q1 and Q3, splitting up the major and minor SDK releases with features only. Put them all together, and Google's changes to Android releases extend far beyond just shipping Android 16 a few months earlier. These are strategic changes that'll help the platform overall but will <em>really</em> help partner OEMs.</p>
<h2 id="the-shifted-schedule-will-make-new-android-phones-better-2">The shifted schedule will make new Android phones better</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="pvCDAx8DLCz47TvnBWuBfP" name="pixel-9-9-pro-xl-4.jpg" alt="Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro XL next to Vivo X100 Ultra and Pixel 8 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pvCDAx8DLCz47TvnBWuBfP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Right now, buying an Android phone is tricky, and the timing of software releases is the reason why. For example, Samsung launched the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Galaxy Z Fold 6</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-6-review">Z Flip 6</a> in July, and the former is the most expensive phone it sells. However, it shipped with Android 14, it's still running Android 14, and it'll <em>keep</em> running Android 14 until at least the new year, when <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/delayed-one-ui-7-update-has-me-worried">Samsung is expected to release One UI 7</a>.</p><p>That's a problem. The best Android phones should be running the best Android version, but that's rarely the case. Even Google's own <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9">Pixel 9 series</a> launched without a new version Android for the first time ever.</p><p>Hopefully, it will soon be a problem of the past. By releasing developer previews, beta releases, and final versions of Android updates sooner, partner OEMs will get plenty of time to tune up their Android skins before device releases. "We're actively working with our device partners to bring the Q2 release [Android 16] to as many devices as possible," Google says.</p><p>Could that mean more devices, not just Pixel, launch with fresh Android updates? Or, might it mean that Android releases become less about being synced up with hardware releases and more about getting installed on as many devices as possible?</p><p>Those are questions we're still waiting for answers to. However, it's hard not to get excited about the future of Android. Google's announcements this week reaffirm a few key things. It's committed to working with partner OEMs to help them update their phones to the latest Android version as soon as possible. It's also going to keep the flow of Android updates continuous with security drops, quarterly updates, and a second major SDK release.</p><p>I'm hoping that Android's leaders — Samsung, Google, and others — use these changes to deliver consistent, high-quality, and rapid Android version releases, dispelling the notion that the platform isn't as reliable as Apple's.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-new-android-16-release-schedule-and-why-it-matters</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ It'll be easier for Android's partner OEMs to ship timely updates and line up releases with new products.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">TNYL9VsmpVnrkc3XZUos2B</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MSK4MbWwUCFo87qBSFcWfa.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 20:44:41 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MSK4MbWwUCFo87qBSFcWfa.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Pixel 8 Pro next to 2024 phones]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Pixel 8 Pro next to 2024 phones]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Messages could have a native backup tool in its future on Android ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google is reportedly working on a native backup/restore tool for its Messages app that leans on its cloud serves and your account.</li><li>Details from its code suggests users can choose to enable the backup/sync feature, sign in, and safely store their contents in case of a new device.</li><li>A backup/restore tool is something Meta's WhatsApp has had for a while; however, users can use that in tandem with Google Drive.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>A recent wave of discoveries points toward Google's development of a critical tool to save your texts when switching to a new device.</p><p>Initially discovered by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/11/19/google-messages-backup-restore/">9to5Google</a>, the company is reportedly creating the necessary systems behind a backup and restoration tool for the Messages app. This was noticed in v20241118_02_RC00 of the app's beta; however, AssembleDebug (<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/google-messages-backup-restore-feature-how-works-3501363/">Android Authority</a>) was able to get a more detailed look at Google's progress.</p><p>The tipster was able to produce the introductory splash screen that will likely greet users once this rolls out. Google description states "backup is better with Messages. Restore your conversations, media, and more anytime in app."</p><p>Once it arrives (if all goes well), it seems users can find a new "Backup & Sync" option within the app's settings. Tapping this will throw you to a page consisting of a backup toggle, what account the sync is tied to, and more. If you're signed in and the feature is toggled on, Messages will begin backing up your app contents to its cloud servers.</p><p>Moreover, Google informs users that their contents are E2EE (end-to-end encrypted).</p><p>If a user has switched devices, Google's early in-app description states signing in will download and restore your conversations "automatically."</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:269px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:223.05%;"><img id="Wprp8dz8GuhjMa6krqLDHM" name="google-messages-backup-settings-option-spotted" alt="Google Messages is seemingly developing a native backup/restoration tool." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Wprp8dz8GuhjMa6krqLDHM.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="269" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:268px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:223.88%;"><img id="7g84ES3LfPgxMqeCMin3GR" name="google-messages-backup-settings-options-discovered" alt="Google Messages will reportedly let users toggle its backup feature on or off alongside additional account/sync options." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7g84ES3LfPgxMqeCMin3GR.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="268" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Of course, the choice to use this feature, should it debut, is up to the user. More importantly, both publications highlight the potential option for users to delete and re-do their Google Messages backup. The folks at 9to5 state that turning off the backup/sync option <em>after </em>backing up texts will see them "permanently deleted from your Google Account."</p><p>Most of the feature seems proper and ready for debut, but there's no indication as to when we might see this.</p><p>A backup/restore option for the Messages app is yet another way Google is playing catch-up. Meta's WhatsApp notably features <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-backup-and-move-your-whatsapp-messages-and-media">a backup and restore tool</a> that users can leverage to save their precious conversations. It's one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-messaging-apps">best messaging apps</a> out there and this convenient feature only strengthens that. WhatsApp also lets users utilize Google Drive to safely store their content. Those on iOS are restricted to Apple's iCloud for such restoration services.</p><p>While users await native backup support, Google rolled out <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-messages-now-has-smarter-detection-to-tackle-tricky-scam-messages">stronger spam detection capabilities</a> for the app. The company states its app now piggybacks off its AI software to better fight off potential spam messages. Elsewhere, some users in the U.S. noticed Google's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-messages-dual-sim-rcs-support-us-rollout">dual SIM support</a> arriving for Messages.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://shop-links.co/link?id=pcmcat1563302848653&publisher_slug=future&exclusive=1&u1=ac-us-8320517100837906307&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Ftop-deals%2Fcell-phone-deals%2Fpcmcat1563302848653.c%3Fid%3Dpcmcat1563302848653&article_name=Google%20Messages%20is%20preparing%20to%20handle%20dual%20SIM%20for%20RCS%20%7C%20Android%20Central&article_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.androidcentral.com%2Fapps-software%2Fgoogle-messages-support-for-dual-sim-rcs" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1943169/565706/9383?subId1=ac-us-1021522894658110806&sharedId=ac-us&u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fcp%2Fcell-phones%2F1105910%3Fpovid%3Dweb_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://shop-links.co/link?publisher_slug=future&exclusive=1&u1=ac-us-5529311218434419633&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.samsung.com%2Fus%2Fshop%2Fall-deals%2Fcell-phone-deals%2F&article_name=Google%20Messages%20is%20preparing%20to%20handle%20dual%20SIM%20for%20RCS%20%7C%20Android%20Central&article_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.androidcentral.com%2Fapps-software%2Fgoogle-messages-support-for-dual-sim-rcs" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://target.georiot.com/Proxy.ashx?tsid=169923&GR_URL=https%3A%2F%2Famazon.com%2Fs%3Fk%3Dcell%2Bphone%26crid%3D19CKV7OMEPEMF%26sprefix%3Dcell%2Bphone%252Caps%252C222%26ref%3Dnb_sb_noss_1%26tag%3Dhawk-future-20%26ascsubtag%3Dac-us-3335110674762739320-20" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-100048248-15733793?sid=ac-us-1414899968902852761&url=https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-100048248-15735111?sid=ac-us-5959603424644066160&url=https://www.att.com/" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-messages-native-backup-sync-tool-spotted</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google is tipped to have a backup/restore function in development for Messages. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">D8M8nkBHxoWA4zs64RGGhE</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qEBpNmWm4DdEDy7sbyynw4.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 19:53:33 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qEBpNmWm4DdEDy7sbyynw4.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Messages left-panel menu]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Messages left-panel menu]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>