<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 13:32:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ OPPO's answer to the Galaxy S25 is launching globally on November 21 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>OPPO is launching the Find X8 globally at a launch event in Bali on November 21.</li><li>The phones will launch alongside the global debut of Android 15-based ColorOS 15.</li><li>The devices are powered by MediaTek's Dimensity 9400 and come with massive batteries.</li><li>Both phones are launching in the U.K. and India in addition to other countries.</li></ul>
<p>After a two-year hiatus, OPPO is launching its flagships globally. The Find X8 and X8 Pro are making their global debut at a launch event in Bali, Indonesia on November 21, and the occasion marks the global availability of ColorOS 15, the brand&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a>-based interface.</p><p>Both the Find X8 and X8 Pro have a new design, and in a sizeable switch, they&apos;re using MediaTek&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/mediateks-dimensity-9400-is-the-biggest-challenger-to-qualcomm-yet">Dimensity 9400</a> in lieu of Qualcomm&apos;s silicon. They have a flatter design that&apos;s a broader trend — the Pixel 9 Pro XL and iPhone 16 Pro Max look similar — and what I like is that they have significantly bigger batteries without any noticeable increase in size or weight.</p><p>The Find X8 has a 5630mAh battery, and the X8 Pro has a massive 5910mAh battery, with both devices using <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/most-android-flagships-are-getting-an-exciting-battery-upgrade-in-2025">silicon-carbon tech</a> to provide better density and longevity. There isn&apos;t much new with the cameras, but the global Find X8 Pro launch means the dual 50MP zoom lenses that debuted on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oppo-find-x7-ultra-review">Find X7 Ultra</a> are finally available outside China, and that&apos;s a big deal.</p><p>Both phones run ColorOS 15 out of the box, and it is based on Android 15. The interface should be similar to what we got on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/oneplus-releases-android-15-based-oxygenos-15-heres-when-your-phone-will-get-the-update">OxygenOS 15</a>, but there might be a few extras. </p><p>The phones are going to be available in the U.K. and India, two countries where the brand has a sizeable presence. I just got started with the devices, and I&apos;ll have more to share in this area next week.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oppos-answer-to-the-galaxy-s25-is-launching-globally-on-november-21</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ OPPO is launching the Find X8 and X8 Pro globally on November 21, with both devices touting considerable upgrades.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">C8gPtLSCt7sXLZjaJG7PHe</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/73yMdYyMsT9vqgfUfLFYFY.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 09:03:30 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/73yMdYyMsT9vqgfUfLFYFY.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Evan Blass]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Oppo Find X8 leaked render]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Oppo Find X8 leaked render]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Pixel Weather app introduces immersive vibration feature ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google's Pixel Weather app exclusive for Pixel phones is getting a handy new feature.</li><li>It now has immersive vibrations feature that syncs with current weather conditions and plays audio effects as well.</li><li>Basically, it vibrates your Pixel phone accoriding to weather, and the feature should reach all Pixel phones in the coming days or weeks.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Pixel Weather app is gaining a handy feature that vibrates the phone according to the weather conditions.</p><p>The latest Pixel Weather app already offers great weather animations on Pixel phones. According to Mishaal Rahman (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/pixel-weather-immersive-weather-vibrations-rollout-3497477/">Android Authority</a>), the app will now have an immersive weather vibrations feature that syncs with the animations and weather conditions and plays relevant audio effects.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="uQZn2NjRtxPg32vHHfNd5W" name="google-pixel-9-pixel-weather-app-ai-summary.jpg" alt="Exploring the new Pixel Weather app on a Google Pixel 9 Pro XL including AI summary and the new widget view" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uQZn2NjRtxPg32vHHfNd5W.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The feature is live on the Pixel Weather app and on Pixel phones with the app bearing <strong>1.0.20240910.678970266.release</strong> version and is noted to be a server-side update.</p><p>If you are a Pixel phone user, including the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-fold-review">Pixel 9 Pro Fold</a>, head over to your avatar on the Pixel weather app and check for the “Immersive weather vibrations” option right under the AI weather report setting (as seen in the shared screenshot).</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:270px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:222.22%;"><img id="VkrwMeXFH9xEpRRjtD7E2Z" name="pixel-weather-immersive-weather-animations" alt="Pixel Weather Immersive Weather Animations feature" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VkrwMeXFH9xEpRRjtD7E2Z.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="270" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:270px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:222.22%;"><img id="9KRZwxc6gfrh3haqG3CH2Z" name="pixel-weather-immersive-weather-animations" alt="Pixel Weather Immersive Weather Animations feature" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9KRZwxc6gfrh3haqG3CH2Z.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="270" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Users can enable or turn the feature off as they prefer. The publication further notes that the new vibrations include various weather patterns comprising drizzle, heavy rain, snow, scatter showers, and thunderstorms, amongst other similar features. Alongside those animations, users can experience their phone vibrating according to these weather conditions, providing an immersive experience.</p><p>It is still unclear whether enabling this feature will affect the battery or be negligible. Since it is a gradual rollout, all Pixel phone users might have to wait a couple of more days to use the feature and check their battery life. We've already seen it go live on some of our phones, and the effect is quite nice, particularly in rainy Seattle, which causes the phone to produce a subtle haptic feedback that mimics the rain falling on the screen.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uAjy6bdd2zk" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>Although the Pixel Weather app was launched as a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-series-hands-on">Pixel 9 series</a> exclusive, it later was rolled out to older Google phones, from Pixel 6 and above. It offers a new UI, widgets, customization features, and an all-new AI-based weather summary alongside a bunch of other useful features.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-pixel-weather-app-gains-immersive-weather-vibrations</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google recently rolled out the Pixel Weather app for older Pixel phones after announcing it for the Pixel 9 series. The app is now getting a nifty new feature. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">NWy69Lq4msgEAfwV6dvK55</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dspAcxjMLyPU3aUAne7MWW.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 03:49:19 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dspAcxjMLyPU3aUAne7MWW.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Exploring the new Pixel Weather app on a Google Pixel 9 Pro XL including AI summary and the new widget view]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Exploring the new Pixel Weather app on a Google Pixel 9 Pro XL including AI summary and the new widget view]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ When will Android 16 debut? One rumor predicts the exact day we could see it on phones ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google effectively confirmed that we can expect Android 16 ahead of schedule in an October 2024 post on the Android Developers Blog.</li><li>Now, a report claims to reveal the exact date that Android 16 will reach AOSP.</li><li>The rumored timeline for Android 16's initial rollout is two to three months earlier than expected, per the report.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google shook things up this year by releasing the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9">Pixel 9 series</a> without the latest version of Android. Of course, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a> is now here, but the rollout was anything but typical. Vivo was the first smartphone brand to release a public operating system based on Android 15, using the version of the OS that's part of the Android Open Source Project (AOSP). So, it's worth wondering: when will we see <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16">Android 16</a>?</p><p>According to a report from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidheadlines.com/exclusive-android-16-release-date" target="_blank">Android Headlines</a>, the next major Android update could hit <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">our favorite phones</a> earlier than ever. The site believes Android 16 will be pushed to the AOSP beginning June 3, 2025. Additionally, the report claims that the OTA update for Android 16 will reach Pixel phones on the exact same day. If this timeline proves to be accurate, it would be months ahead of the pace of Android 15's rollout.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1067px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="GajYiPqudXUA7MKZ3VBJY4" name="Android 16 new Modes feature" alt="New Modes feature on upcoming Android 16" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GajYiPqudXUA7MKZ3VBJY4.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1067" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="caption-text">New Modes feature on upcoming Android 16. </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google broke tradition by launching a new series of phones without a new version of Android, but this rumored rollout schedule would eliminate that problem. The company could launch a new set of Pixel devices in August <strong>and</strong> have those devices run the latest version of Android. By launching Android 16 in June, it would be more than ready for primetime when the Pixel 10 series is expected to debut in August.</p><p>The quicker pace of Android 16's rollout benefits other Android OEMs, not just Google. Think of Samsung, a company that launched the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-6-review">Galaxy Z Flip 6</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Z Fold 6</a> with Android 14 and won't be updating them to Android 15 until next year. If Google delivers Android 16 to AOSP earlier in the summer, it could be ready for Samsung's July releases or the fall, at the very least.</p><p>The company explained as much at the end of last month in a post on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2024/10/android-sdk-release-update.html" target="_blank">Android Developers Blog</a>. "Going forward, Android will have more frequent SDK releases with two releases planned in 2025 with new developer APIs," Google said. "These releases will help to drive faster innovation in apps and devices, with higher stability and polish for users and developers."</p><p>Slow adoption of new OS versions by partner OEMs, like Motorola and Samsung, is a significant problem facing the Android platform in 2024. By sending future versions of Android to the AOSP sooner, Google hopes to solve it.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16-release-date-rumor-aosp-pixel</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Android 16 is confirmed to be arriving earlier than usual next year, and the exact date of its release could already be known. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Y8d7EmxYbZf8UvpJ65im5W</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Y7xScf8egVLFexC5MV6DU5.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 03:36:30 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Y7xScf8egVLFexC5MV6DU5.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9 vs. OnePlus 12]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9 vs. OnePlus 12]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The COROS PACE Pro is the new mid-range running watch to beat ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Sunday Runday</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="rV2GgqHS9nqccNipGMkWqB" name="lloyd-break-dancing.jpg" caption="" alt="Lloyd, the Android Central mascot, break-dancing" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rV2GgqHS9nqccNipGMkWqB.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">In this <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/sunday-runday">weekly column</a>, Android Central Wearables Editor Michael Hicks talks about the world of wearables, apps, and fitness tech related to running and health, in his quest to get faster and more fit.</p></div></div>
<p>The COROS PACE Pro's standout feature is its new AMOLED display, but it also added a new satellite chipset, redesigned GPS antenna, and an "improved watch body design for more accurate HR" than past COROS watches. I decided to put these GPS and HR enhancements to the test against a high-end Garmin watch and a Polar H10 chest strap.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/coros-announces-pace-pro-first-amoled-running-watch">COROS PACE Pro</a> has other upgrades over the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/coros-pace-3-review">PACE 3</a>, such as a faster CPU, bigger buttons, better maps, and significantly longer battery life. However, the accuracy upgrades matter more to me: In my <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-forerunner-165-accuracy-vs-two-best-cheap-fitness-trackers">cheap fitness watch accuracy test</a>, the PACE 3 lost to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-forerunner-165-review">Garmin Forerunner 165</a> significantly for GPS accuracy and slightly for HR accuracy.</p><p>I gave the budget PACE 3 a pass, but the PACE Pro competes directly against more mainline running watches like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-forerunner-265-review">Garmin Forerunner 265</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/suunto-race-review">Suunto Race</a>, and Polar Vantage M3 — with AMOLED displays and other niche perks COROS lacks — so there is less room for error.</p><p>Thankfully, the COROS PACE Pro (mostly) lived up to the challenge, holding its own against the much more expensive Garmin Fenix 8.</p>

<h2 id="coros-pace-pro-accuracy-test-summary-2">COROS PACE Pro accuracy test summary</h2>
<p>Since I'm reviewing the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-fenix-8-has-underwhelmed-me-despite-how-great-it-is">Garmin Fenix 8</a> and COROS PACE Pro simultaneously, I completed several long runs wearing both in low-signal areas, track runs at near-max heart rates in specific lanes, and tree-occluded hikes with plenty of elevation changes.</p><p>For GPS accuracy, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-garmin-smartwatch">Garmin watches</a> with multi-band GPS have traditionally done excellently, winning my <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/coros-vertix-2s-vs-garmin-forerunner-965-vs-polar-vantage-v3-fitness-test">Coros vs. Garmin vs. Polar fitness test</a>. The Garmin Fenix 8 is predictably accurate, but I haven't found it <em>more</em> accurate than the $450 Forerunner 265 or $350 Forerunner 255. So, the high-priced Fenix 8 is a fair GPS baseline for the $350 PACE Pro to match.</p>

<p>For HR accuracy, I typically use my <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/coros-heart-rate-monitor-review">COROS HRM</a> as an optical baseline, but since it pairs automatically to COROS watches on the same account, I used my Polar H10 chest strap paired to my Fenix 8 to test the PACE Pro. I have fewer points of HR comparison than GPS because I paired the COROS HRM to the PACE Pro for a few runs to prepare for my Fenix 8 review.</p>

<p>I'll go more in-depth in both areas below, but if you're in a hurry, here are my main impressions: I see a definite improvement in GPS accuracy, bringing it functionally in range of Garmin so that no one will mind the gap. For HR accuracy, I <em>don't</em> see a significant difference, and I'd probably buy the COROS HRM if I needed the best possible HR precision.</p>
<h2 id="coros-pace-pro-gps-accuracy-2">COROS PACE Pro GPS accuracy</h2>
<p>For standard runs on city streets, the COROS PACE Pro (mostly) did very well. In the gallery below, you'll see how the PACE Pro (<em>blue</em>) does better than the Fenix 8 (<em>orange</em>) at matching my path on sidewalks or bike lanes during a long 12-mile run — but has a few moments later on where COROS has me running through lawns while Garmin has my correct sidewalk position.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 7</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="U4Ne8LxE2TASLyKUYcjNWR" name="COROS_PACE-Pro-GPS-accuracy-test-city-1" alt="A Google Earth satellite image showing GPS lines for the COROS PACE Pro (blue) and Garmin Fenix 8 (orange) to test their dual-band GPS accuracy." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/U4Ne8LxE2TASLyKUYcjNWR.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 7</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="eTFPN7aTFhxoG2GGxQ6QdR" name="COROS_PACE-Pro-GPS-accuracy-test-city-3" alt="A Google Earth satellite image showing GPS lines for the COROS PACE Pro (blue) and Garmin Fenix 8 (orange) to test their dual-band GPS accuracy." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/eTFPN7aTFhxoG2GGxQ6QdR.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 7</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="XrRwbLFCkVHCJJkfnkmybR" name="COROS_PACE-Pro-GPS-accuracy-test-city-2" alt="A Google Earth satellite image showing GPS lines for the COROS PACE Pro (blue) and Garmin Fenix 8 (orange) to test their dual-band GPS accuracy." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XrRwbLFCkVHCJJkfnkmybR.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 4 of 7</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="32tmyJbXAo7ePYuJSEuUVR" name="COROS_PACE-Pro-GPS-accuracy-test-city-7" alt="A Google Earth satellite image showing GPS lines for the COROS PACE Pro (blue) and Garmin Fenix 8 (orange) to test their dual-band GPS accuracy." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/32tmyJbXAo7ePYuJSEuUVR.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 5 of 7</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="StUWgTTTZ4qSbTDiFHUJbR" name="COROS_PACE-Pro-GPS-accuracy-test-city-4" alt="A Google Earth satellite image showing GPS lines for the COROS PACE Pro (blue) and Garmin Fenix 8 (orange) to test their dual-band GPS accuracy." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/StUWgTTTZ4qSbTDiFHUJbR.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 6 of 7</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="szHE7eLqwSzSup8XJphKXR" name="COROS_PACE-Pro-GPS-accuracy-test-city-5" alt="A Google Earth satellite image showing GPS lines for the COROS PACE Pro (blue) and Garmin Fenix 8 (orange) to test their dual-band GPS accuracy." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/szHE7eLqwSzSup8XJphKXR.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 7 of 7</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="yhMwoSFryESZrWPzZppGYR" name="COROS_PACE-Pro-GPS-accuracy-test-city-8" alt="A Google Earth satellite image showing GPS lines for the COROS PACE Pro (blue) and Garmin Fenix 8 (orange) to test their dual-band GPS accuracy." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yhMwoSFryESZrWPzZppGYR.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>In one instance, you can see how both watches captured me running into a little park to take a photo of a cool John Muir statue before backtracking a bit. COROS has me wandering into the street on the way out, while Garmin has more trouble on the return trip. In other words, neither is perfect, but both do excellently at finding me in tree cover and never lose me for long.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="4bipV8pHadSafeZcVryNdR" name="COROS_PACE-Pro-GPS-accuracy-test-city-6" alt="A Google Earth satellite image showing GPS lines for the COROS PACE Pro (blue) and Garmin Fenix 8 (orange) to test their dual-band GPS accuracy." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4bipV8pHadSafeZcVryNdR.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>During a second city run, COROS (now the orange line) loses more visibly to Garmin, consistently showing me slightly misaligned from my actual trail or sidewalk position. It didn't have any real impact on my tracked distance, however, with no wobbling location or lost signal like you typically see with poorer connections.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="B28E2N9sGUj5jPeLEBeYw7" name="COROS_PACE-Pro-GPS-accuracy-test-second-city-run-1" alt="A Google Earth satellite image showing a runner's location data, comparing the COROS PACE Pro (orange) and Garmin Fenix 8 (blue) for multi-band GPS accuracy." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/B28E2N9sGUj5jPeLEBeYw7.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="E6pTQam7zbpY9MQVxqUos7" name="COROS_PACE-Pro-GPS-accuracy-test-second-city-run-2" alt="A Google Earth satellite image showing a runner's location data, comparing the COROS PACE Pro (orange) and Garmin Fenix 8 (blue) for multi-band GPS accuracy." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/E6pTQam7zbpY9MQVxqUos7.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="WykoY9RyRcQQqUrvcnzdu7" name="COROS_PACE-Pro-GPS-accuracy-test-second-city-run-3" alt="A Google Earth satellite image showing a runner's location data, comparing the COROS PACE Pro (orange) and Garmin Fenix 8 (blue) for multi-band GPS accuracy." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WykoY9RyRcQQqUrvcnzdu7.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Hikes can be the most challenging for tracking: tree cover and nearby hills can block or redirect signals, and any wrong lines can mess with your elevation tracking. Thankfully, both watches did well during an 8.5-mile hike. In the gallery below, you can see how COROS (<em>blue</em>) and Garmin (<em>orange</em>) overlap one another in uncovered areas and stay parallel and on-path in occluded areas. Their overall altitude gain was only 4m apart, too.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 6</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="JXeyjjnwbYxgDSrp9RyEDj" name="COROS_PACE-Pro-GPS-accuracy-test-hike-3" alt="A Google Earth satellite image showing how the COROS PACE Pro (blue line) compares to the Garmin Fenix 8 (orange line) for a dual-band GPS accuracy test." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JXeyjjnwbYxgDSrp9RyEDj.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 6</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="LtuFsmH6juqP8g4WgFiMzi" name="COROS_PACE-Pro-GPS-accuracy-test-hike-4" alt="A Google Earth satellite image showing how the COROS PACE Pro (blue line) compares to the Garmin Fenix 8 (orange line) for a dual-band GPS accuracy test." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LtuFsmH6juqP8g4WgFiMzi.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 6</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="hzC9cnhouhdi2sawnMiP9j" name="COROS_PACE-Pro-GPS-accuracy-test-hike-2" alt="A Google Earth satellite image showing how the COROS PACE Pro (blue line) compares to the Garmin Fenix 8 (orange line) for a dual-band GPS accuracy test." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hzC9cnhouhdi2sawnMiP9j.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 4 of 6</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="Bmg3PFW8vETRHbFqMi5E2j" name="COROS_PACE-Pro-GPS-accuracy-test-hike-1" alt="A Google Earth satellite image showing how the COROS PACE Pro (blue line) compares to the Garmin Fenix 8 (orange line) for a dual-band GPS accuracy test." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Bmg3PFW8vETRHbFqMi5E2j.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 5 of 6</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="8o7w8vNrL6hC7UVEd7yz2j" name="COROS_PACE-Pro-GPS-accuracy-test-hike-6" alt="A Google Earth satellite image showing how the COROS PACE Pro (blue line) compares to the Garmin Fenix 8 (orange line) for a dual-band GPS accuracy test." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8o7w8vNrL6hC7UVEd7yz2j.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 6 of 6</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="D8zRNvGkK2zdQUbikhoK4j" name="COROS_PACE-Pro-GPS-accuracy-test-hike-5" alt="A Google Earth satellite image showing how the COROS PACE Pro (blue line) compares to the Garmin Fenix 8 (orange line) for a dual-band GPS accuracy test." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/D8zRNvGkK2zdQUbikhoK4j.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Overall, it's clear that COROS' redesigned antenna and new GPS chipset paid off. COROS' GPS accuracy on past watches has been good but not the best. With these tests, COROS has done exceptionally well or has done well enough to stay in lockstep even when the results aren't quite perfect.</p>
<h2 id="coros-pace-pro-hr-accuracy-2">COROS PACE Pro HR accuracy</h2>
<p>The latest COROS watches have five LEDs and four photodiodes, meant to capture a wide swath of your wrist for reliable HR data. In this case, COROS said the PACE Pro would have improved accuracy thanks to a redesigned body, but the results themselves look fairly comparable to past COROS watches.</p><p>I used my Polar H10 chest strap for comparison. Even though I've had <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/why-im-done-with-heart-rate-monitor-chest-straps">issues with its accuracy in the past</a>, I'm hoping it provided a reliable baseline.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1848px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.28%;"><img id="cJ6D3awAnFT4LNfC4iwXHL" name="COROS-PACE-Pro-heart-rate-chart-jog" alt="A heart rate chart showing how the COROS PACE Pro and Polar H10 chest strap compare for heart rate accuracy." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/cJ6D3awAnFT4LNfC4iwXHL.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1848" height="1040" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The first chart above shows a straightforward 3-mile run. The COROS PACE Pro stays fairly close to the Polar H10 — which is connected to my Garmin Fenix 8, hence the label — but if you look closely, you can see how the COROS' optical monitor lags slightly behind Polar's electrocardiogram, not catching every minor change and showing slightly lower. That's normal for an optical vs. ECG comparison; so far, so standard.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1848px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.28%;"><img id="F2RdegVwD9mQiwtqsa7mNL" name="COROS-PACE-Pro-heart-rate-chart-hike" alt="A heart rate chart showing how the COROS PACE Pro and Polar H10 chest strap compare for heart rate accuracy." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/F2RdegVwD9mQiwtqsa7mNL.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1848" height="1040" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>For my long hike, there are long stretches where the COROS watch and Polar strap are in near lockstep with one another. Then you have moments where COROS measures a heart rate about 10–20 bpm above what the chest strap measures. I've had issues with my chest strap losing my signal in the past, dipping my HR to unlikely lows, so I'm uncertain if this is the fault of COROS or Polar here. The overall HR average was only one bpm off across a 2.5-hour activity, so I tentatively chalk this up as a solid entry for COROS.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1848px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.28%;"><img id="qpX25rqqnEVPzSNkvMDrGL" name="COROS-PACE-Pro-heart-rate-chart-track-workout" alt="A heart rate chart showing how the COROS PACE Pro and Polar H10 chest strap compare for heart rate accuracy." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qpX25rqqnEVPzSNkvMDrGL.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1848" height="1040" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The track workout is, predictably, where the problems arise. The COROS PACE Pro struggles to capture quick changes in heart rate, falling anywhere from 1 bpm to 8 bpm short at all times.</p><p>This is a pretty common weak point for most watches — a lack of responsiveness when running in a high-aerobic or anaerobic HR zone — but I hoped COROS would improve in this area. Instead, you get a 2 bpm gap in average for a relatively short activity.</p><p>That's why, as I said above, I'd probably recommend buying the COROS armband to pair with this if you need the best possible results. For everyday runners who aren't doing that many sprint activities or just need to know generally what heart rate zone you're in, the PACE Pro gets my stamp of approval for being generally reliable for heart rate.</p><p>And to be fair to COROS, other watches I've tested during track runs do significantly <em>worse</em> for anaerobic accuracy, even if it isn't the best I've seen.</p>
<h2 id="the-coros-pace-pro-deserves-your-attention-2">The COROS PACE Pro deserves your attention</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="vqwZivMmeevB2rtwRDyfkM" name="Coros-pace-pro-garmin-fenix-8-training-load" alt="The Garmin Fenix 8 and COROS PACE Pro sitting side by side, showing post-run training load totals." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vqwZivMmeevB2rtwRDyfkM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>When it comes to picking a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-running-watches">running watch</a>, every brand has its strengths and weaknesses. The COROS PACE Pro won't change your mind if you already dislike COROS because the software is largely unchanged. It's a <em>hardware</em> upgrade meant to catch up to the pack in some areas and improve its lead in others.</p><p>The AMOLED facelift aligns with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fitness-watches-mip-to-amoled-transition-long-overdue">industry-wide abandonment of MIP</a>, making it long overdue. The accuracy boost is also an important one, targeting the kinds of runners (like me) that don't take a watch's workout results on blind faith; we <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/sf-half-marathon-distance-controversy-shows-need-for-accurate-gps-watch">notice when the results are wrong</a>, and so COROS is taking GPS and HR accuracy seriously.</p><p>On the software front, COROS has the essentials: a target weekly <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-training-load-focus-needs-one-obvious-fix">training load</a> based on your current fitness level, a monthly distribution of easy/medium/hard effort, a running fitness test to determine your lactate threshold, and downloadable training plans.</p><p>It still has weak spots, but COROS updates all of its watches with new features so long as the CPU can support them; since the PACE Pro has a new CPU and extra RAM, it should receive support for years to come. Though for now, the absence of music streaming apps or contactless payments may be deal-breakers for some runners.</p><p>While I still need another week or two to fully test the PACE Pro for its review, I'm feeling very enthusiastic about its upgrades. It's pricier than the PACE 3 but still on the cheap side compared to other running watches. Frugal "pros" should seriously consider it.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="c2f1f3de-b6d7-4d25-820a-b4d49544dba7">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dXddejbHgnziEVGQrkgdum.jpg' alt="The COROS Pace Pro"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">COROS PACE Pro</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Giving Garmin a run for its money</strong></em></p><p>If you're looking for a great fitness watch, the COROS PACE Pro is a great fit for someone not looking to spend too much on a Garmin watch. It has great fitness tracking capabilities while being more affordable than much of the competition.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/coros-pace-pro-gps-and-hr-accuracy-test</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ I tested the COROS PACE Pro's HR and GPS accuracy against the most powerful Garmin watch; turns out it's one of the best running watches out there. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">tarxzgDL93WHvhRLTtRCjF</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4kfo8hup7wMYNnVuC2YsZM.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 16:00:10 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4kfo8hup7wMYNnVuC2YsZM.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Garmin Fenix 8 and COROS PACE Pro sitting side by side, showing a post-run heart rate summary and chart.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Garmin Fenix 8 and COROS PACE Pro sitting side by side, showing a post-run heart rate summary and chart.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung Galaxy S25 vs. Google Pixel 9: How will they compare? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[         <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="a9559e9b-c827-4b7f-9baf-152dfd633918">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JyBHooJcxaVXhoASHXQEuc.jpg' alt="Leaked render of the Galaxy S25"><span class='featured__label versus__label'>samsung galaxy s25</span></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S25</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Could be the best one yet </strong></em></p><p>While we don’t have official details about the Samsung Galaxy S25 yet, which won’t arrive until early 2025, it’s logical to assume that it will be a step up in more ways than one compared to the already stellar Galaxy S24. Whether you should upgrade from that phone or not depends on the details. But the Galaxy S25 will most certainly be the best Galaxy phone to date when it arrives.</p><p> </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>More powerful chipset (rumored)</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Larger screen than Galaxy S24 (rumored)</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Comes with an S Pen (rumored)</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Likely tons of AI integration</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Not available until 2025</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Likely more expensive</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Potential for shorter battery life and slower charging</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="d429180c-8bd2-41c2-bc1a-6d9c60ab1692">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CRjLfoDu9MyH4Mc9xa3uCj.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 official render front and back - Wintergreen"><span class='featured__label versus__label'>Google Pixel 9</span></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>A Pixel best </strong></em></p><p>As far as Google Pixel phones go, you get a ton of bang for your buck with the Google Pixel 9, which is the entry option in the line that’s almost identical to its higher end Pro and Pro XL sisters. As far as phones you can get right now go, the Google Pixel 9 is among the best, and offers the best value.</p><p> </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Affordable</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Great battery life</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Tons of AI integration</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Front camera is only 10.5MP</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No telephoto camera</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Might not be as powerful</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<p>We can’t see the future. As much as we’d like to say that the Samsung Galaxy S25 <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25"></a>is a fantastic phone the bests anything the company and others have launched to date in the Android space, we don’t know this for sure just yet. The phone isn’t actually launching until the first half of 2025. If launch follows suit with the last two generations, it should he announced before the end of January. With that said, that’s only a few months away.</p><p>Knowing the Samsung Galaxy S25 will be the newest entry-level model in the line, likely accompanied by Plus and Ultra variants, that means it will go head-to-head with the Google Pixel 9, that brand’s newest entry-level model as well. So, we thought we’d take a speculative look with this Samsung Galaxy S25 vs. Google Pixel 9 comparison, based on the unconfirmed rumors so far about the Samsung Galaxy S25. Seeing how these two phones <em>could </em>compare may help you start prepping for a decision.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-s25-vs-google-pixel-9-looks-and-basics-2">Samsung Galaxy S25 vs. Google Pixel 9: Looks and basics</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1412px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="j694D5wu5mdb9MzUKqC72V" name="samsung-galaxy-s25-angled-look-early-alleged-rendering.jpeg" alt="An angled, rumored rendering of the Galaxy S25." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/j694D5wu5mdb9MzUKqC72V.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1412" height="794" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>We haven’t yet seen the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25">Samsung Galaxy S25</a>, but there have been <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-leaked-renders-reveal-flat-design">leaked renders</a> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-leaked-renders-reveal-flat-design"></a>that suggest the phone will increase in size from the 6.2 inches of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-plus-review">Samsung Galaxy S24</a> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-plus-review"></a>to about 6.36 inches, which is more akin to the size of the new Apple iPhone 16 Pro, while also being lighter.</p><p>It seems all three variants of the phone will also employ a similar shape with rounded edges, flat sides, and a flat front. The expectation is that the phone will have the same armor aluminum frame (titanium option for the Ultra variant) with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/corning-gorilla-glass-victus-2">Gorilla Glass Victus 2</a>. It’s also expected that there will be a built-in S Pen, though the leaked render images don’t show one.</p><p>The Galaxy S25 will likely come with the same M13 OLED display. Brightness may still hover around 2,600 nits. Based on the leaked renders, the camera set-up may be similar to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Galaxy Z Fold 6</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review"></a>which resembles a traditional DSLR camera lens with ribbed edges and thick borders.</p><p>Regarding other specs, these have not been confirmed, but assuming this phone would at least match the Samsung Galaxy S24, we can say at the very least that the display will be FHD+ with 120Hz refresh (or better), and storage options may include 128GB and 256GB. Since the Galaxy S24 has an IP68 rating, it’s safe to assume the Galaxy S25 will have at least that as well.</p><p>When it comes to the battery, it should be at minimum 4,000mAh with support for both wired and wireless charging. Some leaks, however, indicate that the battery could be as large as 5,000mAh. One area that we hope is improved upon is wireless charging speeds: the Galaxy S24 still taps out at 15W and considering so many other phones support much faster wireless charging, it’s time Samsung caught up in this department.</p><p>As for finishes, sources claim these may include Moon Night Blue, Silver Shadow, Sparkling Blue, and Sparkling Green for the standard Galaxy S25 variant.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="WFcrajSuHh2pA2Mx3EkwtN" name="Google-Pixel-9-review-20.jpg" alt="The Pixel 9 display" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WFcrajSuHh2pA2Mx3EkwtN.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>How does this compare to the look and feel of the Google Pixel 9? Already available now, it comes in Obsidian, Porcelain, Wintergreen, and Peony. It has a 6.3-inch screen which, if rumors are correct, would make it about the same size as the Samsung Galaxy S25. Its Actua display boasts 2,424 x 1,080 resolution with a refresh rate from 60-120Hz and 2,700 nits peak brightness.</p><p>With rounded corners and square design that Derrek Lee says in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-review">his review of the Pixel 9</a> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-review"></a>that the polished back with a satin metal frame is “surprisingly comfortable to hold.” The screen is made of Corning Gorilla Glass Victus 2 and it boasts an IP68 water and dust resistant rating with a fingerprint-resistant coating.</p><p>It comes with 128GB or 256GB storage and a large 4,700mAh battery that’s a big step-up from the Samsung Galaxy S24 and could be the same if Samsung doesn’t improve on this with the Galaxy S25. There’s also an Extreme Battery Saver mode that can extend battery life to up to four days. The Google Pixel 9 supports both fast and wireless charging as well, along with Battery Share for using it to refuel other devices like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/earbuds/google-pixel-buds-pro-2-review">Google Pixel Buds Pro 2</a>. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/earbuds/google-pixel-buds-pro-2-review"></a>Lee is impressed with the battery life, saying the phone easily lasts through an entire day with up to eight hours of screen time. But he does find the 27W charging to be “almost unbearably slow.”</p><p>A huge advantage with the Google Pixel 9, and all recent Pixel devices, is that Google promises <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-pixel-9-software-updates">seven years of OS and security updates</a>. Samsung offers the same for the Galaxy S24, and it’s safe to assume this will extend to the Galaxy S25 as well.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-s25-vs-google-pixel-9-the-specs-2">Samsung Galaxy S25 vs. Google Pixel 9: The specs</h2>
<p>Let’s look at the specs of these two phones in a side-by-side comparison. Keep in mind that these specs for the Samsung Galaxy S25 are not yet confirmed.</p>

<p>There’s a lot yet we don’t know when it comes down to the nitty-gritty of the Samsung Galaxy S25. But based on the leaks, renders, rumors, and the specs of the current generation Samsung S24, this is our best guess as to how the comparison might look.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-s25-vs-google-pixel-9-features-functions-and-performance-2">Samsung Galaxy S25 vs. Google Pixel 9: Features, functions, and performance</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1413px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.26%;"><img id="34pEszLi7EfbpK34zsgNUQ" name="samsung-galaxy-s25-early-alleged-rendering.jpeg" alt="An alleged look at a rendering of the vanilla Galaxy S25." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/34pEszLi7EfbpK34zsgNUQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1413" height="795" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Now, let’s get down to what’s truly important: processing power and features. The Samsung Galaxy S25 was initially thought to be powered by the "Snapdragon 8 Gen 4" chipset. And while that's technically true, some of the latest rumors suggest it might actually come with a Snapdragon 8 Elite chipset (essentially a rebranded chip), marking an even bigger jump in performance thanks to the Oryon cores. That said, other rumors suggest Samsung <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-models-to-opt-for-flagship-exynos-soc-again">may stick with its in-house Exynos chip</a>s.</p><p>One thing to note if it does use the Snapdragon is that it could mean the Galaxy S25 requires a bigger battery to be able to accommodate all this power. Even if a bigger battery is part of the equation, the end result could be shorter overall battery life, slower charging to accommodate the enhanced power and processing, or a wash in terms of battery life between the S24 and S25. But again, this is all speculation. Plus, some rumors indicate that there could be a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsungs-next-flagship-phones-might-get-a-battery-boosting-ai-feature">new AI battery feature</a> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsungs-next-flagship-phones-might-get-a-battery-boosting-ai-feature"></a>that works to conserve up to 10% of the battery life through each day.</p><p>We do know that the Samsung Galaxy S25 will launch with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-review">Android 15</a>, the latest version of the operating system, and this will be paired with Samsung’s own <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/one-ui-7-beta-could-be-just-around-the-corner-with-an-apple-intelligence-like-twist">One UI 7.</a> It appears that this version of the Samsung UI may be one of the biggest upgrades yet with a new visual style, additional customization options, new icons, and more. Some report that there will be new aminations as well, akin to OnePlus’ parallel processing in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/i-used-oxygenos-15-for-a-week-these-are-my-favorite-features">OxygenOS 15</a>.</p><p>Of course, it goes without saying that the Samsung Galaxy S25 will come with all the same AI features you get with the Samsung Galaxy S24 through <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-galaxy-ai">Galaxy AI</a>. The belief is that these features will be further enhanced in this new phone, including <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/huge-one-ui-7-samsung-parent-ai-features-leak">more parental control features</a>. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/huge-one-ui-7-samsung-parent-ai-features-leak"></a>This is something parents of tweens and teens who monitor their phones will appreciate.</p><p>Keep in mind that this OS update should be available for Samsung Galaxy S24 owners as well, and a beta is reportedly going to launch before the end of 2024. Once it does, those who gain access will effectively be getting a preview into what the experience will be like with the Samsung Galaxy S25.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="dHVLUYzGncvcn5sxANM3G7" name="google-pixel-9-fitbit-app-today-view.jpg" alt="Today View in Fitbit app on Pixel 9" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dHVLUYzGncvcn5sxANM3G7.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2500" height="1406" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>With the Google Pixel 9, it comes out of the box with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review">Android 14</a>, but of course it’s updateable to Android 15, and far beyond. It’s powered by the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-tensor-g4">Google Tensor G4</a> processor and has 12GB RAM, making it a powerful phone that can handle multi-tasking, video streaming, gaming, and more. Lee says it performs well when opening and juggling apps, and he never noticed the phone getting warm when playing especially intense mobile games.</p><p>It, too, has plenty of AI features through <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Google Gemini</a> that range from advanced Google Assistant to photo editing, message composition, and more. It comes with plenty of security features like Google VPN and end-to-end encryption along with safety features like satellite SOS, emergency SOS, car crash detection, and more.</p><p>How these two phones compare when it comes to operability will really come down to two main things: does the Samsung Galaxy S25 have more powerful processing, and how much does this impact battery life? In the end, however, both devices will likely count among the most powerful phones you can buy.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-s25-vs-google-pixel-9-how-good-are-the-cameras-2">Samsung Galaxy S25 vs. Google Pixel 9: How good are the cameras?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4001px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:66.78%;"><img id="yLhXfijjR842Rp9mMWegd6" name="Google-Pixel-9-review-09.jpg" alt="The Pixel 9 camera app" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yLhXfijjR842Rp9mMWegd6.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4001" height="2672" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The camera experience is crucial for most phone users. These are the memories you capture daily that you’ll likely keep for a lifetime, not to mention share with the world through social media.</p><p>There are rumors that there will be some big changes to the cameras in the Samsung Galaxy S25. Notably, the belief is that Samsung will shift entirely to using Sony sensors. Samsung hasn’t historically made sweeping changes to its cameras since the Galaxy S22 jumped from a 12MP main sensor to a whopping 50MP. And we expect that the Samsung Galaxy S25 won’t be too far off from the Galaxy S24.</p><p>The Samsung Galaxy S24, as a refresher, has a 50MP main camera, 12MP ultrawide camera, 10MP telephoto camera, and 12MP selfie camera. We’re guessing the Samsung Galaxy S25 won’t be too far off from these numbers. However, some rumors do indicate the possibility of a massive jump with a 50MP ultrawide camera and a new telephoto lens that has variable capabilities, either relating to zoom or aperture.</p><p>The Galaxy AI features will extend to the camera experience as well with all the same cool photo and video capturing and editing features crossing over to this phone as well. In terms of any new features that will be added to the experience, we’ll have to wait and learn about those later.</p><p>Google likely has nothing to worry about, whatever the case may be, as the cameras in the Google Pixel 9 are pretty darned good. Lee says the images are “detailed and crisp” with a “great deal of dynamic range, even in low lighting conditions.” The Pixel 9 has a 50MP main camera as well with a wide sensor that affords up to 8x Super Res Zoom. Its ultra-wide camera is an impressive 48MP with macro focus but the front “selfie” camera is a measly 10.5MP. Lee does miss the third rear telephoto camera, which the Samsung Galaxy S24 has and the Galaxy S25 may continue with as well.</p><p>A similar set of photo editing features using AI are found in this phone as well, like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-use-magic-editor-on-the-pixel-8">Magic Editor</a>, Magic Eraser, Best Take (a fan favorite that lets you choose the best expressions of each person from multiple version of the same group photo to create the “best” one), Photo Unblur, and more. There’s even a cool <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-audio-magic-eraser">Audio Magic Eraser</a> feature for editing and enhancing videos.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-s25-vs-google-pixel-9-which-should-you-buy-2">Samsung Galaxy S25 vs. Google Pixel 9: Which should you buy?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="B92RTdf3ovHDMjCEdRgTUZ" name="Google-Pixel-9-review-18.jpg" alt="The Pixel 9 on a plant" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/B92RTdf3ovHDMjCEdRgTUZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>For a “right now” decision, consider the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-vs-samsung-galaxy-s24">Google Pixel 9 vs. Samsung Galaxy S24</a><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-vs-samsung-galaxy-s24"></a> comparison since the Samsung Galaxy S25 isn’t coming until early 2025, likely by the end of January. If you are willing to wait, then it’s time to weigh the decision based on what you know so far.</p><p>Looking at the Google Pixel 9 and Samsung Galaxy 24, those two devices are pretty close in almost every respect. The Pixel 9 has more RAM and a slightly higher resolution screen than the Samsung Galaxy S24, while the Samsung Galaxy S24’s ultra-wide camera is much lower resolution. If Samsung rectifies all three of these downsides in the Galaxy S25, it would be an even closer race.</p><p>Considering how close we are to the Samsung Galaxy S25 launch, it’s a good decision to wait if you’re looking to upgrade from a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s23-review">Samsung Galaxy S23</a><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s23-review"></a> or earlier phone and trying to decide if you should stick with that camp or opt for a Pixel phone instead. Once you’re armed with all the confirmed specs and details, you can make the most educated decision.</p><p>With that said, if you’re desperate to upgrade and need something now, maybe even want to take advantage of Black Friday and holiday deals, the Google Pixel 9 is and will continue to be one of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">the best Android phones</a> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones"></a>you can buy for some time. The Samsung Galaxy S24 makes that list as well, and the Samsung Galaxy S25 will probably eventually take its place. It all comes down to whether you can bite your nails and wait just a little bit longer to get it.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="b62b84c2-e7e9-4d84-a60e-00869a634a7d">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JyBHooJcxaVXhoASHXQEuc.jpg' alt="Leaked render of the Galaxy S25"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S25</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>It’s coming soon! </strong></em></p><p>The Samsung Galaxy S25 isn’t here yet, but based on rumors and leaks, it will be the most powerful Galaxy phone yet, potentially among the most powerful Android phones, period. You might find it worth the wait, but expect to pay a lot more for it, too. It really all depends on how big an upgrade it is over the Samsung Galaxy S24, which is already comparable to the Google Pixel 9.</p><p> </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="2b66547b-589d-410c-bcf2-c337fb06e928">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CRjLfoDu9MyH4Mc9xa3uCj.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 official render front and back - Wintergreen"><span class='featured__label horizontal__label'>Google Pixel 9</span></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Still a great option </strong></em></p><p>The Google Pixel 9 is still a great option. If you want something more comparable to what the Samsung Galaxy S25 could be, consider upgrading to the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-review">Google Pixel 9 Pro or Pro XL</a><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-review"></a> instead, which could be more similarly priced anyway. But don’t discount this phone, as it’s a powerful piece of technology, too, that already rivals the current generation Samsung Galaxy S24.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-vs-google-pixel-9</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Galaxy S25 is launching next year, but how will it compare to the Pixel 9? ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">zKGRj33TTAVHk9By4Xaej5</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GSTZrT4GF3toZ8EVFwdWhh.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ christinep2424@gmail.com (Christine Persaud) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GSTZrT4GF3toZ8EVFwdWhh.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Headlines]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Another alleged angled rendering of the Galaxy S25.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Another alleged angled rendering of the Galaxy S25.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Android 15 just made 2024's best phone even better ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>OnePlus's transformation is complete after the release of OxygenOS 15 this week. The Android 15-based update for the OnePlus 12 is a shining example of what a company can achieve when it realizes its past mistakes and resolves to fix them.</p><p>Now, OnePlus is one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-oneplus-12-is-now-getting-the-stable-android-15-update">elite few companies</a> that have pushed an Android 15 update out to its phones in less than a month after Google released the OS. Meanwhile, companies like Samsung are saying not to expect its Android 15 beta release for another month, followed by the full release of One UI 7 sometime early in 2025. I would have lost money if I had to wager a bet against which of these two companies would have had its Android 15 update out first.</p><p>As a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12-review">OnePlus 12</a> user, I'm glad OnePlus got its act together and has been able to deliver such a monumental update in such a short amount of time. OnePlus 12<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12r-review"></a> users can expect to see the update appear on their phones this week, while other OnePlus phones should get the update in the coming weeks and months.</p><p>That's one of the many reasons the OnePlus 12 is a phone you need to consider picking up during Black Friday this year. We've already seen great sales on this phone just this week, with the phone on sale for $649. But if you're willing to wait just 3 weeks for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Black Friday OnePlus deals</a>, I think you'll be able to get it for even cheaper.</p><p>I've reviewed well over a dozen phones this year, but the one I keep coming back to is the OnePlus 12. Here's why I think you'll love it, too.</p>

<h2 id="a-refreshing-look-and-feel-2">A refreshing look and feel</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="rLvRdMrhJdAAySkgoVRevX" name="oneplus-12-never-settle-oxygenos-15" alt="Some new lockscreen customization options in OxygenOS 15 on a OnePlus 12" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rLvRdMrhJdAAySkgoVRevX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/i-used-oxygenos-15-for-a-week-these-are-my-favorite-features">OxygenOS 15</a> sports a fresh coat of paint and refined iconography, including a more powerful theme engine that feels closer to OxygenOS's golden days of yore. Not only that, but the company has added in several new features and options that are sure to get some users excited.</p><p>You can now choose to split the notification shade if you want, adding room for more quick toggles in a separate shade from notifications. You can always swipe left or right to move between these panes, so enabling the iOS-style feature is actually more handy than it is on iOS itself.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="uwSYtRtFWLwH6LYYF8SGvX" name="oneplus-12-oxygenos-15-split-notification-quick-toggles" alt="The new split quick toggle option in OxygenOS 15 on a OnePlus 12" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uwSYtRtFWLwH6LYYF8SGvX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Speaking of iOS, OnePlus joins the swath of OEMs that have added a Dynamic Island-style pop-up notification to the punch-hole camera in the display, but it's disabled by default. Right now, it doesn't seem to support many apps so it's probably not worth using outside of a few first-party OnePlus apps.</p><p>The new animations and optional frosted glass UI look are all quite beautiful and should please anyone who appreciates little details throughout the UI.</p><p>All of this ties in so perfectly with the haptics which have always been one of the real stars of the show when using the OnePlus 12. Move your finger along the brightness or volume sliders and each little notch is felt like you're moving a dial. Keyboard taps are punchy and deep. Unlocking with the one's excellent fingerprint sensor feels like pressing a button. It's all incredible, and it makes me love using this phone over others.</p>
<h2 id="ai-to-the-rescue-2">AI to the rescue</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="RwAuwS2TyzeZC3qt594avX" name="oneplus-12-ai-detail-boost" alt="Using the AI detail boost feature in OxygenOS 15 on a OnePlus 12" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RwAuwS2TyzeZC3qt594avX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>OnePlus phones rarely have the best cameras in the industry, but the OnePlus 12 has surprised me more than once with its unique Hasselblad color tuning engine and the excellent telephoto sensor on the back.</p><p>With that said, I wholeheartedly welcome the new AI features that work to make the camera even better. We already tested OnePlus' AI eraser and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/oneplus-ai-eraser-versus-magic-eraser">found that it was better</a> than Google's Magic Eraser, and now OnePlus is back with three other new tools I'll be using all the time.</p><p>AI Detail Boost can help fill in the gaps to make low-resolution images look crisper and cleaner, or just add some more fine detail to an image that's been zoomed into. This one's nice, but I like AI Unblur even better since it can help clean up some of my favorite blurry photos. Check out this comparison of my son and his friends during Halloween, for example.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="2jN6GSkvNYGFypvu9eR68C" name="oneplus-ai-deblur-example-01" alt="Deblurring a photo using OxygenOS 15's new AI deblur tool on a OnePlus 12" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2jN6GSkvNYGFypvu9eR68C.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>There's also a reflection eraser tool that does exactly what it says on the tin, similar to the tool that shipped with Samsung phones in 2023.</p><p>Lastly, a new global search app uses Google Gemini to locally catalog anything you give it permission to, including photos, messages, contacts, and more. It's not <em>quite</em> as robust as the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-use-the-pixel-screenshots-app-on-the-google-pixel-9">Pixel Screenshots app</a> on a Google Pixel, but it can be helpful for quickly finding photos, videos, or messages on your phone without switching between a bunch of apps.</p><p>OnePlus also upgraded the multitasking to make it more like the brilliant OnePlus Canvas software that debuted on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-open-review">OnePlus Open</a>. Floating windows now support gestures, the smart sidebar can be used like a desktop dock to launch apps, and switching between apps is faster and smoother than on any other phone, thanks to OnePlus's brilliant UI design.</p><p>There are a lot of other little <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/i-used-oxygenos-15-for-a-week-these-are-my-favorite-features">things we've been loving about this update</a> and all of them culminate into an experience that's better than any other phone on the market. I keep coming back to this phone time and time again despite having access to every other Android phone on the market, and I think you will find the same joy if you pick one up for cheap during Black Friday this year.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="82f33f81-fc7e-42e2-ba53-2e01d2e9c075">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yf3PmQ3byJBHbWmMtoDrv8.jpg' alt="OnePlus 12"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">OnePlus 12</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Now even better</strong></em></p><p>The OnePlus 12 may be the most underrated flagship of 2024. It has a great design and a superb camera that rivals other flagships like the Galaxy S24 Ultra and Pixel 9 Pro XL. Now, with OxygenOS 15, it's one of the first to get Android 15, offering plenty of new AI features.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/android-15-just-made-2024s-best-phone-even-better</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The OnePlus 12 is already my favorite phone of 2024 and its Android 15 update makes it better than ever. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">bbzYy4f3DrzCW6mL85Hr8d</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YiTras9m24ousRh2iB9KfK.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YiTras9m24ousRh2iB9KfK.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Android 15 logo on a OnePlus 12 running OxygenOS 15]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Android 15 logo on a OnePlus 12 running OxygenOS 15]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ How will a second Trump presidency affect the tech industry? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>To understand how the tech landscape or anything else would function during a second Donald Trump presidency you first must understand Trump himself. Much ink has been spilled by people with various qualifications about Trump and his flaws, but I think it’s a lot simpler than people make it; Trump is purposefully divisive because he finds humor in the chaos it creates. The man wants to act the way he acts and it’s impossible to tell exactly what he thinks at any point in time. He will say anything to create controversy because he <em>desires</em> controversy. Many people love him for it.</p><p>This trait is also part of his political identity. You may love or loathe the man, but he wants you to manifest those emotions either way. He knows what to say and when to say it for maximum effect, and isn’t shy about it. You don’t know what Trump thinks because that’s not important to him and can change at the drop of a hat. He is the embodiment of the saying that any publicity is good publicity and his time in Hollywood taught him well.</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Android & Chill</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="6okfEqHJFPcbznZSbSNW3n" name="android-n-chill.JPG" caption="" alt="Android Central mascot" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6okfEqHJFPcbznZSbSNW3n.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Future)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">One of the web's longest-running tech columns, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/android-and-chill">Android & Chill</a> is your Saturday discussion of Android, Google, and all things tech.</p></div></div>
<p>More importantly, he has learned how to surround himself with sycophants, some of whom <em>can</em> actually bring about change. Regardless of what you may think, the president is not in control of the price of gas or eggs and can’t make any laws. He can only sign laws that Congress has approved. Executive orders can have a limited effect, but the law of the land comes from Congress.</p><p>With Republicans controlling all three branches of government, expect change. Some change you may not like is bound to happen. But this Congress is unpredictable in a way we’ve never seen before because a sizable portion of the elected officials in both the House and Senate will do and say anything to curry favor with Trump and his ardent followers. Trump can say we should ban TikTok on Monday and change his mind on Wednesday. But if Congress bans TikTok on Tuesday to appease Trump, it’s not undone easily. Trump understands that he can act the way he acts, but Congress <em><strong>must</strong></em> be clear on what is best for the country versus what is said for amusement.</p>
<p>A good example would be Trump’s relationship with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/twitter-x-could-start-charging-users-subscription-fees">Elon Musk</a>. Today, the two seem to share some common goals and we should expect both to profit from the relationship in some form or another. Much of this will affect U.S. consumers and give Musk’s ventures more leeway and lax oversight. However, this relationship can change at any time because of Trump’s (and Musk’s, to an extent) unpredictable nature. Next week Musk could be the villain Trump, and by association, those who follow him in Congress, want to punish.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:480px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:55.83%;"><img id="Urn3rqngFkZFEkcxyCF5eP" name="tesla-launch.gif" alt="A Tesla driving away." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Urn3rqngFkZFEkcxyCF5eP.gif" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="480" height="268" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Future)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>You’ve no doubt read about what to expect for tech companies under Trump across the internet from some reputable sources. My inbox is full of pitches, ideas, and interview offerings from experts on the matter as well.</p><p>I say they all may be right. Also, they all may be wrong. There’s just no telling what we should expect in the future because even the “people in charge” don’t know what to think in the future; Trump hasn’t <em>told</em> them what to think yet.</p>
<p>I’m not saying any of this as someone who opposes (or endorses) the idea of a second Trump presidency; to me, the man is no better or worse than any other successful politician. I’m not a Republican, Democrat, or even an Independent. If I have to apply a label to myself, I’m a Defeatist; I think a ruling class has inserted itself into politics in a way that you either submit and enjoy the enrichment that comes along with it or don’t get elected. Ideally, sowing division among the electorate is the goal to keep anyone who disagrees from ever gaining popularity. Ignoring his personal life, Trump is no better or worse than any other successful politician on the national stage, he's just different. Going by the 2024 election results, plenty of people prefer this sort of governing.</p>
<p>Not counting any personal grievances that make their way into American politics, expect a second Trump term to look a lot like any other administration where Republicans control the government: more friendly to companies like Amazon, Apple, and Google, fewer consumer protection laws successfully introduced to Congress, and a short period of economic growth followed by a hard recession. We have the blueprint of how this works, which is readily available.<br><br>As examples, in 2019 DoJ anitrust division head Makan Delrahim <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/12/19/technology/sprint-t-mobile-merger-antitrust-official.html" target="_blank">actively lobbied regulators and lawmakers</a> to ensure the deal between Sprint and T-Mobile was successful. The Trump administration FTC's lone successful antitrust decision against Qualcomm was sullied when the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://fedsoc.org/commentary/fedsoc-blog/the-doj-and-other-federal-agencies-oppose-the-ftc-in-ftc-v-qualcomm#:~:text=At%20that%20time%2C%20the%20DOJ,Department%20of%20Defense%20(DoD)." target="_blank">DoJ intervened against the FTC</a>, filing a motion that defended Qualcomm. Delrahim recused himself from this case as he was the outside counsel for Qualcomm prior to his position with the DoJ.<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://futureplc.slack.com/archives/C05GZMFJ160/p1731092471289349"></a></p>
<a href="https://awards.concurrences.com/IMG/pdf/us_antitrust_enforcement_in_trump.pdf?73916/5a2a97ddc9b410ba386ec8d19088665f10b3a18dfbda4f269bccea1ef2d50a3e"><figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:538px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:74.91%;"><img id="NjbrUB2x7poUMKBQzYf83R" name="DoJ-under-Trump" alt="Chart detailing criminal fines and penalties from 2011 to 2020" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NjbrUB2x7poUMKBQzYf83R.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="538" height="403" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: U.S. DoJ via Concurrences.com)</span></figcaption></figure></a>
<p>I would not be surprised to see Google prevail in its current <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/why-its-good-that-companies-like-google-face-antitrust-cases">antitrust cases</a> under a new FTC, Amazon dodges any similar charges, and Meta continues its lawful-evil ways without any oversight. The executives of these companies may decree a Trump presidency as a travesty, but money doesn’t lie and plenty of it will continue to change hands with all levels of the administration, just as it would had Harris defeated Trump.</p><p>Expect Biden’s Executive Order <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/ftc-fight-against-ai-scammers-why-it-matters">governing AI</a>, which Trump has pledged to repeal, to disappear. With noticeable support from many of the companies covered under this order, there should be little outcry from the tech sector. Congress will also resist creating any new AI regulation.</p>
<p>On the question of tariffs, under the law, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://constitution.congress.gov/browse/article-1/section-8/"><u>only Congress has the authority to implement them</u></a>. That didn’t stop Trump from imposing tariffs on Chinese goods or Biden expanding them and economists claim there are loopholes that could be used to apply new tariffs on foreign goods.</p><p>Don’t blindly believe that we’ll be paying hundreds more for tech products because the companies that make them have plenty of influence on lawmakers. Nobody will pay $1,400 for the base model <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25">Galaxy S</a> so that simply won’t be the price. Any tariffs and their effects will be mitigated <em>somehow</em>. Let’s hope the solution doesn’t wreak havoc down the road.</p><p>While societal norms and individual rights are going to change, I predict the tech landscape to go mostly the same way it always has, both in the U.S. and abroad, favoring the wealthy donor class over the consumer.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-will-a-second-trump-presidency-affect-the-tech-industry</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ With a second Trump presidency, we should expect some things to change while others stay the same. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">jG7pnkLaihxTQhxNGZpwm7</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/y3svnJjFtZUz59875noaPo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/y3svnJjFtZUz59875noaPo.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Donald-trump]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Donald-trump]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ News Weekly: The Pixel hits new heights, Android 15 on the OnePlus 12, Galaxy S25 Slim rumors, and more ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">News Weekly</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="h7AVxNX2TSFH3rYKHd2Vw" name="lloyd-news-weekly.jpg" caption="" alt="News Weekly Logo" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/h7AVxNX2TSFH3rYKHd2Vw.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text"><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/news-weekly">News Weekly</a> is our column where we highlight and summarize some of the week's top stories so you can catch up on the latest tech news.</p></div></div>
<p>This is Android Central's News Weekly, your go-to source for a concise roundup of the week's most significant tech stories. This is where we delve into the top headlines that provide the latest developments and innovations contributing to the digital landscape.</p><p>This week, we find out just how popular the Pixel 9 is, the OnePlus 12 gets OxygenOS 15 based on Android 15, Samsung is rumored to have a Galaxy S25 Slim in the works, Google rolls out the November 2024 update to Pixels, and Amazon is having some issues with its Colorsoft Kindle.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="google-has-a-hit-on-its-hands-2">Google has a hit on its hands</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="RncLB3ktV7LrgvsbN9x5AK" name="google-pixel-9-pro-pixel-9-pro-xl-camera-1.jpg" alt="Camera app on Google Pixel 9 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RncLB3ktV7LrgvsbN9x5AK.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Read more </strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-google-pixel-9-is-a-hit-pixels-earn-double-digit-market-share-for-the-first-time"><strong>here</strong></a>.</p><p>The Pixel series may not be as popular as Samsung's Galaxy lineup, but Google has seen more success with its smartphones in recent years, and the latest numbers show how popular the phones have become. According to a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.counterpointresearch.com/insight/post-insight-us-smartphone-sellin-down-4-yoy-in-q3-as-demand-remains-muted/">report from Counterpoint Research</a>, Google's smartphone shipments grew 20% in Q3 2024, which can be attributed to the much earlier launch of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-review">Pixel 9</a> series.</p><p>A second report from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://gs.statcounter.com/vendor-market-share/mobile/united-states-of-america/#monthly-202310-202410">Statcounter</a> shows just how drastic Pixel growth has been, with a graph revealing a jump from about 5% to a whopping 14% share between September and October. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-review">Pixel 9</a> series went on sale at the end of August, when there was a noticeable uptick in share, giving Google a good amount of time to see the Pixel 9 affected Q3 sales figures. It's worth noting that the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8">Pixel 8</a> did not go on sale until Q4 2023.</p>
<p>While Google still has some catching up to do to reach the numbers of Samsung Galaxy phones, it's clear that the company's strategy is working. The Pixel 9 series has have been impressive thanks to great cameras, standout designs, a better chipset, and fun <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/why-on-device-ai-processing-is-important">on-device AI</a> features.</p>

<hr>
<h2 id="breathe-new-life-into-the-oneplus-12-with-oxygenos-15-2">Breathe new life into the OnePlus 12 with OxygenOS 15</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="WphVLPi7gJ5G5XXVvDKuNd" name="oxygenos-15-17.jpg" alt="OnePlus 12 with OxygenOS 15" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WphVLPi7gJ5G5XXVvDKuNd.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Read more </strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-oneplus-12-is-now-getting-the-stable-android-15-update"><strong>here</strong></a>.</p><p>It hasn't been that long since Google rolled out <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-review">Android 15</a> to its Pixel phones. Now, OnePlus is getting in on the action by rolling out OxygenOS 15 to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12-review">OnePlus 12</a>, the company's current global flagship (the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-13">OnePlus 13</a> is still China-only for now). Some Android Central staff have already received the update, which is steadily arriving on global variants of the phone.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://community.oneplus.com/thread/1723669843116294150">update</a> brings a host of visual improvements to the home screen, themes, and animations and should make things more fluid and uniform throughout the UI. The pulldown menu can now be separated by notifications and quick settings, similar to iPhones and some other Android phones. There's also a new Live Alerts feature that mimics Apple's Dynamic Island by showing real-time updates for apps and activities in an expandable pill at the top of the display.</p><p>There are a ton of new updates, but Android Central senior editor Harish Jonnalagadda has highlighted some of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/i-used-oxygenos-15-for-a-week-these-are-my-favorite-features">his favorite OxygenOS 15 features</a>.</p>

<hr>
<h2 id="galaxy-on-a-diet-with-an-ultra-appetite-2">Galaxy on a diet, with an "Ultra" appetite</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1412px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="j694D5wu5mdb9MzUKqC72V" name="samsung-galaxy-s25-angled-look-early-alleged-rendering.jpeg" alt="An angled, rumored rendering of the Galaxy S25." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/j694D5wu5mdb9MzUKqC72V.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1412" height="794" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Read more </strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-galaxy-s25-slim-could-pack-a-serious-camera-punch-despite-its-thin-profile"><strong>here</strong></a>.</p><p>Samsung is gearing up to launch the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25">Galaxy S25 series</a> sometime in 2025, but rumors are circulating that the company is preparing a "Galaxy S25 Slim." The device, as hinted by the name, would be a thinner model, but that apparently might not mean that it'll be a watered-down version. A recent leak suggests that despite its thinner profile, the phone may feature an "Ultra" camera.</p><p>While the leak doesn't specify what that means, it's not hard to guess that it could adopt a 200MP camera similar to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review">Galaxy S24 Ultra</a> and previous Ultra models. If true, it'll be interesting to see how this will fit in the phone; will it feature a massively protruding camera sensor? We don't know how "slim" this phone will be, but it may likely be thinner than the current batch of Galaxy S24 models, which come in at 7.6, 7.7, and 8.6mm for the S24, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-plus-review">S24 Plus</a>, and S24 Ultra, respectively.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">That’s a fact and not just a guess https://t.co/AAGlsZVOIW<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1854787657382957146">November 8, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>It's also being said that if the Galaxy S25 Slim does launch, it won't arrive with the rest of the Galaxy S25 series, which is expected in January. That said, it's not clear when Samsung is planning to launch the device if it does end up coming to market.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="pixels-grab-post-android-15-update-2">Pixels grab post-Android 15 update</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="GmKvsVuJfCQVN3E3GTSyy5" name="google-pixel-9-pro-fold-review-5.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold rear camera module" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GmKvsVuJfCQVN3E3GTSyy5.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Read more </strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/googles-pixel-november-update-squashes-the-first-round-of-android-15-bugs"><strong>here</strong></a>.</p><p>October was a big month for Pixel phones with the rollout of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-review">Android 15</a>. November isn't as big, but there's still plenty to look forward to with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/pixelphone/thread/305744117/google-pixel-update-november-2024?hl=en&sjid=11128271663939068219-NC">November 2024 update</a>, which has begun rolling out to Google's smartphones from the Pixel 6 and newer.</p><p>Most of the bug fixes address issues with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9">Pixel 9 series</a>, such as Adaptive brightness not kicking in or problems pertaining to Bluetooth range. There's also a fix for the cameras when zooming in between sensors, which would cause tilting under certain conditions.</p><p>Meanwhile, all eligible Pixel smartphones received performance improvements for UI animations, while the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-review">Pixel 8a</a> received a specific display fix for an issue that would cause flickering.</p><p>The November 2024 update is rolling out with version numbers <strong>AP3A.241105.007</strong> and <strong>.008</strong>, depending on the device, and your phone must be running Android 15 to receive the update.</p>

<hr>
<h2 id="amazon-s-first-color-kindle-runs-into-problems-2">Amazon's first color Kindle runs into problems</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1200px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="6SB7EN5Ns3GmrfsmjwCRR4" name="amazon-kindle-colorsoft-signature-edition-2024-lifestyle-render.jpg" alt="Amazon Kindle Colorsoft Signature Edition" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6SB7EN5Ns3GmrfsmjwCRR4.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1200" height="675" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Amazon)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Read more </strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/amazon-kindle-colorsoft-shipments-suspended-display-problems"><strong>here</strong></a>.</p><p>Amazon made headlines when it launched its first full-color Kindle. However, as exciting as it seems, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/amazon-colorsoft-signature-edition-launch-details">Kindle Colorsoft Signature Edition</a> has already encountered some problems, with owners complaining about a yellow tint at the bottom of the display that bleeds into about an inch of the screen. Not only that, but apparently, the dark mode is not working on the device.</p><p>The problem has led to plenty of low reviews on Amazon, with the device sitting at an average of 2.6 stars. With Amazon well aware of the issue, the company is working on a fix and noting that owners can contact customer service and request a replacement or refund. That said, replacements may take some time to arrive as Amazon works on fixing the screen tint issues, although there's no word on the dark mode issue.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="more-stories-this-week-2">More stories this week</h2>
<p>Those are some of the biggest stories from this week. Meanwhile, here are some other stories that are worth catching up on:</p>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/telegrams-new-update-is-a-visual-treat-for-big-channels">Telegram's new update is a visual treat for big channels</a></li><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/whatsapp-expands-chat-filters-with-new-options">WhatsApp's new customization feature makes managing your chats much easier</a></li><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/google-chromeos-130-chromebook-plus-update-rollout">Google's huge ChromeOS 130 update packs AI features, Focus, and more for laptops</a></li><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-seamless-update-support-rumor">Samsung's Galaxy S25 series might finally adopt Android's seamless updates</a></li><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-emoji-reactions-now-appear-as-they-should-on-iphones">Android emoji reactions now appear as they should on iPhones</a></li><li><a href="">Pixel Screenshots app grabs a few QoL updates and a capture shortcut</a></li><li><a href="">You're not crazy, other Galaxy Watch 7 users report ghost vibrations</a></li><li><a href="">One UI 7 beta could be just around the corner with an Apple Intelligence-like twist</a></li><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-rizr-rollable-phone-updated-fingerprint-patent">Latest Motorola Rizr rollable phone patent highlights new security tricks</a></li><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-fy-q4-2024-earnings">Qualcomm reports $10.2B in FY Q4 revenue thanks to strong headset sales, automotive push</a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/news-weekly-november-9-2024</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Pixel is becoming more popular than ever, the OnePlus 12 gets Android 15, Samsung's Galaxy S25 might get a thinner model, and more. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">U6n6CRX8DGGgyLPTtzGTj6</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3fBjYdhmrr5uPkU5Lt25mb.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ derrek.lee@futurenet.com (Derrek Lee) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3fBjYdhmrr5uPkU5Lt25mb.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Pixel 9 next to a bush]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Pixel 9 next to a bush]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google app is testing an easier way to view your search history and saved items ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The 'Saved' tab is being replaced by an 'Activity' tab that brings everything together in one place, including search history from Chrome and the Google app.</li><li>The update will simplify things by creating a single spot for your search history and saved items, instead of having them scattered across different tabs.</li><li>The change is in a limited test phase, with only a few users getting it so far, and has been in development for the past two months.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google’s working on a new feature to make accessing your search history and saved items easier right from the main app.</p><p>As spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/google-app-activity-tab-3497741/" target="_blank">Android Authority</a>, Google’s main app is getting a big update. The current "Saved" tab will be swapped out for a new "Activity" tab that pulls together all your saved items in one spot. Furthermore, it’ll give you easy access to your search history from both Chrome and the Google app.</p><p>At present, checking your History on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/top-google-chrome-tips-and-tricks">Google Chrome</a> and the Google app can be a hassle, with information spread across different tabs. That said, with this experiment, Google is making that job easier by creating a unified spot to access both your search history and saved items.</p><p>Google is rolling out the new feature as a test, with only a limited number of users getting it so far. According to Android Authority contributor Assemble Debug, it’s been in the works for the past two months.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:229px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:217.90%;"><img id="Zf5W9UaWgC6avhH2yVUKQo" name="Google-app-activity-tab" alt="Google app's new activity tab in testing" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Zf5W9UaWgC6avhH2yVUKQo.png" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="229" height="499" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The new "Activity" tab gives you a seamless, app-based experience instead of a web view. Plus, you’ll be able to easily save, share, or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-to-delete-your-recent-google-search-history-on-android">delete history items</a> right from the app.</p><p>A Telegram user, @andrey4ik21pro1_q, found the new 'Activity' tab on their Pixel 8 Pro with Google app version 15.44.25.29.arm64. However, it seems that the feature wasn’t available on another Pixel 8 Pro running a newer version of the app.</p><p>The feature is expected to roll out more widely in the coming weeks, so users should be able to access it soon.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-app-is-testing-an-easier-way-to-view-your-search-history-and-saved-items</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google’s main search app is getting a handy upgrade. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">5rXVw3e66RZMTrYxzz3NkZ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nWMvZs2495PgsrWCpg8Uib.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 07:03:10 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nWMvZs2495PgsrWCpg8Uib.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google app bottom navigation bar]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google app bottom navigation bar]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ It's not even Black Friday yet and my favorite foldable phone has never been cheaper ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Who said that you <em>needed</em> to wait until Black Friday to enjoy a good deal or two? Best Buy's not making anyone wait that long, as its early Black Friday deal is already underway. And as part of one of the first "Doorbusters," the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-9-pro-fold-5g-256gb-unlocked-obsidian/6587911.p?skuId=6587911"><strong>Pixel 9 Pro Fold has been discounted</strong></a> to its lowest price ever!</p><p>When I wrapped up my review of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-fold-review">Pixel 9 Pro Fold</a>, I just assumed that I would swap my SIM card back to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Galaxy Z Fold 6</a>. Surprisingly, that hasn't been the case, and the 9 Pro Fold remains right by my side every day. And at the very least, I implore you to try out Google's latest foldable phone for yourself, especially considering that it's $300 off.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="b60a30f7-ae50-4808-bbd1-f19deb5a16c8" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google went to great lengths to provide improvements on almost every aspect with the Pixel 9 Pro Fold. While the steep price tag might have left you feeling a bit sour, Best Buy is here to save the day as this is the lowest price we've seen for Google's latest foldable phone." data-dimension48="Google went to great lengths to provide improvements on almost every aspect with the Pixel 9 Pro Fold. While the steep price tag might have left you feeling a bit sour, Best Buy is here to save the day as this is the lowest price we've seen for Google's latest foldable phone." data-dimension25="$1499" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-9-pro-fold-5g-256gb-unlocked-obsidian/6587911.p?skuId=6587911" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="eN3jfcnhHLaPsGfQNGHWdf" name="google-pixel-9-pro-fold-official-render-porcelain-tabletop.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/eN3jfcnhHLaPsGfQNGHWdf.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="500" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>Google went to great lengths to provide improvements on almost every aspect with the Pixel 9 Pro Fold. While the steep price tag might have left you feeling a bit sour, Best Buy is here to save the day as this is the lowest price we've seen for Google's latest foldable phone.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-9-pro-fold-5g-256gb-unlocked-obsidian/6587911.p?skuId=6587911" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="b60a30f7-ae50-4808-bbd1-f19deb5a16c8" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google went to great lengths to provide improvements on almost every aspect with the Pixel 9 Pro Fold. While the steep price tag might have left you feeling a bit sour, Best Buy is here to save the day as this is the lowest price we've seen for Google's latest foldable phone." data-dimension48="Google went to great lengths to provide improvements on almost every aspect with the Pixel 9 Pro Fold. While the steep price tag might have left you feeling a bit sour, Best Buy is here to save the day as this is the lowest price we've seen for Google's latest foldable phone." data-dimension25="$1499">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>If that comes as a surprise to you, you're not the only one. Samsung has a more robust software experience, while also doing a better job with handling aspect ratios. But there's just something about the 9 Pro Fold that keeps me coming back.</p><p>Perhaps it has something to do with the fact that this is basically the phone that I hoped Google would've released as a first iteration. While the original <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-fold-review">Pixel Fold</a> offers a neat design, it's far from refined. However, the 9 Pro Fold solves practically all of my complaints from last year, with a few added benefits.</p><p>I've spoken about this a few times, but as someone who is a first-time father, I've quickly learned that sometimes I need a bit of help to get my son's attention for a picture. The one feature that I keep coming back to is "Made You Look," which not only gets my son's attention but usually makes him smile.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="ig2feRhJcB7YDn6fLWTRMM" name="google-pixel-9-pro-fold-made-you-look.jpg" alt="Made You Look on Pixel 9 Pro Fold" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ig2feRhJcB7YDn6fLWTRMM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2500" height="1406" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It's already come in handy more times than I can count, and with the holiday season rapidly approaching, I suspect this number will grow exponentially. Not to mention that the 9 Pro Fold will also probably act as the "group family picture" camera, as it's easy to prop it up, set a timer, and snap the picture after I jump in.</p><p>But in the event that I'm not actually able to get in the picture, Google has the solution for that. Although I don't use <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-gemini-app-android">Gemini</a> and the various AI features all of the time, I know that they're ready for whenever I am. This includes the "Add Me" feature, so I can snap a picture of the family, then have someone else take one of me, and just add me to the shot.</p><p>The Pixel 9 Pro Fold is not the perfect <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">foldable phone</a>, but I don't even know if such a thing exists. There are trade-offs to be found, no matter what phone you end up deciding on. But one thing I know for sure is that if I didn't already have the 9 Pro Fold, I'd be picking one up.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/pixel-9-pro-fold-early-black-friday-deal</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Are you in the market for a new foldable phone? Run, don't walk, to get the Pixel 9 Pro Fold for its lowest price ever. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">LSqUm4gfdXmoESZbkBNggH</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CSEN8YF9buUQ3gQXgCAdT5.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ andrew.myrick@futurenet.com (Andrew Myrick) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CSEN8YF9buUQ3gQXgCAdT5.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold review hero 21x9 ]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold review hero 21x9 ]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>