<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 08:49:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Review: This Baseus charging station makes me worry less about outlets ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>My workspace is always buzzing with different devices that I constantly plug in and unplug. This gadget jungle leads to a messy tangle of various power adapters. Even though modern devices mostly use <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/everything-you-need-know-about-usb-c">USB-C ports</a>, making charging a bit easier, juggling multiple phones, headphones, laptops, tablets, and accessories is still a bit of a hassle.</p><p>On the other hand, the rise of fast-charging technology for smartphones and other smart devices has brought a wave of versatile accessories. These new products focus on compatibility with various devices, offering solutions beyond just charging phones and tablets. Enter the Baseus PowerCombo GaN3 Pro power strip. This product goes beyond a typical power strip, featuring multiple ports that can charge up to six devices at once.</p>

<h2 id="price-and-availability-2">Price and availability</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="AQvbbgyeiZ9d3JsJ6ef7Kk" name="Baseus-PowerCombo-GaN3-Pro-6.jpg" alt="Baseus PowerCombo GaN3 Pro charging station" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AQvbbgyeiZ9d3JsJ6ef7Kk.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1687" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Jay Bonggolto / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Baseus PowerCombo GaN3 Pro is available from major retailers, with Amazon selling it for around $90. Currently, it only comes in black. While this might not bother everyone, it can stand out against lighter-colored furniture. As I write this review, my eyes keep drifting to the PowerCombo—not because of its sleek design (which it has) but because its matte-black finish contrasts sharply with my warm wood desk.</p>
<h2 id="an-all-around-charger-2">An all-around charger</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="SGqymvey62mPsjR9iheoMf" name="Baseus-PowerCombo-GaN3-Pro-4.jpg" alt="Baseus PowerCombo GaN3 Pro charging station" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SGqymvey62mPsjR9iheoMf.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Jay Bonggolto / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>This 100W charging station leverages GaN technology for powerful performance. Gallium nitride (GaN) makes the design compact and ensures efficient charging. I can charge multiple devices at once. After months of real-world use, I&apos;ve found it pretty reliable despite a few quirks (more on that later). As a result, this charger is now a permanent fixture on my desk.</p><p>The Baseus PowerCombo 100W redefines the traditional power strip, moving beyond the old AC strips hidden behind desks. Unlike bulkier models, the Baseus PowerCombo 100W is compact, measuring only 4.4 x 1.8 x 1.5 inches and weighing a mere 15.7 ounces.</p><p>Gone are the days of bulky chargers hogging precious space in my travel bag. Thanks to GaN technology, the Baseus PowerCombo 100W packs a powerful punch in a remarkably compact design. Its small footprint allows for effortless placement on my desk, or any desk for that matter, but its true potential shines when on the go. This lightweight charger is a serious contender for becoming your travel charging companion, ensuring all your devices stay powered up during trips and adventures.</p><p>The Baseus PowerCombo 100W maintains the brand&apos;s reputation for quality. Its performance, especially with the USB-C ports, is impressive. With two AC outlets, two USB-A ports, and two USB-C ports, the PowerCombo covers a wide range of devices.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="64XFf9NYQnd3qoetXjTLvc" name="Baseus-PowerCombo-GaN3-Pro-3.jpg" alt="Baseus PowerCombo GaN3 Pro charging station" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/64XFf9NYQnd3qoetXjTLvc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1687" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Jay Bonggolto / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<figure><blockquote><p>This lightweight charging station is perfect for keeping your devices charged on the go, making it an ideal travel buddy.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>While the Baseus PowerCombo GaN3 Pro delivers up to 100W of power, it&apos;s important to understand how this works in real-world use. Its impressive output is most noticeable when charging a single device through one of the USB-C ports. However, when multiple devices are connected, the power is smartly distributed to ensure each gadget charges efficiently.</p><p>When you connect two devices, the power splits between the ports. One device will receive 65W, while the other gets 30W. Check out the image below for a full guide on multi-port charging.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:61.87%;"><img id="7TkyomsdzFkWY9Ta8XaCNb" name="Baseus-powercombo-100W-charging-guide.jpg" alt="Baseus Powercombo 100W charging guide" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7TkyomsdzFkWY9Ta8XaCNb.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1267" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Baseus)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>This charger is a breeze to use with its conveniently accessible ports. It effortlessly keeps my devices charged up without any issues. Its minimalist design, featuring a sleek black casing, fits well with most setups. The bright orange ports add a fun touch and make it easier to insert USB cables correctly, solving that all-too-common struggle.</p><p>The Baseus PowerCombo GaN3 Pro smartly manages power across multiple devices, prioritizing faster charging for power-hungry gadgets. It ensures all connected devices get enough power. Although its charging speeds might not quite match those of dedicated wall chargers, the difference is minor, and the convenience of having a single hub for multiple devices is unbeatable.</p><p>It&apos;s worth mentioning that even with GaN technology, the Baseus PowerCombo GaN3 Pro can get slightly warm during extended use, but it never reaches worrying temperatures. Additionally, I&apos;ve noticed brief power interruptions when plugging in multiple USBs at once. According to Baseus, this is due to "overpower protection," a safety feature to prevent overloading. While this can be a minor inconvenience, it underscores the charger&apos;s built-in safeguards.</p>

<h2 id="should-you-buy-it-2">Should you buy it?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="vQcHHzh2paWaC3Rd6WKT3e" name="Baseus-PowerCombo-GaN3-Pro-5.jpg" alt="Baseus PowerCombo GaN3 Pro charging station" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vQcHHzh2paWaC3Rd6WKT3e.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Jay Bonggolto / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Baseus PowerCombo GaN3 Pro is a must-have for anyone managing multiple devices and needing to keep them charged all at once. It eliminates the hassle of finding outlets and keeps your workspace neat and efficient. Its compact design also makes it a reliable travel companion, ensuring all your devices stay charged during both adventures and business trips.</p><p>While the charging station may not provide the full 100W to each device at the same time, its GaN3 technology ensures fast charging that meets most needs. Even when powering multiple devices and a laptop, you&apos;ll notice a significant charging boost for all. Its compact, portable design also creates a more organized and visually appealing workspace. Overall, the Baseus PowerCombo GaN3 Pro offers a practical and user-friendly solution for managing multiple devices efficiently.</p><p>That said, if you need top speeds for all your devices simultaneously, there might be better options from the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-gan-chargers">leading GaN chargers</a> on the market. Also, the small, always-on light could be a minor annoyance for some.</p><p>Despite these minor drawbacks, the convenience and portability of the PowerCombo GaN3 Pro are hard to beat. Its built-in safety features, including overcharge and overheat protection, offer peace of mind. You can connect your devices and let them charge without worry.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="b835c0aa-af50-49ad-af70-0f89e112416d">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/e4ZeubqFgdckyicFMzzStF.jpg' alt='Baseus Powercombo 100W charging station'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Baseus PowerCombo 100W</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="70" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Charge everything, everywhere</strong></em></p>
<p>The Baseus PowerCombo GaN3 Pro levels up multi-device charging with fast, efficient power. It's portable and keeps your workspace a bit tidy. Though it doesn't deliver 100W to all devices simultaneously, it still charges quickly and efficiently.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/baseus-powercombo-100w-gan-charger-review</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Baseus PowerCombo 100W GaN charger is a beast, charging six devices at once, though it has a few limitations. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">LZVHnB8WQBM3DgC324de4P</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/woJVYnzNxESAxiLafMpsWi.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 08:00:38 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/woJVYnzNxESAxiLafMpsWi.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Baseus PowerCombo GaN3 Pro charging station]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Baseus PowerCombo GaN3 Pro charging station]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Samsung Galaxy S25 may be all Snapdragon again — not all Exynos ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A new report claims that Samsung will use Qualcomm for all the Galaxy S25's processors. </li><li>Previously, Samsung used a mix of its own Exynos processors and Qualcomm's Snapdragon chips to power Galaxy phones.</li><li>This would mark the second time that Samsung used Snapdragon processors for its S-series lineup in all regions — the first time was with the Galaxy S23 series last year. </li></ul>
<hr>
<p>We&apos;re still waiting for Samsung to unveil its next-generation lineup of foldables, including the Galaxy Z Flip 6 and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-slim-rumor-mill">Galaxy Z Fold 6</a>. However, leaks surrounding the further-out Galaxy S25 series are already heating up. There are conflicting reports about what kind of processor will power Galaxy S25 phones, but a new one from analyst Ming-Chi Kuo predicts that Samsung will release another series of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">flagships</a> featuring Qualcomm processors in all regions. </p><p>Historically, Samsung has used a mix of Qualcomm Snapdragon chips and its own Exynos platforms, with different regions getting different processors. That changed in 2023 when the Galaxy S23 series shipped with Snapdragon chips everywhere. When the current Galaxy S24 lineup was unveiled this year, Samsung returned to using a mix of Snapdragon and Exynos processors. </p><p>Qualcomm <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-snapdragon-8-gen-3-for-galaxy">explained earlier this year</a> that the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 for Galaxy platform powers the Galaxy S24 Ultra in all markets, but the S24 and S24 Plus use Samsung&apos;s Exynos chips "in select regions." By comparison, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/snapdragon-8-gen-2-launch">Snapdragon 8 Gen 2</a> for Galaxy chipset powered all of Samsung&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s23-review">Galaxy S23</a> phones globally.</p><p>Now, analyst Ming-Chi Kuo says that Qualcomm will "likely" produce all the chips for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25">Samsung Galaxy S25 series</a>. That might not be by choice, though. Kuo adds that Samsung has seen lower-than-expected yield for the upcoming flagship Exynos platform built on the 3nm process. It&apos;s expected to be called the Exynos 2500. Due to the rumored low yield, Kuo predicts Samsung will use the upcoming Snapdragon 8 Gen 4 chipset — likely in a "for Galaxy" version — for every Galaxy S25 device.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Qualcomm will likely be the sole SoC supplier for the Samsung Galaxy S25 (vs. 40% for the S24), as the Exynos 2500 may not ship due to Samsung's lower-than-expected 3nm yield.In addition to the significant increase in supply share, Qualcomm's Snapdragon 8 Gen 4 will see a price…<a href="https://twitter.com/mingchikuo/status/1802737528874955169">June 17, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>This contradicts an earlier, but less credible, rumor surrounding the Galaxy S25 chipset. An X (formerly Twitter) user <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/OreXda/status/1763379083935936999" target="_blank">@OreXda</a> claimed in March 2024 that the entire Galaxy S25 series would be powered by Exynos processors — ditching Qualcomm entirely. This rumor also stated that the Galaxy Z series would use Qualcomm chips and the Galaxy A series would use a mix of MediaTek and Exynos processors.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">So currently 2025 Samsung phones will be :Galaxy Z - Snapdragon OnlyGalaxy S - Exynos OnlyGalaxy A - Mediatek & Exynos<a href="https://twitter.com/OreXda/status/1763379083935936999">March 1, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>It&apos;s possible that there is some degree of truth to both reports. If Samsung had been able to producer better yield for the upcoming Exynos 2500 systems-on-a-chip, perhaps it had a goal of moving to Exynos entirely. This would&apos;ve been a risky move, since the Exynos versions of Samsung phones still typically perform worse than their Snapdragon counterparts. But if the yield for the new platform was lower than expected, as Kuo reports, that would explain why Samsung is shifting gears entirely. </p>
<h2 id="why-samsung-may-have-wanted-to-move-away-from-qualcomm-chips-2">Why Samsung may have wanted to move away from Qualcomm chips</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="7P2ErZCEHSc73umEzHChMN" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-Ultra-back-titanium-04.jpg" alt="The back of the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra in the Titanium Grey colorway" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7P2ErZCEHSc73umEzHChMN.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It&apos;s certainly understandable why Samsung would want to use Exynos processors in all Galaxy S25 phones. In the same report, Kuo says that Qualcomm plans to raise prices for the Snapdragon 8 Gen 4 mobile platform. This aligns with previous reports, but this time, we got an idea of how much. Kuo adds that Qualcomm will charge phone manufacturers 25-30% more for the Snapdragon 8 Gen 4 chip than it charged for the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 chip. That would make these processors priced at nearly $200 alone. </p><p>Kuo says that the price increase has to do with the way the Snapdragon 8 Gen 4 chip is manufactured. It&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/snapdragon-8-gen-4-tsmc-rumor">made using TSMC&apos;s N3E process node</a>, per the report, which is costly. It would be the first Android mobile platform to be created using a 3nm process, which Apple first used in the A17 Pro chip in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/apple-iphone-15-pro-max-long-term-review">iPhone 15 Pro and Pro Max</a>. </p><p>Samsung&apos;s rumored Exynos 2500 processor is also set to use the company&apos;s own 3nm process, but as Kuo reports, it may not ship at all due to low yield. Of course, Samsung would rather make its own chips at a lower cost than Qualcomm is charging for the Snapdragon 8 Gen 4 mobile platform. However, if Samsung&apos;s 3nm process doesn&apos;t have a great yield rate, Samsung can end up spending more time, money, and manufacturing resources on Exynos chips than it would&apos;ve by simply paying Qualcomm. </p><p>It&apos;s still fairly early in the rumor cycle for the Galaxy S25 series, and things can certainly be changed before the phones are officially announced, which isn&apos;t expected to happen until early 2025. But if it&apos;s true that the Exynos 2500 has bad yield rates, it makes sense that Samsung would pivot to going all-in on Snapdragon. After all, it did the same thing just a year ago. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:65.97%;"><img id="ur2UZV7sHPk4tJ8uwtZoDe" name="tsmc.jpg" alt="TSMC" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ur2UZV7sHPk4tJ8uwtZoDe.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1351" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co., Ltd.)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>If anything, this just goes to show how far ahead TSMC really is in the chip manufacturing industry. Samsung has plenty of incentive to make a flagship Exynos chip with Qualcomm raising Snapdragon 8 Gen 4 prices. The higher build-of-materials cost would almost certainly be passed on to customers, which I&apos;m sure buyers won&apos;t be thrilled about. By developing its own chips, Samsung could keep phone prices where they are while increasing profit margins.</p><p>But that only works if Samsung can make Exynos competitive and efficient to produce. It can&apos;t seem to do that if Kuo&apos;s report is accurate. The clear winners here are TSMC and Qualcomm, which appear to be leaving Samsung Foundry, Intel, and everyone else in the dust. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-samsung-galaxy-s25-may-be-all-snapdragon-again-not-all-exynos</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ An unconfirmed rumor from March 2024 suggested that Samsung could go all-Exynos for the Galaxy S25, but a new report says the opposite. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">b2NNApTyWvr6djNRpxduDA</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/H7pxJnSUSSLBy3dNadjs7M.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 06:30:30 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/H7pxJnSUSSLBy3dNadjs7M.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Amber Yellow Samsung Galaxy S24 colorway and its vibrant display]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Amber Yellow Samsung Galaxy S24 colorway and its vibrant display]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung News picks up a much needed update in the US ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung announced on Wednesday (June 20) that it will be expanding its News App<br>
to include more comprehensive political and sports news coverage.</li><li>The app will showcase a dedicated tab for the upcoming 2024 presidential U.S. elections and the popular soccer league La Liga.</li><li>The update has rolled out to all Galaxy users in the U.S.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>It&apos;s almost election season in the U.S., and Samsung doesn&apos;t want you playing catch up, hunting down news channels to keep up with the happenings of the day. This is why it <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://news.samsung.com/us/samsung-news-product-updates-for-galaxy-owners-news-sports-more/">announced</a> on Wednesday (June 20) that it will be expanding its News App to include in-depth coverage of major upcoming events, including the 2024 United States Presidential Election, with a new update to the app. </p><p>The company <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-news-launch">launched</a> the Samsung News app a year ago—a revamped version of the existing Samsung Free application that helps Galaxy users explore news globally from trusted sources like Bloomberg Media, CNN, and Fox News. The app offers daily news briefings, a customized news feed based on the user&apos;s interests, and podcasts from news/entertainment channels within the app.</p><p>In the past year, "Samsung News has become a daily touchpoint for millions of people looking for easy-to-access updates from their favorite local and national news outlets," said Avner Ronen, VP of product development for Samsung.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1200px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="nM7LyJKbnL2YmWvD7EnrKC" name="samsung-news-galaxy-mobile.jpg" alt="Samsung News App Update" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nM7LyJKbnL2YmWvD7EnrKC.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1200" height="675" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Samsung)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>With this new update, targeted towards people in the U.S., Samsung News will sport a dedicated tab within the app that will be a "comprehensive hub for the Presidential election coverage." This tab will host an updated calendar of key dates such as debates, party conventions, other upcoming events, candidate profiles, and updated presidential polls. </p><p>Additionally, Samsung is taking it further and collaborating with La Liga before its 94th season kick-off. As their new content partner, Samsung aims to showcase up-to-date information on everything soccer and trending news stories of the user&apos;s favorite teams and players. </p><p>"This partnership will serve as a new tool to not only promote the league and its clubs but also expand our reach in North America through a timely and effective channel,” said Alan Nissim, head of business operations for La Liga North America.</p><p>Samsung has partnered with other news sources, such as Yahoo Sports, ESPN, CNBC, and Good Morning America.</p><p>It looks like Samsung is trying to keep up with users as more people continue to reach for their mobile devices to access the news of the day, more so on the go. The news update is now available to all Galaxy users in the U.S. However, it remains unclear when the said update will roll out to other markets across the board. </p><p>Android Central contacted Samsung for more details, but it did not get back to us in time for publication. We will update this article once we have more information.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-news-update-presidential-election-sports</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung rolled out a new update for its news app that will now showcase all the political happenings in the country ahead of the elections, along with something fun for hardcore soccer enthusiasts. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">PiyZy42MS5vA4uyjvEbeuR</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/j4ZjX8wuwEKqReV3xYbxDc.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 01:26:20 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nandika.iyerravi@futurenet.com (Nandika Ravi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/j4ZjX8wuwEKqReV3xYbxDc.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Samsung]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[New Samsung News app]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[New Samsung News app]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google's June System updates bring better data transfers and device security ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google detailed several patches for June regarding its Play Systems for Android users, which brings security and privacy fixes alongside Play Protect improvements.</li><li>Google also rolled out "auto-lock" for lost or stolen devices alongside the ability for users to use a USB cable and WiFi for data restoration and backup.</li><li>Pixel phones received a June security patch earlier this month, which packed loads of fixes for several user-reported issues.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google is starting to roll out another wave of Play Service updates for Android users that encompass a range of issues.</p><p>The company detailed its recent set of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/product-documentation/answer/14343500">patch notes</a> on its Systems page (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/06/20/june-2024-google-system-updates/#more-623645">9to5Google</a>). Google is starting to roll out version <strong>24.24 </strong>of its Play Services, which brings a new set of goodies for app developers. The notes state that there are several "new features" rolling in for Google and other developers creating apps that could piggyback off Wallet.</p><p>Those users should find new support for Digital Wallets & Payment-related processes within their apps. Google is also patching a few security and privacy issues for users on PC, mobile, and smart TVs.</p><p>Version 41.5 of the Google Play Store aims to provide "improved protection" from Play Protect when users install apps.</p><p>Several more system updates for June are as follows:</p>
<ul><li>With this new security feature, you’ll be able to set a lost or stolen device to auto-lock once it loses connectivity (Phones).</li><li>With this new feature, you can now use your USB and Wi-Fi at the same time to backup and restore your device during setup (Phones).</li><li>New developer features for Google and third party app developers to support Maps related processes in their apps (App Developers).</li><li>New developer features for Google and third party app developers to support Account Management related processes in their apps (App Developers).</li></ul>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4032px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="rqNR9WF3NtKSHhQjGZgYqM" name="OnePlus-9-Google-Play-Store-logo-16x9-hero.JPG" alt="Google Play Store on OnePlus 9" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rqNR9WF3NtKSHhQjGZgYqM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4032" height="2268" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Chris Wedel/Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>For "Device Health," Google rolled out a patch that included optimizations for Android&apos;s "Adaptive Battery" feature. Additional bug fixes for device disconnections have arrived in June, as well.</p><p>Google&apos;s listed addition of "auto-lock" for a lost or stolen device seemingly refers to "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-io-2024-android-upcoming-security-privacy-layers">Offline Device Lock</a>." The company detailed the coming feature during I/O 2024, stating it would help users with devices on its Find My Device network. If a device is taken offline for too long, it will automatically lock itself to protect your data.</p><p>Additionally, if a malicious person fails too many sign-in attempts, your phone will lock down.</p><p>What&apos;s unclear is if Google&apos;s listed USB and WiFi usage for data transfers is referring to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/android-preps-data-restore-tool-transfer-upgrades">what was discovered in May</a>. The company&apos;s Data Restore Tool app featured a few glimpses into this new method to speed up data transfers. Essentially, users should be able to restore the data of an old phone without needing to factory reset.</p><p>Google&apos;s June updates for its services should automatically download and install as we finish the week. In other news, Pixel phones <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-june-2024-security-patch">grabbed a June patch</a> with loads of fixes for stability, battery, charging, and camera problems.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-play-system-june-updates-detailed</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google detailed the various updates that have started rolling out for users in June for its Play Systems. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">ZNoG8PMLRBHduk8dmE8bWF</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kYLd8oCULjmdAuCAfdcVDN.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 21:03:44 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kYLd8oCULjmdAuCAfdcVDN.jpeg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Alex Dobie / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Close-up of Google Play Services app info]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Close-up of Google Play Services app info]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ This early Prime Day deal drops our favorite tablet to its lowest price EVER — 25% off the Galaxy Tab S9! ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>If you&apos;re awaiting the next great Samsung tablet deal, your wait might be over! For a limited time, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C4BCNRVQ"><strong>Amazon has cut $200 OFF the price of the Samsung Galaxy Tab S9</strong></a>, our favorite Android tablet on the market. This deal is for the 128GB version of the tablet, though the S9 also has a microSD slot that you can use for even more storage. The 11-inch AMOLED display boasts a 120Hz refresh rate, and the S9 also has a super-long battery life and a powerful processor for smooth performance.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="cb38bdd3-8253-4402-80c6-a8253c280b3c" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799.99" data-dimension48="$799.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C4BCNRVQ" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1052px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:90.59%;"><img id="SmiJZBuVtWeFGoVK8RnxK4" name="samsung-galaxy-tab-s9-render-w-space.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SmiJZBuVtWeFGoVK8RnxK4.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1052" height="953" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 128GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C4BCNRVQ" data-dimension112="cb38bdd3-8253-4402-80c6-a8253c280b3c" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799.99" data-dimension48="$799.99"><del>$799.99</del> <strong>$599.00 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>The Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 is currently selling for $200 off, marking a 25% discount on the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-tablets#section-best-overall">best Android tablet</a> out there. From the S9's 11-inch, 120Hz AMOLED display to its excellent battery life and quick performance, this is a great device—especially at this price.</p>
<p><strong>Price comparison:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-tab-s9-11-128gb-wi-fi-with-s-pen-graphite/6546661.p">Best Buy - $699.99</a> | <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C4BCNRVQ" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="cb38bdd3-8253-4402-80c6-a8253c280b3c" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799.99" data-dimension48="$799.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/amazon-prime-day-2024-dates-early-deals-and-what-to-expect-from-the-sale"><strong>Amazon Prime Day 2024 — early deals and FAQ</strong></a></li></ul>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if:</strong> you&apos;re looking for a deal on a tablet that normally comes at a premium price point; having a tablet with a solid refresh rate is a priority for you; you want a tablet that offers top-notch battery life.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if:</strong> you&apos;re a casual tablet user and would rather go with one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-android-tablet">best cheap Android tablets</a>; you can afford to upgrade to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/samsung-galaxy-tab-s9-ultra-review">Galaxy Tab S9 Ultra</a>.</p><p>The Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 is a great tablet, due in no small part to its Snapdragon 8 Gen 2 processor and aided by the 11-inch AMOLED display&apos;s 120Hz refresh rate. You can expect some of the industry&apos;s smoothest, quickest performance, especially at this low-level premium price point. The S9 offers great first-party keyboard options for those who prefer to use their tablets like a laptop computer, and it offers around 10 hours of battery life per charge.</p><p>If you&apos;re willing to pay the extra premium to upgrade to the Galaxy Tab S9 Ultra, you&apos;ll certainly get what you pay for. But if you want an excellent midrange device that won&apos;t break the bank, the S9 is worth every penny right now. </p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/this-early-prime-day-deal-drops-our-favorite-tablet-to-its-lowest-price-ever-25-off-the-galaxy-tab-s9</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 is our favorite tablet out there, and at 25% off the normal price from Amazon, this one is a certified good deal. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">NRf6YYAhUkrJ7bCszrvZB3</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kzoFLLehuF5oeeNQbWLxSN.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 20:41:55 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kzoFLLehuF5oeeNQbWLxSN.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Samsung]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Official lifestyle images of the Samsung Galaxy Tab S9]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Official lifestyle images of the Samsung Galaxy Tab S9]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ New OnePlus Watch certification and specs suggest an impending launch ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A new OnePlus Watch has appeared for its TENAA certification with specifications and a rendering in tow.</li><li>The device will reportedly arrive with LTE support, a 500mAh battery, and 10W charging capabilities.</li><li>Its render showcases a circular watch face and dials with two physical (pressable) buttons on the right side.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>It appears that OnePlus is preparing a new smartwatch to hit the market, though it&apos;s unclear where it will fall in the series.</p><p>The folks over at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.mysmartprice.com/gear/wearables/wearables-news/alleged-oneplus-watch-3-tenaa-certification/">MySmartPrice </a>discovered the upcoming OnePlus Watch receiving its TENAA certification (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/oneplus-watch-2-lte-variant-leak-3453013/">Android Authority</a>). A few key specs accompanied the database listing, such as its LTE support for e-SIM devices. Further details state that the watch will support e-SIMs provided by China Unicom, China Telecom, and China Mobile.</p><p>Other specifications suggest the device will feature a 500mAh battery, similar to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oneplus-watch-2-review">OnePlus Watch 2</a>. The publication reiterated that a previous certification discovery shows the device will likely offer 10W wired charging capabilities.</p><p>However, it seems OnePlus isn&apos;t attaching a power adapter with this launch, meaning consumers may need to use one on hand or purchase one separately.</p><p>The upcoming OnePlus device, rumored to be the Watch 3, had a few of its renders uploaded with its certification. The device appears similar to the Watch 2, but there seem to be two circular (pushable) physical buttons on the right side. The circular watch face is here to stay alongside evidence of a dial.</p><p>The certification lists the device as model number <strong>OPWW234</strong>, furthering speculation that it&apos;s the OnePlus Watch 3. With its listed specifications and the fact that the Watch 2 launched in February, this device feels more like a Watch 2 variant than anything else.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:450px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:133.33%;"><img id="xMXRX8Yh2wKr2dZfJQH3gA" name="oneplus-watch-lte-variant-2024.jpg" alt="A rendering of the new OnePlus Watch appearing for its certification." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xMXRX8Yh2wKr2dZfJQH3gA.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="450" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: MySmartPrice)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>There aren&apos;t many more details to unpack about this upcoming OnePlus Watch aside from its battery, connectivity, and design elements. The watch has continued to make its certification rounds in multiple databases, which could indicate an impending launch.</p><p>For context, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oneplus-watch-2-mwc-2024-launch">OnePlus Watch 2 launched</a> during MWC 2024 in February with a 100-hour battery and Qualcomm&apos;s Snapdragon W5 performance chipset. The device arrived with 7.5W VOOC fast charging, able to reach a full charge in an hour. OnePlus hit the U.S. market with a $299 price tag, though it&apos;s hard to say where this new device could land.</p><p>One thing to note is that the Watch 2 debuted <em>without </em>LTE support — this new device making its certification rounds solves that. So, it seems more likely that this upcoming watch is more of an LTE variant for those who fancy that more.</p>
<ul><li> <strong>Smartwatch deals: </strong><a href="https://shop-links.co/link?st=smartwatch&_dyncharset=UTF-8&_dynSessConf=&id=pcat17071&type=page&sc=Global&cp=1&nrp=&sp=&qp=&list=n&af=true&iht=y&usc=All+Categories&ks=960&keys=keys&publisher_slug=future&exclusive=1&u1=ac-us-1083275179513787569&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fsearchpage.jsp%3Fst%3Dsmartwatch%26_dyncharset%3DUTF-8%26_dynSessConf%3D%26id%3Dpcat17071%26type%3Dpage%26sc%3DGlobal%26cp%3D1%26nrp%3D%26sp%3D%26qp%3D%26list%3Dn%26af%3Dtrue%26iht%3Dy%26usc%3DAll%2BCategories%26ks%3D960%26keys%3Dkeys&article_name=OnePlus%20Watch%202%20arrives%20as%20a%20sleek%2C%20100-hour%20battery%20powerhouse%20with%20Wear%20OS%204&article_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.androidcentral.com%2Fwearables%2Foneplus-watch-2-mwc-2024-launch" target="_blank"><strong>Best Buy</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1943169/565706/9383?subId1=ac-us-4609842893382133366&sharedId=ac-us&u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fsearch%3Fq%3Dsmartwatch" target="_blank"><strong>Walmart</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://target.georiot.com/Proxy.ashx?tsid=169923&GR_URL=https%3A%2F%2Famazon.com%2Fs%3Fk%3Dsmartwatch%26crid%3D19YAPQ38561AK%26sprefix%3Dsmartwatch%252Caps%252C138%26ref%3Dnb_sb_ss_ts-doa-p_1_10%26tag%3Dhawk-future-20%26ascsubtag%3Dac-us-9514502244344936274-20" target="_blank"><strong>Amazon</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://shop-links.co/link?publisher_slug=future&exclusive=1&u1=ac-us-1324430769081366862&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.samsung.com%2Fus%2Fshop%2Fall-deals%2Fwatches-audio-accessories-deals%2F&article_name=OnePlus%20Watch%202%20arrives%20as%20a%20sleek%2C%20100-hour%20battery%20powerhouse%20with%20Wear%20OS%204&article_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.androidcentral.com%2Fwearables%2Foneplus-watch-2-mwc-2024-launch" target="_blank"><strong>Samsung</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-100048248-12578053?sid=ac-us-2105808479633308005&url=https://www.dell.com/en-us/search/smartwatch" target="_blank"><strong>Dell</strong></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/new-oneplus-watch-certification-specs-rendering</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A new OnePlus Watch appeared for certification with a few key specifications along with it. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">U4AjDUtma8uujm69sfPxSQ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/eQBqDky2XkE7PBWYDQekpQ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 20:29:12 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/eQBqDky2XkE7PBWYDQekpQ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus Watch 2 activity data]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus Watch 2 activity data]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ 1Password highlights account-saving Recovery Codes if you're locked out ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>1Password detailed its rollout of "Recovery Codes" that should help users regain access to their accounts if they lose their credentials or Security Key.</li><li>The company encourages users to create a code as soon as possible, as the option to do so will be unavailable if they're locked out.</li><li>1Password is also reportedly preparing to bring a QR code sign-in method for existing users and new devices.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Today (June 20), 1Password announced a new, user-friendly method folks can utilize to ensure they never lose their data.</p><p>According to a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.1password.com/introducing-1password-recovery-codes/">blog post</a>, 1Password is starting to roll out "Recovery Codes" to all users. The company states that it wants users to have "peace of mind and control that comes with knowing you’ll never be locked out of your account." 1Password states its Recovery Codes are "unique and secure" as they&apos;re generated by the main website or its app as a backup.</p><p>Users can grab a recovery code if they&apos;ve forgotten their passwords, if two-factor authentication isn&apos;t an option, or if their Security Key is lost.</p><p>The post encourages users to create a recovery code as soon as possible, as that option will disappear if they can&apos;t access their account. Users can begin doing so with the following steps:</p>
<ul><li>Open and unlock the 1Password app.</li><li>Select your account or collection at the top of the sidebar and choose <strong>Manage Accounts</strong>.</li><li>Choose your account and then select <strong>Sign-in & Recovery</strong>.</li><li>Select <strong>Set up recovery code</strong> and follow the onscreen instructions.</li></ul>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:732px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:72.54%;"><img id="kjieiQbAT9L5SPzemrnAXA" name="1password-recovery-code-setup-page.jpg" alt="Users can navigate into their 1Password account page to begin creating a Recovery Code." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kjieiQbAT9L5SPzemrnAXA.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="732" height="531" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: 1Password)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:727px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:62.17%;"><img id="sQgHPgeqTPNpYWdEWvv9yD" name="1password-recovery-code-saving-example.jpg" alt="An example of the lengthy Recovery Code users are encouraged to create to save their accounts if they forget its credentials." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sQgHPgeqTPNpYWdEWvv9yD.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="727" height="452" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: 1Password)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>After regaining account access through a code, 1Password states users can reset their credentials (password). Recovery codes can be generated through the app or the website on Android, iOS, Windows, Mac, and Linux devices.</p><p>The codes are lengthy, and 1Password suggests saving them somewhere you won&apos;t lose or forget.</p><p>This new account-saving method should help users breathe a sigh of relief as there was previously no way of saving their data, even with support. The company states its new codes should help Family Organizers and customers on its Individual plan breathe easy.</p><p>That&apos;s not all as <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/06/20/1password-recovery-code-sign-in-beta/">9to5Google</a> states 1Password is preparing to incorporate a new, easier sign-in method for new devices "by the end" of the summer. According to the post, the company is preparing to bring a QR code sign-in for new devices that will be using your account.</p><p>The feature will reportedly arrive in beta first before hitting all users later in the year.</p><p>Recovery codes are starting to arrive a few months after 1Password brought <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/1password-existing-user-passkey-support-android-rollout">passkey support</a> to all users rocking Android 14.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q8rZxntMlN0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/1password-details-account-access-recovery-codes</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ 1Password detailed its new "Recovery Code" method for users to avoid a complete account lockout. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">BqhTks7kCtYECp7mbHvqpj</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jUTessiAh4x7EyxQB4zHzL.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 19:43:58 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jUTessiAh4x7EyxQB4zHzL.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[1Password welcome screen on an Android phone]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[1Password welcome screen on an Android phone]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Alleged Galaxy Buds 3 case render is very Apple, but with a clear dome ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>An apparent Galaxy Buds 3 retail listing was discovered on a South Korean website, spilling the device's upcoming charging case redesign.</li><li>To accommodate the new stem, the Buds stand upright in the case, which features a clear dome and several lights to indicate its charging progress.</li><li>A recent leak suggests that Samsung is preparing to unveil its new suite of devices this summer on July 10.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>A discovery made on a South Korean website seemingly spoils the new Galaxy Buds 3 charging case.</p><p>The early site listing was found by X user <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/TEQHNIKACROSS/status/1803771740902035561">TEQNIKA</a>, which shows a case change made to accommodate Samsung&apos;s new design (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/06/20/galaxy-buds-3-leak-shows-off-a-case-nearly-identical-to-airpods-pro/">9to5Google</a>). The user states that the Korean website Coupang is the source behind the new clear-top Galaxy Buds 3 case. The initial rendering suggests consumers can see their buds alongside a green dot on the outside, likely indicative of the case&apos;s reserves.</p><p>The second photo from the retail listing gives us a better look at how the buds will sit in the case. Considering the supposed new stem-like design, the buds stand upright in the case within black holders. There are lights on each holder, most likely another indicator of its charging process when the top is opened.</p><p>It also looks like users can clip their charging case onto their bags. On a related note, 9to5 mentions that this revamped design looks similar to Apple&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/airpods-pro-review">AirPods Pro</a> case — which is true, minus the clear dome.</p><p>Lastly, that early retail listing gives us our clearest look at the new Buds 3. Its smooth, silvery design is evident alongside its new stem, forgoing the old bulbous look.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">갤럭시 버즈3의 제품 이미지가 쿠팡에서 발견되었습니다. pic.twitter.com/aCWUEyigVd<a href="https://twitter.com/TEQHNIKACROSS/status/1803771740902035561">June 20, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>A redesigned Galaxy Bud has been theorized for a while now, and a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/earbuds/galaxy-buds-3-pro-apple-like-redesign-leak">pixelated render leak</a> earlier this month expanded on it. Again, it showed Samsung&apos;s apparent interest in moving toward an Apple-like design, which might not be bad as it could introduce a stem over the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/samsung-galaxy-buds-2-review">stabilization wingtip</a>.</p><p>What&apos;s more, a recent leak shows that this new supposed stem design might come packed with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/earbuds/galaxy-buds-3-stem-design-to-feature-pinch-controls">pinch-based touch controls</a>. The discovery was made through the code of the Samsung Members app, revealing that the Galaxy Buds 3 stem could feature pinch <em>and </em>hold-based touch controls.</p><p>Speculation says double pinching could skip songs or decline phone calls. Single pinches might act as the "play" button for songs and to answer incoming calls.</p><p>We&apos;re not far from knowing how true this early listing is as a summer <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-and-z-flip-6-gets-launch-date">Unpacked countdown</a> recently surfaced. It appears that Samsung is preparing for its full reveal of devices on July 10 at 10 PM Korean Standard Time (9 am EST).</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/earbuds/alleged-galaxy-buds-3-retail-listing-leak</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A supposed retail listing for the Galaxy Buds 3 leaked, showcasing its apparent charging case redesign. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">9z4S4MBHbgfn5e5Rp9pB53</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kWVmPBz2aDVx7Df5jNLQoh.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 17:56:44 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Earbuds]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kWVmPBz2aDVx7Df5jNLQoh.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Buds 2 Pro review]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Buds 2 Pro review]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ YouTube is targeting VPN tricks for cheaper Premium plans ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="#section-update"><strong>Update (June 20, 2:50 pm ET)</strong></a>: Google has indirectly confirmed that it is tightening things up to make sure every YouTube Premium user pays the price for their region.</p>
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-32">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Many YouTube Premium users are experiencing random cancellations, likely due to using VPNs for cheaper rates.</li><li>A Reddit user confirmed with customer support that changes in their location led to their subscription being canceled.</li><li>Customer service suggests affected users re-subscribe using their local address and payment method.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Several YouTube Premium users see their memberships randomly canceled, likely because they used a VPN to get a cheaper rate.</p><p>A recent <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/youtube/comments/1di5mz5/comment/l91rrqr/" target="_blank">thread on Reddit</a> highlighted a wave of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/youtube-premium">YouTube Premium</a> subscriptions being axed. It appears that these cancellations are linked to users resorting to VPN services in order to score cheaper rates by taking advantage of regional pricing loopholes (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/youtube-premium-vpn-cheap-subscription-clampdown-3452674/" target="_blank">Android Authority</a>).</p><p>YouTube offers a tiered pricing system for its Premium service to account for differences in global purchasing power. However, some users have been gaming it by using <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-vpn">VPN services</a> to fake their location and get cheaper rates. This trick undermines the fairness of YouTube&apos;s regional pricing model.</p><p>To illustrate the price disparity, a Premium subscription in Ukraine costs £2.30 per month, whereas it normally costs $13.99 per month in the US.</p><p>By exploiting regional pricing differences with VPNs, some users managed to get YouTube Premium for a fraction of the cost in their home market. Although the subscription worked fine after the initial VPN trick, Google now seems to be cracking down on this loophole in its pricing system.</p><p>In one case, a Reddit user contacted YouTube customer support about their canceled subscription. The response suggested that the user&apos;s location had supposedly changed from the one they used at signup.</p><p>Customer service also advised affected users to re-subscribe using their local address and a payment method from their region. This apparent crackdown seems to be aimed at enforcing regional pricing for YouTube Premium.</p><p>We&apos;ve reached out to Google to confirm if the company is targeting VPN-sourced YouTube Premium subscriptions and will update this article once we hear back.</p><p>Notably, reports of subscription cancellations aren&apos;t limited to Ukrainian users who use VPNs. Users from multiple countries who used VPNs to score cheaper YouTube Premium subscriptions have reported cancellations as well.</p><p>To regain access to YouTube Premium, affected users need to re-subscribe using their verified location details.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-update"><span>Update</span></h2>
<p>A YouTube spokesperson told Android Central in an emailed statement that the service has implemented stricter measures to ensure regional pricing compliance for YouTube Premium subscriptions.</p><p>"To provide the most accurate plans and offers available, we have systems in place to determine the country of our users," the spokesperson said. "In instances where the signup country does not match where the user is accessing YouTube, we&apos;re asking members to update their billing information to their current country of residence."</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-is-targeting-vpn-tricks-for-cheaper-premium-plans</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ YouTube may have just plugged the hole for those sneaky Premium discounts. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">wC2xqUgACfPP9QczWFfTkK</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MNCR5i4Bt6Kn3tnttXyUEd.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 17:35:20 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MNCR5i4Bt6Kn3tnttXyUEd.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Youtube Premium Up Close Galaxy Z Fold]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Youtube Premium Up Close Galaxy Z Fold]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Sony no longer cares about the PSVR 2, and neither should you ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Until now, the PSVR 2 has been a pretty darn good VR headset. Well over 200 games are currently available, with several impressive releases like Horizon Call of the Mountain, Gran Turismo 7, and the duo of Resident Evil Village <em>and</em> Resident Evil 4 Remake. However, the headset now has an insurmountable problem: Sony no longer cares about it.</p><p>Sources close to Android Central have revealed that Sony is making deep cuts to funding for VR games. While I&apos;ll paraphrase for anonymity, my source was told that there will be very few opportunities for VR game development at Sony going forward.</p><p>To back that up, another source informed me that only two PSVR 2 games are in development at Sony. Given the state of the games industry with constant layoffs and studio closings, I don&apos;t exactly feel confident that even these games will ever see the light of day if Sony continues on its current trajectory.</p><p>Android Central has reached out to Sony about its PlayStation VR2 development plans but they did not get back to us in time for publication. We will update the article once we have more information.</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">AC thVRsday</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="LGmZZrc8DWcxmZm6RRUYbC" name="ac-thvrsday-logo.jpg" caption="" alt="AC thVRsday logo" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LGmZZrc8DWcxmZm6RRUYbC.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">In his <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/ac-thvrsday">weekly column</a>, Android Central Senior Content Producer Nick Sutrich delves into all things VR, from new hardware to new games, upcoming technologies, and so much more.</p></div></div>
<p>I should have seen the writing on the wall when Sony&apos;s Insomniac Games studio got hacked in December 2023, revealing the fact that the company <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/18lvqor/insomniac_leaks_compilation/">wasn&apos;t working on</a> a single VR game for Sony&apos;s flagship VR system, the PlayStation VR2.</p><p>That&apos;s important because Insomniac Games, maker of the Spider-Man series, Ratchet & Clank, Spyro the Dragon, and several other well-known and successful properties, made four games for Meta&apos;s (then Facebook) Oculus Rift platform. Three of those games were very well received, and many consider Stormland to still be among the very best open-world VR games playable on PC today. Yet, Sony has them working on exactly zero PSVR 2 games.</p><p>Last year, Sony released just three PSVR 2 games and has yet to officially announce even one first-party game coming out for the system in 2024, let alone in 2025. Of those three games, Firewall Ultra developer First Contact Entertainment <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/vr-developer-first-contact-closes-down">has since shut down</a>. To add insult to injury, Sony then <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/sony-reevaluating-playstation-studios-and-cutting-900-jobs">closed down London Studio</a> in February—a team responsible for another of the PSVR&apos;s highest-rated games, Blood & Truth, as well as the PlayStation VR Worlds demo disc.</p><p>Even Firesprite, the developer behind the excellent Horizon Call of the Mountain, has seen <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/firesprite-lays-off-horizon-director-alex-barnes-in-playstation-layoffs">substantial budget and personnel cuts</a> and even game cancellations. That doesn&apos;t leave much for Sony&apos;s first-party development studios.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>Sources close to Android Central have revealed that the company only has two first-party PSVR 2 titles in development.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>Fast forward to the May 2024&apos;s State of Play, Sony&apos;s Summer gaming showcase that revealed all sorts of fun games including a brand new Astro Bot title that fans have been salivating for. The original Astro Bot Rescue Mission is the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/astro-bot-rescue-mission/">highest-rated PSVR game</a> of all time and was recommended as a must-play for any new PSVR owner for as long as that system was supported.</p><p>The trouble is that the sequel doesn&apos;t have any kind of VR support at all. Games like Astro Bot take years to make, which tells me that Sony gave up on the PSVR 2 a long time ago. These decisions aren&apos;t made arbitrarily, and while it&apos;s perfectly within a studio&apos;s right to decide its own path forward, the evidence makes it clear that Sony no longer has an interest in supporting its VR headset.</p>
<h2 id="total-lack-of-vision-2">Total lack of vision</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.49%;"><img id="zrdSeLsaE2QtMcsJ8z8ef9" name="astro-bot-rescue-mission-psvr.jpeg" alt="Astro Bot Rescue Mission Psvr" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zrdSeLsaE2QtMcsJ8z8ef9.jpeg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1157" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Sony)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>When Astro made an appearance on May&apos;s State of Play showcase, I immediately got excited. Astro is such a lovable character, and the appearance of the PS5 controller on-screen—with Astro riding it, no less—certainly looked like PSVR 2 support was in the game. That is until I noticed there was no PSVR 2 logo at the end of the trailer. Only the PS5 logo.</p><p>Unfortunately for me and every other PSVR Astro fan, a recently published interview <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/astro-bot-no-playstation-vr2-support/">on Digital Trends</a> confirmed that the company isn&apos;t planning a VR mode for Astro Bot at all. There is no DLC, no update later down the road, and no VR. What a stab in the back for what made Astro popular in the first place.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>The sequel to the best PSVR game doesn't even have PSVR 2 support. Talk about a stab in the back.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>When Giovanni Colantonio asked why, he was given this incredibly disingenuous response by Team Asobi studio head Nicolas Doucet:</p><p>"We&apos;re focusing 100% on PS5. Rescue Mission was great fun to make. Every medium has its strong points. In the case of a third-person game, whether you work on TV or VR is radically different. This idea that we could add a VR mode is not applicable to this kind of game. It&apos;s applicable to some first-person games like racing, but not for this kind of game. So our choice was to go 100% for TV to really have as many people as possible playing this game."</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-JWtDQcXJqs" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>Yet, studios like Flat2VR have proven that modifying games made for TVs isn&apos;t all that difficult. Popular PC modder Praydog released <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.uploadvr.com/praydogs-uevr-mod/">a new app in January</a> of this year that turns any modern Unreal Engine game into a VR game with just a few clicks.</p><p>To prove its worth, VR gaming streamer Paradise Decay used Praydog&apos;s app to turn Sony&apos;s Sackboy PS5 platformer into a lovely VR title, viewable in the YouTube video below.</p><p>Some of this can be chalked up to Sony&apos;s overall strategy shifting. As of June 2024, the company <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hideaki-nishino-and-hermen-hulst-playstation-ceos">now has two CEOs</a> as it split the PlayStation business into separate hardware and software divisions, and Sony&apos;s software CEO seems to have a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/tomwarren/status/1795966798942158935">very narrow-minded vision</a> of the future of PlayStation as a brand.</p>
<h2 id="what-happened-to-hybrid-aaa-2">What happened to hybrid AAA?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1280px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="PjCrhnfZWnk4MPKLJrP8K8" name="resident-evil-4-vr-remake-psvr-2.jpg" alt="A screenshot from Resident Evil 4 Remake VR on PSVR 2" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PjCrhnfZWnk4MPKLJrP8K8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1280" height="720" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Capcom)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In January 2022, Sony executives were said to be focusing on a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/sonys-psvr-2-strategy-puts-it-odds-apple-and-meta-and-thats-good-thing">hybrid AAA strategy</a>, meaning AAA games like Horizon, Uncharted, The Last of Us, Spider-Man, and potentially other Sony games could see a VR mode launch alongside the regular version of the game. In the case of Resident Evil Village and Resident Evil 4 Remake, the VR version came just a few months after the TV version launched.</p><p>But other than Gran Turismo 7, we haven&apos;t seen or heard of another hybrid AAA game from any of Sony&apos;s studios. If any game should have received the treatment, it was Astro Bot, which we obviously already covered.</p><p>So if Sony has all but abandoned dedicated VR games and doesn&apos;t seem convinced that hybrid AAA games will work, what&apos;s left? Because of some absurdly stupid software limitations, there&apos;s no backward compatibility support for original PSVR games, and Sony has already told fans to forget about ever getting it. Scratch another thing off the list.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EPcCWR3DTIw" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>So, how about PC VR support? Earlier this year, Sony announced that it would <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/psvr-2-pcvr-firmware-update">make the PSVR 2 work on PCs</a>. Just after it virtually wrung its proverbial hands of the PSVR 2 in the State of Play showcase, Sony finally detailed the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/06/03/playstation-vr2-players-can-access-games-on-pc-with-adapter-starting-on-august-7/">PSVR 2 PC adapter</a>, which would cost $60 and be available on August 7.</p><p>The problem? All of the tentpole features of the headset <em>won&apos;t work</em> on PCs. That includes HDR, headset vibration, eye tracking (and eye-tracked foveated rendering), adaptive triggers, and controller haptic feedback. All that, and you&apos;re still tethered to your PC with a USB cable and a dongle box that looks like it came packed with the original Oculus Rift from 2016.</p><p>At this point, we need to forget that PSVR 2 even exists. Sony already has. You&apos;re far better off getting yourself a Meta Quest 3 this year, which has exclusives like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/batman-arkham-shadow-gameplay-story-interview">Batman Arkham Shadow</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/summer-games-fest-has-already-begun-for-the-meta-quest-3">Hitman 3 VR: Reloaded</a>, and Just Dance VR, to name a few.</p><p>Plus, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/upcoming-meta-quest-games">upcoming Meta Quest games</a> list is far longer than the PSVR 2 list and includes many AAA games like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/behemoth-hands-on">Skydance&apos;s Behemoth</a>, Alien: Rogue Incursion, Metro Awakening, Metal: Hellsinger VR, and maybe, <em>just maybe</em>, even Grand Theft Auto VR.</p>
<hr>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/sony-no-longer-cares-about-the-psvr-2-and-you-shouldnt-either</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The PlayStation VR2 launched in February 2023 to high hopes from fans, but early signs pointed to an apathetic Sony. Turns out, those feelings were more than just intuition. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">eUtx68uQ2K7BNQa2f8Wr2L</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Pws8JUwYqQJax7LBnbt8QB.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 15:38:07 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Pws8JUwYqQJax7LBnbt8QB.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central / Peacock]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A meme from Parks &amp; Rec modified to show a PlayStation VR2 being thrown into a dumpster]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A meme from Parks &amp; Rec modified to show a PlayStation VR2 being thrown into a dumpster]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>