<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 20:08:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Android 15 might add less disruptive, more 'compact' notifications ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A discovery in Android 15 Beta 4 showed that Google plans to bring a "compact" version of the software's notifications to users.</li><li>The "compact" layout displays an app's logo, a single line of text, and a quick "REPLY" button, leaving the rest in its dropdown expansion menu.</li><li>Android 15 Beta 4 launched in mid-July and marches Google toward a (hopeful) August release if testing goes swimmingly.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>It seems Google plans to rework the pop-up notifications that appear when using your device or watching videos.</p><p>The discovery was made by Mishaal Rahman (<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/android-15-compact-heads-up-notifications-3468061/">Android Authority</a>) when searching through the depths of Android 15 Beta 4. To make them intrusive and disruptive, Rahman found mention of a "compact" notification layout. Getting it to work showed Google plans to have notifications displayed smaller and as a single line of text, accompanied by the app&apos;s logo.</p><p>What&apos;s more, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a> still plans to give users a quick and easy way to reply instantly. The upcoming compact form factor features a "REPLY" option beside an arrow, indicating an expansion of the notification.</p><p>It seems that tapping the arrow will open the notification to what users are currently used to seeing on Android. In doing so, users will find an extensive look at the received message alongside a small snapshot of any included photos. The "mark as read" option should be visible after expanding the compact view, as well.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1302px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:46.08%;"><img id="Zm6ZY7HLAGmwJFafjtudoA" name="google-android-15-compact-notification-layout.jpg" alt="An early look at Google's planned "compact" notification layout for notifications." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Zm6ZY7HLAGmwJFafjtudoA.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1302" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Mishaal Rahman / Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>There&apos;s some uncertainty regarding Google&apos;s intended debut of this "compact" notification variant. Rahman suggests it may not roll out during Android 15&apos;s official debut, considering the option isn&apos;t readily available for beta testers in Beta 4. Moreover, he states there&apos;s no option to set your notifications to abide by the compact view or the regular expanded version.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-beta-4-is-here-as-the-stable-release-gets-closer">Android 15 Beta 4</a> started arriving for enrolled Pixel testers in the middle of July. The update marked quite a significant step for the next major OS release as Google marches toward a stable launch. Users downloaded a patch rife with productivity, security, and privacy improvements.</p><p>Among them was the upcoming <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-private-space-full-details">Private Spaces</a> feature, which helps users hide and secure sensitive information like photos, emails, and more <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-private-spaces-revamp-features-added">with various tools</a>. Early findings show that Google will inform users that their Private Space <em>cannot </em>be transferred to another device due to the nature of creation.</p><p>As developers put the final touches on their apps ahead of Android 15, its launch date isn&apos;t set in stone. If all goes well, it&apos;s speculated that Google could begin <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/made-by-google-event-2024-date-announced">rolling it out in August</a> to coincide with the Pixel 9 reveal. The upcoming series is expected to arrive <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-satellite-sos-consumer-charge-potential">with satellite connectivity</a>, but it might cost you if you really like it.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-compact-notification-layout-discovered</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ An Android 15 beta discovery showed Google plans to make its notifications a little less disruptive. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">HNmWDJPgqKW88Udg7VrYF4</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/skASRE5PwdHQGoTTr98rLg.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 19:53:48 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/skASRE5PwdHQGoTTr98rLg.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android 15 logo in hand]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android 15 logo in hand]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Landmark ruling says Google maintained search monopoly illegally ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google has been embroiled in a case over its power in online search and advertising.</li><li>On Monday, a judge ruled that Google acted illegally to maintain its search monopoly.</li><li>This is just one of many cases the U.S. has filed against Big Tech over their practices, which have been deemed anticompetitive.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>A major blow was struck against Google on Monday after a judge ruled that the company illegally maintained a monopoly in search, reports <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/05/technology/google-antitrust-ruling.html">The New York Times</a>. The ruling comes years after the Justice Department and U.S. states sued Google over its search dominance back in 2020. The ruling could have far-reaching consequences for Alphabet and Big Tech.</p><p>Judge Amit P. Mehta made the ruling after closing arguments were made in May. According to the ruling, Google has made "shrewd business decisions" to maintain its market dominance, but the problem lies in how it has positioned itself as the default search engine across various products.</p><p>"For years, Google has secured default placements through distribution contracts," Judge Mehta states in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/25032745-045110819896">289-page ruling</a> obtained by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/5/24155520/judge-rules-on-us-doj-v-google-antitrust-search-suit">The Verge</a>. It explains how this is achieved through advertising revenue share, which it pays to companies <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/doj-sues-google-for-anti-competitive-practices">in exchange for making Google Search the default</a> on products like Safari.</p><p>"In exchange for revenue share, Google not only received placement at the key search access points, but its partners also agree not to preload any other general search engine on the device. Thus, most devices in the United States come preloaded exclusively with Google."</p><p>Because users generally stick to the default search engine on their devices, this is seen as extremely valuable real estate, forcing competitors to find other avenues to get consumers to use their search engines. To put into perspective, Google had nearly 95% of search market share on mobile phones by 2020, with Microsoft&apos;s Bing making up the rest.</p><p>The ruling goes on to note how Google has become synonymous with Search, going largely unchallenged by the competition.</p><p><em>Developing...</em></p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/justice-department-vs-google-ruling-search-dominance</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A judge ruled on Aug. 5 that Google violated antitrust laws, allowing it to maintain an illegal monopoly on search. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">7fbJTBK7TWR4mX2V2XBKQ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/M6HFoKyPCZeGYFyfkYRK5n.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 19:22:44 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ derrek.lee@futurenet.com (Derrek Lee) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/M6HFoKyPCZeGYFyfkYRK5n.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Google Logo in Black and White under a sepia shade]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Google Logo in Black and White under a sepia shade]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung's Galaxy A series could get a Galaxy AI makeover later this year ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A report claims that Samsung plans on bringing a few Galaxy AI features to the Galaxy A35 and the Galaxy A55 midrange phones.</li><li>This will reportedly occur during the rollout of One UI 6.1.1, but the AI's arrival will not include "everything."</li><li>One UI 6.1.1 is still under development and has supposedly further delayed the start of Samsung's One UI 7 (Android 15) beta.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Amid Samsung&apos;s rapid push for its AI software, rumors swirl about its next potential expansion to another range of phones.</p><p>A few unnamed sources have reportedly informed <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.sammobile.com/news/galaxy-ai-select-2024-galaxy-a-phones/">SamMobile</a> that Samsung will bring Galaxy AI to its Galaxy A series. Although the information given was limited, there&apos;s a chance the company will roll out its AI software on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-launches-galaxy-a55-and-a35">Galaxy A35 and the Galaxy A55</a> mid-range phones. The publication could "confirm" as much, though it&apos;s stated that there&apos;s no chance of it coming to any older A-series devices.</p><p>It was then rumored that "not every" Galaxy AI feature would be featured on the A35 and the A55. This is likely due to the lack of some internal hardware components as Samsung&apos;s Galaxy AI heavily relies on the NPU and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini Nano</a>. A more concrete answer to which features we could see was left unanswered.</p><p>With the hardware limitations in mind, it would come as little surprise if the Galaxy A35 and A55 received Galaxy AI features that rely on the cloud. This means that we could see the likes of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-circle-to-search">Circle to Search</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-galaxy-ai-generative-edit">Generative Edit</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-create-generative-ai-wallpapers-android-14">Generative Wallpaper</a>, and others. </p><p>This move isn&apos;t entirely unprecedented, as the Galaxy S24 series&apos; <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-s24-instant-slow-mo-galaxy-ai-pure-magic">Instant Slow-Mo</a> feature was mentioned as the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s23-fe-hands-on">S23 FE</a> lacks it. That trend may continue with the A series devices as that feature may require a processing power they don&apos;t have.</p><p>When it could land is reportedly up to Samsung&apos;s planned release of the One UI 6.1.1 update. The post claims that this could take place "this month or the next."</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:66.20%;"><img id="L3quxmvqF9QotvkCNqsbmN" name="samsung-galaxy-ai-is-here.jpg" alt=""Galaxy AI is here" in white font on a grey background" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/L3quxmvqF9QotvkCNqsbmN.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1000" height="662" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Samsung)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Earlier this year, Samsung rolled out its One UI 6.1 update to a few devices, including a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-one-ui-6-1-midranges-may-rumor">couple of A series phones</a>. The patch notably lacked any Galaxy AI upgrades for the devices and their hardware capabilities were the culprit. However, with the latest round of rumors, it seems that Samsung has found a way to implement Galaxy AI into its mid-range devices to some capacity.</p><p>The Galaxy S22 <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-s22-galaxy-ai-support-potential">went through a similar issue</a> and the Korean brand found a way to patch in <em>some </em>AI features despite the limited hardware.</p><p>More importantly, Samsung&apos;s Head of Mobile, TM Roh, discussed the company&apos;s newfound <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-discusses-the-ai-phone-future">R&D focus on AI</a> following Unpacked. In the future, Roh stated that AI will become "multi-modal" and that the "AI Phone" will become Samsung&apos;s main business since the introduction of the Galaxy S24. Additionally, this new era will require the company to invest in new hardware to meet the software&apos;s requirements.</p><p>We&apos;re still <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-has-allegedly-put-the-brakes-on-the-one-ui-7-beta-rollout">waiting on One UI 6.1.1</a>, which seems to have delayed the originally planned start of the One UI 7 (<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a>) beta. So, those with a Galaxy A35 or Galaxy A55 will have to wait a little longer to see if these rumors pan out.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-galaxy-a-series-galaxy-ai-rumor</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A report claimed that Samsung plans on bringing Galaxy AI to a couple of A series midrange devices. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">sPgNZrSFhBwBjHVe9K2EA4</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QhMYCatHdk4DkwU4kQib8E.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 17:44:28 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QhMYCatHdk4DkwU4kQib8E.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Galaxy AI&#039;s Live Translate in the settings menu]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Galaxy AI&#039;s Live Translate in the settings menu]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Does the OnePlus Pad 2 support stylus input? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <section class="article__schema-question"><h3>Does the OnePlus Pad 2 support stylus input?</h3><article class="article__schema-answer"><p><strong>Best answer:</strong> Yes! The OnePlus Pad 2 does support stylus input, however, its compatibility is limited to the company's Stylo 2.</p></article></section>
<h2 id="the-oneplus-pad-2-has-stylus-support-with-a-catch-2">The OnePlus Pad 2 has stylus support, with a catch</h2>
<p>After the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/oneplus-pad-review">OnePlus Pad</a> was released with stylus support, complete with the OnePlus Stylo, it would have come as a bit of a shock to see a new tablet arrive without it. Thankfully, that&apos;s not something we need to worry about as the OnePlus Pad 2 features stylus support.</p><p>In addition to the OnePlus Pad 2 and Smart Keyboard, the Stylo 2 was also introduced. Currently, this is the only stylus that works with OnePlus&apos; latest tablet. We tried using an array of USI stylus options, such as those that work with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/best-stylus-pixel-tablet">Pixel Tablet</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-stylus-chromebook">Chromebooks</a>, but none of those worked with the Pad 2.</p><p>There was a bit of hope that this might not be the case after noticing that the "eraser" on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/penoval-usi-2-pen">Penoval USI 2.0 Stylus</a> was able to interact with the display. However, it was extremely inconsistent and isn&apos;t something that we recommend trying to use.</p><p>Nevertheless, the OnePlus Stylo 2 was released alongside the Pad 2, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.oneplus.com/us/product/product/oneplus-stylo-2">retailing for $99</a>, and is available directly from the company. The Stylo 2, too has been slightly redesigned, as it ditches the matte white finish from its predecessor in favor of a leather-like texture for improved grip.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="FtyN6zA3XTxzign7yKn49f" name="oneplus-pad-2-stylo-2-notes-app.jpg" alt="OnePlus Pad 2 with Notes app open and Stylo 2" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FtyN6zA3XTxzign7yKn49f.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2500" height="1406" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Other features of the Stylo 2 include 16,000 levels of pressure, while OnePlus claims it offers "near-instant response." When used with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/the-oneplus-pad-2-just-launched-but-it-might-be-the-best-prime-day-tablet-deal">OnePlus Pad 2</a>, the Stylo 2 also provides "subtle feedback" by interacting with the display using the stylus. This also applies when jotting down notes, attempting to replicate the feeling when writing with pen and paper.</p><p>Pushing the boundaries even further, the Stylo 2 can double as a laser pointer for presentations. All you&apos;ll need to do is press and hold on to the built-in touchpad, and the Stylo 2 will spring into action, removing any headaches that might&apos;ve occurred if you didn&apos;t have the Pad 2 and Stylo 2. Plus, the aforementioned touchpad can even be used to scroll through documents without needing to touch the screen or the Smart Keyboard&apos;s trackpad.</p><p>Additionally, those worried about the potential of losing the Stylo 2 can rest easy. Thanks to the series of magnets built into both the tablet and stylus, just place the Stylo 2 along the top and it will snap into place. This is how you pair the two devices together, and while the Stylo 2 is attached, it will also be wirelessly charged until you remove it or the battery is full.</p><p>Although we wish the OnePlus Pad 2 featured USI 2.0 support, at least the Stylo 2 is here to prevent any additional frustrations.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="e71dc390-2ea8-41a9-83d6-bdf884e4da39">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/d3nVtLBDDHmpauhhTBQJth.jpg' alt="OnePlus Pad 2 render"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">OnePlus Pad 2</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Impressive and affordable</strong></em></p>
<p>The OnePlus Pad 2 could end up offering the best value of the year, as it's the first Android tablet to launch with the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3, and is priced less than the Galaxy Tab S9. Plus, you can pair it with the OnePlus Stylo 2 and Smart Keyboard for the ultimate portable workstation.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/does-the-oneplus-pad-2-support-stylus-input</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The OnePlus Pad 2 is quite a versatile device, offering flagship-level performance, without breaking the bank. Does it work with a stylus though? ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">RxP8hT4c4dsLS2Q2SAn5wC</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/iMHAwthLHVXSkpMY5sa4qh.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 17:10:56 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ andrew.myrick@futurenet.com (Andrew Myrick) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/iMHAwthLHVXSkpMY5sa4qh.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus Stylo 2 up-close on OnePlus logo]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus Stylo 2 up-close on OnePlus logo]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ How to find your lost Samsung Galaxy Ring ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Knowing in advance how to find your lost Samsung Galaxy Ring is important, because you need to set up the "find my ring" features <em>before</em> you lose it, not after. It&apos;ll only take you a minute, assuming you have a Galaxy phone.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-ring">Galaxy Ring</a> has no built-in GPS or UWB. The Galaxy Wearable app will save the last <em>known</em> location based on your phone&apos;s GPS data, but if you leave your Galaxy Ring in a public bathroom and someone takes it, you&apos;ll have no way of finding it.</p><p>Worse, if you connect your Galaxy Ring to a non-Samsung phone, you have no way of tracking it, because the system uses the Samsung Find app only available through the Galaxy Store. All you can do is light up the ring&apos;s LEDs to make it more visible, which won&apos;t help if the tiny wearable falls into a couch cushion.</p><p>Our <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-ring-review">Galaxy Ring reviewer</a> has middling impressions of it thus far, and his inability to track it with a non-Samsung phone is a big knock against it. Still, for Samsung phone owners, here&apos;s how to find your lost Galaxy Ring!</p>
<h2 id="how-to-find-your-lost-samsung-galaxy-ring-2">How to find your lost Samsung Galaxy Ring</h2>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> As mentioned above, most of the steps below only work on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-samsung-phones">Samsung phones</a>. </p><p>1. On your Galaxy phone, open <strong>Settings > Security and privacy > Lost device protection</strong>. </p><p>2. Toggle <strong>Offline finding</strong> and hit <strong>Turn on</strong> on the subsequent pop-up screen.</p><p>3. Open the <strong>Galaxy Wearable app</strong>. If you have multiple devices connected — like the Galaxy Ring and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-7-review">Galaxy Watch 7</a> — and the Galaxy Ring isn&apos;t immediately visible, tap the <strong>devices button</strong> (a hovering circle with two squares and circles) and switch to it.</p><p>4. Tap <strong>Find My Ring</strong> at the bottom of the app menu.</p><p>5. Samsung will tell you to <strong>enable location permissions</strong>. Be sure to enable these to <strong>allow devices to be found</strong>. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="HXKx6YkTg2wbAgkh9bppea" name="how-to-find-lost-samsung-galaxy-ring-screenshots.jpg" alt="Galaxy Wearable and Samsung Find screenshots showing how the Lost Ring feature works for the Galaxy Ring." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HXKx6YkTg2wbAgkh9bppea.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>At this point, Samsung will track the Galaxy Ring&apos;s location by default in the <strong>Samsung Find app</strong>, which Samsung uses instead of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/find-my-device">Google&apos;s Find My network</a>. </p><p>With a Samsung phone, you open Samsung Find and tap your ring under <strong>Devices</strong>. A Galaxy Ring icon will appear wherever it was last detected, whether online or offline.</p><p>You&apos;ll see the <strong>Blink light</strong> option, as well as a <strong>Refresh</strong> button to update its last known location. Under <strong>More</strong>, you can toggle <strong>Notify me when it&apos;s found</strong> or <strong>Notify when left behind</strong>. The latter is especially useful for warning you immediately if your phone detects it disconnecting.</p><p>With a non-Samsung phone, your process is simpler (and less useful). Open the Galaxy Wearable app and tap Find My Ring. You&apos;ll find a threadbare menu with only one option: <strong>Tap Start</strong> to make the Galaxy Ring LEDs blink.</p>
<h2 id="finding-your-galaxy-ring-shouldn-apos-t-be-a-samsung-exclusive-2">Finding your Galaxy Ring shouldn&apos;t be a Samsung exclusive</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="C36SKfEDC3XzvmGDA4crLM" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Ring-battery-life-02.jpg" alt="The gold Samsung Galaxy Ring showing battery percentage on the Samsung Wearables app" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/C36SKfEDC3XzvmGDA4crLM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It&apos;s a common trend for Samsung to make vital tools exclusive to push you to buy all of their devices, like making life-saving AFib detection on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-7">Galaxy Watch 7</a> or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-ultra-review">Galaxy Watch Ultra</a> restricted to the Health Monitor app.</p><p>In this case, Samsung made a few <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/which-samsung-galaxy-ring-features-are-exclusive-to-samsung-phones">Galaxy Ring features exclusive to Samsung phones</a>, including the Energy Score, Wellness Tips, and gesture controls. But making the Find My Ring feature Galaxy exclusive, with no alternative option like Google&apos;s network, is borderline inexcusable for a device this small and expensive.</p><p>Our Galaxy Ring tester tried connecting it to Google&apos;s Find My Network, but it wasn&apos;t visible. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/rings/galaxy-ring/" target="_blank">official Samsung Galaxy Ring page</a> claims that the lost ring feature "requires a smartphone with the SmartThings app," but he couldn&apos;t make the Galaxy Ring appear there, either. He even tried a third-party Bluetooth finder app to see if he could use it to hunt it down locally; again, it wasn&apos;t visible in the devices list. </p><p>We&apos;ve emailed Samsung to ask whether they have any plans to add lost-ring tracking to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a> besides Samsung&apos;s own. They responded that "Android phone users will see blinking lights when prompted to locate their ring," and didn&apos;t provide further details. As it is, it&apos;s extremely easy to lose track of a smart ring unless it&apos;s left in plain sight, and you should be careful whenever you take it off to note where you&apos;ve left it.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="8c29fbb0-00a4-4175-bb9a-7f96da9aa96c">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PjGYwYg2vgeMwknCtD4Qab.jpg' alt="Render of the titanium black Samsung Galaxy Ring"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy Ring</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Don't lose track of anything</strong></em></p>
<p>The Samsung Galaxy Ring lasts up to a week per charge, 10ATM and IP68 protection via the titanium frame, an ultra-lightweight design, and a complimentary charging cradle for on-the-go charging. It tracks a bunch of heart rate and sleep data passively, while being much more comfortable than a smartwatch.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/how-to-find-your-lost-samsung-galaxy-ring</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ If you have a Samsung phone, finding your lost Galaxy Ring is fairly straightforward, though you need to set up the feature before you lose it. If you have another Android phone brand, you're going to have a lot more trouble finding it, even if it's lost in your own home. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">wLKyAU5CcNphjF7disZGGF</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6ZbxiTFz2AU8sEwWMHvK8k.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 17:03:52 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6ZbxiTFz2AU8sEwWMHvK8k.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Holding the gold Samsung Galaxy Ring]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Holding the gold Samsung Galaxy Ring]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ OnePlus Watch 2R vs. Samsung Galaxy Watch 7: Which should you buy? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[         <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="2c270d35-0188-4a0f-b8a1-c3cde50802e4">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qQJxwHNYmusKyGAdKcgboA.jpg' alt="Rendered front view of the Forest Green OnePlus Watch 2R"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">OnePlus Watch 2R</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Superb value for money</strong></em></p>
<p>The OnePlus Watch 2R features powerful hardware, a classy yet modern design, and a unique dual-OS approach that gives it an unmatched battery life, complete with super-fast charging.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Unbeatable battery life</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Workout tracking works great</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Affordable price tag</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No 4G/LTE connectivity</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Available in just one size</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="6b747b75-2196-4da6-b09b-67c0dc6a9caa">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/twg3XFZJ889G3SKztd3TTj.jpg' alt="Render of the green Samsung Galaxy Watch 7"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy Watch 7</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Has everything you want</strong></em></p>
<p>The Samsung Galaxy Watch 7 is a fully loaded smartwatch that sports the newest version of Wear OS enhanced by AI, all kinds of improved sensors, and fuss-free untethered connectivity.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Available in two sizes</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>More accurate sensors</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Optional 4G/LTE connectivity</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No rotating bezel for navigation</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No Wireless PowerShare</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<p>If you&apos;re planning to get a new smartwatch soon, it only makes sense to compare the OnePlus Watch 2R vs. Samsung Galaxy Watch 7, which are hands-down two of the finest wearables available in the market right now. Both are recent launches, with the former sitting next to the awesome OnePlus Watch 2, and the latter sitting alongside the uber-premium Galaxy Watch Ultra.</p><p>Offering powerful hardware, great software, and the ability to track a wide range of health and fitness parameters, the Samsung Galaxy Watch 7 and the OnePlus Watch 2R have a lot going for them. The two are priced (fairly) reasonably too, but which one really deserves the moolah? Let&apos;s find out!</p>
<h2 id="oneplus-watch-2r-vs-samsung-galaxy-watch-7-design-hardware-and-display-2">OnePlus Watch 2R vs. Samsung Galaxy Watch 7: Design, hardware, and display</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="o8oMMm8bAgxKY3PjpEhKEd" name="OnePlus-Watch-2R-closeup.jpeg" alt="The OnePlus Watch 2R and its standard watch face, worn on the author's wrist." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/o8oMMm8bAgxKY3PjpEhKEd.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Both the Galaxy Watch 7 and the OnePlus Watch 2R do a solid job of replicating the look and feel of traditional wristwatches, thanks to their circular cases made from aluminum. The two smartwatches also support standard (albeit different-sized) straps, so you shouldn&apos;t have any issues <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch/best-samsung-galaxy-watch-7-bands" target="_blank">finding one</a> that suits your style. However, while the Galaxy Watch 7 lets you choose between two (40mm and 44mm) sizes, the OnePlus Watch 2R only comes in one (46mm) size. Both wearables have an IP68 rating and are water-resistant up to 5ATM, but only the Galaxy Watch 7 is compliant with the MIL-STD-810H standard, which makes it a bit more rugged than the OnePlus Watch 2R.</p>
<p>While the Galaxy Watch 7 is powered by a 3nm Exynos W1000 SoC, the OnePlus Watch 2R is driven by a 4nm Snapdragon W5 Gen 1 chipset, and you also get 2GB of RAM and 32GB of eMMC storage with each. If these specifications look familiar, it&apos;s because they&apos;re exactly the same as what you&apos;d find if you were to take a look at our <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-ultra-vs-oneplus-watch-2" target="_blank">Samsung Galaxy Watch Ultra vs. OnePlus Watch 2</a> comparison. The Galaxy Watch 7 does have a slightly more efficient processor, but the OnePlus Watch 2R also comes with a secondary BES2700BP processor for less resource-intensive activities like step tracking and notification alerts.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="WQbshdpZ6mYeN6wdpY8bQg" name="samsung-galaxy-watch-7-review-3d-watch-face.jpg" alt="3D watch face on the Samsung Galaxy Watch 7" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WQbshdpZ6mYeN6wdpY8bQg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4000" height="2249" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ara Wagoner / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Galaxy Watch 7 is available in two display sizes — 1.3-inch and 1.5-inch — with both having Sapphire Crystal protection. On the other hand, the OnePlus Watch 2R comes with just one display size — 1.43-inch — which is shielded with Gorilla Glass. Nonetheless, the screens on both wearables are incredible touch-enabled AMOLED panels having deep blacks, rich contrast levels, and super-high pixel density. The two smartwatches also get identical physical controls — a pair of tactile buttons that can be customized to perform a variety of functions — located on the right edge.</p>

<h2 id="oneplus-watch-2r-vs-samsung-galaxy-watch-7-health-and-fitness-features-2">OnePlus Watch 2R vs. Samsung Galaxy Watch 7: Health and fitness features</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="9qjBDpNQm4Px8yDduZqsBa" name="OnePlus-Watch-2R-buttons.jpeg" alt="A right-side view of the OnePlus Watch 2R and its two buttons." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9qjBDpNQm4Px8yDduZqsBa.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Both smartwatches are no slouch when it comes to keeping tabs on your activity and personal wellness metrics, having a variety of sensors to help you do just that. As far as essentials like heart rate, sleep quality, and stress levels are concerned, the two wearables fare equally well. However, the Galaxy Watch 7 comes with an upgraded &apos;<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/galaxy-watch-7-to-get-a-new-sensor-that-boosts-health-tracking" target="_blank">BioActive&apos; sensor</a> that not only allows for improved accuracy, but also helps in monitoring your metabolic health. Female users will also appreciate the menstrual cycle tracking feature, which is something the OnePlus 2R doesn&apos;t have.</p><p>As Android Central&apos;s Ara Wagoner found in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-7-review" target="_blank">her review</a>, the majority of these features work great. What&apos;s not so great is that many of them are exclusive to Galaxy phones.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3674px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.26%;"><img id="vuxNbiHMbhfntEpiiysHQY" name="samsung-galaxy-watch-7-review-health-sensor-button-color.jpg" alt="The Samsung Galaxy Watch 7's curvy new sensor array and orange home button accent" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vuxNbiHMbhfntEpiiysHQY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3674" height="2067" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ara Wagoner / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The OnePlus Watch 2R and the Galaxy Watch 7 definitely seem like they can give the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-smartwatches-fitness" target="_blank">best fitness smartwatches</a> a run for their money. Both wearables can automatically detect and log a number of workouts and provide detailed information (e.g., average speed, distance travelled) about the wearer&apos;s overall performance when playing a variety of sports. The two smartwatches also have dual-frequency GPS that should help you in tracking your outdoor running sessions with even better accuracy.</p>
<h2 id="oneplus-watch-2r-vs-samsung-galaxy-watch-7-software-battery-life-and-other-features-2">OnePlus Watch 2R vs. Samsung Galaxy Watch 7: Software, battery life, and other features</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="MLBUy5ULSWnwQV847qeXMc" name="OnePlus-Watch-2R-apps.jpeg" alt="The apps drawer on the OnePlus Watch 2R." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MLBUy5ULSWnwQV847qeXMc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Galaxy Watch 7 is among the first smartwatches to run <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/wear-os-5" target="_blank">Wear OS 5</a> out of the box. While the latest version of Google&apos;s wearable-centric software platform is largely focused on under-the-hood enhancements, Samsung&apos;s One UI 6 Watch overlay brings several interesting features. Arguably the most notable of these is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-galaxy-ai" target="_blank">Galaxy AI</a>, which analyzes the health and fitness data collected by the smartwatch and turns it into actionable insights. Not just that, Galaxy AI also enables things like suggested replies and voice-to-text summaries.</p><p>The OnePlus Watch 2R does come with Wear OS 4, but the platform works in conjunction with a proprietary version of RTOS (Real Time Operating System) to manage basic functions like notifications.</p>
<p>As noted by Android Central&apos;s Michael Hicks in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oneplus-watch-2r-review" target="_blank">his review</a>, this dual-OS architecture allows the wearable to go for up to three days with the battery completely juiced up. Speaking of which, the OnePlus Watch 2R has a large 500mAh battery with super-fast wired charging. In comparison, the Galaxy Watch 7 does have smaller 300mAh (40mm) and 425mAh (44mm) batteries, but you do get fast wireless charging.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="ubr3aUgtSFHaXthdqnK6fZ" name="samsung-galaxy-watch-7-review-app-drawer.jpg" alt="The Samsung Galaxy Watch 7's app drawer" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ubr3aUgtSFHaXthdqnK6fZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4000" height="2250" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ara Wagoner / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Talking about connectivity, both smartwatches include basics like dual-band Wi-Fi, Bluetooth, and NFC for contactless payments. That said, only the Galaxy Watch 7 is offered with (optional) 4G/LTE. That makes the OnePlus Watch 2R a no-go for proper untethered calling, even though it&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/i-used-to-want-lte-smartwatch-but-not-anymore" target="_blank">not that big of a deal</a> as you might think.</p>
<h2 id="oneplus-watch-2r-vs-samsung-galaxy-watch-7-which-should-you-buy-2">OnePlus Watch 2R vs. Samsung Galaxy Watch 7: Which should you buy?</h2>
<p>If there&apos;s one thing that&apos;s clear, it&apos;s that the OnePlus Watch 2R and the Galaxy Watch 7 are among the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wear-os-watch" target="_blank">best Wear OS watches</a> currently available in the market. They&apos;re well-built, have stunning displays, and do just about everything you&apos;d expect from a modern wearable without issues. Sure, the Galaxy Watch 7 does have a MIL-STD-810H certification for added durability, but the OnePlus Watch 2R features phenomenal battery life with its dual-engine architecture. Just like any other product, both have their own sets of pros and cons. But the question is, which one should you spend your money on?</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="HNhfwnyfVhHuac6RGU34TP" name="OnePlus-Watch-2R-running-form-stats.jpeg" alt="Running form data on the OnePlus Watch 2R" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HNhfwnyfVhHuac6RGU34TP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The OnePlus Watch 2R is priced at $229.99, which is a very reasonable price for what it offers. On the other hand, the Galaxy Watch 7 will cost you $299.99 or $329.99, depending on the size you go for. The extra $70-100 is not a small amount, but you do get features like better software support and menstrual tracking. However, if you want 4G/LTE connectivity, you&apos;ll have to spend $349.99 or $379.99 for the cellular version of the Galaxy Watch 7. That&apos;s $120-150 over the OnePlus Watch 2R, which is only offered with Wi-Fi/Bluetooth connectivity.</p><p>So, here&apos;s the thing! If all you want is a well-rounded smartwatch that can perform the usual core functions (e.g., health and fitness tracking, managing notifications from a paired smartphone) admirably, either of these two wearables should fit your requirements (and wrists) just fine. Go for the OnePlus Watch 2R if you&apos;re on a budget and value battery endurance over anything else. Conversely, get the Galaxy Watch 7 if money is no object and untethered calls are a must-have for you.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="7556f8d9-b314-49ee-8fdb-b99846683953">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qQJxwHNYmusKyGAdKcgboA.jpg' alt="Rendered front view of the Forest Green OnePlus Watch 2R"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">OnePlus Watch 2R</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>All the essentials</strong></em></p>
<p>The OnePlus Watch 2R is a well-rounded wearable that excels at the basics. You also get an innovative dual-engine architecture that allows the battery to go up to three days on a full charge.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="bbead7ed-d684-4d1e-ae46-eb0b5a4a74f2">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/twg3XFZJ889G3SKztd3TTj.jpg' alt="Render of the green Samsung Galaxy Watch 7"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy Watch 7</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Packed with features</strong></em></p>
<p>The Samsung Galaxy Watch 7 is powered by a new and efficient processor, runs the latest AI-enhanced software, and is capable of tracking a plethora of health & fitness parameters with ease.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oneplus-watch-2r-vs-samsung-galaxy-watch-7</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Take a look at our detailed OnePlus Watch 2R vs. Samsung Galaxy Watch 7 comparison and find out which of these Wear OS wearables you should go for. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">nsSiBXxfgJBpQHzXwbKRrS</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qdWXjUPJfbgrFcWQruHNdj.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 16:48:36 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ sharmarajat@zoho.com (Rajat Sharma) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qdWXjUPJfbgrFcWQruHNdj.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Ara Wagoner / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Samsung Galaxy Watch 7 with the Ultra Info Board watch face]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Samsung Galaxy Watch 7 with the Ultra Info Board watch face]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Former iPhone users reveal if an Apple foldable would bring them back from Android ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Off the Record</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="B6hq8h3CPcPnREiyx6XWUN" name="shruti-lloyd-bow-with-desk.jpg" caption="" alt="Off the Record. Lloyd with a bow and computer" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/B6hq8h3CPcPnREiyx6XWUN.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text"><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/off-the-record">Off the Record</a> is a weekly column written by Android Central&apos;s editor-in-chief. The column looks to expand and go in-depth on topics in the Android space without any limitations.</p></div></div>
<p>A recent report from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/apple-moves-forward-with-foldable-iphone?rc=bdqvyp">The Information</a> dropped in late July, indicating that Apple could release a foldable device as early as 2026. We’ve known about a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.imore.com/iphone/iphone-flip">potential Apple foldable</a> as early as 2021, with a more definitive rumor <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.imore.com/iphone/a-foldable-iphone-could-be-closer-than-ever-thanks-to-this-new-patent">circulating last year</a>. But even if the company releases one within the next couple of years, would people be interested in buying an Apple-made foldable?</p><p>I decided to speak with Victor Hoyos, a 32-year-old long-time iPhone user who recently switched over to the Motorola Razr Plus 2024, and ask whether he would switch back to Apple if it made a foldable. </p><p>“I’m not going to move,” Hoyos told me in an interview. </p><p>He believes that Apple is at a point of maturity with its iPhone and is now trying to shift gears to have another wow-factor moment with its Apple Vision Pro VR headset.  </p><p>“They know that their iPhone is mature enough, [and] their market is just not going to grow. And you can see it in their phones. They’re just very iterative,” he said, adding that he also thinks if Apple were to make a foldable, it would likely be in book form rather than a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-flip-phones">flip phone</a>, and Apple would slap a $2,500 price tag on it.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>An Apple foldable will likely be priced at a premium, and that could deter potential buyers and even long-time iPhone users.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>Hoyos recently posted on Reddit <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/razr/comments/1dznx6j/im_an_iphone_user_deep_in_their_ecosystem_but_the/">asking other long-time Apple users about </a><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/razr/comments/1dznx6j/im_an_iphone_user_deep_in_their_ecosystem_but_the/" target="_blank">their experience switching</a> to an Android-based phone and whether it was hard. Though relearning a new device and operating system was a challenge, he still said it was “very exciting.” </p><p>“It was pure nostalgia for me. I heard the word Razr and…it was the same level of awe and excitement for technology that I haven’t felt in years,” Hoyos said. “I think the last time I felt that excited was probably the iPhone 5s.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4073px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="Jd2WofGy5Vkrr4SVFvsnaS" name="Motorola-Razr-Plus-2024-review-hero-16-9.jpg" alt="The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 open at an angle" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Jd2WofGy5Vkrr4SVFvsnaS.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4073" height="2291" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Hoyos isn’t the only person who feels this way about his iPhone. I also spoke with Shepherd Howe, a 16-year-old high school student who switched to an Android in 2020 despite living in an Apple-centric household. </p><p>In an interview, Howe said one of the main reasons for switching over was that he felt <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones" target="_blank">Android phones</a> looked cooler. While he still has his iPhone, he felt that over time, his iPhone’s performance fell short of that of his Android device. </p><p>Like Hoyos, Howe also doesn’t think he’d switch back if Apple made a foldable device. </p><p>“I don’t think I would switch even though it would be cool to have a folding phone that was an iPhone,” he said. “But my final answer would be no.”</p>
<h2 id="apple-will-still-win-if-it-launches-a-foldable-xa0-2">Apple will still win if it launches a foldable </h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="GB5TtmLRcpbMih8aXYemjj" name="Google-Messages-iMessage-green-bubble.jpg" alt="Google Messages on an Android phone and iMessage on an iPhone" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GB5TtmLRcpbMih8aXYemjj.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Despite Hoyos and Howe both strongly stating they would not switch back to Apple if it created a foldable, there is still a large market of people who would still choose Apple.</p><p>Alex Mar is one of those people. In an interview with Derrek Lee, Android Central&apos;s managing editor, Mar, who is in his early 30s and lives in the Seattle area, said he switched to a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-5-review">Galaxy Z Flip 5</a> for reasons similar to Hoyos. He said it brought a nostalgic feeling, something that companies like Motorola have focused heavily on when <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-should-feel-threatened-by-motorola">marketing their flip phones</a>.</p><p>He also revealed that he had a little bit of “iPhone fatigue.” However, after several months with the Flip, Mar eventually decided to switch back to his iPhone, ultimately because of the Apple ecosystem. </p><p>“In the United States, most people have iPhones here. If It were another country where everyone uses WhatsApp, WeChat, or they just use [a] regular [messaging service], I would have stuck with Android,” he said. </p><p>More importantly, Mar said he would “absolutely get an iPhone flip phone.”</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4132px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="noi6MWaEc9AzXzjiR2f4H9" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Z-Flip-5-how-it-started-how-its-going-7.jpg" alt="The Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 5" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/noi6MWaEc9AzXzjiR2f4H9.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4132" height="2324" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Counterpoint Research <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.counterpointresearch.com/insights/survey-28-of-us-smartphone-users-highly-likely-to-opt-for-a-foldable-as-next-purchase/">data from 2022</a> suggested that while 46% of people would buy a Samsung foldable phone, 39% would pick a potential Apple foldable over other foldables that are in the market. </p><p>“Foldables have performed better in controlling the shift from Android to iOS,” said Hanish Bhatia, associate director of North American research at Counterpoint Research. “However, we don’t expect foldables to become the dominant form factor anytime soon in the U.S.” </p><p>Despite the unavailability of an Apple foldable, the data shows “a lot of excitement among consumers for a foldable iPhone,” said Jeff Fieldhack, research director of North America at Counterpoint Research.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>There is a lot of excitement among consumers for a foldable iPhone.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>I myself have been a foldable hater for a while now, although not because I don’t think the form factor is cool; it&apos;s mostly because I simply can’t stand the display crease. </p><p>But when Lee wrote his <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2024-review"><u>Motorola Razr Plus 2024 review</u></a>, I somehow became convinced that Android manufacturers have almost figured it out. As he writes, “the crease looks and feels even less noticeable than on the Razr Plus 2023, which is saying something.”</p><p>If Apple were to create a foldable phone, the crease would definitely be something the company would seriously need to work on perfecting. </p>
<h2 id="apple-isn-x2019-t-late-to-the-game-it-x2019-s-being-strategic-xa0-2">Apple isn’t late to the game; it’s being strategic </h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="MuCaSbRUb9nUjqD4WgGaii" name="nearby-share-neardrop-galaxy-z-fold-5-macbok-pro-iphone-15-pro-max.jpg" alt="Nearby Share on Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MuCaSbRUb9nUjqD4WgGaii.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>However, give credit where it’s due. While most people might think Apple is silly for not having a foldable in the market yet, there is a very smart reason why. The company wants to avoid putting out a shoddy and lackluster product. Maybe the new iPhones are iterative in nature, but I know that if Apple were to release a foldable, it’d be a quality phone. </p><p>Jiitesh Ubrani, research manager for IDC&apos;s worldwide device tracker, agrees, indicating that “Apple often isn’t the first to the game, but it does tend to offer some of the best and well-thought solutions.”</p><p>Neil Shah, vice president of research at Counterpoint Research, also added that Apple (and likely other manufacturers) consider many components before releasing a product. </p><p>“It’s a question of getting the product definition, positioning, durability, and experience right,” he said. “There are multiple factors, which Apple needs to consider before jumping into foldables to maintain the standardization and scale at a global level from silicon to software to devices.”</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>Apple often isn’t the first to the game, but it does tend to offer some of the best and well-thought solutions.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>So, is Apple too late to the game, particularly when companies like Samsung are now in their 6th generation of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">foldable phones</a>?</p><p>“Foldables, even in 2026, will only account for less than 3% of the global smartphone volumes (this is assuming only Android foldables exist). However, a folding iPhone would be a great way for Apple to further increase average selling prices and address an ultra-premium segment of the market that is currently being served by Android brands,” he said. </p><p>In the scenario where Apple decides to have a foldable device, it will likely be a premium phone and “not something that the average consumer would afford initially unless Apple continues to offer great trade-in programs or financing options like they currently do.”</p><p>Take the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.tomsguide.com/computing/smart-glasses/apple-vision-pro-review">Apple Vision Pro</a>, for example. There are plenty of consumer <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/best-vr-headsets">VR headsets</a> in the industry that do not cost an arm and leg, but Apple decided to launch a $3,500 headset for its first iteration of a new device in this category, priced well beyond what an average consumer might pay.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="dNhxa3KRfjRfNt5ZJdBeb3" name="Apple-Vision-Pro-Viva-Tech-demo.jpg" alt="Using the Apple Vision Pro at Viva Tech 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dNhxa3KRfjRfNt5ZJdBeb3.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4080" height="2295" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>However, Hoyos, Howe, and Mar all make interesting points. While I am incredibly bored with the Apple ecosystem and its lack of ingenuity with newer phones, I am intrigued by Apple potentially releasing a foldable. </p><p>Still, I haven’t been excited about an iPhone for a while now, and I’ve asked myself the same question: would I switch if Apple released a foldable?</p><p>No. </p><p>Meanwhile, I have been <em>very </em>excited about the Android foldable ecosystem. So perhaps it’s time for me to officially switch over to Android-based devices permanently. I’ll leave that story for another time. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/former-iphone-users-discuss-interest-in-apple-foldable</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ We interviewed former iPhone users who have switched to Android, asking if they would move back if Apple launched a foldable phone. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">7K7DptRqAhQUTGS64Av24i</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MuCaSbRUb9nUjqD4WgGaii.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 15:00:40 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ shruti.shekar@futurenet.com (Shruti Shekar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MuCaSbRUb9nUjqD4WgGaii.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Nearby Share on Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Nearby Share on Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung Quick Share now lets you double up on your daily file sharing ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung has updated Quick Share for Galaxy devices, doubling the daily file-sharing limit for QR codes and links.</li><li>For remote sharing via web links or QR codes, the limit was 5GB per file and 5GB total per day, but this is now increased to 10GB per file and 10GB total per day.</li><li>The update improves user experience with clearer device names and total file size info in transfer pop-ups.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Samsung has rolled out a new update for the Quick Share app, doubling the daily file-sharing limit for the QR code and link options.</p><p>For the uninitiated, Quick Share is a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-use-nearby-share-your-android-phone">handy app that makes it super easy to transfer files</a> between nearby Android devices and Windows computers. And there&apos;s no limit on how many files you can send or how big they are, giving you complete freedom to share as much as you need.</p><p>Meanwhile, if you need to send files to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phones</a> or Windows devices that aren&apos;t close by or in your contacts, Quick Share lets you do so via web links or QR codes. Keep in mind, though, that each file can&apos;t be bigger than 5GB, and you can only transfer up to 5GB in total per day using this method.</p><p>Starting this week, Samsung is doubling the daily transfer limit to 10GB and increasing the individual file size limit to 10GB. This update was first spotted and shared by @theonecid on X (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.sammobile.com/news/samsung-quick-share-file-transfer-limit-increased-10gb/" target="_blank">SamMobile</a>).</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">New Quick Share 😳Increased daily file size from 5GB to 10GB!! pic.twitter.com/jxS97uVauR<a href="https://twitter.com/theonecid/status/1819558441192399282">August 3, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>This increase will definitely <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/embargo-19-1pm-et-quick-share-becomes-a-true-airdrop-alternative-with-support-for-all-android-and-chrome-os-devices">make sharing large files easier and improve the overall user experience</a>. It&apos;s a game-changer, in particular, for anyone dealing with large files. It’s a big win for pros in graphic design, video editing, and photography, making their work much more efficient and convenient.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:868px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:86.41%;"><img id="JbEqhBZ6dpNY3x3nvuR4Ej" name="samsung-quick-share-update-log.jpg" alt="Quick Share update log" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JbEqhBZ6dpNY3x3nvuR4Ej.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="868" height="750" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: @theonecid / X)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The update further improves the user experience with clearer device identification, showing device names on two lines for nearby devices. Plus, the incoming file transfer pop-up now shows the total file size, so you know exactly what’s coming in.</p><p>The latest Quick Share update, version 13.6.51.13, is now live on the Galaxy Store. Samsung says it’s rolling out gradually but should be available to everyone in the next few days.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-quick-share-now-lets-you-double-up-on-your-daily-file-sharing</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Quick Share now lets you share double the files each day with links and QR codes. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">eua7oJW3zPTu4df4K4LSTF</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zPZCNRKLbNCUErQThBym5S.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 12:32:06 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zPZCNRKLbNCUErQThBym5S.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung quick share interface on a smartphone]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung quick share interface on a smartphone]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Check out the Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold flaunting its official case in the wild ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The Pixel 9 Pro Fold was spotted at a Starbucks in Taiwan, confirming earlier leaks.</li><li>The device was seen in an official Google case with the familiar "G" logo.</li><li>The Pixel 9 Pro Fold has a sleek Obsidian black color, paired with a contrasting Porcelain finish case.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>The leaks keep pouring in for Google’s next Pixel lineup, and the latest one gives us a real-life look at the Pixel 9 Pro Fold.</p><p>As Google’s big August 13 launch event gets closer, the mystery around its new products is pretty much gone. Tons of leaks have flooded in, giving us all the details about the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9">Pixel 9</a> series, including that long-rumored foldable phone.</p><p>Most recently, the Pixel 9 Pro Fold has reportedly been seen in action at a Starbucks in Taiwan, and the sighting was shared with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/pixel-9-pro-fold-leak-starbucks-3467562/" target="_blank">Android Authority</a>. It seems the phone was in one of the official cases Google plans to release with it, sporting the familiar "G" logo that we&apos;ve come to associate with Pixel devices.</p><p>The person using the device had it propped up on a stand, showing off the rear panel to the camera. Even with the case on, the unique design of the Pixel 9 Pro Fold was unmistakable, making it clear what device it was.</p><p>The device itself is dressed in a sleek Obsidian black, one of the expected color options for the Pixel 9 Pro Fold. The case, in contrast, sports a Porcelain finish. These color choices match the rumors we’ve been hearing.</p><p>As seen in the picture, the phone flaunts the same <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-confirms-the-pixel-9-pro-fold-is-real-in-official-tease">quirky camera setup and sleek curved front display we’ve seen in official teasers</a> and leaks, and it’s impressively slim. The camera bump isn&apos;t as noticeable as we thought, probably thanks to the case it&apos;s in.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:73.70%;"><img id="weEZxxKzBUrkuFSzr6GdW8" name="Google-Pixel-9-Pro-Fold-leak.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro fold with official case seen in public" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/weEZxxKzBUrkuFSzr6GdW8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1000" height="737" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The original Pixel Fold was a solid first try, but it had its hiccups like any new piece of hardware. Naturally, expectations for the next version are through the roof. The Pixel 9 Pro Fold could shake up the market, going head-to-head with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">leading foldable phones</a>.</p><p>We&apos;ll have to wait for the full reveal to make a final call, but from the looks of it, it&apos;s already shaping up to be a strong competitor.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/check-out-the-google-pixel-9-pro-fold-flaunting-its-official-case-in-the-wild</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Someone's out and about with the new Pixel 9 Pro Fold, and it's got the full Google protection. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">zDzyNHvXbJXdXfXFfSTgBm</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FsYx3qzboUzTS7HKa5gJW5.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 23:40:24 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FsYx3qzboUzTS7HKa5gJW5.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Obsidian Google Pixel Fold closed]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Obsidian Google Pixel Fold closed]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Telegram drops a Web3 upgrade for its built-in browser ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Telegram updates its in-app browser, brings a new bottom bar while browsing, and adds features like support to Web3.</li><li>The messaging platform further added a new "Apps" tab in search to find its popular mini apps.</li><li>Other nifty additions are also seen for the Stories feature as part of the new update.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Telegram has rolled out a major update to its messaging platform that introduces several new features, such as an in-app browser with Web3 support and a mini app store.</p><p>New updates to the in-app browser include the ability to collapse and reopen with a new bottom bar. The goal is to make navigating the app as easy as possible while also preserving browser content. For example, if a user receives a notification while reading in the browser, they can respond without losing their place. The browser also supports features such as instant article viewing and bookmarking.</p>
<div class="looped-video"><video class="lazyload-in-view lazyloading" data-src="https://telegram.org/file/400780400224/2/jqbHSFRXZfQ.7339277.mp4/b9a5db90c5ecf53405" autoplay loop muted playsinline src="https://telegram.org/file/400780400224/2/jqbHSFRXZfQ.7339277.mp4/b9a5db90c5ecf53405"></video></div>
<p>In the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://telegram.org/blog/w3-browser-mini-app-store">announcement post</a>, the company notes that the browser will also support decentralized websites hosted on TON (The Open Network), an in-house developed open internet. It further makes Web3 accessible to around one billion monthly users on the messaging platform.</p><p>Another interesting feature of the new update is the Mini App Store. Telegram says that out of its 950 million users, at least 500 million interact with mini-apps every month. To complement them, Telegram is now adding a new "Apps" tab in the Search section, showcasing the list of apps users use alongside the popular apps available on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-messaging-apps">messaging platform</a>. It further allows users to quickly access games and services, which is in addition to finding something new to play around with.</p>
<div class="looped-video"><video class="lazyload-in-view lazyloading" data-src="https://telegram.org/file/400780400928/1/bb7CeIf11Es.6604686.mp4/ea45ba121b84766f1d" autoplay loop muted playsinline src="https://telegram.org/file/400780400928/1/bb7CeIf11Es.6604686.mp4/ea45ba121b84766f1d"></video></div>
<p>For app developers, Telegram allows them to upload "video demos and screenshots" of their mini-app previews to give platform users what to expect from the respective app. </p><p>"Mini apps can now generate custom story content—like AI-generated videos, achievements, or snapshots of leaderboards—for users to share as a Telegram Story right from the mini app."</p><p>Telegram Stars is another fun way to interact with friends on the messaging app. With this update, users will be able to gift stars to their contacts, with which the recipients can purchase digital goods in mini apps or have access to paid content in select channels. Users can head to Settings> My Stars to see their stars.</p>
<div class="looped-video"><video class="lazyload-in-view lazyloading" data-src="https://telegram.org/file/400780400676/1/yDZoLCZ9bKQ.3403169.mp4/6e2b8eca9d3a23cc64" autoplay loop muted playsinline src="https://telegram.org/file/400780400676/1/yDZoLCZ9bKQ.3403169.mp4/6e2b8eca9d3a23cc64"></video></div>
<p>Suppose you often record video messages on the Telegram app. In that case, the messaging service will <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://telegram.org/file/400780400798/1/VgYgplyJ3G4.6475691.mp4/be34647913f92219f7">allow users to use</a> their front flash. This means the display lights up with a white screen, giving users extra light when recording in the dark.</p><p>Lastly, other nifty additions in the latest update include adding a new weather widget in Telegram Stories and giving a thumbnail for a video story, which Telegram calls it cover photo.</p><p>Telegram says these new updates, along with the mobile, are also available on the Mac OS, especially the new browser next to games, mini-apps, instant view pages, and access to Web3.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/telegram-rolls-out-bunch-of-new-features-in-july-update</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Telegram is beefing up its in-app browser, launching a mini app store, and adding fresh features to Stories. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">R7G2stJyxPur4sayG43gFi</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Nm2iJhbJ3PDgcxQCo2XRKM.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 22:08:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Nm2iJhbJ3PDgcxQCo2XRKM.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Telegram]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Telegram browser update]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Telegram browser update]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>