<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 01:10:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Galaxy AI makes its debut on Samsung's past-gen phones in One UI 6.1 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung announced it will begin rolling out its One UI 6.1 update, packed with Galaxy AI for past-gen devices, on March 28 in the U.S.</li><li>The update brings Google's "Circle to Search," Live Translate, Chat Assist, and Generative Edit.</li><li>Galaxy AI is now available on the Galaxy S23 series, Galaxy S23 FE, Galaxy Z Flip 5, Fold 5, and Tab S9 series.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Samsung will begin rolling out its major One UI 6.1 update starting Thursday (Mar. 28), which brings its AI software to U.S.-based users.</p><p>According to a press release, owners of Samsung&apos;s past-gen devices should begin preparing to download and install the coming update. The Korean OEM states the update is on tap for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s23-ultra-review-understated-grandeur">Galaxy S23</a> series, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s23-fe-hands-on">Galaxy S23 FE</a>, Galaxy Z <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-5-review">Flip 5</a>, Fold 5, and Tab S9 series. The update brings these past-gen devices closer to the experience of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review">Galaxy S24</a> series.</p><p>One UI 6.1 features the company&apos;s Galaxy AI software throughout, delivering several on-device features. Kickstarting the update is Google&apos;s "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-circle-to-search-ai-powered-multisearch-rollout">Circle to Search</a>." Users can run a search based on anything on their Android device without switching to Chrome or another Google-created app.</p><p>Users of past-gen devices can now circle, scribble, highlight, or tap items in images to find more information through Google Search. Moreover, you can write your own query to help guide the search.</p><p>Live Translate is another feature One UI 6.1 brings, enabling users to experience real-time translations during phone calls.</p><p>Chat Assist and Samsung&apos;s Generative Edit arrive to bring some utility to what its Galaxy device owners can utilize. The former, available through the Samsung Keyboard, can help users adjust their "message tone" and translate messages in 13 languages. Generative Edit&apos;s arrival is said to help users "customize their photos" with resizing, removal, and other AI tools for image enhancements.</p><p>Galaxy AI through One UI 6.1 will start rolling out on March 28 on the previously mentioned past-gen devices. Samsung states the update will roll out on devices sold through various carriers like AT&T, T-Mobile, Verizon, and USCC.</p><p>Additionally, devices purchased through Amazon, Best Buy, and more will also receive the update.</p><p>Samsung reiterates in its press release that certain Galaxy AI features, like Circle to Search, require an internet connection. The company also informs users that its Galaxy AI features are free, but the company will look to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-plans-to-charge-for-certain-galaxy-ai-features-after-two-years">start charging for them</a> in 2026.</p>
<ul><li> <strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-one-ui-6-1-galaxy-ai-announcement</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung announced it will begin rolling out One UI 6.1 and Galaxy AI features this week in the U.S. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">58F7QxW9DLy5hxssSFEKk3</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/k8uq6C3DgSNoTTnwmaav7V.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/k8uq6C3DgSNoTTnwmaav7V.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Using Google Circle to Search on a Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Using Google Circle to Search on a Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung brings a refreshed Galaxy Tab S6 Lite with minor changes ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung announces the Galaxy Tab S6 Lite (2024) model globally.</li><li>While it looks much like the predecessor model, it packs a new chipset underneath.</li><li>The chipset is believed to be the same Exynos 1280 that powered the Galaxy A53 5G.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Putting an end to multiple leaks and rumors, Samsung finally introduced the third interaction of its Galaxy Tab S6 Lite.</p><p>In an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://news.samsung.com/global/samsung-galaxy-tab-s6-lite-2024-style-and-function-in-a-compact-package">announcement post</a>, Samsung shared the details of the Galaxy Tab S6 Lite (2024) model, which comes as the successor to the model released in 2022 with the same moniker. Samsung says that the new tablet is “a stylish offering designed for both work and play. “</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1146px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:52.36%;"><img id="Wsz292gmpAdy25ceMPiqgU" name="samsung-galaxy-tab-s6-lite-2024-render-02.jpg" alt="Galaxy Tab S6 Lite (2024) in Mint" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Wsz292gmpAdy25ceMPiqgU.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1146" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: 91mobiles)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>On the design front, the new tablet doesn’t have significant changes compared to the predecessor model. It still packs in the same 10.4-inch screen on the front with 2000 x 1200 resolution, and the device, on the whole, measures 7mm in thickness. </p><p>The tablet comes in Wi-Fi and LTE models, weighing around 465 grams and 467 grams, respectively. The color options include Oxford Gray, Chiffon Pink, and Mint, the new color that the company is offering for the first time.</p><p>The Galaxy Tab S6 Lite (2024) is powered by an octa-core CPU with clock speeds at 2.4GHz. While Samsung doesn’t mention the chipset in the announcement, it is believed that the Exynos 1280 powered Samsung phones like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/samsung-galaxy-a53-5g-review">Galaxy A53 5G</a>. The storage options include 4GB of RAM and up to 128GB of onboard storage with additional microSD support for up to 1TB.</p><p>Keeping the lights on the tablet is a massive 7040mAh battery capacity, which promises at least 14 hours of non-stop video playback. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="2mUzX3xLKx96HmJkbLi3RU" name="samsung-galaxy-tab-s6-lite-2024-render.jpg" alt="Galaxy Tab S6 Lite (2024) in Mint" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2mUzX3xLKx96HmJkbLi3RU.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: 91mobiles)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Samsung is emphasizing the S-Pen support on the Galaxy Tab S6 Lite (2024), as it claims to lift the productivity aspect with the help of Samsung Notes on the large screen tablet as users would be able to take notes even without unlocking the device, which is familiar on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review">Galaxy S24 Ultra</a>, and other preceding Ultra models that come with built S-Pen.</p><p>While the tablet doesn’t feature a built-in S-Pen, it comes bundled and sticks to the device, and no separate charging is necessary. Samsung notes that users can take advantage of the large screen for efficient multitasking.</p><p>Other notable highlights of the device include dual speakers powered by AKG, Dolby Atmos, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review">Android 14</a>, a single 8MP primary rear camera, and a 5MP selfie shooter.</p><p>While Samsung is assigning the Galaxy Tab S6 Lite (2024) model as a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-tabletshttps://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-android-tablet">mid-range Android tablet</a> for young professionals, students, and families alike, its pricing and availability in the regions have yet to be determined. </p><p>Users have to bear in mind that the storage options alongside the color options may change based on their regions when the tablet becomes widely available, which could begin on March 28, 2024.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Tablet deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/ipad-tablets-ereaders/tablets/pcmcat209000050008.c?id=pcmcat209000050008"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/search?q=tablet"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/tablets-laptops-computers-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=tablet&crid=2HCFROTF588S1&sprefix=tablet%2Caps%2C159&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.dell.com/en-us/search/tablet"><u><strong>Dell</strong></u></a><strong> |</strong></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/samsung-galaxy-tab-s6-lite-2024-announced</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ After two years, Samsung finally introduced a new iteration, the Galaxy Tab S6 Lite. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">kvKwqHd2yj4Nbe9P7ajG8U</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vrP4P5eoRLs5B2ykEY8BtE.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 21:25:01 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vrP4P5eoRLs5B2ykEY8BtE.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Samsung]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Galaxy Tab S6 Lite (2024)]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Galaxy Tab S6 Lite (2024)]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Chat finally picks up voice messages as its rollout begins ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google is rolling out user's "highly requested" voice messages feature in Chat.</li><li>Users can tap the microphone icon in a chat or group thread in the app with the option to re-record if needed before sending.</li><li>Unfortunately, Google left out personal accounts from voice messages in Chat, meaning Enterprise customers are first in line.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google is beginning to roll out a new update to Chat today (Mar. 26) that brings a long-awaited messaging feature to the platform.</p><p>Google Chat now supports voice messages on its platform, according to a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://workspaceupdates.googleblog.com/2024/03/send-voice-messages-in-google-chat.html">Workspace update</a>. The company states that the feature will only be available on mobile devices with this rollout as it continues to develop a version for desktops. Google states that voice messages in Chat should help users "convey more information" and deliver more emphasis.</p><p>Users on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android</a> and iOS can tap the microphone icon beside the image option in a one-on-one or group chat. Chat will begin recording audio; when you&apos;re done, you&apos;ll have the chance to listen to it and re-record if there are mistakes. After that, users can send their recordings.</p><p>Those you&apos;re chatting with can quote, react, and reply to it within a thread. Google teased that it&apos;s also working on adding voice message transcriptions, which should arrive "in the coming months."</p><p>Unfortunately, Google has left personal account holders out of its rollout of voice messages in Chat. The company states Enterprise Essentials, Enterprise Essentials Plus, Enterprise Standard, and Enterprise Plus users are eligible to receive it.</p><p>Users on Google&apos;s rapid release schedule will see voice messages arrive today (Mar. 26). They should give the process at least 15 days to complete. Google will shift to the "Scheduled Release" domains on April 15.</p><p>Admins of the previously mentioned domains will find that voice messages are turned on by default.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:294px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:204.08%;"><img id="KcEFAfhUPVZRPQPdgeXYd3" name="google-chat-voice-messages-rollout.jpg" alt="Google has started rolling out voice messages in Chat." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KcEFAfhUPVZRPQPdgeXYd3.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="294" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:293px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:204.78%;"><img id="ensHfZqRquQH3yQQz6UB68" name="google-chat-voice-messages-in-thread.jpg" alt="Users in a Google Chat thread can reply, react, and quote voice messages." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ensHfZqRquQH3yQQz6UB68.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="293" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Google has been working on voice messages in Chat for a while now, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-chat-voice-messages-spotted">an interview</a> with the company also stated that its customers had requested the feature quite often. Google stated that a feature like this would help further evolve Chat from a simple text-based app to one that supports multimedia modalities.</p><p>Chat also picked up <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-chat-for-android-gets-starred-messages-feature">an update in February</a> that brought it closer to Messages as users can now "Star" messages. Starring messages in Chat enables folks to rediscover them through search and spot what&apos;s important easily using its bright star icon. Searching for saved or "starred" messages joins users&apos; ability to discover mentions in the app.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-chat-voice-messages-mobile-rollout</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google Chat has started rolling out voice messages to users on mobile. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">qimSbqA9mk9goSFmGQZYvU</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pTFT5tahw4qCHXi2NqSn5M.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 20:13:15 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pTFT5tahw4qCHXi2NqSn5M.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Chat overflow menu on mobile]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Chat overflow menu on mobile]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The latest Galaxy S24 update brings even more camera improvements ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung has started pushing its second camera update for the Galaxy S24 series in Europe.</li><li>The update attempts to improve its low-light capabilities once again, alongside exposure fixes and more support for videos shot in Slow Mo mode.</li><li>The Galaxy S24's first camera update landed in February, bringing image quality and sharpness improvements.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Samsung has started pushing its latest major camera update to its Galaxy S24 series today (Mar. 26).</p><p>As spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.sammobile.com/news/galaxy-s24-april-2024-update-camera-improvements-europe/">SamMobile</a>, the latest update is available for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-hands-on">S24</a> trio in Europe, bearing version number S92xBXXU1AXCA. With a focus on its cameras, Samsung&apos;s changelog states it has improved the S24&apos;s white balance accuracy and exposure for its cameras.</p><p>Low light image quality is another area that is receiving an update today. Samsung threw in a few more camera updates, which include the following:</p>
<ul><li>Text clarity in high-zoom shots.</li><li>Color accuracy in the ExpertRAW camera app.</li><li>Support for videos with 480×480 pixels resolution in the Instant Slow Mo feature.</li></ul>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:206px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:291.26%;"><img id="Q9NXstPF6ZNz5dPvdeacVD" name="samsung-galaxy-s24-march-camera-patch.jpg" alt="Samsung's changelog for the latest camera patch for the Galaxy S24 series." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Q9NXstPF6ZNz5dPvdeacVD.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="206" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: SamMobile)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>This Galaxy S24 update is hefty, arriving with an approximate 920MB download size. Samsung&apos;s patch notes add that the device has also picked up the April 2024 security patch with these camera improvements. Neither Samsung nor Google have detailed what the April security patch contains just yet.</p><p>Those in Europe should begin noticing the patch today (Mar. 26). With that, it should only be a matter of time before those in other regions, like the U.S., begin picking it up. The patch has also been spotted <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.sammobile.com/news/huge-galaxy-s24-update-improve-camera-quality-released-india/">rolling out in India</a>. If you&apos;d like to check manually, you can head into <strong>Settings > Software Update > Download & Install.</strong></p><p>This is the second camera patch Samsung has created for the Galaxy S24 series, as the first <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-galaxy-s24-series-get-february-security-patch">landed in February</a>. The Korean OEM fine-tuned the image quality and sharpness that its latest flagship launch could provide. The update attempted to improve the low light capabilities of the S24, but it looks like more was required, as we&apos;re seeing it mentioned again.</p><p>That patch also introduced the company&apos;s new Vivid display slider for folks unhappy with the changed profile on the S24 trio.</p><p>Meanwhile, we&apos;re still waiting for the large One UI 6.1 update to drop for Samsung&apos;s past-gen devices, which <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/signs-point-to-a-one-ui-61-rollout-coming-this-week">might happen soon</a>. A notification from Samsung teased the update in China, stating it could arrive on March 28. It&apos;s still unclear when other regions could see the update, but at least it&apos;s on the way.</p>
<ul><li> <strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="e0bc6ff2-7906-41f5-b7ed-4a4dba904bfb">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.52%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QQfCey54Mda248SVrvmGSn.jpg' alt='The yellow Galaxy S24 Ultra'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>A vivacious return to the top</strong></em></p>
<p>Samsung's Galaxy S24 Ultra, much like the entire series, is packed full of the company's Galaxy AI software. The device offers a range of on-device tools, capable of handling simple tasks like summarizing long pieces of text and live translations. The S24 Ultra still delivers a stunning, immersive display and multiple cameras strong enough for clear photos and videos.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-march-camera-update</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung has started rolling out its second camera update for the Galaxy S24 series. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">w75A93aL7QL6AN5dwbCyVB</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YEvRkm3AKzKNVWSMzh3gZM.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 19:35:29 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YEvRkm3AKzKNVWSMzh3gZM.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[null]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The back of the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra in the Titanium Grey colorway]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The back of the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra in the Titanium Grey colorway]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Chrome gets optimized for Arm-compatible Windows devices ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google announced the arrival of an upgraded variation of Chrome for Windows PCs and laptops that are Arm-compatible.</li><li>This browser has received increases in performance alongside several built-in security enhancements.</li><li>Google is preparing for Qualcomm's Snapdragon X Elite chip, which should boost Chrome's power later this year.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google is rolling out a new version of Chrome for Windows PCs supercharged by Qualcomm&apos;s Snapdragon chip.</p><p>According to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.google/products/chrome/download-google-chrome-windows-pc-arm/">Google</a>, this new variant of Chrome for Windows supports Arm-based devices. The company states this upgraded browser experience should help users engage with a "faster and smoother" Chrome.</p><p>As users discover the upgraded browser on Windows desktops and laptops, Google states there&apos;s more in store beyond browser performance.</p><p>The post adds that users will receive stronger built-in security and access to Google&apos;s generative AI features, extensions, and themes to decorate the browser.</p><p>Google teased that the purpose behind its new Chrome variant for Arm-compatible computers is in preparation for Qualcomm&apos;s Snapdragon X Elite. The company states it expects the browser to receive an even larger performance boost once the chip arrives.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1999px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="pm7fGJSzuhYvPj8uQtdEUQ" name="qualcomm-snapdragon-x-elite-1.jpg" alt="Qualcomm Snapdragon X Elite touchscreen device" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pm7fGJSzuhYvPj8uQtdEUQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1999" height="1124" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Qualcomm)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In response to Google&apos;s new Chrome, Qualcomm&apos;s president and CEO Cristiano Amon stated, "The new version of Google Chrome will help cement Snapdragon X Elite&apos;s role as the premier platform for Windows computing starting in mid-2024."</p><p>Qualcomm is going all in on AI with its upcoming Snapdragon X Elite chipset, and Google <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/qualcomm-is-betting-its-future-on-ai-and-google-could-benefit-the-most">seems poised</a> to join the journey. The chipmaker is pairing its X Elite chip with its new, stronger Oryon CPU. The chip has been estimated to achieve a CPU speed 2x faster than the competition and AI processing 4.5 times quicker.</p><p>There is hope that Google continues to plug Qualcomm&apos;s new X Elite in more places, namely its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-chromebook">Chromebook</a> line, for a massive performance boost.</p><p>Elsewhere, many of the generative AI features Arm-compatible PCs and laptops are preparing to receive include "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/embargo-222-12pm-et-google-chrome-update-brings-help-me-write-and-generative-ai-to-any-website">Help me write</a>." Chrome&apos;s AI update in February lets Workspace users utilize its generative AI software&apos;s "experimental writing AI" to assist them with drafting articles of text. Additionally, users can use information on web pages to help the AI bot form its response to your writing queries.</p>
<ul><li> <strong>Chromebook deals:</strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/browse/electronics/google-chromebooks/3944_3951_1089430_1230091_1103213"><u><strong> Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> |</strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/searchpage.jsp?id=pcat17071&st=chromebook"><u><strong> Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> |</strong><a href="https://www.lenovo.com/us/en/d/chromebook-laptop/"><u><strong> Lenovo</strong></u></a><strong> |</strong><a href="https://www.hp.com/us-en/shop/mlp/laptops/chromebook-344506--1"><u><strong> HP</strong></u></a><strong> |</strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/8667F8E9-10FC-4DCC-AB6A-97566CE718A5?ingress=0&visitId=46ceb076-1b26-4ec4-8324-90885a489a11"><u><strong> Amazon</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/chrome-chrome-windows-arm-optimization-rollout</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google rolled out a new version of Chrome with support for all Arm-based Windows computers. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">iAy4WMV5EM88AqPMqxkPP5</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yW898rfyAU8H93z54gtmpN.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 19:24:23 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yW898rfyAU8H93z54gtmpN.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Chris Wedel / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Chrome lifestyle]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Chrome lifestyle]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Pixel 6a listing removed from Google Store ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The Google Pixel 6a has been removed from the US Google Store sale.</li><li>Shoppers are being redirected to the Pixel 7a listing instead.</li><li>The Pixel 8a is expected imminently, with rumors suggesting Google’s I/O event in May as a likely launch date.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>The release of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-6a-review">Google Pixel 6a</a> marked Google’s first foray into the more affordable sector of the phone market with its refreshed Pixel range. At the time, the handset was very well-received, offering many of the features of its more expensive siblings at a much more affordable price. Having subsequently been replaced by the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-7a-review">Pixel 7a</a>, it appears that the time is drawing near for us to bid the Pixel 6a a fond farewell.</p><p>As spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.droid-life.com/2024/03/25/google-stops-selling-pixel-6a/">Droid Life</a> (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/google-pixel-6a-removed-store-3428543/">Android Authority</a>), the Pixel 6a has been removed from sale on the official US Google Store at some point in the last few days. The phone is no longer available on the site, and if you attempt to access it via an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://store.google.com/gb/config/pixel_7a?hl=en-GB&selections=eyJwcm9kdWN0RmFtaWx5IjoiY0dsNFpXeGZOMkU9In0%3D">old URL</a>, you’ll find yourself on the page for the newer Pixel 7a instead. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="YgCoruYwPuJQaXupVMkJmA" name="Google-Pixel-8a-leak.jpg" alt="Pixel 8a hands-on leak" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YgCoruYwPuJQaXupVMkJmA.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Abhishek Yadav/ via X)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While the Pixel 6a is unlikely to be a big seller at this stage of its life cycle, the fact it has quietly disappeared indicates that Google is ready to send it to a farm upstate in preparation for a newer device. This is, in all likelihood, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a">Pixel 8a</a>, which is hotly anticipated to be unveiled shortly. </p><p>A recent report confirmed that a new Google handset – almost certainly the Pixel 8a – has been spotted in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-reaches-us-fcc-listing">FCC databases</a>, lending further weight to its imminent release. The working assumption is that the 8a will be revealed at Google’s I/O event in early May 2024. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-leaked-display-upgrade">Other rumors</a> suggest it will be a significant upgrade over the Pixel 7a, which could make it almost as good as the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-review">Pixel 8</a>.</p><p>In the meantime, anyone who wants to get their hands on a Pixel 6a can still do so from some other retailers, just not directly from Google. The alternative is to consider getting the Pixel 7a, now the only budget handset available on the Google Store. But, given how soon the Pixel 8a is expected to come out, it may be worth hanging on for a few more weeks to see what that handset offers.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/pixel-6a-listing-removed-from-google-store</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Pixel 6a has finally been removed from the Google store, which is a clear sign that the Pixel 8a is about to be revealed. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Fy3mTWtBAhzGaC5hvvLB6P</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/r8qBJtWbXaH8yFjMSEteGc.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 19:10:14 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ stevenshaw444@gmail.com (Steven Shaw) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/r8qBJtWbXaH8yFjMSEteGc.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[null]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The home screen of the Google Pixel 6a with wallpaper from Backdrops]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The home screen of the Google Pixel 6a with wallpaper from Backdrops]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Meta Quest 3: Everything you need to know ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>To some, the Meta Quest 3 is the best VR headset available, hitting the right balance between next-gen tech upgrades and affordable compromises. To others, it&apos;s too expensive compared to the Quest 2 or not powerful enough against the premium Apple Vision Pro. </p><p>We&apos;ve followed the Quest 3 closely since its late 2023 launch, tracking all of its updates, new games, and controversies. Aside from sharing all the specs and comparisons to other headsets, we&apos;ll share everything that new Quest 3 owners or prospective buyers should know about the headset.</p><p>If you want a more personal breakdown of what it&apos;s like to use the Quest 3, you can read our <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-3-review">Meta Quest 3 review</a> for all the highs and lows. In particular, we praised the upgraded mixed-reality passthrough in full color, the more ergonomic controllers, and the revamped graphical power, while noting some design issues and poor battery life.</p><p>Below, we&apos;ll focus instead on all of the raw numbers, prices, accessories, and so on, to help you decide if it&apos;s worth upgrading to the new headset.</p>

<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-meta-quest-3-price-and-availability"><span>Meta Quest 3: Price and availability</span></h2>
<p>The Meta Quest 3 became publicly available on October 10, 2023. The base 128GB Quest 3 costs $499 / £479 / €549, while the 512GB model is $649 / £619 / €699. </p><p>Aside from storage, you won&apos;t find any other differences, except that all 512GB Quest 3 buyers get six months of free <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-plus-subscription">Meta Quest Plus</a>, an $8/month subscription that gives you two Quest games for free, as chosen by Meta.</p><p>We have a guide comparing the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-3-128gb-vs-512gb">128GB vs. 512GB Quest 3</a> that breaks down the decision. To summarize it briefly, most Quest 3 games measure about 2–3GB in size, but major releases can swell up to 10GB or more — especially with post-launch updates and DLC. 512GB is more than most people need, but if you choose the default 128GB model, you may have to delete games to make space.</p><p>Thankfully, Quest games support cloud storage, so if you do choose the 128GB Quest 3, you can make space in your library and redownload games later.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-meta-quest-3-design-and-display"><span>Meta Quest 3 design and display</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="mimFbEYQrczyqqaPkENH8f" name="Meta-Quest-3-hands-on-gasket-removed-angle.jpg" alt="The side of the new thinner Meta Quest 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mimFbEYQrczyqqaPkENH8f.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The most visible change to the Meta Quest 3 stems from its pancake lenses, which take up less space than the Quest 2&apos;s fresnel lenses by magnifying through thin, reflective mirrors instead of one thick layer. This makes the Quest 3 headset 40% skinnier in front. </p><p>Despite being skinnier, the Quest 3 <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/why-quest-3-weighs-more-than-quest-2">weighs slightly more than the Quest 2</a>, which Meta itself attributes to new components like the depth sensor, extra cameras, and depth adjuster. Thankfully, the weight distribution is much more balanced, meaning it&apos;s not all resting on your forehead and slowly creating pressure. </p><p>It&apos;s still going to feel heavy after a while, though. Like the Quest 2, the Quest 3 ships with a cloth strap with velcro to adjust the fit, instead of the built-in Elite Strap with rear padding and adjustment knob you get on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-pro-review">Quest Pro</a>. </p><p>Unlike the single Quest 2 strap, which could slide to one side of your head, the Quest 3 uses a split overhead strap design that gives you better support but "rubs on the top of your ears," according to our reviewer. </p><p>That&apos;s why we called a Quest 3 strap replacement the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/this-is-the-one-quest-3-accessory-you-actually-need">"one accessory you actually need."</a> It provides a more comfortable and secure fit, and you can even buy a strap with a built-in battery to improve the Quest 3&apos;s longevity. Since the Quest 3 has a modular design, installing a new strap should only take you a few minutes and doesn&apos;t require any expertise. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="nDBZV76enBKAZSWUdzjrQD" name="Meta-Quest-3-hands-on-headset-with-controllers-side-blue.jpg" alt="The USB-C port and power button on the left side of the Meta Quest 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nDBZV76enBKAZSWUdzjrQD.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>A subtle but vital upgrade from the Quest 2 is how you can change how close or far the lenses sit from your eyes, a function built into the facial interface. You&apos;ll choose between four options, with the furthest setting leaving enough room for you to wear glasses without a spacer. </p><p>Plus, there&apos;s the underrated perk that the full-color mixed-reality means you have fewer reasons to <em>take off</em> the headset and worry about adjusting the fit. You can simply double-tap the side to leave your game, see your surroundings, and resolve whatever real-world issue is happening. </p><p>Our one frustration with the new Quest 3 facial design is the lack of venting, which can cause the lenses to fog up from your face&apos;s heat. That&apos;s why you may want to buy a new facial interface that allows for better air circulation. </p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xfy42Q_i944" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>Moving on to the Meta Quest 3 display, it uses an LCD, a cost-saving measure that&apos;ll make its colors less vibrant than the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/sony-ps-vr2-review">PSVR 2</a>&apos;s OLED. Putting that aside, though, it&apos;s still a significant visual upgrade over the Quest 2: 2064 x 2208 pixels per eye instead of 1,920 by 1,832 pixels. That gives you an extra 445 pixels per inch (1,218) or 4 pixels per degree (25).</p><p>The PSVR 2&apos;s 2,000 by 2,040 pixels (800ppi) falls short, too, and that headset uses fresnel lenses with a trickier "sweet spot" than the Quest 3&apos;s pancake lenses. For comparison, Meta claims that the new lenses increase visual "sharpness" by 25% by creating "significantly fewer stray or scattered light artifacts." Our experience with the Quest 3&apos;s visual clarity thankfully lives up to Meta&apos;s marketing. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="34jWvW4mHM2HaXcBzLEbJC" name="Meta-Quest-3-hands-on-headset-lenses-02.jpg" alt="Looking closely at the lenses on the Meta Quest 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/34jWvW4mHM2HaXcBzLEbJC.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>We&apos;ll also point out that the passthrough resolution is 18 pixels per degree. That&apos;s 7 PPD fewer than its standard VR PPD, but 10X better than the Quest 2 and 3X better than the Quest Pro, enough to make your surroundings fully visible while wearing the headset. In our tests, we found we could read our phone or smartwatch screens without removing our headsets, though it&apos;s still a bit blurry.</p><p>Of course, if you compare the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/apple-vision-pro-vs-meta-quest-3">Apple Vision Pro vs. the Quest 3</a>, you&apos;ll find that the Vision Pro hits 3,386 pixels per inch or 34 pixels per degree, with micro-OLED displays that offer a gorgeous 92% of the DCI-P3 color gamut. But is this resolution boost worth paying an extra $3,000? Frankly, we&apos;re satisfied with what the Quest 3 brings to the table already.</p><p>As a final Quest 3 design point, the newer headset has a redesigned interpupillary distance (IPD) wheel with thirteen spacing settings at 1mm apart. The Quest 2 supported 56–70mm IPDs with three fixed settings, leaving plenty of users stuck with a less-than-ideal distance. Now, anyone from 53–75mm can use it, and finding the right lens spacing will be easier. </p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-meta-quest-3-specs"><span>Meta Quest 3 specs</span></h2>

<p>One of the main reasons to upgrade from the Quest 2 is the performance gap. The Quest 3&apos;s Snapdragon XR2 Gen 2 has twice as fast graphical performance and improved loading times compared to the Quest 2&apos;s Gen 1 chip. You also get an extra 2GB of RAM. </p><p>In practice, this allows developers to patch Quest 2 games to add better shadows, lighting, textures, and so on. Plus, of course, you get mixed-reality modes that the Quest 2 can&apos;t support with its low-res, black-and-white passthrough. </p><p>One thing that hasn&apos;t changed with the new generation: the Quest 3 battery life is just as short as the Quest 2&apos;s, if not worse. Meta estimates it lasts 2.2 hours per session or 2.4 hours for gaming, but we&apos;ve found it&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/how-long-does-the-quest-3-battery-last">usually close to 2 hours flat</a> unless you use a battery pack. Once dead, the Quest 3 takes two hours to recharge; it ships with an 18W power adapter and charging cable in the box. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="oGtnEn7cUewqXtPJPMCGGG" name="Meta-quest-3-pc-link-cable-01.jpg" alt="A Link cable connected to the USB-C port of the Meta Quest 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oGtnEn7cUewqXtPJPMCGGG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nick Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Qualcomm says this chip works with the new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/wi-fi-7-is-here-but-should-you-care">Wi-Fi 7</a> standard, but Meta has only promised <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wi-fi-6e-router">Wi-Fi 6E router</a> support thus far. The faster Wi-Fi should help with improved PC VR gaming, but you can still stick with a USB-C Link cable for the most reliable connection. </p><p>Meta improved the speaker quality for the Quest 3, claiming it hits a 40% louder volume with increased bass compared to the Quest 2. You still have the 3.5mm headphone jack for private audio and sparing your neighbors, but otherwise, you may not need to buy Quest 3 headphones if you&apos;re happy with the built-in solution. </p><p>If you own the Quest 2 or PSVR 2 and are considering buying this headset, we have guides on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/oculus-quest-2-vs-quest-3">Quest 3 vs. Quest 2</a> or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-3-vs-psvr-2">Quest 3 vs. PSVR 2</a> to help you decide. </p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-meta-quest-3-games"><span>Meta Quest 3 games</span></h2>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ljehojScnCQ" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>All of your Quest 2 games will transfer over to the Quest 3, as your account won&apos;t change. Our old list of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-oculus-quest-2-games">best Quest games</a> still applies to the new headset, and we can hope to see faster loading times for those games, too.</p><p>From now on, all of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/oculus-quest-2-games-launching-this-month">upcoming Quest games</a> will release simultaneously on the Quest 2 & 3. Although some of these games will have a unique Quest 3 patch with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/quest-3-vs-quest-2-graphics-upgrade">enhanced graphics</a>, that&apos;s not a guarantee. The enhanced Snapdragon chip will lower loading times automatically, but many developers cap refresh rates and assets with the Quest 2 in mind, since more people have the older headset.</p><p>For the most part, the only Quest 3 exclusives will be games that require full-color mixed reality, something the Quest 2 can&apos;t offer. </p><p>If you&apos;re a new Quest 3 owner, we&apos;ve recommended the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/best-quest-3-launch-games">five best Quest 3 launch titles</a> to get you started. </p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-meta-quest-3-accessories"><span>Meta Quest 3 accessories</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="iqYfySavJ2n2hS93o9QdJN" name="BoboVR-M2-quest-2-head-strap-replacing-battery.jpg" alt="Replacing the battery on the BoboVR M2 battery head strap for the Meta Quest 2" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/iqYfySavJ2n2hS93o9QdJN.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Thus far, Meta has announced these official Quest 3 accessories:</p>
<ul><li>Meta Quest 3 Silicone Facial Interface ($40)</li><li>Meta Quest Active Straps for Touch Plus Controllers ($40)</li><li>Zenni VR Prescription Lenses for Meta Quest 3 ($50)</li><li>Meta Quest 3 Elite Strap ($70)</li><li>Meta Quest 3 Carrying Case ($70)</li><li>Meta Quest Link Cable ($80)</li><li>Meta Quest 3 Elite Strap with Battery ($130)</li><li>Meta Quest 3 Charging Dock ($130)</li><li>Meta Quest Touch Pro Controllers ($300)</li></ul>
<p>Most of these names will look familiar. You&apos;ll buy these Quest 3 accessories to improve the battery life, store and charge the headset, play PC VR games, and so on. One new thing to note: you can now buy straps and facial interfaces in new colors like orange and blue, not just the usual white. </p><p>They&apos;re also quite expensive! And in one instance, Meta&apos;s Elite Strap with Battery had <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/quest-3-elite-strap-battery-charging-defect">a charging firmware issue</a> that required a recall. The current version for sale is fixed, but it still frustrated people that this expensive accessory didn&apos;t work as intended.</p><p>Thankfully, third-party Quest 3 accessory makers like BoboVR, AMVR, and KIWI Design have already made more affordable accessories, with more in the works for later this year. Check our guide on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/best-meta-quest-3-accessories">best Quest 3 accessories</a> to see where to get started. </p><p>Most of your old Quest 2 accessories <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/most-quest-2-accessories-wont-work-on-quest-3">won&apos;t work with the Quest 3</a>. Thanks to the redesigns to the new headset, most of this old tech won&apos;t fit properly. We know that some 3rd-party accessory makers like BoboVR have promised to release mod kits to make your old accessories work, but there&apos;s no guarantee every brand will do this.</p><p>So far, we know that your old <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-link-cable-alternative-oculus-quest-2">Link cables</a> should continue to work, if you don&apos;t want to rely on Air Link and the new Wi-Fi 6E capabilities for wireless PC VR. And if you own the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/are-quest-pro-controllers-worth-buying-for-quest-2">Quest Pro controllers</a> (normally $300), you can use those in place of the Quest 3 Touch Plus controllers. </p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-quest-3-post-launch-news"><span>Quest 3 post-launch news</span></h2>
<p>These are the main post-launch Quest 3 updates, announcements, and controversies that you&apos;ll want to know about!</p><p>After its early October launch, the Quest 3 received the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/quest-v59-update-adds-battery-saver-mode-fix">v59 software update</a> that added a battery saver mode, in Meta&apos;s attempt to counteract its short battery life. It also made it easier to set up a mixed-reality space automatically instead of drawing the space manually.</p><p>We learned in November 2023 that Meta <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/google-play-store-not-on-meta-quest-headsets">tried to get the Play Store on Quest headsets</a>, but Google didn&apos;t want to play ball. We learned later, during some <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/google-android-xr-meta">public Meta-Google beef</a>, that Google would only provide its apps if Meta agreed to make Quest headsets run fully on Android, with Google in control of software. Because of this, the Quest 3&apos;s productivity software continues to be meager compared to the Vision Pro&apos;s. </p><p>As part of this drama, Meta suddenly disabled Chromecasting at some point last year before <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/chromecasting-is-officially-back-on-meta-quest">restoring the feature</a> due to a flurry of Quest user complaints. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="b8k5H77TMKux3unQRpbMfk" name="meta-quest-pro-google-play-store-logo.jpg" alt="The Google Play Store logo on the lenses of a Meta Quest Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/b8k5H77TMKux3unQRpbMfk.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>We then learned that the Meta Quest 3 <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-3-manufacturing-cost">costs about $430 to make</a>, meaning that Meta barely makes any profit on headset sales and must recoup its investment in game and accessory sales. </p><p>In December, Meta released the v60 update with new Horizon Home environments and boundary fixes, but it also came with some <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-v60-slowdown-bug">behind-the-scenes bugs</a> slowing down game performance that took Meta some time to update. On the more positive front, this update <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-patches-quest-3-mic-issues-after-3-months">resolved longstanding mic issues</a> that plagued fans of social VR games. </p><p>With the February <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-62-update-spatial-video-gesture-controls">Quest v62 update</a> (Meta skipped v61), the Quest 3 made a ton of mixed-reality fixes and updates that seemed to directly target the recently-launched Apple Vision Pro, like support for iPhone 15 spatial videos and a pinch hand gesture. </p><p>Mark Zuckerberg proved later that month that Meta had Apple on its mind, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/zuckerberg-quest-3-better-product-period-than-vision-pro">"reviewing" the Apple Vision Pro</a> in a Threads video that bashed the rival headset and called the Quest 3 a "better product, period."</p><p>In March, Meta&apos;s CTO Andrew Bosworth started hinting about a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-ui-first-details">major Quest UI overhaul</a>, one that&apos;s yet to arrive. He hinted that it will provide a revamped keyboard and put a heavy emphasis on mixed reality, including stationary and pinned menus and apps.</p><p>Most recently, Meta unveiled a new AI-backed feature called SceneScript that will automatically map your room layout, including walls, doors, and furniture. It should make it a lot easier to play in different locations, without having to constantly redraw boundaries. </p>
<hr>
<p>The Meta Quest 3 costs $200 more than the Quest 2 did at launch. In exchange, it delivers significant visual, performance, and comfort upgrades across the board, maintains its wireless design despite the increased power demands, and adds mixed-reality apps. </p><p>Full-color mixed reality lets you tap out of games and clearly see your home space instead of a nauseating black-and-white blur. You can incorporate your surroundings <em>into</em> games like Supernatural, so you never need to worry about accidentally punching a wall. And some MR games make your physical space part of the experience. </p><p>We can assume that the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-4">Quest 4</a> will take another few years to arrive, but we&apos;ve also heard rumblings about a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-lite">Quest 3 Lite</a> with the same CPU but several major cuts to hit a $200 price tag, such as shipping without controllers. In theory, if the Quest 3 costs too much, you could wait for its cheaper sibling, so long as you&apos;re willing to accept the trade-offs. </p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="6cb5ebbb-f73c-4563-83c4-df52d66370a2">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/E75vg2n9urJXwhnVrgFvsQ.jpg' alt='Meta Quest 3 headset and controller render on a white background'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Meta Quest 3</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Meta's latest</strong></em></p>
<p>The Meta Quest 3 VR headset delivers powerful Snapdragon XR2 Gen 2 performance, a more balanced and comfortable design, full-color mixed reality, and one of the best VR displays we've ever seen. It arrives on October 10. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-3</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Meta Quest 3 is the best VR headset available today (yes, even better than the Apple Vision Pro, in our opinion). Here's what you should know about it.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">fsDeezaca2qLM2rQPCs3tP</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VjWv9mJEbFBxst6ToaqpGf.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 19:09:10 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VjWv9mJEbFBxst6ToaqpGf.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[null]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Meta Quest 3 with Touch Plus controllers and a coral color strap]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Meta Quest 3 with Touch Plus controllers and a coral color strap]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Max deal takes 40% OFF an entire year of streaming — here's what you need to know ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>If you&apos;re on the hunt for something good to watch, Max just launched a streaming deal that you seriously shouldn&apos;t miss. From now through April 9th, if you pay for a year of streaming in advance you&apos;ll <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.max.com/"><strong>score a massive 42% discount</strong></a><em>. </em>And that goes for any plan, from the no-frills "With Ads" tier to the premium "Ultimate Ad-Free" option. In other words, you could an entire year of Max streaming for as little as $69.99 (or $5.83/month).</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="6bf5990b-a35f-4dd3-98ba-f472ab10833d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Save over 40% on any annual streaming plan at Max" data-dimension48="Save over 40% on any annual streaming plan at Max" href="https://www.max.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:652px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="ENtfexsrTSHzJkgoZ8Wf8j" name="max-logo-square.JPG" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ENtfexsrTSHzJkgoZ8Wf8j.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="652" height="652" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><a href="https://www.max.com/" data-dimension112="6bf5990b-a35f-4dd3-98ba-f472ab10833d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Save over 40% on any annual streaming plan at Max" data-dimension48="Save over 40% on any annual streaming plan at Max"><strong>Save over 40% on any annual streaming plan at Max</strong></a></p>
<p>New and existing subscribers alike can save a whopping 42% when they pay for ANY annual streaming plan at Max. No promo code needed, no strings attached. </p>
<p>The result of a merger between HBO and Discovery, Max is home to a bounty of popular TV series and films, from hit series like Succession and The Last Of Us to guilty pleasures like 90 Day Fiancé. This streaming deal could get you a full 12 months of streaming for as little as $69.99 (with the ad-supported plan). <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.max.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="6bf5990b-a35f-4dd3-98ba-f472ab10833d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Save over 40% on any annual streaming plan at Max" data-dimension48="Save over 40% on any annual streaming plan at Max">View Deal</a></p></div>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/tvs/2024-pre-order/"><strong>Preorder any 2024 Samsung TV and get a 65" TV for FREE (ends April 11th)</strong></a></li></ul>
<p>Investing in an entire year of streaming all at once can feel like a big purchase, but the savings really add up when you look at it on a month-to-month basis. Instead of paying $15.99 every month for the popular Ad-Free plan, for instance, you could drop a single $110.99 payment and be streaming to your heart&apos;s content for an entire year. That particular plan also comes with the ability to download up to 30 titles for offline viewing. </p><p>Interested in the most premium streaming experience possible? The 42% off deal also applies to the Ultimate Ad-Free plan, which comes with everything mentioned above alongside 4K Ultra HD streaming on select titles, Dolby Atmos support, and up to 100 titles for offline enjoyment. Pay $139.99 during the promotional period (usually $19.99/month) and you&apos;ll get all of those goodies for an entire year. Max will even throw in the Sports Add-on for 100% free. It&apos;s the best streaming deal we&apos;ve seen in a long time, so don&apos;t miss your chance to save. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/max-deal-takes-40-off-an-entire-year-of-streaming-heres-what-you-need-to-know</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ For a limited time, the popular streaming service Max is offering a 40% discount when you pay for an annual plan in advance.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">8NfnHXL4aJVnvYgVVYatpA</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/n5jtnR94r3mLynD2mEF6S4.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 18:05:07 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Streaming &amp; TV]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/n5jtnR94r3mLynD2mEF6S4.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[MAX]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[MAX logo with blue gradient background]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[MAX logo with blue gradient background]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Wallet adds 'Verification settings' to balance security and convenience ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-32">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google Wallet has added a new verification settings menu for Android devices.</li><li>This setting allows users to decide whether or not they need to be verified before paying for a ticket on public transport.</li><li>This will help to make Google Wallet even more secure.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>The ability to store card details, transit passes, boarding passes, and contactless payments, means <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet">Google Wallet</a> is a convenient way to save time.  Now, Google is working hard to make Wallet even more secure and user-friendly by introducing a new ‘Verification settings’ menu.</p><p>The new addition, as spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/03/25/google-wallet-verification-settings/">9to5 Google</a>, lets users decide whether or not verification is required, specifically when paying for a transit ticket. Under “Wallet settings” is the new “Security” heading, under which “Verification settings” are listed. When selected, the user can “choose if you’ll need to verify it’s you when using your items stored in Wallet.” </p><p>At the moment, the only available option here is “Transit payments.” When the “verification required” toggle is on, Wallet will require “verification for paying for bus, metro, and more with a credit or debit card.” This means the usual options for a device include a PIN or fingerprint scan, for example.  </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="24RZvziPWUj2G9RkvaYvxc" name="Google-Wallet-verification-settings.jpg" alt="Screenshots of the new verification settings menu in Google Wallet" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/24RZvziPWUj2G9RkvaYvxc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Phone Arena)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>If a user already has a transit pass stored in Wallet, the toggle will be switched on by default. The wallet will then require verification before paying with their bank card. If no transit pass is stored, this option will be automatically turned off. </p><p>This means that anyone without a transit pass can quickly pay for their ticket without needing to verify themselves. Users can, however, switch it on even if they don’t have a transit pass if they want that added security.</p>
<p>Importantly, this feature is only applicable to paying for transit. As it says underneath the toggle: “You’ll still verify for all other payments with this card.” This means that even if you disable the setting, it won’t allow someone to swipe your phone and go wild with your credit card. Although, they may get to enjoy a day out on your local metro system.</p><p>The new setting is available in version 24.10 of Google Wallet. It’s another example of how Google is trying to strike a balance between security and convenience on Google Wallet. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet-verification-change">A recent change</a> for some European users where all transactions now require verification (previously, unlocks weren’t always required for small payments) has met a mixed response. Hopefully, this latest update will be a little less controversial.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet-adds-verification-settings-to-balance-security-and-convenience</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ New settings could speed things up for users when paying for transport. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">EtawrdeNqzXeGykhrSgVFf</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yn9qGuZok7LNMr7ARZkrAS.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 16:19:39 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ stevenshaw444@gmail.com (Steven Shaw) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yn9qGuZok7LNMr7ARZkrAS.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Wallet new features]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Wallet new features]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ How to change the color of text bubbles on Google Messages ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Google Messages don&apos;t always have to look dull in the same colors. You can spice things up by adding a new color whenever you need a change. You can make these changes from your device&apos;s settings, so you won&apos;t need to install another app.</p><p>You can also do other things on Google Messages, such as <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-set-message-reminders-in-google-messages">set message reminders</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-photomoji-google-messages">use Photomoji</a>. But now you don&apos;t always have to stare at the same color. Keep reading to learn about your color options and how easy it is to switch between them.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-change-text-bubble-colors-for-all-chats-in-google-messages-2">How to change text bubble colors for all chats in Google Messages</h2>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> The following instructions were performed on a Samsung Galaxy with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review">Android 14</a>. The steps might be slightly different depending on your device and Android version.</p><p>1. Open the <strong>Settings app</strong>.</p><p>2. Tap <strong>Wallpaper and style</strong>.</p><p>3. Choose the <strong>Color palette</strong> option.</p><p>4. Toggle on the <strong>Color palette</strong> option.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2160px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:108.33%;"><img id="He34sXMiFZZQMHJBiLLS3o" name="Google-Messages-Settings.jpg" alt="Wallpaper and style option in Samsung phone settings" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/He34sXMiFZZQMHJBiLLS3o.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="2160" height="2340" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Judy Sanhz / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Choose your new color from the Wallpaper colors or Basic colors option. You can&apos;t choose the colors in the Wallpaper colors option since the choices are limited to the wallpaper. The Basic color options give you solid or two color options.</p><p>When you know what color you want to use, tap the Apply button at the bottom. The colors will be applied, and you&apos;ll return to the Wallpaper and style section.</p><p>The steps will be slightly different depending on your phone. For example, for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-motorola-phones">Motorola phones</a>, the steps would be <strong>Settings > Wallpaper > Change Wallpaper</strong> and choose your new wallpaper that has your preferred color. Depending on the Motorola phone, you may also find this in the <strong>Personalize</strong> option in the settings menu, which gives you the option to adjust the color palete separate from the wallpaper.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-oneplus-phones">OnePlus phones</a> and Pixel devices have fewer steps since you only need to tap on <strong>Wallpaper and Style</strong> to see the option. Repeat the same steps when you&apos;re ready to change the color again.</p><p>As long as you&apos;re on your Galaxy phone, whether it&apos;s one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-samsung-phones">best Samsung phones</a> or not, you <strong>can also use Accessibility</strong> to change the colors of the text bubbles for Google Messages. It won&apos;t give it a drastic change, but it&apos;s another option. To give it a try:</p><p>1. Go to <strong>Settings</strong>.</p><p>2. Open <strong>Accessibility</strong>.</p><p>3. Tap the <strong>Vision enhancements</strong> (or <strong>Color and motion</strong> on Pixels and other Android phones) option.</p><p>4. Choose <strong>Color correction</strong> and <strong>toggle on</strong> the option at the top.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2160px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:108.33%;"><img id="X6DpyVawh6ZhzCtQkaJCLn" name="Vision-enhancements-settings.jpg" alt="Vision enhancement option in Galaxy settings" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/X6DpyVawh6ZhzCtQkaJCLn.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="2160" height="2340" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Judy Sanhz / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Choose a color option at the bottom and preview your option in the image above with all the veggies.</p><p>Another option would be to choose <strong>Color inversion</strong> instead of Color correction in the above steps. These two options can be accessed following the same steps.</p><p>1. Go to <strong>Settings</strong>.</p><p>2. Open <strong>Accessibility</strong>.</p><p>3. Select <strong>Vision enhancements</strong> and swipe down a little to access the Color inversion option. </p><p>You can enable the Color inversion option directly from Vision enhancements. However, if you select it, you&apos;ll see an option to create a shortcut for this feature. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2160px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:108.33%;"><img id="R4sXpyzy3Wj4sVURoRSKQd" name="Vision-enhancements-options.jpg" alt="Vision enhancement options in Galaxy phone settings" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/R4sXpyzy3Wj4sVURoRSKQd.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="2160" height="2340" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Judy Sanhz / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Dark Mode</strong> will also give the Google Messages bubble a different look. If you want to give it a try, you can enable it by:</p><p>1. Opening <strong>Settings</strong>.</p><p>2. Go to <strong>Display</strong>.</p><p>3. Tap the <strong>Dark</strong> option at the top.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2160px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:108.33%;"><img id="RW94PTg2ZufDDZUHtCJsuT" name="Dark-Mode-Settings-Galaxy.jpg" alt="Dark mode steps for Galaxy phones" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RW94PTg2ZufDDZUHtCJsuT.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="2160" height="2340" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Judy Sanhz / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<h2 id="how-to-change-text-bubble-colors-for-individual-rcs-chats-2">How to change text bubble colors for individual RCS chats</h2>
<p>With Google Messages, the ability to change the text bubble color of individual chats is also rolling out, although its availability is currently limited since it&apos;s in beta. That said, the steps for RCS (Rich Communication Services) chats are easy and quick for anyone currently in the beta:</p>
<p>1. <strong>Open the chat</strong> to which you want to give a new color.</p><p>2. Tap the <strong>dots</strong> at the top right.</p><p>3. Choose the <strong>Change Color</strong> option. </p><p>4. <strong>Select a color</strong> and tap <strong>Confirm</strong> at the bottom right.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1238px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:68.26%;"><img id="wTBxSCeuY6gaxArsPsUfbd" name="RCS-Messages-Text-Bubbles.jpg" alt="Color change for RCS chats on Android phone" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wTBxSCeuY6gaxArsPsUfbd.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1238" height="845" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>A notice at the bottom will tell you so when you change the color. Each <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/what-rcs-and-why-it-important-android">RCS</a> chat can have a different color, and you can go back at any time to choose another color. The color change should also apply to the receiver but don&apos;t worry if that is not always the case since it&apos;s still in beta.</p>
<h2 id="make-your-google-messages-text-bubbles-colorful-2">Make your Google Messages text bubbles colorful</h2>
<p>Google announced <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.google/products/android/7-new-messages-features/">seven new features</a> in late 2023 that will change how you use Google Messages. One of those changes is Custom Bubbles, which allows you to change the color of your conversation right from the chat. The changes don&apos;t end there; you can <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-messages-pin-up-to-five-conversations">pin up to five messages</a>. </p><p>There are many other <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/top-5-tips-and-tricks-google-messages">tips and tricks for Google Messages</a> you can try. It&apos;s great to see how users get more options regarding their conversations. Only time will tell what other great features you will enjoy.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="4341440a-d678-44c5-8617-1e03e0395bef">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GUWyZjgsTsmWu9xWniJ5sb.jpg' alt='google pixel 8 pro square press render'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 8 Pro</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="90" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Enjoy the Google features first</strong></em></p>
<p>With the Google Pixel 8 Pro, you can enjoy Photomoji and other Google features before anyone else. You also get top-notch haptics, a fantastic camera, and seven years of updates.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-change-text-bubble-color-google-messages</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google Messages can be boring with the same colors all the time. See how quickly you can give your conversations a new look. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">smPZArh4Ai8jEWPLwNNVBg</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CfW88vPyqUwfFxjW8uKGvZ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 16:12:19 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ judysanhz30@gmail.com (Judy Sanhz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CfW88vPyqUwfFxjW8uKGvZ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Judy Sanhz / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Google Messages app open on a smartphone]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Google Messages app open on a smartphone]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>