<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 17:09:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Android 15’s new tablet features get me one step closer to ditching my laptop forever ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Android 15 is now available <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-now-makes-pixel-phones-a-fortress-against-thieves-and-fraudsters">on Pixel devices</a>! Along with the myriad of changes and new features is a taskbar update that transforms Android tablets in a way that’s been sorely needed for a long time. In short, the taskbar can finally be pinned like it can on a desktop OS, and app pairs can be easily made and pinned for quicker productivity.</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Android Central Labs</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="7WCXSEZSk3FX9EmxxzaGE9" name="android-central-labs-lloyd-logo.jpg" caption="" alt="Android Central's Lloyd mascot wearing a lab coat for the Android Central Labs column" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7WCXSEZSk3FX9EmxxzaGE9.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">A weekly column devoted to deep dives and a focused look into tech you didn&apos;t know you needed, covering phones, tablets, and everything in between.</p></div></div>
<p>You’ll be able to check out these changes on a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-fold-2">Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold</a> first, but they’ll be headed to plenty of other Android foldable phones and tablets soon. Of course, just because it’s now finally part of Android doesn’t mean you weren’t able to use these features on some other devices on the market, including foldables like the Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 and tablets like the Honor MagicPad 2.</p><p>In fact, the Honor MagicPad 2 is the very device I’m writing this article on and has been my go-to productivity device for over the past two weeks since Hurricane Helene devastated my hometown. It, along with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-v3-hands-on">Honor Magic V3</a>, has been the device combination I never knew I needed until I had no power, no home internet connectivity, and no real way to do my at-home job.</p><p>The combo is made possible by what the company calls Honor Magic Ring which enables instant screen, connection, and control sharing between Honor devices in a way that’s been utterly clutch during this difficult time.</p>
<h2 id="a-surprising-combination-2">A surprising combination</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="bfSY57HkiqTNAFdTbmeXZk" name="honor-magicpad-2-and-honor-magic-v3.jpg" alt="The Honor MagicPad 2 and Honor Magic V3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bfSY57HkiqTNAFdTbmeXZk.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Let’s say you had a work-from-home job like me but had no internet connection or power at your house, and no cafes or other places with reliable internet were open because your entire town didn’t have running water. That’s the exact scenario I found myself in over these past two weeks, and it left me with an interesting problem to solve: how do I continue to do my job?</p><p>At first, I figured I’d just use the hotspot on my phone to tether the Honor MagicPad 2 and carry on as usual. Problem is that I’m on a grandfathered T-Mobile plan with limited hotspot data and no way to increase this limit without changing my plan. I’ve kept this cheaper plan for well over a decade and this isn’t going to be the thing that changes that, so that option was out.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:64.00%;"><img id="LcjcsvhVRfK9L9mLfsMPun" name="honor-magicpad-2-magic-ring-writing-music.jpg" alt="Using Honor Magic Ring to mirror the display of an Honor Magic V3 onto an Honor MagicPad 2" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LcjcsvhVRfK9L9mLfsMPun.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1920" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>So I decided to dive a little deeper into the Honor Magic Ring, a technology that pairs Honor devices together in a way that others would be envious of. Two swipes and two quick taps mirrored my Honor Magic V3’s large foldable display onto the tablet, letting me run it split-screen alongside Honor’s note-taking app on the tablet. I was even able to stream music from my phone to the Honor MagicPad 2’s unbelievably good speakers, helping to closely recreate the feeling of working in my (now dark) basement office.</p><p>Since the Honor MagicPad 2 can easily make and save app pairs, it was easy to quickly launch into my mirrored workspace with notes on one side of the screen and my phone’s screen on the other. Once I had this set up, I was golden. I wrote from the comfort of the large tablet display, then used the mirrored phone display to upload things to Google Drive or Android Central’s CMS.</p><p>Because I was using my phone and not tethering off the data connection, I was able to use my unlimited phone data plan like it was natively running on the tablet. At one point, I accidentally figured out how to change the mirrored phone screen into a full screen tablet display ON the tablet, taking things one step further.</p>
<h2 id="what-android-15-will-make-better-2">What Android 15 will make better</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:60.69%;"><img id="r3gXxGK8ytD9Acd2xyKLt5" name="android-15-taskbar-pinning.jpg" alt="A look at the new pinnable taskbar in Android 15" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/r3gXxGK8ytD9Acd2xyKLt5.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1243" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>So while I’ve really been enjoying how deeply Honor ties its products together, a few small changes will take things to the next level. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a>’s new pinnable taskbar will complete the “laptop experience.” By that, I mean a dedicated taskbar at the bottom that can be used to launch and swap between running apps quickly.</p><p>Some tablets like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/oneplus-pad-2-review">OnePlus Pad 2</a> let you temporarily pin the taskbar, but on Android 15, you&apos;ll be able to pin it permanently like a laptop. I fully expect this feature to come to all Android tablets that get the Android 15 update, too.</p><p>Next, I’d love to see more enhanced content sharing between devices. Honor launched it’s revamped Magic OS 8 interface with the Honor Magic 6 series earlier in 2024 — including a clever new side-mounted share UI — but there’s no easy way to drag-and-drop content between devices using split-screen windows. Copying and pasting text between devices works very well, but moving images or other media is still clunkier than I would like, requiring you to use Quick Share or Honor Share to get them there instead of just dragging and dropping between windows.</p><p>Lastly, Honor’s Magic OS doesn’t let you force all apps into a split screen view. This doesn’t make much sense to me since it lets you float any app and then adjust its aspect ratio freely, so I’m not sure what the hold up is here.</p><p>What I ultimately drew from this forced experiment was that tablets are truly ready to replace laptops for a large number of tasks — even if they are a bit clunky at time — making it possible to do a large majority of my job from a device that’s got a lot better battery life than a laptop.</p><p>Now, if we could just get Adobe to put the FULL Creative Cloud suite on Android, or at least essentials like the full version of Photoshop, so I can ditch the Windows or Mac laptop forever.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/android-15s-new-tablet-features-get-me-one-step-closer-to-ditching-my-laptop-forever</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Android 15 sports a handful of new tablet features that make productivity nearly as good as a laptop. Some tablets already have these features, and I got to put them to good use after Hurricane Helene. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">bsHNqLwqQ7hSrjjBEfg7ND</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ADFZ3zq4xuESeKM3MfFPrk.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 17:06:43 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ADFZ3zq4xuESeKM3MfFPrk.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Pointing at the Honor MagicPad 2&#039;s taskbar with the Honor Magic Pen]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Pointing at the Honor MagicPad 2&#039;s taskbar with the Honor Magic Pen]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ YouTube gains a new sleep timer, custom playlist thumbnails, and an updated mini-player ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>YouTube has launched many new features for its video and audio streaming platforms.</li><li>As part of the update, users can invite or collaborate playlists with friends and family using a unique link or QR code.</li><li>People using playlists on the platform can use their preferred photos as thumbnails. </li><li>Other features include creator badges and new UI for Shorts on TV, among others.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>YouTube has announced several new features coming to the streaming platform alongside YouTube Music. Google notes that users can expect over two dozen improvements in updates that include the platform on the web, mobile, and TVs as well.</p><p>In the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.youtube/news-and-events/youtube-features-and-updates-2024/">announcement blog post</a>, these updates comprise some "highly requested features"—like fine-tunable playback speed (with 0.05 increments), improved landscape browsing experience, updates to thumbnails, and some visual improvements.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="svjsRbZNt29rgfBXijXien" name="youtube-new-mini-player.gif" alt="YouTube's updated mini player" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/svjsRbZNt29rgfBXijXien.gif" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: YouTube)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>YouTube&apos;s mobile app now has a new mini-player. Browsing for other videos while already watching a video should be a lot smoother now, as users can now even resize and play with it by moving it around across all sides of the screen.</p><p>YouTube playlists are also improved with the latest release. People can invite others to their playlists using a "special link" or a QR code for easy additions. The capability is said to be coming soon to TV as well.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:62.00%;"><img id="qytDZvfVRvPwaVrmcKNbCR" name="YouTube-QR-code-invite.jpg" alt="YouTube QR Code invite system for playlists" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qytDZvfVRvPwaVrmcKNbCR.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="496" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: YouTube)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>YouTube and YouTube Music already allow users to create custom thumbnails for their playlists with the help of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-music-generative-ai-art-experiment">generative AI</a>. This ability is now expanding as users can even add their preferred photos by picking from their camera roll to give it a personal touch. Personalization can include adding text to the image, filters, or stickers.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NWFS03p3W0M" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>Furthermore, friends in the playlists can also vote on videos to curate the best ones from the playlist. It is also believed to be beneficial for creators as they can have their viewers rank their content. YouTube states this feature will roll out later this year.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:410px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:146.34%;"><img id="N6yiSXHZTTjC396zkqQRmi" name="youtube-badges.gif" alt="New YouTube Badges" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/N6yiSXHZTTjC396zkqQRmi.gif" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="410" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: YouTube)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Besides, YouTube is also introducing badges for the first time on its mobile and YouTube Music apps. They can badge their favorite creators for the content they love. Similarly, users can also earn badges "for being a top listener of their favorite artist or having a creator heart your comment."</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FtaSfHwwjoo" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>YouTube is also gaining Sleep Timer, which allows users to set a timer to "automatically pause videos after a certain duration of time." The feature was initially tested for Premium subscribers; however, it is said to be available for all users starting Tuesday (Oct 12).</p>
<p>YouTube&apos;s TV experience will also receive some improvements with the new update, and visual changes can be seen on the web and mobile. For instance, watching Shorts on TV should be more seamless, as a new UI offers "continued interaction with the content."</p><p>YouTube also states that all these new updates are the result of consumers&apos; feedback and highly requested features, as mentioned above. Users across <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android devices</a>, iOS, the web, and TV should be seeing these new changes starting this week.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Streaming deals: </strong><a href="https://www.disneyplus.com/"><u><strong>Disney+</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.max.com/"><u><strong>Max</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.sling.com/"><u><strong>Sling</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://geni.us/YkQAuWd"><u><strong>Fubo</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.peacocktv.com/blackfriday"><u><strong>Peacock</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.paramountplus.com/"><u><strong>Paramount+</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-and-youtube-music-gain-new-improvements</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ YouTube has rolled out some highly requested features, like fine-tunable playback speed and some visual improvements. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">s8QS7mM6RU8vgAXkPMKBid</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/s8TPShBnp3umv4YW98tnXE.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 16:52:06 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/s8TPShBnp3umv4YW98tnXE.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[YouTube]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[YouTube October 2024 features]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[YouTube October 2024 features]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ This One UI 7 Good Lock module update could bring serious customization ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>An X (formerly Twitter) user posted screenshots of several upcoming customization changes for Good Lock's "Home Up" module in One UI 7.</li><li>The module will reportedly bring a host of animation customization options and sliders alongside tools for folders.</li><li>One UI 7 (Android 15) is expected to debut in 2025 alongside the Galaxy S25, though a beta should begin late this year.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Samsung is reportedly preparing a Good Lock module update that&apos;ll make your phone one of a kind.</p><p>The major changes in question regard Samsung&apos;s "Home Up" Good Lock module. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/renz_pzaway/status/1845129251387052292">A user on X</a> posted screenshots of the potential additions for One UI 7 (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidpolice.com/one-ui-7-could-supercharge-good-lock-modules/">Android Police</a>). The module&apos;s update focuses on bringing more customization options to users for "animation tuning." The tipster purports Samsung will show users "Pixel by Pixel" and "The scent of a certain fruit" options.</p><p>The former is said to deliver "pure animation." It&apos;s not clear what the latter could be; however, the publication suspects it could be Apple-esque, in a way. We know that Samsung has been moving into a more Apple-like world <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-one-ui-7-changes-teased-sdc-2024">with its designs</a>, though <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-management-furious-latest-product-design">not everyone is happy</a> about that.</p><p>The "Home Up" module was also spotted with an "advanced tuning" option, which blows open its possibilities. Users may find sliders for things like damping, stiffness, friction, blur, and duration. These sliders directly impact how your device&apos;s animations are played and stylized.</p><p>The final option is labeled "Simple tuning." As suspected, this option is the most basic as the module gives a singular slider to adjust an animation&apos;s speed. The tipster then located an option to alter the "bottom gesture sensitivity."</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Home gesture animation tuning pic.twitter.com/BYBWoNAmWG<a href="https://twitter.com/renz_pzaway/status/1845129251387052292">October 12, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>The "Home Up" module continues with an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/renz_pzaway/status/1845266909887070283">update for folders</a>. The screenshots show that Samsung plans to display size customizations (medium and large) for folders. Moreover, a "detail settings" option will let users change the grid and the size of the icons within it.</p><p>The changes continue to suggest a shift toward Apple&apos;s iOS design aside from what&apos;s been seen for One UI&apos;s elemental adjustments.</p><p>With these changes seemingly primed for One UI 7 (Android 15), users have more time in the waiting room. Samsung <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-confirms-one-ui-7-wont-hit-beta-until-end-of-this-year">confirmed</a> that its next major OS will roll out in 2025 alongside the Galaxy S25 series. More importantly, a community moderator confirmed that the company is still <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-plans-one-ui-7-public-beta">preparing a Public Beta program</a> for One UI 7.</p><p>Users can "preview" the software alongside developers and deliver feedback and test results before launch. The moderator adds that users should look out for a notification of the program&apos;s start via Samsung Members. The company states users can likely expect the beta to begin "by the end of the year."</p><p>Other than the visual refresh, Samsung&apos;s Sally Hyesoon Jeong highlighted the update&apos;s fine-tuned motion dynamics and a new blur system.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/one-ui-7-good-lock-module-customization-update-spotted</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A leak showed off Samsung's supposed update for a Good Lock module in One UI 7 for better customization. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">DaYjp7Y43bPixKp68tbfL9</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jR2Gcb2Wo8XSNoioVVm5pD.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 16:49:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jR2Gcb2Wo8XSNoioVVm5pD.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Good Lock on the Galaxy Z Flip 6]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Good Lock on the Galaxy Z Flip 6]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung's One UI update rolls onto TVs far quicker than imagined ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung is reportedly rolling out its major One UI update for smart TVs after its recent SDC 2024 announcement.</li><li>The update brings Tizen OS 8.0, a revamped settings overlay, and a new "Samsung Daily Plus" hub feature.</li><li>Samsung stated during SDC 2024 that it wants to move into a unified One UI experience across phones, TVs, and appliances by 2025.</li><li>One UI 7 is expected to drop early in 2025 with the Galaxy S25 series, but a beta should begin "by the end of the year."</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>As One UI starts appearing, Samsung will give its TV owners a much quicker update than initially anticipated.</p><p>Today (Oct 14), <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.sammobile.com/news/samsung-tv-one-ui-update-released-tizen-8-0/">SamMobile</a> states the One UI update Samsung detailed during SDC 2024 is rolling out. The publication spotted the patch on the company&apos;s 2023 OLED TV (<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/televisions-home-theater/tvs/oled-tvs/65-class-s90c-oled-4k-smart-tv-2023-qn65s90cafxza/">the S90C</a>), which has more similarities with its Galaxy phones than originally stated. During the event, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/one-uis-next-release-is-delayed-and-samsung-wants-it-on-your-tvs-and-appliances">Samsung said</a> it wanted to "integrate the software experiences" of its devices. This concerns its smartphones, TVs, and home appliances.</p><p>However, the update reportedly shows a UI on smart TVs that mirrors what users can find on a Galaxy phone. Animations are stated to be similar to new icon designs for the Gallery, Samsung Internet, Bixby, and more like Galaxy&apos;s One UI.</p><p>The settings menu, accessible via the icon on your remote, has picked up changes. The One UI update adds an overlay that displays your most used (or most likely) options at the top of selected categories. When opened, the overlay is said to display the following three static options: settings, SmartThings, and the number pad.</p><p>Changelog-wise, Samsung states TVs picking up this One UI update will see the OS bumped up to Tizen 8.0. The home screen now offers a "For You" page with "personalized recommendations," a Live Tab, and an Apps tab. A "Watch Later" button enters, so users can quickly save interesting content.</p><p>Another new feature is "Samsung Daily Plus." According to the company, this is a "lifestyle service hub" for the home screen. An integrated workout tracker for a user&apos;s connected Galaxy Watch joins this hub. Samsung says users can view "calories consumed" and their heart rate.</p><p>The remainder of the changelog is as follows:</p>
<ul><li>Recently searched content and related content have been implemented as recommendations.</li><li>You can control multiple Samsung devices signed in with the same Samsung account using the same keyboard and mouse.</li><li>Based on usage history and present circumstances, tailored channel and setting recommendations can be provided</li><li>loT cameras can be used through the Smart Things app on mobile devices</li><li>The Accessibility Shortcut can rearrange its options according to usage frequency.</li><li>Zoom in screens on request. When mirroring a mobile device, you can use keyboard and mouse controls.</li><li>With Daily Board, you can decorate the screen with beautiful wallpapers and useful widgets – even when the screen is off.</li><li>Enhanced data protection measures have been implemented (Samsung account sign-in required.</li><li>Wi-Fi Speaker Surround Setup has been upgraded to Q-Symphony, enabling connection to the Music Frame.</li></ul>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="ZjzFDh8C4UZQoJt6aQcnSo" name="samsung-tv-plus-menu-bar-lifestyle-alt_2.jpg" alt="Samsung Tv Plus Menu Bar Lifestyle Alt" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZjzFDh8C4UZQoJt6aQcnSo.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Source: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>SDC 2024 opened our eyes and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/one-uis-next-release-is-delayed-and-samsung-wants-it-on-your-tvs-and-appliances">confirmed a few things</a>, like Samsung&apos;s newfound interest in a unified One UI. The company mentioned Tizen OS — the software that powers its TVs — in today&apos;s update and during the event&apos;s announcements. However, Samsung says it wants to move into fully renaming the experience "One UI" by 2025, so this may be the last we hear of Tizen.</p><p>While the Korean OEM was busy toiling away at its smart TV patch, its Galaxy phones, tablets, and foldables are still waiting on One UI 7. The good thing (kind of) is that the company confirmed One UI 7 will roll out alongside the Galaxy S25 next year. Samsung also highlighted a beta period for developers <em>and </em>regular users.</p><p>A community <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-plans-one-ui-7-public-beta">moderator confirmed</a> that Samsung is still planning on hosting a Public Beta program for One UI 7 "by the end of the year." We&apos;re seemingly waiting on the company to "confirm a schedule" before we can get it. To satiate your curiosity, a Galaxy S24 Ultra was <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-one-ui-7-changes-teased-sdc-2024">running One UI 7 during SDC 2024</a>, showcasing a major change like the separation of the notification and Quick Settings panels.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-smart-tv-one-ui-update-rollout</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A report stated that Samsung is pushing its major One UI update to its smart TVs. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">ZYnacDcQMG5bVveFu6Qmw9</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xmz5To8FLPAnEhhqT8KxAg.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 16:05:11 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xmz5To8FLPAnEhhqT8KxAg.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Samsung]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung Tv Smart Hub Promo Image]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung Tv Smart Hub Promo Image]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Which finger should you wear the Oura Ring 4 on? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <section class="article__schema-question"><h3>What finger should you wear the Oura Ring 4 on?</h3><article class="article__schema-answer"><p><strong>Best answer:</strong> In Oura's official <a href="https://ouraring.com/sizing" target="_blank">sizing guide</a>, they state that "Your Oura Ring can be worn on any finger. We recommend the index, middle, or ring finger for optimal performance."</p>
<p>However, on this <a href="https://support.ouraring.com/hc/en-us/articles/360025590653-Tips-for-Determining-Your-Oura-Ring-Size">Oura support page</a>, they state, "we recommend wearing your Oura Ring on your index finger" and that "the middle or ring fingers are the next best but try to avoid fingers with large knuckles" because it's more likely for the Oura Ring 4 to get stuck or for you to choose a size that's too large. </p>
<p>Oura's reps told us specifically that they recommend wearing the Oura Ring 4 on your non-dominant index finger for the most consistent fit. But if you're between sizes on that finger, it's better to choose another finger where the fit is more snug.</p></article></section>
<h2 id="finding-the-right-oura-ring-4-finger-and-size-for-you-2">Finding the right Oura Ring 4 finger and size for you</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="2VXbzrrwUpGnHjMAUKPQqc" name="Oura-Ring-4-colors-2.jpg" alt="Oura Ring 4 in different colors" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2VXbzrrwUpGnHjMAUKPQqc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4000" height="2250" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Oura)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Choosing your Oura Ring 4 finger and size isn&apos;t as simple as just matching your <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/oura-ring-gen-3-review">Oura Ring Gen 3</a> choices. </p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oura-ring-4-launch">Oura Ring 4</a> has a new titanium design, new enhanced sensors, smarter automatic workout detection, and longer battery life. Whatever Oura did to achieve these upgrades, it changed the size of the ring compared to the last generation, so you&apos;ll need the new sizing kit to confirm your size.</p><p>While American buyers can go to Best Buy for an in-store sizing, we recommend against it. You should wear your dummy ring sizer for 24 hours because your finger size changes from day to night; you may find a ring snug during the day but uncomfortable at night, or too loose for a proper reading.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3921px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.26%;"><img id="5fUZtXkXsQyBx4L2G3858h" name="Oura-Ring-4-2.jpg" alt="Oura Ring 4" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5fUZtXkXsQyBx4L2G3858h.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3921" height="2206" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Oura)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Here is our recommendation: First, wear the ring on your non-dominant hand. Right-handed people <em>can</em> wear it on their right hand, but you&apos;ll find it gets in the way during random activities like cooking or using the bathroom, and it becomes easier for the Oura Ring 4 to get dirty or scratched.</p><p>Second, try the ring on your left index finger first, as that&apos;s most likely to get accurate results. Samsung also <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/which-samsung-galaxy-ring-finger-is-best-to-wear">recommends the left index finger</a> for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-ring-review">Galaxy Ring</a>, and we&apos;ve seen similar recommendations from other brands. </p><p>The middle or ring finger is your backup. We&apos;ve heard of people using <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/best-smart-rings">smart rings</a> as a replacement for wedding bands, but single people will probably avoid that.</p><p>Lastly, don&apos;t be afraid to wear your Oura Ring 4 on <em>multiple</em> fingers. Our fingers expand during workouts because of excess blood flow or can swell at night due to sleeping position, arthritis, or other health or diet concerns. One thing you can do is swap to a different finger or hand preemptively before a run or before you go to sleep, knowing it&apos;ll stay snug.</p><p>To be clear, you should have a primary Oura Ring 4 finger where the ring fits snugly during the day. But don&apos;t be afraid to experiment!</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="f8d7eb2b-ba8d-474b-9b88-4fc178a898c8">
            <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oura-ring-4-smart-ring-size-before-you-buy-with-oura-ring-4-sizing-kit-size-13-silver/6595520.p?skuId=6595520" data-model-name="Oura Ring 4"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nG8MVq445oJMCacip4R7FR.jpg' alt="The Oura RIng 4 in silver"></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Oura Ring 4</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Build for any finger</strong></em></p>
<p>The Oura Ring 4 has a titanium frame, 8-day battery life, 100m water resistance, and a weight between 3.3 and 5.2 grams. It tracks the same info as the Gen 3 like heart rate, stress, blood oxygen, sleep quality, and daily readiness, but Oura claims the data will be much more accurate, especially during workouts.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oura-ring-4-which-finger-is-best</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Even though Oura promises that you can wear the Ring 4 on all ten fingers, you'll have a better experience wearing it on specific fingers. Make sure to try the sizing kit on a few different finger options. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Xd7G49yakCXjXmxJPD8G9X</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DKKZY3QzYthWXAKHNAtiHn.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 16:02:23 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DKKZY3QzYthWXAKHNAtiHn.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Oura]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Someone on their phone with the Oura app]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Someone on their phone with the Oura app]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Pixels stock up on features in its October drop as Android 15 arrives ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google is rolling out its October Pixel feature drop, which packs several new Pixel 9 series tools, such as underwater photo/ video capabilities.</li><li>Several past-gen devices, like the Pixel 6 series, received new Theft Protection features and Night Sight.</li><li>The Pixel Watch 3 expands its "Loss of Pulse Detection" to more countries and upgrades its Contact app.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Today (Oct 15) is a big day for all Android devices, but Google&apos;s Pixels are getting a little extra with an exclusive feature drop.</p><p>Google detailed a lot in store for Pixel devices across the board in October and kicked things off with what&apos;s new for the Pixel 9 series. According to a press release, the latest devices are picking up a Gemini Extension for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-use-the-pixel-screenshots-app-on-the-google-pixel-9">Pixel Screenshots</a>. The company states users can say "Hey Google, use Screenshots to find the brand of sneakers I saved." Google states the AI will take you to the screenshot you asked about after the voice command.</p><p>This update is rolling out for the entire Pixel 9 series in the U.S., Canada, Ireland, Australia, India, Singapore, and Malaysia.</p><p>For the camera, Google states that "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-audio-magic-eraser">Audio Magic Eraser</a>" is making its way to the Pixel 9 and Pixel 8 series. The feature lets users adjust the sound levels of people speaking individually for better clarity. While this is arriving globally for last year&apos;s Pixel 8 series, the Pixel 9 series is picking up in "limited markets." Google did not state which markets will grab it, so keep your eyes open.</p><p>Underwater photography and video capabilities arrive for the Pixel 9, Pixel 9 Pro, and Pixel 9 Pro XL. If you attempt to film or shoot while swimming, for instance, your media should be richer and more accurate in color. While the Pixel 9 series has IP68 water resistance, Google recommends using a waterproof case if you&apos;re going to take advantage of this tool regularly.</p><p>Additionally, the "Object Temperature Sensor" has been enhanced as better integration with the camera arrives. Users can utilize their camera as a viewfinder for the temperature sensor alongside a "live reading" function, and a save feature for your most recent measurements. This is rolling out globally for the Pixel 8 Pro, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-review">Pixel 9 Pro, and the Pixel 9 Pro XL</a>.</p><p>Google also teased a coming upgrade to the Pixel 9&apos;s casting feature. The company states users can transfer media from their Pixel Tablet to their Pixel 9 device so long as the latter is in "close proximity." Songs from Spotify and YouTube videos can jump from one device to another without tapping the casting icon. This feature is arriving for the Pixel 6 Pro, Pixel 7 Pro, and Pixel 8 Pro alongside the entire Pixel 9 Pro, Pixel 9 Pro XL, and Pixel 9 Pro Fold.</p>
<h2 id="pixel-feature-arrive-for-google-apos-s-quot-legacy-quot-phones-2">Pixel Feature arrive for Google&apos;s "Legacy" phones</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="A5JUsMmXbpHi5T5WexKYy9" name="google-pixel-9-pro-xl-in-hand-rear.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL in hand" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/A5JUsMmXbpHi5T5WexKYy9.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>A wave of features are arriving for Google&apos;s "legacy" devices, such as the Pixel 6 series. The post states the devices (minus the Pixel 6a) receive a Night Sight update for Instagram content. Taking low-light photos from inside the Instagram app now benefits from Night Sight&apos;s capabilities to retain clarity and sharpness in darker scenarios.</p><p>Arriving globally for all Pixel 6 devices is Google&apos;s suite of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-adds-anti-theft-security-features-like-theft-detection-lock">Theft Protection</a> features. Users can use "Theft Detection Lock," an AI-powered lock screen that will batten down the hatches if it senses someone running off with your phone. Other features like "Offline Lock" and "Remote Lock" round out for additional tools to safeguard your data if your phone is stolen.</p><p>With the release of Android 15 today (Oct 15), Pixel 6 and newer devices are picking up "Private Spaces" for sensitive apps.</p><p>An Astrophotography update makes it easier to use through the Night Sight tab within the camera app. This update was <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-pixel-camera-astrophotography-manual-control">spotted earlier this year</a> and it&apos;s now arriving more consistently today. Users can manually produce it within Night Sight&apos;s duration slider instead of waiting for their phone to activate Astrophotography on its own.</p><p>The new Pixel Weather app is arriving on Pixel 6 devices and newer alongside the Pixel Tablet. Joining this is an addition to the app called the "Pollen Data Block." This box in the weather app will display information about pollen index levels, types, and forecasts for those with seasonal allergies. The data block is hitting Pixel 6 and newer devices and the Pixel Tablet in France, Germany, Italy, and the UK.</p><p>Google Pixel&apos;s next-gen call screen for enhanced privacy is expanding in a rollout for Pixel 6 and newer devices in Japan and the UK. Gemini Live&apos;s audio version is arriving in France, Germany, Brazil, India, Spain, and Latin America for Pixel 6 (and newer) phones.</p><p>Adaptive Vibration leverages your phone&apos;s microphone and various sensors to determine how loud or intense a notification&apos;s alert is. The idea is to help ensure users don&apos;t miss out on important messages, notifications, etc. Google states this is rolling out for Pixel 7 and newer devices globally.</p>
<h2 id="the-pixel-watch-drop-2">The Pixel Watch drop</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="srNCFV47V4GVdhvZkNZ3km" name="google-pixel-watch-3-porcelain-on-stands-4.jpg" alt="Pixel Watch 3 41mm and 45mm with Porcelain bands" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/srNCFV47V4GVdhvZkNZ3km.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2500" height="1406" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google is expanding its major safety "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/pixel-watch-3-loss-of-pulse-detection-explained">Loss of Pulse Detection</a>" feature for the Pixel Watch 3 to more places. The company highlighted the feature during its August hardware event, stating your <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-3-hands-on">Pixel Watch 3</a> can piggyback off its heart rate sensors and AI software to determine if a user&apos;s pulse has stopped. If no heartbeat is detected, the Pixel Watch 3 will call emergency services with an audible message in tow to explain the situation.</p><p>The feature is debuting in Belgium, Italy, and Spain.</p><p>All three Pixel Watches welcome emoji email reactions via the smartwatch&apos;s notifications and Wear OS-based app. Users can quickly send a smiley face or other emoji in response to an email they&apos;ve received.  Additionally, the trio of watches gained an update to the Contacts app.</p><p>A new "Contact Tile" arrives, giving users a convenient place to display who they contact the most without diving into their lists. Quick actions for the tiles deliver options to call, text, or open the person&apos;s full contact details.</p>
<h2 id="a-little-more-for-the-pixel-tablet-and-pixel-buds-2">A little more for the Pixel Tablet and Pixel Buds</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="8YusvDBivTmj5P9YAbVZq7" name="google-pixel-buds-pro-2-wintergreen-close-up-1.jpg" alt="Google Pixel Buds Pro 2 Wintergreen earbud" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8YusvDBivTmj5P9YAbVZq7.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2500" height="1406" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Google Gemini</a> is debuting on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/earbuds/google-pixel-buds-pro-2-review">Pixel Buds Pro 2</a>, Buds Pro, Pixel Buds A-Series, and the original Pixel Buds. The AI is said to provide walking directions, email information, and additional options for brainstorming.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/google-pixel-tablet-review">Pixel Tablet</a> is grabbing a few updates, like Panel Screensaver. While the device is idle (or charging), Google states users can access smart home controls and camera feeds. Photo Frame lets users save, share, or archive photos directly from the device&apos;s screensaver. Lastly, Clock Screensaver gives users a few new options when its sitting idle for a while.</p><p>These Pixel Tablet features are rolling out globally.</p>
<ul><li> <strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="b5791319-599d-4927-a6bd-6c29d494b107">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sr66Lm9uCSgvS29MgezixS.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL render"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 Pro XL</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>The Pixel 9 Pro XL is the larger of the two Pro models for Google's 2024 flagship series. The device features a 6.8-inch display with 120Hz refresh rate and a larger 5,060mAh battery. On its AI kick, Google loaded the Pixel 9 Pro XL up with Gemini's on-device features to make your life a little easier.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-pixel-october-2024-feature-drop</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google drops its October exclusive bundle of features for its entire Pixel portfolio. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">WaAeEBCtiwTfuSY8rjiFW9</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Ppx2XnXUjksHgLDqz4RePJ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 16:02:23 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Ppx2XnXUjksHgLDqz4RePJ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9 Pro and Pixel 9 Pro XL angled view]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9 Pro and Pixel 9 Pro XL angled view]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Android adds 3 anti-theft security features to your phone, with more on the way ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Android is becoming more secure with three new anti-theft features: Theft Detection Lock, Offline Device Lock, and Remote Lock.</li><li>These features are gradually rolling out now, and will become widely available on most Android 10 or higher devices today.</li><li>They're not enabled by default, so people interested in using them must turn them on in the settings app on their devices manually.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Our smartphones are expensive devices that are crucial to our daily lives, and unfortunately, that makes them a natural target for theft. A lost or stolen phone not only costs a lot of money to replace, but more importantly, has valuable data inside. In the grand scheme of things, it&apos;s easy to buy a new phone, but it&apos;s not as easy to secure banking apps, password managers, and other cruxes of your digital life after they&apos;ve been compromised. </p><p>That&apos;s why starting today, Google is rolling out three new anti-theft features for Android devices: <strong>Theft Detection Lock</strong>, <strong>Offline Device Lock</strong>, and <strong>Remote Lock</strong>. These tools are becoming available alongside the release of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a>, but they&apos;re not limited to devices running the latest operating system. In fact, they will be available on most devices running Android 10 and up via Google Play System updates.</p><p>Anti-theft features for smartphones are not uncommon, but Google takes a creative and unique approach with <strong>Theft Detection Lock</strong>. It uses artificial intelligence and machine learning, plus device signals and sensors, to detect if a phone has been snatched out of your hand. Think about how features like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-enable-car-crash-detection-pixel">Car Crash Detection</a> or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-explains-fall-detection">Fall Detection</a> use device sensors to detect impacts. Theft Detection Lock works in a similar way; instead of an impact, Google&apos;s AI and ML algorithms are looking for a snatching movement. </p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8zYNNLxy9L0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>When the Theft Detection Lock algorithm detects your phone has been stolen, it will automatically lock your device. This is intended to have your back in the worst possible scenario — the event your phone is snatched while it is already unlocked. It&apos;s also quite unobtrusive. If Theft Detection Lock mistakes an intended motion for a snatch-and-grab, you&apos;ll simply have to unlock your device again to keep using it like normal. </p><p><strong>Offline Device Lock</strong> is also entering the fold to make sure that clever thieves can&apos;t get around Find My Device protections by taking your stolen smartphone offline. This feature, when enabled, will automatically lock the screen of an Android phone that goes offline for prolonged periods. A thief might turn off Wi-Fi or Cellular to try and avoid a remote lockdown or erase from Find My Device, but Offline Device Lock is a small step that tries to avoid this. It&apos;s also a failsafe in case Theft Detection Lock doesn&apos;t lock your phone immediately while it is being stolen. </p><p>The last piece of the puzzle is <strong>Remote Lock</strong>, which makes it easy to lock down your <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phone</a>. Most remote lock tools require you to sign into accounts and use two-factor authentication, and this can take a while if you&apos;re not on a familiar device — and you probably aren&apos;t on one if your phone just got stolen. With Remote Lock, you can secure a lost or stolen Android device with just a verified phone number. It&apos;s available at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="http://www.android.com/lock" target="_blank">Android.com/lock</a>.</p><p>Google is also making a few smaller changes to Android 15 security settings to keep your device and data secure:</p>
<ul><li>With Android 15, you need to enter a PIN, password, or use biometrics to change sensitive settings, like Find My Device options</li><li>Multiple failed login attempts will lock down your device</li><li>Enhanced factory reset protections will make it more difficult for a thief to factory reset your device without the proper Google account credentials</li></ul>
<p>Google isn&apos;t done with this slate of security announcements. Later this year, it plans to introduce <strong>Identity Check</strong>, a feature that can require biometrics to make changes like setting a new PIN, turning off theft protection, or using Passkeys from an untrusted location. The company says this will give Android users another, optional layer of protection if your device PIN or password is compromised. </p><p>Theft Detection Lock, Offline Device Lock, and Remote Lock are all <strong>opt-in features</strong>, so you&apos;ll want to manually enable them in Settings if you plan to use them. These already began gradually rolling out and will become widely available today, but it may take some time for them to appear on your device. They&apos;ll also be unavailable on some devices, like Android Go products.</p>
<h2 id="why-it-matters-2">Why it matters</h2>
<p>There&apos;s a lot that you can do as a responsible smartphone owner to protect yourself in the event of an accident. You can purchase insurance to make sure you get a new phone (minus the cost of the plan and deductible) in the event that it is lost, stolen, or damaged. Or, you could simply keep an emergency fund of cash available to replace your phone in case the worst happens. </p><p>However, there&apos;s little that you can do to protect your data if your phone is stolen while it is unlocked. Banking information, personal identifiers, and more could be at risk of falling into the wrong hands. The new Android security features announced today aim to give you a few extra layers of protection in this scenario, and I&apos;ll be enabling them immediately. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-adds-anti-theft-security-features-like-theft-detection-lock</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ We've heard a lot about Theft Detection Lock and other security features coming to Android, and now they're finally here. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Y298ka4AG65mDiYzRn6KMc</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/C7LibQK4QYiF3rnTsefJyB.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 16:00:49 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/C7LibQK4QYiF3rnTsefJyB.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central / Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Three Android 15 screens against a gradient background.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Three Android 15 screens against a gradient background.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Android 15 now makes Pixel phones a fortress against thieves and fraudsters ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Android 15 is live for Pixel phone users after its source code was shared in early September.</li><li>Pixel devices now offer one-touch passkeys, advanced theft protection, improved multitasking on larger screens, and options to limit app access.</li><li>With Theft Detection Lock, your phone automatically locks if snatched.</li><li>Foldables and tablets now let you easily pin or unpin the taskbar for quick access to your favorite apps.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Android 15 officially arrived for Pixel phone owners today after Google <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/android-15-is-officially-launching-on-pixel-phones-near-you">shared its source code on the Android Open Source Project in early September</a>, though the OTA update for Pixel phones and tablets wasn’t released until now.</p><p>At first glance, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a> doesn’t seem all that thrilling. However, it’s clear that Google has put in a ton of effort behind the scenes to improve the experience for users.</p><p>Pixel devices on Android 15 bring one-touch passkeys, advanced theft protection, better multitasking for bigger screens, and the ability to limit app access.</p><p>Privacy takes the spotlight in the latest Android update. Now, you can create a "Private space" to hide apps with sensitive info or anything you want to keep under wraps.</p><p>There&apos;s also "Theft Detection Lock," which locks your phone if it’s snatched. Extra authentication steps are added for high-target settings like removing your SIM or disabling Find My Device, and your phone will lock down after multiple failed attempts. These updates aim to make it harder for thieves to wipe and resell stolen devices, potentially preventing thefts in the first place.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1816px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:210.13%;"><img id="7AqTjAgFiiELTZs5XtdLXo" name="Theft Protection settings (includes Theft Detection Lock).png" alt="Theft protection lock in Android 15" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7AqTjAgFiiELTZs5XtdLXo.png" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1816" height="3816" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1816px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:210.13%;"><img id="nvMhsjeYYHmm24ttK8TnWD" name="Theft Detection Lock notification.png" alt="Theft protection lock in Android 15" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nvMhsjeYYHmm24ttK8TnWD.png" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1816" height="3816" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1816px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:210.13%;"><img id="9KeFUBRZNHZpNsGBcYsKY4" name="Remote Lock settings.png" alt="Theft protection lock in Android 15" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9KeFUBRZNHZpNsGBcYsKY4.png" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1816" height="3816" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Additionally, Google has rolled out a few user-friendly upgrades, like smoother multitasking on large screens, edge-to-edge displays as the new default, and the ability to snap a photo to add passes and tickets to Google Wallet.</p><p>With foldables and tablets, you can now pin or unpin the taskbar effortlessly, giving you more control over your layout. This means your favorite apps, like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-photos">Google Photos</a> or Gmail, are always within reach for quicker access and smoother productivity.</p><p>You can now use single-tap passkeys with autofill, and Low Light Boost along with in-app camera controls work even better in low light. On top of that, carrier messaging apps can now connect via satellite to send and receive messages without needing mobile or Wi-Fi.</p><p>The Android 15 update arrives alongside the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-pixel-october-2024-feature-drop">October Pixel Feature Drop</a>, bringing new features and improvements that didn&apos;t make it into the beta.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-now-makes-pixel-phones-a-fortress-against-thieves-and-fraudsters</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Android 15 is here for Pixels, and it's packing a punch when it comes to protecting your sensitive info and deterring theft. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">DerDJ2REPySPYEfHvasLdn</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LmDEBeSE5Yia7z5BCvWuDg.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 16:00:44 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LmDEBeSE5Yia7z5BCvWuDg.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android 15 logo on Pixel 8 next to Pixel 7a and 7 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android 15 logo on Pixel 8 next to Pixel 7a and 7 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Android 15: All the new features, eligible devices, and release date ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>After months of testing and several beta builds, Android 15 has finally hit stable release. Google rolled out the stable build to Pixels on October 15, and other devices will follow suit over the coming weeks and months.</p><p>While there wasn't a lot of excitement around <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review">Android 14</a>, there's plenty of new stuff in Android 15. Google is introducing welcome tweaks to navigation with predictive back gestures, updated notifications, and a suite of foldable features. I tested every beta build of Android 15 and just got started with the stable release, and this is what you need to know about the latest version of Android.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-android-15-release-timeline"><span>Android 15 release timeline</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="Gor37rkx9LtEEZRJASiyog" name="android-15-schedule.jpg" alt="Android 15 release schedule" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Gor37rkx9LtEEZRJASiyog.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google was originally slated to release Android 15 in Q3, the stable build was pushed back. Thankfully, the stable Android 15 release is now available, and as of October 15, eligible Pixel devices can install the update.</p><p>While Google doesn't use codenames in public-facing documentation, all Android releases still have internal dessert codenames, and Android 15 is designated Vanilla Ice Cream. Like previous years, you can install the beta on Google devices, but the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-pixel-5-review">Pixel 5</a> series isn't eligible — only the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-pixel-6">Pixel 6</a> and upwards will pick up the update. Here's the list of devices:</p>
<ul><li>Pixel 6</li><li>Pixel 6 Pro</li><li>Pixel 6a</li><li>Pixel 7</li><li>Pixel 7 Pro</li><li>Pixel 7a</li><li>Pixel 8</li><li>Pixel 8 Pro</li><li>Pixel 9</li><li>Pixel 9 Pro</li><li>Pixel 9 Pro XL</li><li>Pixel 9 Pro Fold</li><li>Pixel Fold</li><li>Pixel Tablet</li></ul>
<p>The Android beta program debuted on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a>, with most major manufacturers getting in on the action. That said, the devices listed below will switch over to their manufacturer's skins — based on Android 15 — over the coming weeks. As such, the list below serves as a good guide to which non-Pixel devices will get the Android 15 update ahead of other phones:</p>
<ul><li><a href="https://developer.honor.com/en/docs/11100/guides/android_15_beta_guide">Honor</a>: Honor Magic 6 Pro, Honor Magic V2</li><li><a href="https://www.mi.com/global/support/guidance/androidtbeta">Xiaomi</a>: Xiaomi 14, Xiaomi 13T Pro, Xiaomi Pad 6S Pro 12.4</li><li><a href="https://community.oneplus.com/thread/1595803862105587712">OnePlus</a>: OnePlus 12, OnePlus Open</li><li>OPPO: Find X7</li><li><a href="https://developer.vivo.com/promotion/android15">Vivo</a>: Vivo X100</li><li><a href="https://developer.vivo.com/promotion/android15">iQOO</a>: iQOO 12</li><li><a href="https://nothing.community/d/10106-android-15-developer-preview-program-beta-1">Nothing</a>: Nothing Phone 2a</li><li><a href="https://c.realme.com/in/post-details/1790269629646561280">Realme</a>: Realme 12 Pro+ 5G</li><li><a href="https://dev.lenovo.com/android15">Lenovo</a>: Lenovo Tab Extreme</li><li><a href="https://k-tai.sharp.co.jp/support/developers/android15_betaprogram/">Sharp</a>: Sharp Aquos sense8</li><li><a href="https://tspot.tecno.com/#/detail?tid=411927">Tecno</a>: Tecno Camon 30 Pro 5G</li></ul>
<p>As usual, Samsung devices aren't on the list, and ASUS is a notable omission. If you have a Galaxy phone, you will need to wait a little while; Samsung usually rolls out its One UI beta shortly after the stable Android release, so there shouldn't be a lengthy wait.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-theft-detection-lock-secures-your-device-data"><span>Theft Detection Lock secures your device data</span></h2>
<p>Google is leveraging AI to safeguard your device in the event of a theft with a feature dubbed Theft Detection Lock. Basically, the feature relies on your phone's accelerometer to determine if someone has snatched your device and is trying to run, bike, or drive away, and it immediately locks the device.</p><p>Remote Lock allows you to remotely lock your device, and it works on conjunction with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/find-my-device">Find My Device</a>. Google is adding additional measures to deter thieves accessing sensitive information, such as authentication when removing a SIM card or disabling Find My Device.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-private-space-gives-you-an-additional-layer-of-security"><span>Private Space gives you an additional layer of security</span></h2>
<p>This feature has been around on several Chinese skins, and I use it quite a bit whenever I'm testing a phone running ColorOS. And with Android 15, Google is integrating Private Space into Android, so it will be available on all devices.</p><p>The feature allows you to lock sensitive apps locked away in a separate section that needs an additional layer of authentication. Once locked, these apps don't show up in the app drawer or the overview menu, and they're squirreled away inside a new user profile. Any data that's generated — photos, videos, and documents — is also hidden.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-notification-cooldown-turns-down-the-noise"><span>Notification cooldown turns down the noise</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="kiuynbZRkJSBsn6cyAv9zg" name="android-15-notifications.jpg" alt="Android 15 notification cooldown" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kiuynbZRkJSBsn6cyAv9zg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Notification cooldown is a great new feature that lowers the volume of incoming notifications when you get successive notifications from the same app. So if you're in a group chat and start getting constant notifications, Android 15 automatically lowers the volume of subsequent notifications. What's great is that you can select this setting for just conversations, or all apps. As someone who doesn't like getting many notification alerts (I use DND most of the day), this is a great new addition, and one that I will use to good effect.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-keyboard-vibration-gets-its-own-toggle"><span>Keyboard vibration gets its own toggle</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="gYViU9VahDfiu4YX38UNof" name="android-15-keyboard.jpg" alt="Android 15 keyboard vibration toggle" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gYViU9VahDfiu4YX38UNof.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Android 15 is adding a system-wide toggle to enable or disable keyboard vibration. You could do this previously by going into a keyboard's settings and toggle the feature individually, but the option to do so at a system-wide level that works across keyboards is a good addition. Google is also integrating a slider that lets you adjust the intensity of haptic feedback, similar to what OPPO does with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/oppo-coloros-13-review">ColorOS</a>.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-the-brightness-slider-vibrates-now"><span>The brightness slider vibrates now</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="HzD3qv9czFhiUjhPJyYnff" name="android-15-brightness.jpg" alt="Android 15 brightness slider in action" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HzD3qv9czFhiUjhPJyYnff.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In a bid to bring better feedback across the system, Google is adding haptic feedback to the brightness slider in Android 15. The effect is very subtle — it's not on the same level as the nav gesture intensity, but it is still great that you get some amount of feedback when adjusting the brightness.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-partial-screen-recording-lets-you-share-only-what-s-needed"><span>Partial screen recording lets you share only what's needed</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="9AqLjyR8TTy32ofebF9P9h" name="android-15-record.jpg" alt="Android 15 screen record" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9AqLjyR8TTy32ofebF9P9h.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google took its sweet time integrating a screen recorder into Android, and by the time it added it, all other brands had their own take on the feature, which was usually better. Anyway, Android 15 is getting an update that lets you take partial screen recording. Instead of recording the entire screen by default, you can now select to record an individual app, and it won't show the rest of the screen and notifications.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-bluetooth-tile-is-actually-useful"><span>Bluetooth tile is actually useful</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="qQ3JfHpNrxcsMWgr33tNQf" name="android-15-bluetooth.jpg" alt="Android 15 Bluetooth tile" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qQ3JfHpNrxcsMWgr33tNQf.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google moved the Wi-Fi and cellular connection tiles to a single tile called Internet, and it is a constant source of frustration as it adds another step if I just want to toggle my home internet on or off. By contrast, the Bluetooth tile — which could have actually benefitted with this functionality — was a standard toggle that turned the Bluetooth radio or on off.</p><p>Thankfully, Google is addressing this issue in Android 15, and a short press on the Bluetooth tile now pulls up a dialog box similar to the Internet one — you get to see your paired devices, and you have the ability to easily switch between devices, and there's the option to toggle Bluetooth connectivity. If you want to pair a new device, hitting the + icon at the bottom of the dialog box to pull up the Bluetooth settings page and connect a new device.</p><p>Samsung's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-one-ui-6">One UI</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/nothing-os-2-review">Nothing OS</a> already use this system, and it's good to see Google baking it into Android.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-android-15-enables-edge-to-edge-displays"><span>Android 15 enables edge-to-edge displays</span></h3>
<p>With Android 15, apps can show content that covers the entire width of the display, so if you have the gesture recognition bar enabled at the bottom of the page, you'll see content on either side of it. This should make content look a little more immersive — particularly when you're using a tablet.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-better-continuity-and-multitasking-on-foldables"><span>Better continuity and multitasking on foldables</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="otdGLT6rYiTxVh5oAktd2H" name="oneplus-open-25.jpg" alt="OnePlus Open review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/otdGLT6rYiTxVh5oAktd2H.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google is lifting a feature that debuted on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-open-review">OnePlus Open</a> that switches whatever action you're doing on the inner screen to the cover screen when you fold a device. This is a very useful feature, and other foldables like the Honor Magic V2 also have it. With it being integrated into Android 15, we should see it heading to even more foldables in the future.</p><p>Multitasking is also getting an upgrade, and you can now save split-screen app combinations to launch both at the same time.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-android-15-should-have-better-optimization"><span>Android 15 should have better optimization</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="AxWTrfRYJAJ7DLJEZoxu5g" name="android-15-home.jpg" alt="Android 15 home screen" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AxWTrfRYJAJ7DLJEZoxu5g.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google is making it easier for game and app makers to directly access the hardware, and the Android Dynamic Performance Framework consists of a set of APIs that allow better optimization, and in Android 15, Google is introducing a power-efficiency mode that's designed for "long-running background workloads." This is to ensure any background apps don't utilize more system resources than necessary.</p><p>In a similar vein, Google is rolling out new thermal thresholds that should make a difference with throttling. Even the latest phones with powerful hardware struggle with throttling issues in demanding titles, and I'm excited to see if this change makes a difference in real-world use.</p><p>And as for the interface as a whole, Google is adding smoother transitions, so Android 15 should feel fluid if you're on a device that has a high refresh panel.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-android-15-rolls-out-an-hq-webcam-mode"><span>Android 15 rolls out an HQ webcam mode</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="AriHAnbWjHYfa6q4QWWvVG" name="Google-Pixel-8-Pro-camera-bar-01.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 8 Pro camera bar in the porcelain colorway" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AriHAnbWjHYfa6q4QWWvVG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>You can <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-use-your-android-phone-webcam-your-pc">use your phone as a webcam</a>, and with Android 15, Google is rolling out an HQ mode that makes a difference to video quality. There's now a toggle that lets you enable HQ mode, and it offers better detail resolution. The only issue is that your device will get noticeably warm, but it is a nice addition nevertheless</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-android-15-has-an-always-active-taskbar"><span>Android 15 has an always-active taskbar</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2043px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:42.88%;"><img id="QtA2nUGNH7HEavU6yCjZ3R" name="Google-Pixel-Fold-display-unfolded-home-21x9.jpg" alt="The home screen on the large inner display of the Google Pixel Fold" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QtA2nUGNH7HEavU6yCjZ3R.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2043" height="876" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Android 15 DP2 brings a new feature to the Pixel Fold and Android tablets that enables a persistent taskbar at the bottom of the screen. Other brands offer this feature as standard on their foldables, so it is good to see Google adding it natively in Android 15.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-android-15-lets-you-share-audio-like-its-the-90s"><span>Android 15 lets you share audio like its the '90s</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="oUS42RqQJZhbPVtv5JKjTW" name="nothing-ear-2-26.jpg" alt="Nothing Ear (2) earbuds review on red background" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oUS42RqQJZhbPVtv5JKjTW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Another new feature in Android 15 is the ability to pay the same audio across multiple headphones — no need to share earbuds. The Audio sharing sub-menu is located within the Connected devices page, and it lets you cast music to more than one Bluetooth device at a time. It is intuitive to use, and makes Bluetooth sharing a breeze.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-android-15-is-now-available"><span>Android 15 is now available</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="a7NZY6fiEXh9Dfx4A7Xwkg" name="android-15-logo-wide.jpg" alt="Android 15 logo on Pixel 8" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/a7NZY6fiEXh9Dfx4A7Xwkg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>After an extensive beta program, the stable Android 15 is finally rolling out to Pixels, and should be available on other devices shortly.</p><p>If history is any indication, Samsung and OnePlus will roll out their own beta initiatives — using the stable Android 15 build as the foundation — in the coming days. There's no mention of that just yet, but I will update this post as soon as I hear more details. In the meantime, if you don't want to wait and need Android 15 now, your best bet is to get a Pixel.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="add76e79-1907-4ea7-9d50-d3393d336e0e">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bES27Em9ivhDZB88WYAtKk.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL official render - Hazel - front and back"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 Pro XL</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>The Pixel 9 Pro XL has considerable upgrades over its predecessors, and the build quality is on par with the best phones. It's also smoother in daily use, doesn't lag, and has better battery life. Oh, and the AI features are pretty good too. If you need Android 15 right now and don't want to wait, this is the phone to get. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The stable version of Android 15 is now available, and it is packed with new features. This is what you need to know.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">iU3jbtKzdGYbaWzYQtJSa5</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LmDEBeSE5Yia7z5BCvWuDg.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 16:00:37 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LmDEBeSE5Yia7z5BCvWuDg.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android 15 logo on Pixel 8 next to Pixel 7a and 7 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android 15 logo on Pixel 8 next to Pixel 7a and 7 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Beyerdynamic Verio 200 review: I was confused until I listened! ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Early in 2024, I reviewed the Bose Ultra Open earbuds and was blown away by their audio quality. The sound quality was exceptional for open earbuds, and the features were premium. They stood out head and shoulders above everything else, but then I heard about another premium brand doing something interesting that could change that.</p><p>Wait, what? A brand known for audiophile-quality audio gear is doing open-ear earbuds? When I heard that Beyerdynamic was bringing an open earbud to market, I was confused but eager to give the Verio 200 a shot! I was confused because, given Beyerdynamic’s reputation for high-quality audio tech, why? I was eager because of that same reputation.</p>

<h2 id="higher-price-higher-sound-quality-2">Higher price, higher sound quality</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="vcM7btRSacwnXaYHvP4ZYP" name="beyerdynamic-verio-200-unbox-cu.JPG" alt="Beyerdynamic Verio 200 box and case with earbuds inside" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vcM7btRSacwnXaYHvP4ZYP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Released in June 2024, the Beyerdynamic Verio 200 is available for $220 directly from beyerdynamic.com or Amazon. They are available in black, cream, or an orange and black “Sport” version.</p>

<h2 id="what-i-like-2">What I like</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="BusDPZoMbTH4kSFCza54cP" name="beyerdynamic-verio-200-in-open-case" alt="Beyerdynamic Verio 200 inside their charging case with the lid open" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BusDPZoMbTH4kSFCza54cP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>There’s much to like regarding Beyerdynamic’s first foray into open-ear products, the Verio 200. First up, the soft touch case is the first thing you’ll notice after unboxing.</p><p>It has a two-stage hinge, which keeps the lid open. Inside, you’ll find the earbuds, a status LED, and a multifunction button for pairing the earbuds, which support multipoint pairing; the feature worked flawlessly in my testing when simultaneously connected to a Pixel 9 and iPhone 15 Pro Max. The back of the case is where you’ll find the USB-C port for charging.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/bose-ultra-open-earbuds-review">Compared to Bose’s offering</a>, the Verio 200 is much larger, favoring the ear hook-style build, but they don’t feel heavy on me. They’re quite comfortable during extended wear, which is great because the sound quality is so good you’ll likely want to wear them for as long as the battery lasts. It&apos;s around 8 hours, depending on your listening volume. Part of the reason the Beyerdynamic Verio 200s sound so good is because they support Bluetooth 5.3 and Qualcomm aptX Adaptive Lossless, as well as the usual AAC and SBC codecs.</p><p>In other articles on open-ear true wireless earbuds, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/earbuds/best-open-ear-earbuds">I’ve talked about auditory masking</a> and how that affects the sound output of these types of earbuds. With that in mind, I first hit my Bass Test playlist and The Roots radio playlist on Tidal when trialing the audio quality. AptX 16 bit, 48kHz was the audio quality from Tidal and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-review">Pixel 9</a>, and I have to say that the bass reproduction was very full for a pair of headphones that don’t sit inside your ear canal. I&apos;d say it&apos;s on par with Bose.</p><p>The intensity of bass response will be predicated on the environmental noise around you. Less noise more bass rumble. More noise, less rumble. The Verio 200 isn’t for bass heads, but for those who enjoy deep, dark bass and require or want open earbuds, these are among the best I’ve listened to, outdone only by the newer <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/earbuds/nothing-ear-open-review">Nothing Ear (open) I recently reviewed</a>.<br></p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="VZ8QKUR8b9BQ4394bJXoXP" name="beyerdynamic-verio-200-earbud-in-hand.JPG" alt="Beyerdynamic Verio 200 in hand, showing the outside of the earbud" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VZ8QKUR8b9BQ4394bJXoXP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>What about other aspects of the sound signature? Mids and highs are a delight here. Vocals are bright and airy. The Beyerdynamic Verio 200’s love well mastered Jazz. Charles Mingus’ “Moanin’” was an absolute joy to listen to with the Verio 200. The track is currently my “go-to” for examining the stereo imaging and soundstage of a pair of headphones or earbuds and the Verio 200 did not let me down—beautiful imaging, with instrumentation layers well nuanced in the mastering of that track.</p><p>Listening to “Violin Duel” from the Chevalier belies the level of clarity the transducers in the Verio 200 reproduce. The attack and chord changes on the violins in the song are full of tension and texture as if you’re standing next to the musician, watching them aggressively attack these movements with the bow asserting itself over strings.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 7</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:224.44%;"><img id="sQCcLvbTX8RBzpMTNapzC3" name="beyerdynamic-verio-200-app1" alt="Screenshot of Beyerdynamic app home" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sQCcLvbTX8RBzpMTNapzC3.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1080" height="2424" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 7</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:224.44%;"><img id="DZhyt5oLjzy39X7uWJpiC3" name="beyerdynamic-verio-200-app2" alt="Screenshot of Beyerdynamic app custom EQ" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DZhyt5oLjzy39X7uWJpiC3.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1080" height="2424" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 7</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:224.44%;"><img id="DrvJbEkYuEdgQPbaJ3mLC3" name="beyerdynamic-verio-200-app3" alt="Screenshot of Beyerdynamic app 5-band EQ" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DrvJbEkYuEdgQPbaJ3mLC3.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1080" height="2424" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 4 of 7</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:224.44%;"><img id="MogYjRsW8Xcxm9eDXs9jC3" name="beyerdynamic-verio-200-app4" alt="Screenshot of Beyerdynamic app EQ presets" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MogYjRsW8Xcxm9eDXs9jC3.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1080" height="2424" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 5 of 7</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:224.44%;"><img id="Q59DLC8V6rf3wLd6WWzqC3" name="beyerdynamic-verio-200-app5" alt="Screenshot of Beyerdynamic app connection screen" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Q59DLC8V6rf3wLd6WWzqC3.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1080" height="2424" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 6 of 7</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:224.44%;"><img id="85wkD8R6VPBSTsev3cYtC3" name="beyerdynamic-verio-200-app6" alt="Screenshot of Beyerdynamic app customize playback settings" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/85wkD8R6VPBSTsev3cYtC3.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1080" height="2424" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 7 of 7</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:224.44%;"><img id="mhSCvbFcPigEXiiygMRtD3" name="beyerdynamic-verio-200-app7" alt="Screenshot of Bluetooth settings for Beyerdynamic Verio 200" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mhSCvbFcPigEXiiygMRtD3.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1080" height="2424" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Though not the most feature-laden app to come with earbuds, the Beyerdynamic app has what you need. Though the sound is solid out of the box, I tuned it a bit more to give me what I want when I’m wearing these in the streets. I boosted the low and high end, adopting a v-curve with the five-band EQ found in the app. You can also choose from several presets, along with the ability to set the auto power-off time, control the assistant functionality, and customize the playback and call functionality.</p><p>Last but definitely not least, the call quality was solid. Callers said I came through clear and didn’t sound tinny or like I was in a closet.</p>
<h2 id="what-could-be-improved-2">What could be improved</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="wvbAGcDvCm4vj6xWKL3rYP" name="beyerdynamic-verio-200-open-empty-case-in-hand.JPG" alt="Beyerdynamic Verio 200 case with lid open, no earbuds" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wvbAGcDvCm4vj6xWKL3rYP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I have two issues with the Beyerdynamic Verio 200, which are somewhat related. First, there is a lack of wireless charging support. I wonder why we couldn&apos;t get Qi charging on board in 2024 at this price point and with a case this large (my second issue).</p><p>If Beyerdynamic puts out a second-generation version of the Verio 200, it should support wireless charging.</p>
<h2 id="does-anything-else-compare-2">Does anything else compare?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="rPyAhMqzK2ox3a94gBShWZ" name="nothing-ear-open-cu-in-hand-cu.jpg" alt="Nothing Ear (open)" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rPyAhMqzK2ox3a94gBShWZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>There are products by Shokz, Anker’s Soundcore, and 1More in this category. All of these products are sold at a lower price than the Verio 200, but the products that most directly compete on features are <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/earbuds/nothing-ear-open-review">the Nothing Ear (open)</a> and the Bose Ultra Open earbuds. Both compete on sound quality, but you’ll pay a premium for the Bose experience. Bose&apos;s Ultra Open are one of my favorite open earbuds to date, but I don’t know that they’re $80 better than the Verio, which cost $220 on Amazon.</p><p>On the other hand, I would take a serious look at the Nothing Ear (open). They retail for $150 and are one of the most compelling open-ear products launched in 2024.</p><p>Though more expensive than the Ear (open), your other options in this category are Shokz OpenFit with its wireless charging case or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/anker-soundcore-aerofit-review">Soundcore’s AeroFit Pro</a> with its LDAC support. Both will save you around $40, though, as I stated, they are more expensive than Nothing.</p><p>If you’re an avid swimmer, check out our review of Shokz $180 <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/shokz-openswim-pro-and-openfit-air-review">OpenSwim Pro</a>, which are open-ear bone conduction headphones specifically tailored for watersports, that sound amazing <em>underwater!</em></p>
<h2 id="should-you-buy-the-verio-200-2">Should you buy the Verio 200?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="fKAmrsTqhJd9EWNyNMQ3YP" name="beyerdynamic-verio-200-earbud-speaker-medium.JPG" alt="Beyerdynamic Verio 200 in hand, showing the speaker and charging pins" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fKAmrsTqhJd9EWNyNMQ3YP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>My review period answered my initial question, “Why open ear?” The answer is likely that they knew they could do it and live up to their pedigree.</p><p>The Verio 200s live up to Beyerdynamic’s reputation for creating refined, high-end audio experiences! No, these won’t sound like their audiophile-grade, over-ear headphone cousins, but my time with the Verio 200 has given me an experience on par with two of my favorite open earbuds, the Bose Ultra Open and Nothing Ear (open) earbuds. With that, I can wholeheartedly recommend the Verio 200 as a solid option if you’re looking for high-quality audio in the open earbuds format.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="2bd84694-3d6c-4080-bd5a-e7aed6a9a794">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dZqYULXeX2TyvSH2uQVkp.jpg' alt="Product render of the Verio 200"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Beyerdynamic Verio 200</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="70" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>High-quality open earbuds</strong></em></p>
<p>The Beyerdynamic Verio 200 offers one of the best audio experiences in the open-ear audio category. Robust sound, a capable companion app, an IP54 water resistance rating, and good battery life make these a great option, if you're in the market for an open ear product.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/beyerdynamic-verio200-review</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Why would Beyerdynamic enter a market known for audio products that may not live up to its audiophile pedigree? You only need to listen to find out! ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">NiCG8may4qkGFC5MLchmma</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kQeZiWa5fE2WbhfZue2nse.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 13:35:20 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ klpmediallc@gmail.com (Tshaka Armstrong) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kQeZiWa5fE2WbhfZue2nse.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Tshaka Armstrong]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Beyerdynamic Verio 200 earbud in reviewer&#039;s hand]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Beyerdynamic Verio 200 earbud in reviewer&#039;s hand]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>