<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 20:36:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung simplifies Link to Windows app mirroring in One UI 6.1.1 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>While we wait on One UI 6.1.1, it was discovered that Samsung improved its app mirroring capabilities on Android.</li><li>Samsung simplifies the experience by removing the constant need for approval before Link to Windows can mirror an app to a computer.</li><li>Only Samsung's recent foldables have One UI 6.1.1 as the rest of its cast awaits the major AI update.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Windows and Android have had a comfortable app streaming relationship for a while, but it seems Samsung is improving that foundation.</p><p>According to a deep dive conducted by Mishaal Rahman (<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/one-ui-6-1-1-streaming-apps-windows-3469490/">Android Authority</a>), Samsung&apos;s One UI 6.1.1 software takes app streaming to a new level. A user must give permission to Link to Windows and the Phone Link to stream an app on their computer. Rahman&apos;s findings show that Samsung has "migrated" those necessary services into Android&apos;s purpose-built implementation.</p><p>This creates the opportunity for a streamlined experience when streaming an app to Windows since that permission page only appears once. Rahman showed that users are given the approval screen when initially attempting to stream an app. Your device will produce "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/microsoft-your-phone-android-what-it-and-how-does-it-work">Link to Windows</a>" permission page for phone information (your apps) followed by the mirroring page.</p><p>It&apos;s there that users can set whether or not they should allow mirroring "always," "only this time," or "don&apos;t allow."</p><p>Tapping "always allow" will remove that constant permissions acceptance prompt from appearing. However, it&apos;s required that your Android device remain on and not off (locked).</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1052px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:57.03%;"><img id="gqtjgqEjZ2TXB5XAc4Ea9e" name="samsung-one-ui-6-1-1-windows-link-change.jpg" alt="Samsung's One UI 6.1.1 software improves the Link to Windows experience." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gqtjgqEjZ2TXB5XAc4Ea9e.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1052" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Before, users were required to constantly approve an app to be streamed from their Android device to their computer. It was unnecessarily monotonous, but this small migration should alleviate that. Rahman adds that the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-6-review">Galaxy Z Flip 6</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Fold 6</a> have this capability, considering those are the only devices with the next iteration of the software.</p><p>Microsoft detailed <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/microsoft-phone-link-announcement">a huge revamp for Phone Link</a> that switched the app&apos;s name from "Your Phone." Users were given a much cleaner look at <em>everything </em>involving their phone on their computer, like their messages and other notifications. Minimizing the new sidebar offers an intuitive experience when receiving new notifications. That announcement arrived a few months after Windows 11  launched, which brought even more UI changes for those users.</p><p>With only Samsung&apos;s recent foldables having access to One UI 6.1.1, the rest of its Galaxy portfolio <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-one-ui-6-1-1-devices-confirmed">is still waiting on it</a>. Speculation guessed it would arrive before the summer, but now we&apos;re nearly midway through August and there&apos;s still no word. The software is expected to bring loads of AI improvements across the board.</p><p>Samsung confirmed as much on its community forum, stating users can expect new AI-backed camera features like Portrait Studio and Sketch to Image. Additionally, the weight of One UI 6.1.1 has reportedly <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-one-ui-7-delay-one-ui-6-1-1-ai">delayed the arrival of One UI 7</a> (Android 15) in its beta and stable capacities.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-one-ui-6-1-1-app-mirroring-improved</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung's One UI 6.1.1 software improves the app mirroring experience for Galaxy devices. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Wimm9LLKqW8SkKj65ERALQ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zGx7Y9D825WjuFnPgeS67i.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 19:59:59 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zGx7Y9D825WjuFnPgeS67i.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Microsoft Phone Link listing in the Microsoft Store]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Microsoft Phone Link listing in the Microsoft Store]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Made by Google event 2024 live blog: Pixel 9, Pro Fold, Watch 3, Gemini, and everything else we expect to see ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Google is holding its annual Made by Google event two months early, and we’re excited to see what’s in store! </p><p>The livestream begins at 10 a.m. PT / 1 p.m. ET., though Google has already “introduced” several products it intends to showcase, including the Pixel 9 Pro and Pixel 9 Pro Fold.</p><p>We have an in-depth guide of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/made-by-google-pixel-9-how-to-watch-what-to-expect"><u>what to expect from the Made by Google event</u></a>. Below, we’ll break down all the most important leaks and things we hope to see. Then, during the main event, we’ll chime in with our thoughts on everything Google has revealed about its 2024 Pixels!</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-live-stream"><span>Live stream</span></h3>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/N_y2tP9of8A" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>Long-time Pixel users might be excited by this blast from the past: Google reportedly plans to bring back “XL” devices! After the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-pixel-4-xl-review-one-month-later"><u>Pixel 4 XL</u></a> — which Senior Editor Harish Jonnalagadda had a “love-hate relationship” with in 2019 — you’ve been stuck with whatever size Google chose.</p><p>The Pixel 9 Pro XL <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-and-pixel-9-pro-xl-leaked-hands-on-video"><u>leaked on TikTok</u></a>, and even before that, a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/a-massive-pixel-9-leak-ruins-the-suspense-ahead-of-googles-big-event"><u>Google promo leak</u></a> suggested that the Pixel 9 Pro would ship in 6.3-inch and 6.8-inch sizes. Phones aside, Google allegedly wants to sell a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-3-xl-renders"><u>Pixel Watch 3 XL</u></a>, so you can choose between 1.2- and 1.4-inch displays.</p><p>We hope this rumor ends up being true at the Made by Google event; fans of smaller phones will appreciate having all the bells and whistles, with extra display space as optional. The small size of the Pixel Watch 2 was one of our only complaints about the Android watch, as well.</p>
<p>We at Android Central don’t endorse turning Made by Google into a drinking game (it’s five o’clock somewhere but definitely not in Mountain View). But if you took a shot every time they say  “Gemini” tomorrow, you’d probably die.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OMVpP-Zam1A" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>Google introduced the Pixel 9 Pro in the promo video above, but a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini"><u>Gemini</u></a> generative AI demo takes center stage, and the glimpse of the Pixel 9 Pro’s new camera bar is surrounded by an “Oh hi, AI” quote. It’s clear Google will try to stand out from iPhones and Galaxy phones by going all-in on Gemini, for better or worse.</p><p>A <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-series-to-have-nifty-freebies"><u>recent leak</u></a> suggested Google will give a free year of Google One AI Premium ($20/month) for all Pixel 9 buyers, plus Fitbit Premium and YouTube Premium trial runs. But will new AI tricks tempt Pixel 8 Pro buyers to upgrade? </p>
<p>Our biggest question with the new Pixel 9 series is the Tensor G4 CPU. Google’s Samsung LSI-made chips have always prioritized AI and camera performance compared to Snapdragon’s raw power, with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-pro-review"><u>Pixel 8 Pro</u></a> and older models frequently overheating.</p><p>An alleged Google insider claimed that the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/pixel-9-tensor-g4-minimalistic-upgrade-report"><u>Tensor G4 will have middling Cortex cores</u></a> and a new layout designed to improve cooling performance. While it could have a new modem with satellite connectivity, the GPU would remain unchanged.</p><p>While this rumor has some Android Central staffers planning to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-tensor-g4-rumors"><u>wait for the Pixel 10</u></a>, we assume that Google’s <em>NPU</em> for AI tricks and camera processing will be industry-leading. So even though the Tensor G4 benchmarks <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/pixel-9-tensor-g4-benchmark-test-scores-details"><u>only give a “slight boost” over the G3</u></a>, some Pixel 8 owners may still want to upgrade.</p>
<p>That same <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/a-massive-pixel-9-leak-ruins-the-suspense-ahead-of-googles-big-event"><u>Pixel 9 Pro leak</u></a> suggests it’ll have a 42MP selfie camera and a triple rear camera array: a 50MP main sensor, a 48MP ultrawide, and a 48MP telephoto lens. At first glance, all three rear sensors are the same as the Pixel 8 Pro’s, but Google could easily upgrade in other areas like exposure, zoom, or AI tricks. </p><p>Still, if you’re a fan of selfies, that might be the main reason to get excited about the Pixel 9 Pro.</p><p>One other 8 Pro to 9 Pro upgrade: You’ll allegedly have the chance to pay extra for 16GB, 4GB more than previous flagships. That could make stomaching another year of average Tensor speeds a little more bearable.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/made-by-google-event-2024-live-blog-pixel-9-pro-fold-watch-3-gemini-and-everything-else-we-expect-to-see</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Follow along with the Android Central staff as we cover the biggest Google product launch of the year! Here’s everything you need to know from the Pixel fall event 2024. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">3wHDBZBv3mfaaprd8zVSWJ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/stZNksMYs6ARKTmqb66xn8.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 18:30:25 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ shruti.shekar@futurenet.com (Shruti Shekar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/stZNksMYs6ARKTmqb66xn8.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Made By Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold advert]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Made By Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold advert]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Ask Jerry: I need the right Chromebook. Why is this so hard? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Welcome to Ask Jerry, where we talk about any and all the questions you might have about the smart things in your life. I&apos;m Jerry, and I have spent the better part of my life working with tech. I have a background in engineering and R&D and have been covering Android and Google for the past 15 years.</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Ask Jerry</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="rbW6k4ZmBUAZL7mR2bMnV6" name="jerrydude-avatar.gif" caption="" alt="Android Avatar of Jerry" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rbW6k4ZmBUAZL7mR2bMnV6.gif" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Future)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">Ask Jerry is a column where we answer your burning Android/tech questions with the help of long-time Android Central editor Jerry Hildenbrand.</p></div></div>
<p>I&apos;m also really good at researching data about everything — that&apos;s a big part of our job here at Android Central — and I love to help people (another big part of our job!). If you have questions about your tech, I&apos;d love to talk about them. </p><p>Email me at <strong>askjerryac@gmail.com</strong>, and I&apos;ll try to get things sorted out. You can remain anonymous if you like, and we promise we&apos;re not sharing anything we don&apos;t cover here.</p><p>I look forward to hearing from you!</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="picking-the-right-product-is-so-hard-2">Picking the right product is so hard</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="rSFRDGUDAcddj4Q3XrvP3E" name="acer-chromebook-spin-714-acer-stylus-penoval-stylus.jpg" alt="Acer Chromebook Spin 714 USI stylus next to Penoval Stylus Pen" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rSFRDGUDAcddj4Q3XrvP3E.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2500" height="1406" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>G. asks:</strong></p><p><em><strong>I&apos;ve never used a Chromebook before but I think I&apos;m interested in changing that. I&apos;m looking for something affordable (under $800), durable, travel-friendly, with great battery life.</strong></em></p><p><em><strong>I like to draw, binge-watch series, and stream movies. I also do lots of sporadic web browsing so I may have multiple browser tabs open (usually a dozen or fewer). One of the main reasons I mention battery life is that I travel a lot. I&apos;m not much of a gamer but I do play light or moderate games sometimes.</strong></em></p><p><em><strong>I just want something that can handle all this (and hopefully more). I&apos;ve read reviews and seen videos and even asked people online and in person, and what I gather is that one of the newer Acer models would work for me. </strong></em></p><p><em><strong>I&apos;m still not sure. Why is this so hard?!</strong></em></p>
<p>Hi there, G.! I paraphrased your question a bit, so it&apos;s better formatted for the web, but I am <em>so</em> glad you wrote in and asked. This is hard. It&apos;s good, but it&apos;s hard because there is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-chromebook">so much stuff out there to choose from</a>.</p><p>I like to give a quick answer for anyone searching before I talk more about anything, so here&apos;s what I think might work best for you:</p>
<p>You mentioned the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/acer-chromebook-spin-714-2023-reviewhttps://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/acer-chromebook-spin-714-review">Acer Chromebook Spin 714</a> (the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BJH9LGK8">older model</a> with its own stylus that doesn&apos;t use a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.theregister.com/2024/07/13/game_raptor_intel/">flawed Intel CPU</a>) and it&apos;s the Chromebook that leaps to my mind based on everything you&apos;re looking for. It has a great screen, excellent stylus support, plenty of ports, and good battery life. No Chromebook is great at gaming, but a model with an Intel core CPU can play some <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/play-steam-games-chromebook">light Steam games</a>. For what you mention you need it fits the bill while still coming in under your price point.</p><p>But I also have to ask if you&apos;ve considered a tablet. An iPad Air or a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/samsung-galaxy-tab-s9-hands-on">Galaxy Tab S9</a> is going to be better than a Chromebook when it comes to drawing, portability, and battery life. Of course, you don&apos;t have access to a desktop web browser like you would in a Chromebook and you&apos;re limited to mobile games. Either will also meet your set budget.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="HjSE9hHHy9vdAZVrycrBqX" name="samsung-galaxy-tab-s9-fe-s-pen-angled.jpg" alt="Writing on Galaxy Tab S9 FE with S Pen" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HjSE9hHHy9vdAZVrycrBqX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The point is that it&apos;s incredibly difficult to find a single device that can meet all of our needs, but there are usually choices out there that can come really close. In your case, you&apos;re not looking for something to use for office work or school work, prioritize usability over specs, and aren&apos;t trying to find some sort of tech unicorn that can do crazy things.</p><p>You want something good at the normal things a lot of us want out of our devices. Your needs are a lot like my own — I need to be able to work using the web browser, I want my battery to last, I love to kick back and stream a show or a movie, and I like to draw once in a while. I&apos;m still using an ancient <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-pixelbook-3-months-later" target="_blank">Google Pixelbook,</a> and whenever I think about upgrading, I notice I&apos;m flooded with good choices. Then I give up because I&apos;m worried I&apos;ll make the wrong choice and complain that my Pixelbook battery isn&apos;t up to snuff.</p>
<p>Ultimately, you have to decide what&apos;s right for you and live with how you spend your money. I gave you a few quick, easy choices, but that&apos;s a lot more to consider: <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/snapdragon-chips-are-going-make-chromebooks-even-better">ARM Chromebooks</a> have better app compatibility (important for gaming and drawing) and battery life, and tablets suck to type on and have a far worse web browser but are better than Chromebooks in some areas important to you, etc., etc.</p><p>One thing I think you absolutely should do is take the time to see these devices in person. Visit a store like Best Buy and see what&apos;s on display that you can play with for a bit to see if there is something you <strong>don&apos;t</strong> like.</p>
<p>In the end, I think you would be happy with either the Acer Spin 714 or the iPad Air/Galaxy Tab S9. If you want to stop trying to choose and start having fun, either is the way to go.</p><p>If you want to keep looking so you know you made the very best choice you could make, you&apos;re not alone. Having so many things to choose from makes this a really hard decision.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/ask-jerry-choosing-the-right-chromebook</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Have a question about the tech in your life? If so, maybe we can get them answered! ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">s4U2UKbdpEuPxhztPWZxVR</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HrmCzNcQDgwjg2sArrBf7S.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 18:11:31 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Chromebooks &amp; Laptops]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HrmCzNcQDgwjg2sArrBf7S.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android statues]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android statues]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Amazon knocks 36% OFF the already affordable Samsung Galaxy Tab S6 Lite —but for how long? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>If you&apos;re looking for a great deal on a tablet that comes with a stylus, Samsung and Amazon have got you covered this week. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Android-Included-Expandable-Exclusive/dp/B0CWS8MNW1" target="_blank"><strong>Amazon has launched a limited-time deal of 36% off the Samsung Galaxy Tab S6 Lite</strong></a>, representing $110 in savings from the normal purchase price. This economy-level tablet features 64GB of storage and a microSD slot for those who need more. It also comes with a headphone jack, a 10.4-inch LCD screen, and a lightweight, simple design.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="71abcffc-5c93-4d6a-9c50-2403e8e53cdc" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy Tab S6 Lite 64GB: $329.99" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy Tab S6 Lite 64GB: $329.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Android-Included-Expandable-Exclusive/dp/B0CWS8MNW1" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="dX6X67VdRuANy24L72Uedn" name="samsung-galaxy-tab-s6-lite-uniform-space.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dX6X67VdRuANy24L72Uedn.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy Tab S6 Lite 64GB: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Android-Included-Expandable-Exclusive/dp/B0CWS8MNW1" target="_blank" data-dimension112="71abcffc-5c93-4d6a-9c50-2403e8e53cdc" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy Tab S6 Lite 64GB: $329.99" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy Tab S6 Lite 64GB: $329.99"><del>$329.99</del><strong> $209.98 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>I certainly wouldn't call the S6 Lite one of the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-tablets" target="_blank">best Android tablets</a>, but it's enough to get the job done for most casual users. With an extra $110 off, Amazon has made this cheap tablet even more appealing to those who want a deal and don't need peak performance. The major selling points for the S6 Lite include its impressively long battery life, the inclusion of the Samsung S Pen, and its lightweight, minimal design.</p>
<p><strong>Price comparison: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-geek-squad-certified-refurbished-galaxy-tab-s6-lite-10-4-64gb-oxford-gray/6500284.p?skuId=6500284" target="_blank">Best Buy - $229.99</a><strong> </strong>| <a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Samsung-Galaxy-S6-Lite-2020-10-4-Tablet-64GB-Wi-Fi-S-Pen-Included-Oxford-Gray/769699649" target="_blank">Walmart - $209.98</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Android-Included-Expandable-Exclusive/dp/B0CWS8MNW1" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="71abcffc-5c93-4d6a-9c50-2403e8e53cdc" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy Tab S6 Lite 64GB: $329.99" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy Tab S6 Lite 64GB: $329.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>battery life is a major selling point for you; you want a good deal on a tablet that also comes with the Samsung S Pen; you&apos;re looking for something with at least 64GB of storage and the option to expand that.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if:</strong> you think you may be better off just going with an iPad; you require a tablet with industry-leading performance.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/samsung-galaxy-tab-s6-lite-review">Samsung Galaxy Tab S6 Lite</a> features the same size battery as the company&apos;s regular Galaxy Tab S6, but the lower-resolution display and other less power-intensive hardware give the S6 Lite superb battery life. This model comes with 64GB of storage on its own, as well as expandable storage of up to 512GB with the use of the microSD slot. The included S Pen also magnetically attaches to the side of the tablet, which is just plain old fun.</p><p>To be sure, the S6 Lite isn&apos;t a premium-level tablet, as evidenced by the general latency you&apos;ll experience when switching from one app to the next or trying to run games. Still, if you&apos;re a casual tablet user and you&apos;re just looking for something cheap, this deal might not be a bad option for you.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/amazon-knocks-36-off-the-already-affordable-samsung-galaxy-tab-s6-lite-but-for-how-long</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Right now, Amazon is selling the Samsung Galaxy Tab S6 Lite for $110 off, or 36% in savings, marking a great deal on a tablet that comes with a stylus. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">uvyFXU9XBrudvFQ5p9dKoH</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/aMRpgha7SDFdUoVitDngjB.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 16:32:08 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/aMRpgha7SDFdUoVitDngjB.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Tab S6 Lite tablet on couch arm]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Tab S6 Lite tablet on couch arm]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ YouTube is trying to save your roommates from your late-night binges ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>YouTube has a new feature for Premium users in the testing phase.</li><li>Dubbed Sleep Timer, it works similarly to what we have seen on the YouTube Music app.</li><li>It allows users to pause the playback after a certain period of time, ranging from 10 minutes to one hour.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>A sleep timer in an app is a lifesaver, especially for media apps. While plenty of music apps already have this handy feature, Google is now experimenting with it for YouTube.</p><p>The feature is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/new">currently available</a> for YouTube Premium subscribers and works similarly to what we have seen on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/youtube-music">YouTube Music</a> app. Users can select any random video on YouTube, hit play, and head to the little settings icon where they can find the new "Sleep timer" option.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:927px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:64.72%;"><img id="5V5u4eFEqQQaGMpLJwJJeP" name="youtube-sleep-timer-feature-02.jpg" alt="YouTube Sleep Timer feature" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5V5u4eFEqQQaGMpLJwJJeP.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="927" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:927px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:64.72%;"><img id="dhzZnkvitNpM7fRX7iokXP" name="youtube-sleep-timer-feature-01.jpg" alt="YouTube Sleep Timer feature" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dhzZnkvitNpM7fRX7iokXP.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="927" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Digging in further gives them a few options, like the ability to select several minutes ranging from 10, 15, 20, 30, 45, and 60 minutes. You can also sync it up with the video&apos;s run time.</p><p>This new feature is especially handy for those who love to watch videos or stream playlists before bed—it’s perfect if you tend to doze off mid-play. As <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/08/09/youtube-is-now-testing-a-built-in-sleep-timer-but-only-with-premium-subscribers/">9to5Google notes</a>, the best part is that it won’t mess up your watch history or mess with future recommendations from the platform.</p>
<p>As mentioned, the feature is currently experimental, and YouTube allows Premium subscribers to test it out until September 2.</p><p>You can find this feature on both the mobile and web versions of the platform. If the feedback is good—and it probably will be, given how useful this feature is—it’s likely to roll out for everyone soon.</p><p>YouTube has been testing several new features lately, with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-tests-less-disruptive-mid-roll-ads">most recent one</a> being intended to help creators serve up less disruptive ads. The service is experimenting with picture-in-picture (PiP) mid-roll ads, where the content shrinks into PiP mode while the ad takes over most of the screen—or possibly the reverse. You can spot this new option under "Monetization" in the Live Control Room.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-testing-sleep-timer-for-its-premium-users</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ YouTube wants to help you sleep peacefully by letting them pause playback after a certain period of time. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">6W7CUeATvHJZBbKhtXkh8d</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vUw4N2Xcsn5RUC2f49tmSA.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 14:30:58 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vUw4N2Xcsn5RUC2f49tmSA.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[YouTube]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[YouTube Sleep Timer feature]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[YouTube Sleep Timer feature]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ What does it mean if both Google and Samsung's Android 15 updates are delayed? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung reportedly delayed its One UI 7 beta rollout last month, and now, the delays are set to impact the upgrade's official rollout.</li><li>The new reports say that the rollout has been "delayed indefinitely" and there isn't even a concrete beta testing schedule for the Android 15-based One UI 7.</li><li>The news comes following an earlier report that Google is likely to ship the Pixel 9 series with Android 14, not Android 15.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Samsung typically releases new One UI updates, which are based on the latest version of Android, in the fall for its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best phones</a>. However, if the reports are any indication, Samsung&apos;s development and testing of One UI 7 haven&apos;t gone according to plan. We expected to see official information, and perhaps a beta, for One UI 7 at the end of last month. Instead, we got nothing, and now the situation appears to be getting worse.</p><p>As reported by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/08/07/samsung-android-15-update-delay/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a>, two reliable Android tipsters are now saying that One UI 7 is delayed, and the public rollout could be affected. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/UniverseIce/status/1820356963714335226" target="_blank">Ice Universe on X (formerly Twitter)</a> said "there are still no plans to launch it in the near future." By comparison, the One UI 6 beta rolled out to the Galaxy S23 series in the U.S. and a few other regions around this time last year.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">The latest situation of One UI 7 Beta: There are still no plans to launch it in the near future.<a href="https://twitter.com/UniverseIce/status/1820356963714335226">August 5, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/chunvn8888/status/1820488203679445482?s=19" target="_blank">Chun Bhai on X</a> followed up with a post on Aug. 5 that described the One UI 7 update as having been "delayed indefinitely" as of the prior week. When we first <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-has-allegedly-put-the-brakes-on-the-one-ui-7-beta-rollout">reported on the apparent One UI 7 beta delay in late July</a>, it was thought that Samsung was prioritizing One UI 6.1.1 development ahead of One UI 7. Or, that instability issues with One UI 7 were holding things up. Now, it&apos;s unclear what exactly is the cause for Samsung&apos;s delay.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Has been delayed indefinitely last week<a href="https://twitter.com/chunvn8888/status/1820488203679445482">August 5, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>The good news for Samsung is that it isn&apos;t the only company delaying the release of Android 15. Google&apos;s Pixel and earlier Nexus brands have typically ushered in new versions of Android. However, that might be changing this year. Reports indicate that the four new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9">Pixel 9</a> series phones launching at the Made by Google event this week will ship with Android 14, not Android 15. That big update will come later in a shocking move, if the leaks are correct.</p><p>Of course, the delay somewhat makes sense for Google. Although the Android 15 beta is nearing the platform stability stage of development, we have to remember that the Pixel 9 series is launching a whole two months earlier than usual. That would explain why <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a> isn&apos;t ready for the Pixel 9, Pixel 9 Pro, Pixel 9 Pro XL, and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-fold-2">Pixel 9 Pro Fold</a>. </p><p>Still, this sets up a situation where both Google and Samsung are releasing their software updates on an abnormal timetable, and it&apos;s going to affect consumers and the market in a real way.</p>
<h2 id="key-takeaways-from-google-and-samsung-apos-s-schedule-shifts-2">Key takeaways from Google and Samsung&apos;s schedule shifts</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="V2nvETLDpK7ckzSSrSsXF5" name="android-14-logo-samsung-4.jpg" alt="Android 14 logo on a Galaxy S23 Ultra" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/V2nvETLDpK7ckzSSrSsXF5.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google and Samsung both promised seven years of software updates with the Pixel 8 and Galaxy S24 series, respectively. Presumably, the companies will at least match that going forward. But what happens if Android 15 ships behind schedule? Google would need to give the Pixel 9 series <em>eight</em> full OS upgrades to match the support it gave the Pixel 8. There&apos;s no way calling the jump from Android 14 to Android 15 a month or two after the Pixel 9 releases as "a full OS upgrade" will fly well with buyers.</p><p>Samsung might not be affected by this predicament if it gets its One UI 7 development in order. One UI 6 debuted in October 2023, roughly three months before the Galaxy S24 series debuted in January of this year. As long as Samsung manages to get its Android 15-based update ready before the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25">Galaxy S25</a> lineup launches, it could avoid chaos. It looks like Google might be in for a sticky situation, though.</p><p>For Google, the rumored choice to ship the Pixel 9 lineup with Android 14 is a big shift in strategy. The company&apos;s own Android phones have always been the standard for "stock Android," sometimes to a fault. But it&apos;s leaving that behind. Pixels are far from stock Android nowadays, since they&apos;re full of Pixel-exclusive features and now Google AI tools. Google is treating the Pixel brand like any other Android brand, and the culmination of that is breaking up the ties between new Android releases and new Pixel releases. </p><p>For Samsung, the delays to One UI 7 development appear to continue for a rough few weeks for the company&apos;s mobile and wearable teams. The company faced criticism for its new Galaxy Watch Ultra and Galaxy Buds 3 releases, which were not-so-subtly inspired by Apple products. More importantly, there are quality control issues, delayed release dates, and product availability concerns that are still being worked out. A significant delay to One UI 7 would be another black mark on Samsung&apos;s record. </p><p>Finally, the delays to both Android and Google&apos;s Android 15 updates underscore the feebleness of Android updates in general. We see missed targets and long waits for software upgrades in the Android world all too often. Recently, Motorola took a full year to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2023-how-it-started-how-its-going">give the Razr+ (2023) an Android 14 update</a>. For some, the lack of consistency in Android updates is just another thing pushing them to the iPhone.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/what-does-it-mean-if-both-google-and-samsungs-android-15-updates-are-delayed</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Reports indicate that Google isn't shipping the Pixel 9 series with Android 15, and Samsung's One UI 7 won't be ready on-time either. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">mvXKTcejFDQn4DaEEuzVW4</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/a7NZY6fiEXh9Dfx4A7Xwkg.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 14:05:02 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/a7NZY6fiEXh9Dfx4A7Xwkg.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android 15 logo on Pixel 8]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android 15 logo on Pixel 8]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The OnePlus Buds Pro 3 could be here any day now ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The upcoming OnePluds Buds Pro 3 are rumored to be around Rs 13,999 in India, and about €199 (or $217) in Europe—a bit of an increase from previous models.</li><li>They might feature a dual-tone look with polished metal stems, a matte base, and a redesigned charging case in faux leather and an oval shape.</li><li>We can expect up to 43 hours of battery life, Bluetooth 5.4, LHDC 5.0 codec, and improved noise cancellation (up to 50dB), as per recent rumors.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>It looks like OnePlus might be dropping its highly anticipated flagship earbuds as soon as this week.</p><p>Tipster Yogesh Brar spilled the beans on the OnePlus Buds Pro 3&apos;s unveiling. We’ve seen the specs from earlier leaks, but Brar hints that the launch might happen later this week.</p><p>As for the price, the latest tip suggests that OnePlus&apos; next <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-earbuds">flagship wireless earbuds</a> might hit the Indian market for Rs 13,999, though the final price is expected to be similar to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/oneplus-buds-2-pro-review">Buds Pro 2</a>.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Here's the upcoming OnePlus Buds Pro 3- 11 mm woofer & 6 mm tweeter- LHDC 5.0- 50 dB ANC- Dynaudio EQ- 43 Hrs battery life- IP55 rating(Box price - Rs 13,999)Launches next weekSale price similar to Buds Pro 2Thoughts? pic.twitter.com/Mrame8FrQW<a href="https://twitter.com/heyitsyogesh/status/1821534555917922734">August 8, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>Brar didn’t mention any pricing information for the Western markets, but earlier leaks suggested the OnePlus Buds Pro 3 could be around €199 in Europe, or about $217 USD. That’s a €20 bump from earlier models.</p><p>OnePlus seems to be shaking things up with its new flagship earbuds. Leaked images show they’ll have a sleek dual-tone look, keeping some style from the current model.</p><p>The OnePlus Buds Pro 3’s charging case is supposedly getting a stylish upgrade with a faux leather finish. Leaked images from Brar also reveal new left (L) and right (R) markings on the earbuds and a fresh white color option.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1725px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="Td5DPFvA65ZwaMfsiBbGZ5" name="OnePlus-Buds-Pro-3-white.jpg" alt="OnePlus Buds Pro 3 leaked image" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Td5DPFvA65ZwaMfsiBbGZ5.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1725" height="1725" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Yogesh Brar / X)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1117px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="7yHHUnHug32gywZKGWDBn5" name="OnePlus-Buds-Pro-3.jpg" alt="OnePlus Buds Pro 3 leaked image" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7yHHUnHug32gywZKGWDBn5.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1117" height="1117" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Yogesh Brar / X)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>The Buds Pro 3 might also have an impressive battery life of up to 43 hours. Plus, with Bluetooth 5.4, you’ll get better connectivity and audio quality.</p><p>The earbuds will likely have the same driver setup as the previous model, with an 11mm woofer and a 6mm tweeter in each earbud. But don’t fret about audio upgrades—OnePlus might be working with Dynaudio to fine-tune the sound. Plus, noise cancellation is expected to get a boost, with up to 50dB of noise reduction.</p><p>The earbuds are said to upgrade to LHDC 5.0 codec technology, moving beyond the LHDC 4.0 found in the Buds Pro 2.</p><p>Earlier leaks also revealed that the Buds Pro 3 will boast an IP55 rating for water and dust resistance.</p>
<h2 id="a-fresh-look-and-ai-summary-on-the-horizon-2">A fresh look and AI Summary on the horizon</h2>
<p>The OnePlus Buds Pro 3 are said to have a fresh new look. They keep a similar shape to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/oneplus-buds-3-review">Buds 3</a>, but add polished metal stems and a matte base for a fancier feel. The charging case also gets a redesign, moving from a boxy to a sleek, oval shape.</p><p>OnePlus might also <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/oneplus-may-introduce-ai-call-summary-to-its-earbuds">bring its AI Summary feature to the Buds Pro 3 soon</a>. If it happens, future OnePlus Buds could start generating call transcripts using AI.</p><p>If the latest rumor holds up, we won’t have to wait long for these details to be confirmed.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/earbuds/the-oneplus-buds-pro-3-could-be-here-any-day-now</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Looks like OnePlus is about to blow our ears away with the Buds Pro 3. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">jgf2sAdqfmXtMUkBatzWYF</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/P84tEYd3nxSDVysXNdi6xU.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 13:53:41 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Earbuds]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/P84tEYd3nxSDVysXNdi6xU.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[OnePlus USA / X (Twitter)]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus Buds 3 case in blue]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus Buds 3 case in blue]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ YouTube Music may soon let you broadcast your jams with a shareable personal radio ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>YouTube Music is adding a personal radio feature that you can showcase on your profile, alongside your other top stats.</li><li>This personal radio playlist will presumably update daily and reflect your latest listening habits.</li><li>You will be able to share this playlist with friends via a link, and they can add it to their own libraries.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>YouTube Music is adding a feature to showcase your personalized radio on your profile and channel, alongside your top songs, artists, music videos, and playlists.</p><p>According to Reddit user <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/YoutubeMusic/comments/1enphjl/yt_music_is_slowly_adding_social_features/" target="_blank">Rolan_Albarico</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/youtube-music">YouTube Music</a> is rolling out a shareable personal radio feature (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/08/10/youtube-music-personal-radio/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a>). This playlist, updated daily and pinned to your profile, is said to reflect your latest listening habits and musical tastes.</p><p>YouTube Music&apos;s customizable profiles, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/youtubemusic/answer/13407991?visit_id=638590584419707655-3959287141&rd" target="_blank">launched in April of last year</a>, let users highlight their top songs, artists, playlists, and videos. Now, the platform is adding a new twist in the form of a shareable personal radio.</p><p>This playlist can be shared with others via a link or added to your library. Plus, anyone with the URL can save it to their own library as well.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1187px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:62.59%;"><img id="akjPBDoE2fHiDd3erw3Bzd" name="youtube-music-personal-radio-feature.png" alt="Youtube music shareable personal radio feature" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/akjPBDoE2fHiDd3erw3Bzd.png" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1187" height="743" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Rolan_Albarico / Reddit)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It’s a fresh way to showcase and share your evolving music tastes.</p><p>YouTube Music&apos;s shareable personal radio appears to be rolling out in stages. When it’s available for you, just go to your profile settings and find "Privacy and location" under "Channel settings." Then, flip the switch for "Enable public stats" or "Enable public personal radio" to start sharing your personalized radio station.</p><p>Unlike collaborative playlists that mix tastes from multiple users, YouTube Music&apos;s new personal radio is all about you. It zeroes in on your own listening history to create a music stream that&apos;s the perfect match for your specific tastes.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-streaming-music-apps-android">music streaming</a> world is a real battleground, with YouTube Music, Spotify, and Apple Music constantly vying for the top spot. These platforms are always innovating, copying each other’s best features, and trying to one-up each other to win and keep users.</p><p>But if you love sharing your music tastes with friends, YouTube Music’s upcoming personal radio might be a game-changer.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-music-may-soon-let-you-broadcast-your-jams-with-a-shareable-personal-radio</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ YouTube Music might soon let you rock out and share your personal radio with everyone. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">5hdBDvsqRPsVN9odSxDMQA</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vG9DF8AGbGzcVZmZ8sniwf.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 11:22:11 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vG9DF8AGbGzcVZmZ8sniwf.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Chris Wedel/Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[YouTube Music]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[YouTube Music]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung's Galaxy S24 FE just leaked, and it may come in more colors than ever ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung is gearing up for its next device launch, probably in October.</li><li>The Galaxy S24 FE is fully leaked, revealing display and camera specs ahead of the anticipated launch.</li><li>The device will have a triple camera setup, look a lot like Galaxy S24, and will likely be powered by an Exynos 2400e chipset.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>With Samsung&apos;s major Galaxy flagship launches wrapped up for the year, the next big thing to watch for is a Fan Edition. The rumored Galaxy S24 FE just got fully revealed, thanks to a new leak.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidheadlines.com/exclusive-samsung-galaxy-s24-fe-specs-features">Android Headlines</a> obtained a bunch of renders for the Galaxy S24 FE&apos;s marketing materials, showing off the device, its colors, and most of the specs. At first glance, it looks similar to the flagship <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-hands-on">Galaxy S24</a> and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s23-fe-hands-on">Galaxy S23 FE</a>, featuring flat edges, rounded corners, and the familiar triple camera setup on the back. But this time, the colors seem to stand out as different in the renders.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 6</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:783px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:76.63%;"><img id="dUZBCnjeuAao9iMWXwinw" name="galaxy-s24-fe-marketing-images-leak-10.jpg" alt="Galaxy S24 FE renders" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dUZBCnjeuAao9iMWXwinw.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="783" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 6</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:828px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:72.46%;"><img id="99U9Fdox8DemwM4hQJF6s" name="galaxy-s24-fe-marketing-images-leak-04.jpg" alt="Galaxy S24 FE renders" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/99U9Fdox8DemwM4hQJF6s.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="828" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 6</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:694px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:86.46%;"><img id="eZeJMyfzegtQPJ9SXBThm" name="galaxy-s24-fe-marketing-images-leak-03.jpg" alt="Galaxy S24 FE renders" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/eZeJMyfzegtQPJ9SXBThm.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="694" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 4 of 6</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:797px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.28%;"><img id="b8zNcD66jX7ndJdeBwJf43" name="galaxy-s24-fe-marketing-images-leak-12.jpg" alt="Galaxy S24 FE renders" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/b8zNcD66jX7ndJdeBwJf43.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="797" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 5 of 6</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:785px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:76.43%;"><img id="hqHqogCwRMHAJCX6Uk2rg" name="galaxy-s24-fe-marketing-images-leak-02.jpg" alt="Galaxy S24 FE renders" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hqHqogCwRMHAJCX6Uk2rg.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="785" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 6 of 6</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:748px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:80.21%;"><img id="5U9uTcxWqhu3AwWEZHrBb" name="galaxy-s24-fe-marketing-images-leak-01.jpg" alt="Galaxy S24 FE renders" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5U9uTcxWqhu3AwWEZHrBb.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="748" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>The upcoming Fan Edition phone might come in shades of blue, black, silver, green, and yellow, giving users plenty of options to choose from. According to the marketing materials, the Galaxy S24 FE will feature an aluminum frame and an Infinity-O display, protected by Corning Gorilla Victus Plus on both the front and back.</p><p>The display is expected to be 6.7 inches with a 120Hz refresh rate and Full HD+ resolution. It could also reach a peak brightness of 1900 nits, with bezels as thin as 1.99mm.</p><p>The rear cameras might include a 50MP primary wide-angle shooter, a 12MP ultra wide-angle lens, and an 8MP telephoto lens with 3x optical zoom. On the front, there’s expected to be a 10MP sensor for selfies.</p><p>The battery capacity isn’t confirmed yet (though it’s rumored to be 4565mAh), but it’s expected to deliver 78 hours of listening time and up to 29 hours of video playback. Like the flagship Galaxy S24 series, the recent <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Galaxy Z Fold 6</a>, and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-6-review">Galaxy Z Flip 6</a>, the Fan Edition will also feature Samsung&apos;s proprietary <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-galaxy-ai">Galaxy AI</a>.</p>
<p>The report also mentions that the Galaxy S24 FE will likely run on an Exynos 2400e processor, shipping with One UI 6.1.1, and featuring the Portrait Studio. In the U.S., its predecessor came with the Snapdragon 8 Gen 1, while other markets received the Exynos version. It seems likely that Samsung will follow a similar strategy this year.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-fe-supplier-launch-reported">launch is expected</a> to be sometime around October, and the device will presumably compete with the higher <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-android-phones">mid-range segment</a>, including models like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-review">Pixel 8a</a>. As for pricing, we expect it to be similar to the Galaxy S23 FE, which started at $599.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-fe-marketing-images-leak</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The leaked marketing material of Samsung's next Fan Edition phone shows the device from all angles. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">ty4GehMpgsowaVK8cDYBxc</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uSyBPJeByGJmBhwUeSb8V.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 09:23:43 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uSyBPJeByGJmBhwUeSb8V.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Headlines]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Galaxy S24 FE renders]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Galaxy S24 FE renders]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ GameSir G8 Plus review: The best mobile gaming controller gets even better ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>When I <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/gamesir-g8-galileo-review">reviewed the G8 Galileo</a> gaming controller earlier in the year, it was evident that GameSir was onto something special. The full-size controller just feels better to hold and use, and the hall effect thumbsticks and triggers are better than what&apos;s on console-grade controllers.</p><p>With the G8 Plus, GameSir is reusing the same design, but eschewing USB-C connectivity in favor of Bluetooth. In doing so, it is making the G8 Plus compatible with a significantly wider range of devices, including Android phones and tablets, iPhones, iPads, the Nintendo Switch, Windows, and just about anything that takes a Bluetooth controller.</p><p>That means you get the same great features as the G8 Galileo, but with the added convenience of Bluetooth. In short, if you&apos;re in need of a new mobile gaming controller, there really isn&apos;t anything better right now.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-gamesir-g8-plus-pricing-and-availability"><span>GameSir G8 Plus: Pricing and availability</span></h2>
<p>GameSir unveiled the G8 Plus mobile gaming controller on July 29, and it is now on sale globally. The G8 Plus is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Bluetooth-Controller-iOS-Wireless-Joysticks-Minecraft/dp/B0D8JJRCJN">available for just $79 on Amazon</a>, and that&apos;s a bargain considering what you actually get. The regular G8 with USB-C connectivity <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/GameSir-G8-Galileo-Controller-Joysticks/dp/B0CM3C9HRG">also costs the same</a>, and I&apos;d argue that the Bluetooth model is much more versatile.</p><p>You can also pick up the controller <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.gamesir.hk/products/g8plus-bluetooth-mobile-controller">from the brand&apos;s own website</a>. Just like the standard edition, there isn&apos;t a carrying case bundled with the package — that&apos;s an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/GameSir-Controller-Bag/dp/B0CR15KD1W">additional $15</a> if you&apos;re buying the controller on Amazon.</p>

<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-gamesir-g8-plus-what-i-like"><span>GameSir G8 Plus: What I like</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="HH3iJgika9kQfp2jYyuK7h" name="gamesir-g8-plus-2.jpg" alt="GameSir G8 Plus next to the standard G8 Galileo" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HH3iJgika9kQfp2jYyuK7h.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>GameSir nailed the design of the G8 Galileo, and it isn&apos;t changing anything with the G8 Plus. The controller has a full-size design, and there&apos;s a textured finish at the back that makes it easy to hold and use. The size is easily one of the best things about the G8 Plus; having full-size triggers, action buttons, and thumbsticks is just much more convenient, and the contoured design is comfortable.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="5F4ccgBitEpL5Yt7BTdZXi" name="gamesir-g8-plus-10.jpg" alt="GameSir G8 Plus controller with Vivo X100 Ultra slotted in" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5F4ccgBitEpL5Yt7BTdZXi.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Another plus point is the customizability; the faceplates detach easily, and you can switch out the thumbsticks — two additional sizes are bundled in the package — and even the configuration of the X, Y, A, and B action buttons, ideal if you&apos;re pairing it with the Switch.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="rXtSLuLfyxe9HepV4HtnLi" name="gamesir-g8-plus-9.jpg" alt="GameSir G8 Plus controller with Vivo X100 Ultra slotted in" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rXtSLuLfyxe9HepV4HtnLi.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The action buttons and D-Pad have good tactility, but it&apos;s the triggers and thumbsticks that differentiate the G8 Plus. GameSir uses hall effect magnetic sensors, and that means you&apos;ll never see any stick drift; while I&apos;ve only had the G8 Plus for a month, I used the G8 Galileo for the better part of a year now, and even after hundreds of hours of use, it has the same great feedback as day one.</p><p>The triggers have a great range of motion and excellent feedback, and the fact that you can change the size of the thumbsticks is an added bonus. There are two paddles at the back, and setting these up with in-game actions is relatively easy.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="M9JTxb5NPph8iw7ENrkvyh" name="gamesir-g8-plus-7.jpg" alt="GameSir G8 Plus triggers have full range of motion" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/M9JTxb5NPph8iw7ENrkvyh.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="8wFaAKs2vEUZDGFNYGqXoh" name="gamesir-g8-plus-6.jpg" alt="GameSir G8 Plus triggers have full range of motion" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8wFaAKs2vEUZDGFNYGqXoh.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Coming in at 314g, the G8 Plus is 60g heavier than the G8 Galileo. The added weight is due to the 1000mAh internal battery, and thankfully, the heft is balanced on both sides (there&apos;s a 500mAh battery underneath each section). The added weight is noticeable, but it doesn&apos;t cause any fatigue even after extended gaming sessions.</p><p>While the G8 is available in a grey color scheme, the G8 Plus switches to a darker grey that looks a little better. You still get the same rubber bridge that ensures the controller doesn&apos;t damage your phone, and the left side has good enough extension that you can slot in tablets without a lot of hassle.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="dbAKUeZNXmEx9Rkj6cedji" name="gamesir-g8-plus-11.jpg" alt="GameSir G8 Plus controller with Vivo X100 Ultra slotted in" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dbAKUeZNXmEx9Rkj6cedji.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Cases aren&apos;t an issue either, and I was able to use my <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/i-switched-back-to-the-pixel-8-pro-and-i-couldnt-be-happier">Pixel 8 Pro</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/apple-iphone-15-pro-max-long-term-review">iPhone 15 Pro Max</a> with rather bulky cases attached. There&apos;s enough clearance available, and the phone is held snugly between the two halves. The matte texture of the G8 Plus doesn&apos;t attract smudges, and overall, there isn&apos;t anything to fault on the design side of things.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="Ei7wnKBktmFvB7vdZnptHh" name="gamesir-g8-plus-3.jpg" alt="Back of the GameSir G8 Plus" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Ei7wnKBktmFvB7vdZnptHh.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Getting started with the G8 Plus is about as straightforward as it gets; pairing over Bluetooth is seamless, and it maintained a rock-solid connection. The GameSir logo has an LED ring that changes color based on what device is connected to it; Android is yellow, iOS is blue, Switch is red, and so on. You can change modes by selecting the record button and one of the action buttons, and you can easily switch between devices.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="mKK4tue7hAmsmEpPbxLHfh" name="gamesir-g8-plus-5.jpg" alt="GameSir G8 Plus with customizable paddles at the back" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mKK4tue7hAmsmEpPbxLHfh.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="eKVpjophSUbhHWFexWKmUh" name="gamesir-g8-plus-4.jpg" alt="GameSir G8 Plus with customizable paddles at the back" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/eKVpjophSUbhHWFexWKmUh.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>In terms of day-to-day performance, there isn&apos;t a mobile gaming controller that is as good as the G8 Plus. The triggers and buttons have fantastic feedback, and I know I&apos;ve said this a few times by now, but the fact that you get full-size buttons makes all the difference. I used mobile controllers that are aimed at portability, and they&apos;re not as much fun to use — particularly during marathon gaming sessions. That isn&apos;t a problem with the G8 Plus.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-gamesir-g8-plus-what-i-don-t-like"><span>GameSir G8 Plus: What I don't like</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="ZiDwadYyzkhLpJ7A9UgC6j" name="gamesir-g8-plus-13.jpg" alt="GameSir G8 Plus doesn't fit phones with big cameras" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZiDwadYyzkhLpJ7A9UgC6j.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>As the G8 Plus retains the same design as the G8 Galileo, it shares the same drawbacks. If you have a phone with a large camera island, you can&apos;t slot it into the controller. I had issues with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/xiaomi-14-ultra-review">Xiaomi 14 Ultra</a>, Vivo X100 Ultra, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oppo-find-x7-ultra-review">Find X7 Ultra</a>, and even the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-6-pro-review">Magic 6 Pro</a>. The only phones that didn&apos;t have clearance issues were the iPhone 15 Pro Max and Pixel 8 Pro, so I ended up using the G8 Plus with these devices most of the time.</p>
<p>However, there is a workaround; as there&apos;s no need to connect over USB-C, I was able to slot in the X100 Ultra in a way that the camera island sits flush with the rubber back of the controller (instead of slotting into the extended section), and while it isn&apos;t as secure a fit, it is usable.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="pXCoEQBj4D5QafPh9QLmEj" name="gamesir-g8-plus-14.jpg" alt="GameSir G8 Plus with USB-C connector highlighted" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pXCoEQBj4D5QafPh9QLmEj.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Because the G8 Plus connects over Bluetooth, it misses out on two extras that I used extensively on the G8 Galileo: 3.5mm jack and passthrough charging. There is a USB-C port on the side of the controller, but that&apos;s to charge its internal battery.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-gamesir-g8-plus-the-competition"><span>GameSir G8 Plus: The competition</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="DezWRoKYyzmuM2x4JWdA9H" name="gamesir-g8-galileo-2.jpg" alt="GameSir G8 Galileo with Pixel 8 Pro docked and playing a game" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DezWRoKYyzmuM2x4JWdA9H.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>There&apos;s no shortage of mobile controllers, and the Backbone One continues to lead the pack. That said, if you want a controller with full-size buttons, I&apos;d recommend the G8 Galileo; it eschews Bluetooth in favor of USB-C, but you get passthrough charging and the convenience of a 3.5mm jack. At $79, it costs the same as the G8 Plus.</p><p>Scuf&apos;s Nomad is a good choice if you want a smaller controller that has high-quality triggers and buttons. It isn&apos;t as comfortable to hold and use as the G8 Plus, but it&apos;s easier to carry on the road, and it has Bluetooth connectivity.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-gamesir-g8-plus-should-you-buy-it"><span>GameSir G8 Plus: Should you buy it?</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="HyJAubpFsGD3f52YszQbvg" name="gamesir-g8-plus-1.jpg" alt="GameSir G8 Plus controller against red and yellow background" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HyJAubpFsGD3f52YszQbvg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>You should buy this if:</strong></p>
<ul><li>You want a mobile controller with Bluetooth</li><li>You need full-size triggers and buttons</li><li>You want excellent battery life</li><li>You need hall effect thumbsticks</li></ul>
<p><strong>You shouldn&apos;t buy this if:</strong></p>
<ul><li>You have a phone with sizeable cameras</li><li>You need a controller with a 3.5mm jack and passthrough charging</li></ul>
<p>GameSir didn&apos;t make any design modifications to the G8 Plus, and that&apos;s a good thing. The G8 Galileo is arguably the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-game-controllers-android">best Android game controller</a> around, and a big part of its allure is the size; the ability to use full-size triggers, thumbsticks, action buttons, and D-Pad on a mobile gaming controller is wonderful, and it is the main reason why I like the G8 so much.</p><p>The G8 Plus follows in the same vein, and Bluetooth integration makes it easier to use. There&apos;s absolutely no lag or delay when using the controller, and the triggers are among the best you&apos;ll find in this segment. It is heavier than the standard G8, but the added heft isn&apos;t too noticeable, and battery life has been terrific.</p><p>To sum up, there isn&apos;t much to fault with the G8 Plus, and if you need a mobile gaming controller that connects over Bluetooth, it&apos;s my go-to recommendation.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="0f8c2efd-411b-45d7-b8d6-1645a7183d80">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ku9R9PmWg4MuaFeKNBGffg.jpg' alt="GameSir G8 Plus"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">GameSir G8 Plus</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>With hall effect thumbsticks and full-size buttons, the G8 Plus gives you the best features of a traditional console controller — and you can take it anywhere. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/gamesir-g8-plus-review</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ GameSir released a Bluetooth-enabled version of the G8 Galileo dubbed the G8 Plus, and it is outstanding.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">vLqcXKibdU45VzdK2ntZGK</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XBkZjWbGt8dVpi3s9iXs9i.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 09:04:52 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XBkZjWbGt8dVpi3s9iXs9i.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[GameSir G8 Plus controller with Vivo X100 Ultra slotted in]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[GameSir G8 Plus controller with Vivo X100 Ultra slotted in]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>