<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 21:43:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Launcher 10 lets you turn an Android phone into a Windows Phone ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A discovery made by MrMobiles on YouTube highlighted an app called Launcher 10 that can turn an Android phone into a Windows Phone OS.</li><li>Users will have an "authentic taste" of what it used to be, outfitted with the boxy, rectangular tiles that the Windows Phone software featured.</li><li>Microsoft discontinued Windows Phone in 2017 and even ended service support for its Surface Duo 2 in October 2024.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Remember the old Microsoft Windows Phone software? Well, another person does, too, and there's a program that can get it done.</p><p>As spotted by our friends at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.windowscentral.com/phones/windows-phone/watch-mrmobile-turn-a-samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-into-a-windows-phone">Windows Central</a>, YouTuber <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://youtu.be/_p4RbXLW8aY?si=aLU9Z6On6A2B1BBk&t=160">MrMobile</a>, AKA Michael Fisher, discovered a way to turn an Android phone into a Windows Phone. MrMobile found an app on the Play Store called <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.nfwebdev.launcher10&hl=en_US&pli=1">Launcher 10</a>, which gives users a "very authentic taste" of what once was for Microsoft's smartphone. If you remember the aesthetic of this phone — and Windows 8 by extension — then you know what you're in for.</p><p>Launcher 10 brings back those boxy, square, rectangular icons or "tiles." The app, when selected to be put to use within your settings, turns everything into what the Windows Phone OS used to be.</p><p>Interestingly enough, most of the apps that you're likely to have on your device like Gmail, Spotify, Google Calendar, Photos, and more appear properly through Launcher 10. Some of the app icons on the tiles take on Android's "Themed Icon," which is just an outline of the logo within it filled in with color. Others, like Chrome, feature a colored background with a recognizable logo in the center.</p><p>Another aspect that is very Windows Phone is the notifications. MrMobile gave a brief glimpse at a notification, which retained that Windows flair.</p><p>If you're interested, you can watch MrMobiles' <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_p4RbXLW8aY&t=160s&ab_channel=MrMobile%5BMichaelFisher%5D">full glimpse at Launcher 10</a>. Additionally, the video highlights the app's multitude of customization options to get the right theme. However, MrMobiles delivers a warning to those who will want to go that extra mile with Launcher 10.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_p4RbXLW8aY?start=161" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>For those looking for a bit of nostalgia, Launcher 10 might be the best gift of the season. Microsoft discontinued its Windows Phone OS in 2017. It didn't come without a heavy heart as the company's CEO Satya Nadella told <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.businessinsider.com/microsoft-ceo-satya-nadella-interview-ai-activision-blizzard-axel-springer-2023-10?r=US&IR=T">Business Insider</a> in 2023 "the decision I think a lot of people talk about – and one of the most difficult decisions I made when I became CEO — was our exit of what I'll call the mobile phone as defined then" (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-ceo-admits-giving-up-on-windows-phone-was-one-of-the-most-difficult-decisions-he-made">IGN</a>).</p><p>The Windows Phone OS was in response to what Apple had done with iOS and Google with Android, but it didn't catch on.</p><p>As such, Microsoft bowed out of the software side of mobile phones, but it still had its a phone: the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/surface-duo-announcement">Surface Duo</a> and the Surface Duo 2 foldables. Neither of those devices lasted particularly long as Microsoft detailed the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/microsoft-ends-surface-duo-2-support-with-final-security-update">end of service for the Surface Duo 2</a> this year in October. The device only received one update that took it from Android 11 to Android 12L.</p><p>It seemed that Microsoft was more interested in "streamlining" its Surface ecosystem and there are no plans to return the Duo.</p><p>Despite Microsoft's rocky smartphone and phone OS history, the company has taken strides to improve its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/phone-link-is-looking-more-like-windows-answer-to-apples-airdrop">computer relationship with Android phones</a>. In August, Windows' latest features for Phone Link for OS 10 and 11 rivaled Apple's AirDrop with quicker file sharing between PC and Android. Additionally, the dedicated app makes this even easier (and faster).</p><p>Elsewhere, Microsoft even <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-one-ui-6-1-1-app-mirroring-improved">improved its Link to Windows</a> mirroring experience for Galaxy devices with One UI 6.1.1 that same month.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/launcher-10-android-phone-windows-phone-os-style</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A Youtuber discovered an app that can turn the Android software into the Windows Phone OS. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">HBFXpiVUe2LgPiRppds22f</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XZafwZdCrLnRXNAFjUCGH4.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 20:37:57 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XZafwZdCrLnRXNAFjUCGH4.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[MrMobile / YouTube]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A Galaxy S24 Ultra running Launcher 10, which turns its theme into the Windows Phone version.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A Galaxy S24 Ultra running Launcher 10, which turns its theme into the Windows Phone version.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Galaxy S25 series will allegedly see sporadic price increases, per reports ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung is rumored to increase the price of the Galaxy S25 in South Korea following a higher exchange rate and chip costs from Qualcomm.</li><li>A concrete number wasn't stated; however, the price is expected to be "slightly" higher than the S24 in South Korea.</li><li>In contrast, another report states Samsung's Galaxy S25 series could have the same price in Europe.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Rumors are surfacing, with details that suggest Samsung's next flagships could see a jump in price for some.</p><p>A recent report by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://m.yna.co.kr/amp/view/AKR20241209139300017">Yonhap News</a> (Korean) cites an industry source in saying Samsung's Galaxy S25 series could see a price increase in South Korea (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/12/11/samsung-galaxy-s25-price-leaks/">9to5Google</a>). There is reportedly a "possibility" for such a future regarding the S25 trio. The publication purports that this apparent "outlook" is due to the use of Qualcomm's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-announces-snapdragon-8-elite-chip">Snapdragon 8 Elite</a> SoC in all three devices.</p><p>Its sources supposedly added that another contributing factor is the "predicted" price increase for the latest flagship chip. The company has reportedly raised the prices of its technology by roughly 30% when compared to previous generations and this is suspected to affect Samsung's views on the Galaxy S25 pricing.</p><p>The exchange rate between Samsung and Qualcomm is also another culprit for the potential price increase as it's higher than it has been in the past.</p><p>The publication didn't state an exact number; however, it's suspected to be "slightly" higher than the cost of the S24 on Samsung's home soil.</p><p>Elsewhere, another report spotted by 9to5 from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://winfuture.de/news,147437.html">WinFuture</a> (German) claims that this price increase might not affect <em>every </em>region. The information comes via a retailer leak in the region, which shows that the Galaxy S25 pricing (seemingly) remains the same as the soon-to-be predecessor trio. The post claims that the prices were allegedly the same in Germany, which <em>could </em>mean that the rest of Europe will see the same prices.</p><p>According to the publication, the following leaked prices regard the base versions of the series: Galaxy S25 128GB: 899 euro (~$943), Galaxy S25 Plus 256GB: 1,149 euro (~$1,205), and the Galaxy S25 Ultra 256GB: 1,449 euro (~$1,520).</p><p>Of course, the U.S. pricing estimates here are not one-to-one, meaning these aren't something you should take as a literal. <em>If </em>Samsung raises prices in the U.S. market, these numbers will likely shift to better suit the area. Meanwhile, a potential price increase <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-4-rumored-price-hike-sour">was rumored in late September</a>.</p><p>Shortly before the Snapdragon 8 Elite launched, a tipster claimed that Qualcomm was placing a ~$190 price increase on its new Oryon CPU-based chip. That was roughly a 20% increase over the price of the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 for this latest generation of flagship models. The 3nm process was supposedly "quite expensive," thus the price increase rumors we've continued to hear.</p><p>The 8 Elite delivers powerful improvements over the SD 8 Gen 3, like a 45% boost in performance and a 44% boost in efficiency.</p><p>Samsung is expected to debut its Galaxy S25 series in January 2024 during Galaxy Unpacked. A recent string of rumors states the devices could even adopt <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-s25-qi2-wireless-charging-support-rumors">Qi2 wireless charging</a>, too.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-s25-series-alleged-sporadic-price-increase-rumored</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Galaxy S25 price rumors paint a sporadic picture for its global launch. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">TLwq9sGbVEcRLWPc9cMRFM</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/aW5aJXDvAiQnLpfxNZ3NE3.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 19:51:46 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/aW5aJXDvAiQnLpfxNZ3NE3.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Hands-on with the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Hands-on with the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Meta confirms widespread Whatsapp, Instagram outage, working on a solution as thousands still wait for a fix ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Users reported issues accessing various Meta apps and platforms Wednesday, Dec. 11.</li><li>Meta acknowledged the "technical issue" in a post on X (formerly Twitter).</li><li>Though the company said it was working "as quickly as possible" to restore service, it did not provide a concrete timetable for a fix.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Meta apps, services, and platforms are currently experiencing a widespread outage, the company confirmed in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/Meta/status/1866918000374280593" target="_blank">post</a> on X (formerly Twitter). Users started experiencing issues in the afternoon on Wednesday, Dec. 11, as evidenced by various social media posts on working platforms and by the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://downdetector.com" target="_blank">Downdetector</a> — a site that tracks interruptions to major services. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/instagram">Instagram</a>, Facebook, WhatsApp, Threads, Messenger, and Oculus are a few platforms that appear to be affected by the outage.</p><p>"We’re aware that a technical issue is impacting some users’ ability to access our apps," the company said in the post. "We’re working to get things back to normal as quickly as possible and apologize for any inconvenience."</p><p>The problems can cause some Meta platforms to be inaccessible, load slowly, or show older posts. Multiple members of the Android Central team experienced issues with Meta apps. However, the number of Downdetector reports have slowly decreased over the last hour, indicating that Meta is making progress restoring service.</p><p>"We know there’s a technical issue impacting some people’s ability to access Instagram," the official Instagram account <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/instagram/status/1866920842443337824" target="_blank">posted</a> on X. "We’re working to get things back to normal as quickly as possible and are sorry for any inconvenience."</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">We’re aware that a technical issue is impacting some users’ ability to access our apps. We’re working to get things back to normal as quickly as possible and apologize for any inconvenience.<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1866918000374280593">December 11, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>The issues appear to be extremely widespread, with Downdetector showing over <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://downdetector.com/status/instagram/" target="_blank">70,000 reports of Instagram being unavailable</a> for users today. The situation is worse for Facebook, which has been reported down for over 100,000 users, according to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://downdetector.com/status/facebook/" target="_blank">Downdetector</a>.</p><p>This isn't the first time Meta's services have faced significant service interruptions. In March 2024, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/facebook-and-instagram-down-right-now">nearly all Meta platforms went offline</a> for a brief period.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/facebook-whatsapp-and-instagram-are-down-as-meta-faces-widespread-outage</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Nearly all of Meta's services, including Facebook, WhatsApp, Instagram, Threads, and Messenger, are currently down. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">8gZrEeKKwqezAnkjKr3JrS</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/g7z7GKTRj49D2GHSqfqYkT.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 19:43:59 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/g7z7GKTRj49D2GHSqfqYkT.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nick Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Facebook and Instagram down statuses on downdetector.com]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Facebook and Instagram down statuses on downdetector.com]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google's Project Astra waitlist signups begin with enhanced AR features ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google announced that it has opened its "trusted testers" waitlist for interested participants for Project Astra, its AR venture.</li><li>The company detailed that users can engage with Project Astra via mobile (Android) and "prototype glasses."</li><li>It seems there will be an experimental Astra app that lets users open their camera or share their screen for quick information on what they see.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google's "vision for the future of AR" is entering an exciting phase today (Dec 11) as it progresses its development.</p><p>Per Google's DeepMind page <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://deepmind.google/technologies/project-astra/">for Project Astra</a>, the company announced that the latest AR venture has opened its "trusted tester" waitlist. The company states those <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScCrFFCFcZ9q_0Ti_a-qkh56W26lysgcArpNiaDDQ8DngG9eg/viewform?utm_source=deepmind.google&utm_medium=referral&utm_campaign=gdm&utm_content=">signing up today</a> (Dec 11) can explore the "future capabilities" of its "universal AI assistant." Signing up will require users to fill out a brief form involving their name, location, age, and Android phone type.</p><p>Additionally, Google will ask if you are interested in "using prototype glasses."</p><p>When it comes to your phone, it seems this early test will see accepted participants downloading a Project Astra Android app. A short demo video shows that users can open the app and activate the camera within it to point at something they're interested in. Google states Astra is "multilingual," meaning users can speak to the AI model in their preferred language and receive information back.</p><p>The demo shows a model asking about a string of Chinese lanterns (in French). Astra responds both vocally and in written text with (hopefully) relevant and useful information about your query.</p><p>Moreover, Google adds that users can "share their screen" with Astra to gain even more assistance.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1050px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:50.19%;"><img id="scrkicTkF2C4mLg9diudmP" name="google-project-astra-enters-signup-phase" alt="Google's Project Astra lets testers point their cameras at items within its app to receive information about it." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/scrkicTkF2C4mLg9diudmP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1050" height="527" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The AI model is said to leverage Google apps like Maps, Lens, and Search to fulfill a user's query. This is reportedly a part of its "enhanced understanding." A <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://deepmind.google/technologies/project-astra/tool-use/">subsequent post</a> shows that Astra is capable of "contextual understanding" for "clear, detailed answers, and it can explain the thinking and context behind" its answers. Moreover, Google has added a memory bank to Astra, meaning the AI <em>should </em>remember key details from your previous encounters.</p><p>This seems like something similar to "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini-saved-info-rollout-detailed">Saved Info</a>" in Gemini, which Google rolled out in mid-November.</p><p>The other side of this sign-up is Google's mention of prototype AR glasses. Its announcement splash page only highlights that Astra can "integrate seamlessly with prototype glasses to see the world as you see it – for an even more immersive and helpful experience."</p><p>We've been expecting AR glasses from Google <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/google-may-have-shown-off-ar-glasses-prototype-at-io-2024">ever since I/O 2024</a> when it showcased Project Astra. The demo showed how interactive and engaged Project Astra is (likely) designed to be. When wearing a pair of AR glasses, the device will "record" your surroundings in real time, so when you ask a question, the AI can answer it.</p><p>It's worth mentioning that Project Astra is an AI routine <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/google-project-starline-astra-ar-glasses">that's built off Gemini</a> to give it that "real person-like" experience during conversations. Google also showed that Astra can remember the location of objects, like where you last set down your AR glasses.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hIIlJt8JERI" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/google-project-astra-ar-waitlist-opens-trusted-testers</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google opens the gates to its trusted tester waitlist for Project Astra. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">9oJhGAtfbfhsmHV6hPSCUc</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AoKqVHdHVKDR67J5V6YHtH.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 18:36:36 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AoKqVHdHVKDR67J5V6YHtH.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google&#039;s Project Astra opens its trusted testers signup.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google&#039;s Project Astra opens its trusted testers signup.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google's latest AI model, Gemini 2.0, is here to usher in the 'agentic era'  ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google is releasing Gemini 2.0 starting today, which will power what it calls the "agentic era."</li><li>Today, Gemini 2.0 Flash Experimental is available to developers in the Google AI Studio and Vertex AI using the Gemini API.</li><li>Gemini 2.0 Flash Experimental is also available in a chat-optimized form in the Gemini web client starting today, and the full lineup of Gemini 2.0 models will make their way to more Google products and services next year.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Roughly 10 months after Google's current generation of AI models were released to the public, the company is previewing the future: Gemini 2.0. Starting today, the smaller Gemini 2.0 Flash Experimental model will be available to developers and Gemini users, with more sizes and implementations to come next year.</p><p>Google views the next step forward for AI as the "agentic era," and in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.google/technology/google-deepmind/google-gemini-ai-update-december-2024/" target="_blank">blog post</a>, the company outlined how Gemini 2.0 models are purpose-built to power AI agents. This will be the foundation for Google's most ambitious projects, from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/google-may-have-shown-off-ar-glasses-prototype-at-io-2024">multimodal helpers</a> to Chrome extensions that can do your browsing for you.</p><p>"Over the last year, we have been investing in developing more agentic models, meaning they can understand more about the world around you, think multiple steps ahead, and take action on your behalf, with your supervision," wrote Google CEO Sundar Pichai. "With new advances in multimodality — like native image and audio output — and native tool use, it will enable us to build new AI agents that bring us closer to our vision of a universal assistant."</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hIIlJt8JERI" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>Although only an experimental model of Google's smallest AI model is available today, there are a few key reasons to be excited. Notably, Google's Gemini 2.0 Flash model not only outperforms Gemini 1.5 Flash, but also the larger and more powerful <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini 1.5 Pro model</a> in certain benchmarks. Gemini 2.0 Flash now supports both multimodal inputs and outputs, meaning the model can natively generate images, text, speech, or a combination of the three.</p><p>Gemini 2.0 Flash Experimental is available globally as an option in the Gemini web client today, and will come to the Gemini mobile app soon. Additionally, developers can try out the experimental version of Gemini 2.0 Flash using the Gemini API in Google AI Studio or Vertex AI.</p><p>Eventually, Gemini 2.0 will power most or all of Google's AI-equipped features. The models are specifically tailored for use with AI agents, like Project Astra, which <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/google-project-starline-astra-ar-glasses">was previewed at Google I/O 2024</a>. It's a multimodal AI helper that can take in what's happening around you and answer questions with the context of your environment. There are also new projects, like Project Mariner. Currently, Project Mariner is a Chrome extension being tested as a research prototype that can handle your browsing needs for you.</p><p>Google's agentic vision is ambitious, with plenty more applications. There's Jules, a helper made for developers that integrates with GitHub workflows. Another proof-of-concept is the company's collaboration with Supercell, which tests how AI agents can be applied to strategy and simulation games.</p><p>Finally, there's now a new Deep Research mode in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-might-let-you-share-custom-gems-for-gemini-in-the-mobile-app">Gemini Advanced</a> that uses long context windows and advanced reasoning to function as a research assistant.</p><p>Many of Google's Gemini 2.0-powered ideas aren't available now, but are in active development. Project Astra, for example, is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/google-project-astra-ar-waitlist-opens">being tested externally through Google's trusted tester program</a>. However, some are available starting today, like Gemini 2.0 Flash Experimental in Gemini and Gemini 2.0 in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/gemini-android-ai-overviews-spotted">AI Overviews</a> — which is in limited testing and will be more widely available next year.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/googles-latest-ai-model-gemini-2-0-is-here-to-usher-in-the-agentic-era</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Gemini 2.0 will power the previously-previewed Project Astra — plus new projects, like Project Mariner.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">L3GPRQ8q6zeKME9SG4ici</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WK7yDjQB2kjcz6MAYd2y4C.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 18:30:16 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WK7yDjQB2kjcz6MAYd2y4C.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Gemini 2.0 graphic provided by Google.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Gemini 2.0 graphic provided by Google.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Gboard's Emoji Kitchen just got a smarter suggestion bar ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Gboard’s Emoji Kitchen redesign adds a top-row suggestion bar for easy emoji combos, replacing the recent creations list.</li><li>A new "Browse" screen with an arrow lets you quickly explore quirky emoji pairings.</li><li>A floating action button in the bottom-right corner lets you pick emojis and instantly see combo options.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google’s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-december-2024-feature-drop-announced">final Pixel update of the year</a> teased Emoji Kitchen changes for Gboard, and now we’re finally seeing them in action.</p><p>Gboard’s redesigned <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-gboard-emoji-mashups-and-how-create-your-own">Emoji Kitchen</a> introduces a top-row suggestion bar in the Emoji tab, replacing the old recent creations list, as spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/12/09/gboard-emoji-kitchen-redesign/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a>. This handy tweak makes it super easy to explore fun emoji combos by just tapping a suggestion.</p><p>The update also makes Emoji Kitchen more accessible with a new arrow that opens an expanded "Browse" screen. Here, you’ll find tons of emoji pairings—including quirky ones as shown below. It’s a quicker, easier way to create stickers without scrolling endlessly.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:552px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:126.81%;"><img id="RCpkHBEpnWD5W7fCJmWBmD" name="Gboard-emoji-kitchen" alt="redesigned emoji kitchen in gboard" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RCpkHBEpnWD5W7fCJmWBmD.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="552" height="700" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: 9to5Google)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:126.85%;"><img id="wMWLsqqaxP47E4QZDqoUkD" name="Gboard-emoji-kitchen" alt="redesigned emoji kitchen in gboard" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wMWLsqqaxP47E4QZDqoUkD.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1080" height="1370" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: 9to5Google)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:552px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:126.81%;"><img id="UGsk4nW4se6e4WpVsVmvmD" name="Gboard-emoji-kitchen" alt="redesigned emoji kitchen in gboard" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/UGsk4nW4se6e4WpVsVmvmD.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="552" height="700" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: 9to5Google)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>This feature is perfect for anyone who values speed and wants to skip the trial-and-error hassle.</p><p>Furthermore, tapping on any emoji combo lets you break it down into the two originals. Plus, there’s a new history button in the top-right corner for quick access to your favorite or recent mashups. This redesign keeps the top suggestion bar clean and focused on fresh emoji ideas instead of past creations.</p><p>A new floating action button in the bottom-right corner gives quick access to the emoji picker. Pick an emoji, and you’ll see a full list of combo options using that emoji as the base. It makes creating unique emoji mashups way easier.</p><p>The changes might fly under the radar for casual users, but for Emoji Kitchen regulars, they make a big difference in how smoothly everything works.</p><p>The revamped Emoji Kitchen is rolling out as a server-side update for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/top-gboard-tips-and-tricks">Gboard</a> beta users on version 14.8. It’s not available for stable users yet, but it’s expected to reach all Android phones, not just Pixels, eventually.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/gboards-emoji-kitchen-just-got-a-smarter-suggestion-bar</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The latest Gboard beta brings a revamped Emoji Kitchen UI. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">HcKvLMXS84VBrn5nLxtCLK</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/chVHj3mxsVVcGRiwYNEkS.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 10:07:24 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/chVHj3mxsVVcGRiwYNEkS.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Gboard emoji and Emoji Kitchen]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Gboard emoji and Emoji Kitchen]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus review: Making the same mistakes over and over again ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>I've always recommended Redmi Note devices in the past, and it was easy to do so; the devices combined great hardware with an unbeatable value, and they undercut their rivals by a considerable margin. But that hasn't been the case in the last two years, with Xiaomi changing focus to the mid-range category. While the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/redmi-note-12-pro-plus-review">Redmi Note 12 Pro+</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/redmi-note-13-pro-plus-review">Redmi Note 13 Pro+</a> had gorgeous designs and decent hardware, they just didn't deliver on the value side of things, and the increase in price meant they didn't quite have the same mainstream likeability.</p><p>The Redmi Note 14 Pro+ is much the same; it costs just as much as its predecessor, but you get better cameras and powerful hardware. The battery life is where you'll see the biggest difference, with the device featuring a massive 6200mAh battery that easily lasts two days between charges. <br><br>However, Xiaomi hasn't done enough on the software side of things. The Redmi Note 14 Pro+ comes with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review">Android 14</a> out of the box, and that just isn't good enough on a mid-range phone at the end of 2024. What's even more annoying is that the device will get just three Android OS updates, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a> — which it should have launched with — counts as one. <br><br>While the hardware is arguably better, the software situation continues to be a real problem for Xiaomi, and the brand doesn't seem to care about it — at least not enough to do change its strategy.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-redmi-note-14-pro-pricing-and-availability"><span>Redmi Note 14 Pro+: Pricing and availability</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="gifS6DhxPL2tE9GtUf9qrS" name="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus" alt="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus angled view of the back" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gifS6DhxPL2tE9GtUf9qrS.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Xiaomi unveiled the Redmi Note 14 series in Q3 2024, and the phones made their global debut in India on December 9. The Redmi Note 14 and 14 Pro are the affordable models in the series, with the Note 14 Pro+ delivering the best hardware and cameras. <br><br>The Redmi Note 14 Pro+ starts at ₹30,999 ($365) in India for the variant with 8GB of RAM and 128GB of storage, and the 8GB/256GB model costs ₹32,999 ($390). There's also a 12GB/512GB edition that's available for ₹35,999 ($425), and all three variants are available in all three color options — blue, black, and purple — so that's good to see. <br><br>Xiaomi accelerated the launch timeline in India, with the Redmi Note 14 Pro+ debuting a month earlier than its predecessor. There's no telling when the phone will be available in the U.K. and other global markets, but if I had to venture a guess, it'd be sometime in January.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-redmi-note-14-pro-design"><span>Redmi Note 14 Pro+: Design</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="GWBwWcxVAhYVdRH5HNkMuS" name="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus" alt="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus back view against colorful background" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GWBwWcxVAhYVdRH5HNkMuS.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It's clear that design is a key area of focus for Xiaomi, and the Redmi Note 14 Pro+ is one of the best-looking devices in this category. In fact, I actually like this design more than that of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/xiaomi-14-review">Xiaomi 14</a>; the smooth curves makes the device look elegant, and you don't feel like you're using a mid-range phone.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="XrKnPRVckGiWbZcmNEB9yS" name="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus" alt="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus back leather view with Redmi logo highlighted" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XrKnPRVckGiWbZcmNEB9yS.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The color I'm using is particularly great, as it has a vegan leather back — the other two models have a regular glass back instead. The leather finish feels great, and there's a stitched pattern that gives the phone a little extra character. There's a new camera island at the back as well, and like the rest of the design, it looks clean and elegant. This area is often an afterthought on most Xiaomi devices, so it's good to see the Redmi Note 14 Pro+ getting a module that accentuates the design.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="rY55FCy8xCQe4Je98J2wyS" name="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus" alt="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus camera housing at the back against colorful background" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rY55FCy8xCQe4Je98J2wyS.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Xiaomi did the right things with material choices as well, with the device featuring an aluminum mid-frame that gives it additional rigidity. The sides have a glossy coat, and while you get symmetric curves, there's still enough width at the sides to hold the device. The sides are color-matched to the back, and again, it makes the device that a bit more upmarket.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="AR3zHgcgirq3jwMuPqRemS" name="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus" alt="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus side view with power button" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AR3zHgcgirq3jwMuPqRemS.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The power and volume buttons have good tactility, and I didn't see any problems in this area. The only issue I have is that the in-screen module sits a little lower on the screen, making it awkward to access one-handed; this is true of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oppo-find-x8-pro-review">Find X8 Pro</a> and several other devices I tested recently, so Xiaomi isn't the only brand doing this.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="cMaJHGRJdGLWJxdpoe6NpS" name="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus" alt="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus IR blaster" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/cMaJHGRJdGLWJxdpoe6NpS.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While the Redmi Note 14 Pro+ is 6g heavier than its predecessor, you get a significantly bigger 6200mAh battery. Honestly, I didn't notice the added heft, and Xiaomi did a good job with the weight distribution. The in-hand feel is similarly great, and the phone isn't bulky or unwieldy in the least. <br><br>The Redmi Note 14 Pro+ retains IP68 ingress protection as well, giving it added resilience against dust and water. Overall, Xiaomi did all the right things with the design of the Redmi Note 14 Pro+, and it doesn't end up looking like a mid-ranger.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-redmi-note-14-pro-display"><span>Redmi Note 14 Pro+: Display</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="Q7vzzZtgNeRiG9qbTkbkwS" name="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus" alt="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus home page with colorful background" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Q7vzzZtgNeRiG9qbTkbkwS.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Redmi Note 14 Pro+ uses the same 6.67-inch panel size as last year, but it gets much brighter, and it gets Gorilla Glass Victus 2 as standard. You get the usual 120Hz refresh and a resolution of 2712 x 1220, but Xiaomi uses the dynamic mode out of the box, so you'll need to go into the settings to enable 120Hz.</p>
<p>Xiaomi usually does a good job with color calibration, but my unit had cooler colors out of the box; thankfully, it's easy to adjust color balance via the settings. Other than that, I didn't notice any issues with the panel as such — it has good contrast and vibrancy.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="pBeHtMTm5H6HUgTZ3fjFtS" name="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus" alt="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus selfie camera" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pBeHtMTm5H6HUgTZ3fjFtS.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>There are no problems using the panel outdoors; it gets sufficiently bright, and there's a slight difference from the Note 13 Pro+ in this regard. That said, the ambient brightness sensor is a little slow to adjust brightness, and I found myself having to use the brightness slider to manually adjust it several times.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="EyqdUaTwhmgzMLi3nQUkwS" name="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus" alt="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/EyqdUaTwhmgzMLi3nQUkwS.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While it won't win any awards, the Redmi Note 14 Pro+ holds up well during gaming, but you will notice jitter in demanding titles. Video streaming is good enough; there's HDR10+ and Dolby Vision, but switching to HDR content in YouTube made the video jittery at times. Outside of that, colors looked great, and there wasn't any excessive blooming. <br><br>Like previous years, you get stereo sound, and it's detailed enough that you can use the onboard audio if you're listening to a podcast. There's 1920Hz PWM dimming, and you get a decent amount of configurability when it comes to always-on styles.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-redmi-note-14-pro-performance"><span>Redmi Note 14 Pro+: Performance</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="kN7GVz7oG5RX7gpdzbtKuS" name="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus" alt="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus about section" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kN7GVz7oG5RX7gpdzbtKuS.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>After using MediaTek-powered designs for the last three years, Xiaomi is back to using Qualcomm in the Redmi Note 14 Pro+. The phone is powered by the latest Snapdragon 7s Gen 3 platform, and it has a higher-clocked Adreno 710 and is manufactured on the 4nm node. <br><br>Given that Qualcomm was slow to switch to the latest Arm cores in the past, it's good to see the use of Cortex A720 and A520 cores this time. I noticed some lag at times — particularly when switching between a video and a game — but outside of that, there weren't any issues in regular use.</p>

<p>The phone does a good job with gaming as well, but it tends to be aggressive with thermal management, so you will see throttling in extended gaming sessions. There isn't much in the way of overheating, but you will see the occasional lag and jitter in demanding games; turning down the settings makes a difference. <br><br>Xiaomi is selling the Redmi Note 14 Pro+ in 8GB/128GB, 8GB/256GB, and 12GB/512GB configurations, and annoyingly, all storage modules of the device come with UFS 3.1 and not UFS 4.0. You miss out on Wi-Fi 6E as well, but there is Bluetooth 5.4 and NFC. I didn't see any issues with connectivity or calling, and I got a reliable cellular signal. <br><br>There's a new x-axis vibration motor, and while it doesn't deliver the same level of granular feedback as the Xiaomi 14, it is decent enough in its own right — considering how much you're paying for the phone.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-redmi-note-14-pro-battery-life"><span>Redmi Note 14 Pro+: Battery life</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="Ysd3QpE3YGmKqTaovSh3qS" name="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus" alt="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus battery" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Ysd3QpE3YGmKqTaovSh3qS.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>One of the best features of the Redmi Note 14 Pro+ is the significantly bigger 6200mAh battery. What's particularly great is that Xiaomi slotted in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/most-android-flagships-are-getting-an-exciting-battery-upgrade-in-2025">silicon-carbon battery</a>, so you get much better density, and the phone can withstand extreme cold without any issues. It's great to see brands bringing this tech to the mid-range segment. <br><br>The increased battery size gives the Redmi Note 14 Pro+ a distinct advantage, and the phone manages to last two days without any issues. Even with heavy use, I only had to charge the device every other day, so if you need a phone with the best battery life in this segment, the Redmi Note 14 Pro+ is the one to get. <br><br>You also get 90W charging, and Xiaomi bundles the requisite charger in the box. It takes just over 65 minutes to fully charge the device, and that's not bad considering the size of the battery. Xiaomi has the usual battery safeguards to extend longevity, including charging limit and optimized charging.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-redmi-note-14-pro-cameras"><span>Redmi Note 14 Pro+: Cameras</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="i6Xd3FCCTzfFfgaNBWRtuS" name="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus" alt="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus camera housing at the back" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/i6Xd3FCCTzfFfgaNBWRtuS.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>After using 200MP cameras, Xiaomi is once again back to a 50MP main camera on the Redmi Note 14 Pro+, and the device features OmniVision's OVX8000 module, dubbed the Light Hunter 800 by Xiaomi. This is the same sensor that's used in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-poco-f6-pro-is-the-most-underrated-phone-of-2024">POCO F6 Pro</a>, Xiaomi 14 Civi, and even the Xiaomi Mix Flip, so the Redmi Note 14 Pro+ is in good company in this regard. <br><br>In a similar vein, Xiaomi added a 50MP Samsung JN1 telephoto lens at the back with 2.5x optical zoom, and this makes the phone much more versatile. After years and years of ineffectual auxiliary cameras, the Redmi Note 14 Pro+ gets usable auxiliary cameras, and the 8MP wide-angle lens is decent enough in its own right. <br><br>However, Xiaomi is yet to address long-standing issues with video recording on the Redmi Note series; the phone still doesn't get 4K60 video, and what's even more annoying is that it doesn't even have 60fps at 1080p when using the wide-angle lens. The camera interface itself is unchanged in four years, so if you've used a Xiaomi or POCO phone in the past, you'll be familiar with all the settings.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 10</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="Ka6t7PUWEppKCyPQ7nuMGS" name="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus" alt="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus camera shots" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Ka6t7PUWEppKCyPQ7nuMGS.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1536" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 10</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="VQMd58isP9tfBJ9piLQ3KS" name="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus" alt="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus camera shots" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VQMd58isP9tfBJ9piLQ3KS.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1536" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 10</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="nd2oChDDrr7kc49jY2MSFS" name="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus" alt="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus camera shots" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nd2oChDDrr7kc49jY2MSFS.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1536" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 4 of 10</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="NJ9Qbiv5CVnawDnpGbgX6S" name="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus" alt="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus camera shots" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NJ9Qbiv5CVnawDnpGbgX6S.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1536" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 5 of 10</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="fo73qtuxNmHgnVtHkpwF2S" name="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus" alt="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus camera shots" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fo73qtuxNmHgnVtHkpwF2S.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1536" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 6 of 10</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="Kh9EyrvsQzJ8RVHBbMkT5S" name="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus" alt="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus camera shots" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Kh9EyrvsQzJ8RVHBbMkT5S.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1536" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 7 of 10</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="SFqL9goEYm9EdNn2PVnTAS" name="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus" alt="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus camera shots" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SFqL9goEYm9EdNn2PVnTAS.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1536" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 8 of 10</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="w3kwTF6ZXLCms49VFDg3KS" name="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus" alt="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus camera shots" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/w3kwTF6ZXLCms49VFDg3KS.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1536" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 9 of 10</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="KpiEQ52Ycu9aT4mnunMFNS" name="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus" alt="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus camera shots" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KpiEQ52Ycu9aT4mnunMFNS.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1536" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 10 of 10</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.10%;"><img id="T7UVSD6Y6cv77UkXzvBsES" name="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus" alt="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus camera shots" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/T7UVSD6Y6cv77UkXzvBsES.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1538" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Thanks to the new sensor, the Redmi Note 14 Pro+ takes fantastic photos in any situation. Daylight shots have great detail and dynamic range, and accurate colors. You don't get overly saturated images, and foliage rendition is detailed without any aggressive smoothing. The camera does a fantastic job in low-light situations as well, providing good color vibrancy and plenty of detail, and no visible noise levels. It takes a smidgen longer to focus in low-light than high-end phones, but that's about the only shortcoming I noticed. <br><br>The telephotos lens is a good addition at the back, and it produces usable shots at up to 5x zoom. There's no OIS, and it may take a few tries to get the ideal shot, but again, the inclusion of a dedicated zoom lens is a big differentiator. The camera isn't quite as good in low-light, but you still get shots that are decent enough for sharing on social media. You get decent portraits as well, and while you can't adjust the focal length, there's a marked difference over the 13 Pro+. <br><br>The wide-angle lens is better than previous years, and while it doesn't measure up to the likes of the Xiaomi 14, it definitely holds its own against other mid-rangers. To sum up, the Redmi Note 14 Pro+ has a versatile camera system that takes great images in most conditions, and it is right up there with the best in this category.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-redmi-note-14-pro-software"><span>Redmi Note 14 Pro+: Software</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="nCTtxpjiJn5omwJKRnwDtS" name="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus" alt="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus Android Easter egg" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nCTtxpjiJn5omwJKRnwDtS.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Redmi Note 14 Pro+ comes with Android 14 out of the box, even though Google rolled out the stable version of Android nearly two months prior to the launch of the phone. Xiaomi's software interface needs an overhaul; the design is four years old at this point, and it's starting to show its age. <br><br>The UI has better fluidity than MIUI skins of yesteryear, and you get a decent amount of customizability. That said, ColorOS and Funtouch OS have better features in this area, and they're optimized much better. You also get plenty of bloatware, and while most of it can be uninstalled, it's annoying that Xiaomi hasn't addressed this yet.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="5scT4zZpiEnAF6mNTCyUxS" name="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus" alt="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus notification shade" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5scT4zZpiEnAF6mNTCyUxS.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Instead of delivering the latest Android version, Xiaomi focused its attention on AI-assisted utilities, and like every other phone today, the Redmi Note 14 Pro+ has a suite of AI tools with questionable usability. Circle to Search and AI-backed transcribing of audio recordings are useful, but I didn't see the utility of AI summaries and translate features baked into the Notes client. <br><br>Gallery has an AI-assisted object eraser, a tool that increases the size of the frame, and one that generates short video highlights from your photos. There's an AI translator and AI subtitles as well, and the main problem is that none of these are available out of the box — they'll be rolling out via software updates down the line. Given Xiaomi's track record at delivering timely updates, I wouldn't hold my breath. <br><br>Then there's the issue with system updates. Xiaomi is guaranteeing three Android OS updates and four years of security updates, but the problem is that Android 15 counts towards one of those updates, and that's just an underhanded move. Xiaomi does this intentionally so it doesn't have to bother with long-term updates down the line, and this practice alone makes me not want to recommend the device.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-redmi-note-14-pro-the-competition"><span>Redmi Note 14 Pro+: The competition</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="xUMpNjChU4ezdTgLXdR7xB" name="oneplus-12r-sunset-dune-18.jpg" alt="OnePlus 12R Sunset Dune next to Cool Blue model" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xUMpNjChU4ezdTgLXdR7xB.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/poco-f6-review">POCO F6</a> is my go-to recommendation in this segment, with the device offering a terrific combination of hardware and battery life. The camera isn't as good as the Redmi Note 14 Pro+, but it comes close, and it does a much better job at gaming. The battery lasts a day and a half, and coming in at ₹29,999 ($353), you get a much better value. <br><br>Obviously, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12r-review">OnePlus 12R</a> continues to be a terrific choice, and while it is costlier at ₹35,999 ($425), you get a better phone in just about every area. The AMOLED panel gets brighter, the phone is significantly faster in regular use, and the main camera takes better photos in just about any scenario. <br><br>Nothing's Phone 2a Plus is also an intriguing choice to consider. It has a distinctive design, great software features, and two usable cameras at the back. And starting at ₹26,999 ($318), you're not paying a hefty premium.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-redmi-note-14-pro-should-you-buy-it"><span>Redmi Note 14 Pro+: Should you buy it?</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="tAuPcNPDL7PvP3tvnoi8yS" name="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus" alt="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus back view with camera highlighted" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tAuPcNPDL7PvP3tvnoi8yS.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>You should buy this if: </strong></p>
<ul><li>You need a good-looking mid-range phone</li><li>You want great cameras at the back</li><li>You need the best battery life in this category</li></ul>
<p><strong>You shouldn't buy this if: </strong></p>
<ul><li>You want good software with meaningful extras</li><li>You need long-term updates</li><li>You want a phone that takes good videos</li></ul>
<p>I tested every Redmi Note phone released in the last decade, so I know what I'm talking about when it comes to these devices. While the Redmi Note 14 Pro+ is costlier than earlier phones that came in the series, there isn't a price hike this year, and that's a good thing. <br><br>The hardware is really rather good, and the cameras are great — the inclusion of a telephoto lens gives it a decent edge, and that's no small feat in this category. The battery life is easily the best I've used on any mid-ranger, and it doesn't take long to charge the battery either. <br><br>But like the last two years, it's the software that ultimately limits the device. If you don't have an issue with the fact that the phone comes with Android 14 out of the box, then yes, the Redmi Note Pro 14+ is a decent choice. But the software makes a bigger difference in how long you can actually the phone, and in this area, Xiaomi is once again found to be lacking.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="68f7a965-aaab-4cef-94c6-ec47e70ef929">
            <a href="https://www.flipkart.com/redmi-note-14-pro-5g-store?param=1112" data-model-name="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:56.25%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RqC73bH9sXbNkR4gC2i754.jpg' alt="Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus"></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>The Redmi Note 14 Pro+ combines terrific cameras with a massive battery, and the phone clearly nails the basics. However, the software is middling at best, and it detracts from what is an otherwise great device. If you don't mind that and need great cameras and two-day battery, the Redmi Note 14 Pro+ is a good overall choice. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/redmi-note-14-pro-plus-review</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Redmi Note 14 Pro+ has huge upgrades around the cameras and battery, but the same software issues rear their head again.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">7yVPsNuDdbwRmxcy4s4gKC</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JSwbgdHuNmykchNFg6NQzS.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 05:29:10 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JSwbgdHuNmykchNFg6NQzS.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus back view with cameras highlighted]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Redmi Note 14 Pro Plus back view with cameras highlighted]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Android Central holiday gift guide 2024 — ring in the season with these 20+ deals on smartphones, tablets, wearables, and more! ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Quick menu</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="StDoGZtqBGmdMzhzYsE66Z" name="2024-phone-pile-5.jpg" caption="" alt="Pixel 9 Pro XL next to Pixel 9 Pro, Pixel 8 Pro, Pixel 8a, OnePlus Open, OnePlus 12, and OnePlus 12R" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/StDoGZtqBGmdMzhzYsE66Z.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text"><strong>1.</strong> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/android-central-holiday-gift-guide-best-deals-2024#section-quick-links">Quick links</a><br>
<strong>2.</strong> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/android-central-holiday-gift-guide-best-deals-2024#section-phones">Phones</a><br>
<strong>3.</strong> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/android-central-holiday-gift-guide-best-deals-2024#section-wearables">Wearables</a><br>
<strong>4.</strong> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/android-central-holiday-gift-guide-best-deals-2024#section-tablets">Tablets</a><br>
<strong>5.</strong> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/android-central-holiday-gift-guide-best-deals-2024#section-best-of-the-rest">Best of the rest</a></p></div></div>
<p>If you&apos;re looking for holiday deals on Android devices, you&apos;ve come to the right place: a bunch of our favorite tech from Samsung, Google, OnePlus, and beyond is currently being discounted across the web, and I&apos;ve collected the best Android Central-approved options into this guide. </p><p>It was an interesting year for Android! AI took center stage, Android 15 dropped, and it felt like just about every OEM under the sun decided to release its own foldable phone. The OnePlus 12 even overtook Samsung and Google as <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">our favorite Android phone</a> of the year! Now that we&apos;re nearing the new year, retailers are ditching their old stock to make room for the next generation, so it&apos;s a great time to shop for deals. </p><p>The holiday deals on display include discounts like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9/6810275/"><strong>$500 off the Google Pixel 9 at Mint Mobile</strong></a> when you add an eligible line, or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/aw/d/B0D84MHZX5/"><strong>this offer that drops a whopping 15% off the brand new Samsung Galaxy Tab S10 Plus</strong></a>. Most of these deals should arrive by Christmas if you place your order today, but I&apos;ll make a note if I think that&apos;s going to be a concern. Either way, we&apos;re getting down to the wire, so act fast if something catches your eye! </p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-quick-links"><span>Quick links</span></h3>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/deals"><strong>Amazon: </strong>up to 54% off Amazon devices, discounted phones, and more</a></li><li><a href="https://www.walmart.com/shop/deals"><strong>Walmart: </strong>huge rollback savings on tech, laptops, and TVs</a></li><li><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/discover-samsung-event/"><strong>Samsung: </strong>enhanced trade-in credit, up to 50% off Galaxy wearables</a></li><li><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/top-deals"><strong>Best Buy: </strong>major savings on Motorola and Samsung, new Doorbuster deals daily</a></li><li><a href="https://mintmobile.com/deals/"><strong>Mint Mobile: </strong>up to $500 off Pixel 9 series, Unlimited for $15 per month</a></li><li><a href="https://www.verizon.com/deals/"><strong>Verizon: </strong>up to $1,500 of free tech when you bundle, new trade-in opportunities</a></li><li><a href="https://www.att.com/deals/"><strong>AT&T: </strong>Motorola phones from $0.99/month with eligible lines</a></li></ul>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-phones"><span>Phones</span></h3>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="3450015b-f8c9-466b-804c-6f95ffa51764" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9/6810275/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:204px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:121.08%;"><img id="Y8nScb7AAtxK4j2d2EnxjV" name="google-pixel-9-render-obsidian.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Y8nScb7AAtxK4j2d2EnxjV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="204" height="247" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Google Pixel 9 128GB: </strong><a href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9/6810275/" data-dimension112="3450015b-f8c9-466b-804c-6f95ffa51764" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799"><del>$799</del><strong> $299, plus 50% off one year of Unlimited at Mint Mobile</strong></a></p>
<p>Purchase the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-review">Google Pixel 9</a> from Mint Mobile today and you'll score a whopping $500 off your purchase, knocking the price of the phone down to only $299. You'll need to purchase a year of wireless to receive the savings, but Mint is sweetening the deal by dropping 50% off the price of the Unlimited plan. </p>
<p>In other words, you'll be getting an excellent phone and a full twelve months of Unlimited wireless coverage for only $479 (or $20/month using affirm). <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9/6810275/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="3450015b-f8c9-466b-804c-6f95ffa51764" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="19a5fe28-872a-434b-93ab-7efc0f310746" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus 256GB: $999.99" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus 256GB: $999.99" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/smartphones/galaxy-s24/buy/galaxy-s24-plus-256gb-unlocked-sm-s926ulbaxaa" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="pb2Z3cawQkbz5RDcGGfxs3" name="samsung galaxy s24 plus square render 2.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pb2Z3cawQkbz5RDcGGfxs3.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="500" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus 256GB: </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/smartphones/galaxy-s24/buy/galaxy-s24-plus-256gb-unlocked-sm-s926ulbaxaa/" data-dimension112="19a5fe28-872a-434b-93ab-7efc0f310746" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus 256GB: $999.99" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus 256GB: $999.99"><del>$999.99</del><strong> $799.99, or up to $650 off with trade-in at Samsung</strong></a></p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-plus-review">Galaxy S24 Plus</a> is a perfectly-balanced flagship with seven years of guaranteed OS updates, a glorious QHD+ display, and a bunch of useful Galaxy AI features straight out of the box. Buy the phone unlocked from Samsung and you'll score a $200 discount, or trade in an old or broken phone and receive up to $650 off your purchase.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/smartphones/galaxy-s24/buy/galaxy-s24-plus-256gb-unlocked-sm-s926ulbaxaa" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="19a5fe28-872a-434b-93ab-7efc0f310746" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus 256GB: $999.99" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus 256GB: $999.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="ee0936a9-b00b-4fde-85d4-ba1ebd19b216" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$999.99" data-dimension48="$999.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/Motorola-razr-Unlocked-MPCamera-73-95x170-83x6-99mm/dp/B0C2X87QW4" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="Jc85GVTAkFfiMQ4UeXdmXP" name="motorola razr plus 2023 reco 600x600.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Jc85GVTAkFfiMQ4UeXdmXP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Motorola Razr Plus (2023) 256GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Motorola-razr-Unlocked-MPCamera-73-95x170-83x6-99mm/dp/B0C2X87QW4" data-dimension112="ee0936a9-b00b-4fde-85d4-ba1ebd19b216" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$999.99" data-dimension48="$999.99"><del>$999.99</del> <strong>$549.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>It may be a bit old at this point, but the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-review">Razr Plus (2023)</a> remains a stellar flip-style phone for most people, with two vibrant displays, solid performance, and a versatile clamshell design. As part of its holiday sale, Amazon is carving a dramatic 45% off the price of the foldable. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/Motorola-razr-Unlocked-MPCamera-73-95x170-83x6-99mm/dp/B0C2X87QW4" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="ee0936a9-b00b-4fde-85d4-ba1ebd19b216" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$999.99" data-dimension48="$999.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="9283c4d9-d0f8-4b87-9330-2f1e8799b4c2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Motorola Razr Plus (2024) 256GB: $999.99" data-dimension48="Motorola Razr Plus (2024) 256GB: $999.99" href="https://www.att.com/buy/phones/motorola-razrplus-2024.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="QYuTf5Mv7cbvGoVpNDwkAC" name="motorola razr plus 2024 render 400x500.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QYuTf5Mv7cbvGoVpNDwkAC.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Motorola Razr Plus (2024) 256GB: </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/buy/phones/motorola-razrplus-2024.html" data-dimension112="9283c4d9-d0f8-4b87-9330-2f1e8799b4c2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Motorola Razr Plus (2024) 256GB: $999.99" data-dimension48="Motorola Razr Plus (2024) 256GB: $999.99"><del>$999.99</del> <strong>$5.99 per month with new line at AT&T</strong></a></p>
<p>Speaking of <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">foldable phones</a>, you can get the latest generation of the Razr Plus for only $5.99 per month when you add a line with an eligible unlimited plan at AT&T. No trade-in required!<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.att.com/buy/phones/motorola-razrplus-2024.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="9283c4d9-d0f8-4b87-9330-2f1e8799b4c2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Motorola Razr Plus (2024) 256GB: $999.99" data-dimension48="Motorola Razr Plus (2024) 256GB: $999.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="14f36edd-54a2-4370-82ce-bce39745e9a2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$399.99" data-dimension48="$399.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-A35-Unlocked-Smartphone-Expandable/dp/B0CV4NH5T9" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1178px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:127.33%;"><img id="aWazoPSQxeFFbVWqyQsKBZ" name="samsung-galaxy-a35-5g-lilac-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/aWazoPSQxeFFbVWqyQsKBZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1178" height="1500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy A35 5G 128GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-A35-Unlocked-Smartphone-Expandable/dp/B0CV4NH5T9" data-dimension112="14f36edd-54a2-4370-82ce-bce39745e9a2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$399.99" data-dimension48="$399.99"><del>$399.99</del> <strong>$299.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>The Galaxy A35 5G is a <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-android-phones">cheap Android phone</a> with a stunning-for-the-price 120Hz display, huge battery, and four years of guaranteed software updates. Pick up the device unlocked from Amazon right now and you'll enjoy a 25% discount, knocking the price down to only $299.99.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-A35-Unlocked-Smartphone-Expandable/dp/B0CV4NH5T9" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="14f36edd-54a2-4370-82ce-bce39745e9a2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$399.99" data-dimension48="$399.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="7fac66e2-b9aa-4e76-bd15-0f268568fa0f" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$849" data-dimension48="$849" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/RedMagic-9S-Pro-5G-Smartphone-Snapdragon-8-Gen-3-LPDDR5X-UFS-4-1-6-8-AMOLED-12-256GB-100W-520Hz-Shoulder-Triggers-6500mAh-144Hz-50M-Black/7081956512" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="AAoJuvePGosiPexwmjzQE3" name="redmagic-9s-pro-space-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AAoJuvePGosiPexwmjzQE3.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>RedMagic 9S Pro 5G 256GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/RedMagic-9S-Pro-5G-Smartphone-Snapdragon-8-Gen-3-LPDDR5X-UFS-4-1-6-8-AMOLED-12-256GB-100W-520Hz-Shoulder-Triggers-6500mAh-144Hz-50M-Black/7081956512" data-dimension112="7fac66e2-b9aa-4e76-bd15-0f268568fa0f" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$849" data-dimension48="$849"><del>$849</del> <strong>$619 at Walmart</strong></a> </p>
<p>One of our favorite <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-phone-gamers">gaming phones</a>, the RedMagic 9S Pro features a large, vibrant display, massive 6,500mAh battery, and a Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 chipset for speedy performance. Pick up the device unlocked from Walmart and you'll score a straight $230 discount — just make sure it works with your carrier before you commit. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/RedMagic-9S-Pro-5G-Smartphone-Snapdragon-8-Gen-3-LPDDR5X-UFS-4-1-6-8-AMOLED-12-256GB-100W-520Hz-Shoulder-Triggers-6500mAh-144Hz-50M-Black/7081956512" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="7fac66e2-b9aa-4e76-bd15-0f268568fa0f" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$849" data-dimension48="$849">View Deal</a></p></div>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-wearables"><span>Wearables</span></h3>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="dcabc19c-f24a-41e0-8c74-2dd4449e2dd3" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Garmin epix Pro (Gen 2) 51mm: $1,099.99" data-dimension48="Garmin epix Pro (Gen 2) 51mm: $1,099.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BYFCZZ9F" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="fgQAnsurLEHrTe4Qw8DLiM" name="garmin epix pro gen 2 reco 600x600.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fgQAnsurLEHrTe4Qw8DLiM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Garmin epix Pro (Gen 2) 51mm: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BYFCZZ9F" data-dimension112="dcabc19c-f24a-41e0-8c74-2dd4449e2dd3" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Garmin epix Pro (Gen 2) 51mm: $1,099.99" data-dimension48="Garmin epix Pro (Gen 2) 51mm: $1,099.99"><del>$1,099.99</del> <strong>$749.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>The epix Pro (Gen 2) is a powerful <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-garmin-smartwatch">Garmin watch</a> with a vast suite of health and fitness tracking tools, mapping features, and even a built-in LED flashlight. The watch's biggest problem is its price, but thanks to this 32% holiday discount from Amazon, that's becoming less of an issue. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BYFCZZ9F" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="dcabc19c-f24a-41e0-8c74-2dd4449e2dd3" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Garmin epix Pro (Gen 2) 51mm: $1,099.99" data-dimension48="Garmin epix Pro (Gen 2) 51mm: $1,099.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="49d9b348-64b5-4d48-bf46-2142bbc8161d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$349.99" data-dimension48="$349.99" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Galaxy-Watch7-40mm-Cream-Bluetooth/6214656451" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="4rP6YrkPPWTFkBtAS9LmeR" name="samsung galaxy watch 7 white reco 400x500.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4rP6YrkPPWTFkBtAS9LmeR.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy Watch 7 40mm:</strong> <a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Galaxy-Watch7-40mm-Cream-Bluetooth/6214656451" data-dimension112="49d9b348-64b5-4d48-bf46-2142bbc8161d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$349.99" data-dimension48="$349.99"><del>$349.99</del> <strong>$224.99 at Walmart</strong></a></p>
<p>Our favorite <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch">Android smartwatch</a> on the market today, the Galaxy Watch 7 is durable, stylish, and lightweight, with all of the health and fitness tracking features you could ever need. Pick up the watch from Walmart and you'll only pay $224.99 during the retailer's holiday sale. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Galaxy-Watch7-40mm-Cream-Bluetooth/6214656451" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="49d9b348-64b5-4d48-bf46-2142bbc8161d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$349.99" data-dimension48="$349.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="bbb3e91f-b1f9-485b-8a4a-84871fd2b6e2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$649.99" data-dimension48="$649.99" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/watches/galaxy-watch-ultra/buy/galaxy-watch-ultra-47mm-titanium-gray-sm-l705udaaxaa/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="HhN65E2dQSqXX8c9Xct7qL" name="samsung galaxy watch ultra 400x500.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HhN65E2dQSqXX8c9Xct7qL.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy Watch Ultra 47mm:</strong> <a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/watches/galaxy-watch-ultra/buy/galaxy-watch-ultra-47mm-titanium-gray-sm-l705udaaxaa/" data-dimension112="bbb3e91f-b1f9-485b-8a4a-84871fd2b6e2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$649.99" data-dimension48="$649.99"><del>$649.99</del> <strong>$489.99, plus up to $300 off with trade-in at Samsung</strong></a></p>
<p>If you missed the Black Friday/Cyber Monday discounts on the premium Galaxy Watch Ultra, you're in luck: Samsung has brought back a deal that gives you a straight $160 off the smartwatch, plus up to $300 off when you trade in. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/watches/galaxy-watch-ultra/buy/galaxy-watch-ultra-47mm-titanium-gray-sm-l705udaaxaa/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="bbb3e91f-b1f9-485b-8a4a-84871fd2b6e2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$649.99" data-dimension48="$649.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="f3b0bdf3-112c-4195-93a9-86d4adab9d88" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$349.99" data-dimension48="$349.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D9138ZXM" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="JNaMKdsoa883vrQMq2MSrC" name="google pixel watch 3 400x500" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JNaMKdsoa883vrQMq2MSrC.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Google Pixel Watch 3 41mm:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D9138ZXM" data-dimension112="f3b0bdf3-112c-4195-93a9-86d4adab9d88" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$349.99" data-dimension48="$349.99"><del>$349.99</del> <strong>$299.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>Sleek and versatile, the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-3-review">Pixel Watch 3</a> is easily one of the best-looking smartwatches around, but thanks to its outstanding battery life and snappy Wear OS software, it's also one of the best watches of 2024, <em>period</em>. Buy the Google watch today and you'll get a nice $50 off your purchase. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D9138ZXM" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="f3b0bdf3-112c-4195-93a9-86d4adab9d88" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$349.99" data-dimension48="$349.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="662072eb-51cc-4eeb-b0b5-fcb4a357f05a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 40mm: $299.99" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 40mm: $299.99" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/watches/galaxy-watch6/buy/galaxy-watch6-40mm-gold-bt-sm-r930nzeaxaa/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="8hugKRfYKaGhfPddhoT4me" name="Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 white bg render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8hugKRfYKaGhfPddhoT4me.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 40mm: </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/watches/galaxy-watch6/buy/galaxy-watch6-40mm-gold-bt-sm-r930nzeaxaa/" data-dimension112="662072eb-51cc-4eeb-b0b5-fcb4a357f05a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 40mm: $299.99" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 40mm: $299.99"><del>$299.99</del><strong> $149.99, plus up to $100 off with trade-in at Samsung</strong></a></p>
<p>It may be last-gen, but the Galaxy Watch 6 continues to impress with speedy performance and a ton of accurate health tracking features. Pick up the watch directly from Samsung and you might get it for as little as $49.99 with the right trade-in. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/watches/galaxy-watch6/buy/galaxy-watch6-40mm-gold-bt-sm-r930nzeaxaa/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="662072eb-51cc-4eeb-b0b5-fcb4a357f05a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 40mm: $299.99" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 40mm: $299.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-tablets"><span>Tablets</span></h3>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="d54d4aa8-91ec-413a-ad10-957f704c9d5a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$999.99" data-dimension48="$999.99" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/tablets/galaxy-tab-s10/buy/galaxy-tab-s10-plus-256gb-moonstone-gray-wi-fi-sm-x820nzaaxar/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1277px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:65.54%;"><img id="ZnyMaWLT87rgbCcmuteb6Q" name="samsung-galaxy-tab-s10-plus-product-image.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZnyMaWLT87rgbCcmuteb6Q.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1277" height="837" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy Tab S10 Plus 256GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/tablets/galaxy-tab-s10/buy/galaxy-tab-s10-plus-256gb-moonstone-gray-wi-fi-sm-x820nzaaxar/" data-dimension112="d54d4aa8-91ec-413a-ad10-957f704c9d5a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$999.99" data-dimension48="$999.99"><del>$999.99</del><strong> $849.99, plus up to $700 off with trade-in at Samsung</strong></a></p>
<p>The Galaxy Tab S10 series has only been out since early October, and yet you can already snag $150 off the S10 Plus when you shop during Samsung's holiday sale. Up to $700 of trade-in credit is also up for grabs. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/tablets/galaxy-tab-s10/buy/galaxy-tab-s10-plus-256gb-moonstone-gray-wi-fi-sm-x820nzaaxar/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="d54d4aa8-91ec-413a-ad10-957f704c9d5a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$999.99" data-dimension48="$999.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="3c74a53e-17cd-4385-810b-00bff67e8072" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799.99" data-dimension48="$799.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C4BCNRVQ" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:70.73%;"><img id="xExRd9hX32XBvLG2UcgVwQ" name="samsung-galaxy-tab-s9-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xExRd9hX32XBvLG2UcgVwQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1500" height="1061" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 128GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C4BCNRVQ" data-dimension112="3c74a53e-17cd-4385-810b-00bff67e8072" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799.99" data-dimension48="$799.99"><del>$799.99</del> <strong>$579 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>Last year's Galaxy Tab S9 features a glorious AMOLED display with a Snapdragon chipset and a ton of useful AI features. Order the versatile device from Amazon today and you'll receive a straight 28% discount, no strings whatsoever. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C4BCNRVQ" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="3c74a53e-17cd-4385-810b-00bff67e8072" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799.99" data-dimension48="$799.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="9db82dbc-4eb8-4baf-a874-16405e89801f" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$279.99" data-dimension48="$279.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0B2SFTGQ6" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:962px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="kYNi2vcu7cdyeP6XFbBPuZ" name="Amazon Fire Max 11 render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kYNi2vcu7cdyeP6XFbBPuZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="962" height="962" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Amazon Fire Max 11 128GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0B2SFTGQ6" data-dimension112="9db82dbc-4eb8-4baf-a874-16405e89801f" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$279.99" data-dimension48="$279.99"><del>$279.99</del> <strong>$169.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>Currently chilling with a 39% discount at Amazon, the Fire Max 11 is pretty much the ideal couch companion. You get up to 14 hours of battery life on a single charge, plus a vibrant 11-inch touchscreen display, aluminum build, and 4GB of RAM. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0B2SFTGQ6" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="9db82dbc-4eb8-4baf-a874-16405e89801f" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$279.99" data-dimension48="$279.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="d3a4c226-692e-449c-8d4a-0b8f28e3b507" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$219.99" data-dimension48="$219.99" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/tablets/galaxy-tab-a9-plus/buy/galaxy-tab-a9-plus-64gb-graphite-wi-fi-sm-x210nzaaxar/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="rUNyvTLboDppMEkJGRiNGo" name="Samsung-Galaxy-A9-Plus-screen.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rUNyvTLboDppMEkJGRiNGo.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy Tab A9 Plus 64GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/tablets/galaxy-tab-a9-plus/buy/galaxy-tab-a9-plus-64gb-graphite-wi-fi-sm-x210nzaaxar/" data-dimension112="d3a4c226-692e-449c-8d4a-0b8f28e3b507" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$219.99" data-dimension48="$219.99"><del>$219.99</del> <strong>$149.99 at Samsung</strong></a></p>
<p>Our top pick for the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-android-tablet">best cheap Android tablet</a>, the Galaxy Tab A9 Plus gives you Snapdragon performance with great battery life and expandable storage up to 1TB using microSD. It was already well-priced at $219.99, but thanks to Samsung's holiday sale, you can get the tablet for a mere $149.99. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/tablets/galaxy-tab-a9-plus/buy/galaxy-tab-a9-plus-64gb-graphite-wi-fi-sm-x210nzaaxar/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="d3a4c226-692e-449c-8d4a-0b8f28e3b507" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$219.99" data-dimension48="$219.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="3e3a7ce9-cb3d-4ed5-847c-31878f173f54" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$499" data-dimension48="$499" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-tablet-11-android-tablet-256gb-wifi-hazel/6578700.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="Fa597SdtCGpg5MdQ2EdNpY" name="google-pixel-tablet-render-no-dock.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Fa597SdtCGpg5MdQ2EdNpY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1500" height="1500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Google Pixel Tablet 256GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-tablet-11-android-tablet-256gb-wifi-hazel/6578700.p" data-dimension112="3e3a7ce9-cb3d-4ed5-847c-31878f173f54" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$499" data-dimension48="$499"><del>$499</del> <strong>$359 at Best Buy</strong></a></p>
<p>Did you ever want the Pixel experience in a tablet form? The Google Pixel Tablet is the answer, with a Tensor processor, gorgeous 11-inch display, and 256GB of storage. Best Buy is currently slashing $140 off the tablet, so check it out. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-tablet-11-android-tablet-256gb-wifi-hazel/6578700.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="3e3a7ce9-cb3d-4ed5-847c-31878f173f54" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$499" data-dimension48="$499">View Deal</a></p></div>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-best-of-the-rest"><span>Best of the rest</span></h3>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="138dce71-5fea-46d5-a9ea-282adeaa831a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Meta Quest 3S 256GB: $399.99, plus $30 credit, three months of Meta Quest Plus, and a free copy of Batman: Arkham Shadow at Meta" data-dimension48="Meta Quest 3S 256GB: $399.99, plus $30 credit, three months of Meta Quest Plus, and a free copy of Batman: Arkham Shadow at Meta" href="https://www.meta.com/quest/quest-3s/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="h34jRAJqFjXZgP5M5ubtV7" name="Meta-Quest-3S-render-w-space.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/h34jRAJqFjXZgP5M5ubtV7.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1080" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Meta Quest 3S 256GB: </strong><a href="https://www.meta.com/quest/quest-3s/?variant=256" data-dimension112="138dce71-5fea-46d5-a9ea-282adeaa831a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Meta Quest 3S 256GB: $399.99, plus $30 credit, three months of Meta Quest Plus, and a free copy of Batman: Arkham Shadow at Meta" data-dimension48="Meta Quest 3S 256GB: $399.99, plus $30 credit, three months of Meta Quest Plus, and a free copy of Batman: Arkham Shadow at Meta"><strong>$399.99, plus $30 credit, three months of Meta Quest Plus, and a free copy of Batman: Arkham Shadow at Meta</strong></a></p>
<p>Pick up the 256GB configuration of the Meta Quest 3S directly from the source and you'll get a free copy of Batman: Arkham Shadow and a $30 credit added to your account. As if that wasn't enough, Meta will also throw in a free three-month subscription to Meta Quest Plus and a one-year warranty. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.meta.com/quest/quest-3s/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="138dce71-5fea-46d5-a9ea-282adeaa831a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Meta Quest 3S 256GB: $399.99, plus $30 credit, three months of Meta Quest Plus, and a free copy of Batman: Arkham Shadow at Meta" data-dimension48="Meta Quest 3S 256GB: $399.99, plus $30 credit, three months of Meta Quest Plus, and a free copy of Batman: Arkham Shadow at Meta">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="f9795a9c-2883-44d2-acf9-bba699b882c5" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$399.99" data-dimension48="$399.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WH-1000XM5-Canceling-Headphones-Hands-Free/dp/B09XS7JWHH" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2440px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="DUqFmZkj5CJA69ikY8sxti" name="Sony-WH-1000XM5-black-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DUqFmZkj5CJA69ikY8sxti.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2440" height="2440" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Sony WH-1000XM5:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WH-1000XM5-Canceling-Headphones-Hands-Free/dp/B09XS7JWHH" data-dimension112="f9795a9c-2883-44d2-acf9-bba699b882c5" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$399.99" data-dimension48="$399.99"><del>$399.99</del> <strong>$298 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>One of our favorite <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones">wireless headphones</a> that we've ever used, Sony's WH-1000XM5 feature outstanding battery life with cutting-edge noise cancellation and customizable EQ settings straight out of the box. Grab a pair from Amazon today and you'll save over a Benjamin.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WH-1000XM5-Canceling-Headphones-Hands-Free/dp/B09XS7JWHH" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="f9795a9c-2883-44d2-acf9-bba699b882c5" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$399.99" data-dimension48="$399.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="05de6ded-7628-486a-98fe-5507debd842b" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$119.99" data-dimension48="$119.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09MVGQRDD" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:36.13%;"><img id="tPM8XMqA5kRTagKjvxAsDc" name="jabra-elite-4-active-render.png" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tPM8XMqA5kRTagKjvxAsDc.png" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="289" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Jabra Elite 4 Active:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09MVGQRDD" data-dimension112="05de6ded-7628-486a-98fe-5507debd842b" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$119.99" data-dimension48="$119.99"><del>$119.99</del> <strong>$69.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>Who says ANC (active noise cancellation) needs to cost an arm and a leg? Currently just $69.99 at Amazon, the Jabra Elite 4 Active boast noise cancellation features that actually work, plus customizable EQ settings and up to 28 hours of battery life on a single charge. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09MVGQRDD" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="05de6ded-7628-486a-98fe-5507debd842b" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$119.99" data-dimension48="$119.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="124029ca-d59a-4208-8bef-b723e6788955" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Razer Kishi V2 Pro Android Controller: $149.99" data-dimension48="Razer Kishi V2 Pro Android Controller: $149.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CCT2Y8BN" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="J6TYTpzYMvzY2xfmcasFcm" name="razer-kishi-v2-pro-render-with-space.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/J6TYTpzYMvzY2xfmcasFcm.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Razer Kishi V2 Pro Android Controller: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CCT2Y8BN" data-dimension112="124029ca-d59a-4208-8bef-b723e6788955" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Razer Kishi V2 Pro Android Controller: $149.99" data-dimension48="Razer Kishi V2 Pro Android Controller: $149.99"><del>$149.99</del><strong> $79.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>Ready to turn your smartphone into a gaming beast? The ergonomic Kishi V2 Pro is one of <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-game-controllers-android">our favorite controllers</a> for Android, and now you can pick one up with a ridiculous 47% discount during Amazon's holiday event. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CCT2Y8BN" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="124029ca-d59a-4208-8bef-b723e6788955" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Razer Kishi V2 Pro Android Controller: $149.99" data-dimension48="Razer Kishi V2 Pro Android Controller: $149.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="98bba261-4b1e-43b1-b1c8-cb08f3aaac4d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$49.99" data-dimension48="$49.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09B8V1LZ3" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:766px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="LdeR7Dvz9zXRXv8xYGvWET" name="amazon-echo-dot-5th-gen-square-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LdeR7Dvz9zXRXv8xYGvWET.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="766" height="766" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Amazon Echo Dot:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09B8V1LZ3" data-dimension112="98bba261-4b1e-43b1-b1c8-cb08f3aaac4d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$49.99" data-dimension48="$49.99"><del>$49.99</del> <strong>$22.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>The latest Amazon Echo Dot is a fantastic entry-level smart speaker with surprisingly great sound, a discreet design, and some new and improved privacy features. Bring Alexa into your home today and you'll get a whopping 54% discount.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09B8V1LZ3" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="98bba261-4b1e-43b1-b1c8-cb08f3aaac4d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$49.99" data-dimension48="$49.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/android-central-holiday-gift-guide-best-deals-2024</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The holiday season is here, and we've gathered all of the best deals on Android devices into this guide, from smartphones to watches.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">ptmPBq4i2BZK87zHbdQsfe</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/StDoGZtqBGmdMzhzYsE66Z.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 23:15:35 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/StDoGZtqBGmdMzhzYsE66Z.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Pixel 9 Pro XL next to Pixel 9 Pro, Pixel 8 Pro, Pixel 8a, OnePlus Open, OnePlus 12, and OnePlus 12R]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Pixel 9 Pro XL next to Pixel 9 Pro, Pixel 8 Pro, Pixel 8a, OnePlus Open, OnePlus 12, and OnePlus 12R]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Docs adds 40 new pageless templates, with more coming soon ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-32">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google Docs added 40 new pageless templates aimed to help users "build high-quality, modern documents faster.</li><li>The new templates cover blog posts, press releases, business proposals, and journals, as well as specialized options for business and education Workspace users.</li><li>Google previously added similar modernized templates to Slides last month.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google's latest addition to Workspace is a set of 40 new pageless templates for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-docs-is-tapping-into-gemini-to-whip-up-formatted-documents">Google Docs</a> that are available starting today. The company announced the new templates, which come with integrated Docs features, in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://workspaceupdates.googleblog.com/2024/12/new-templates-in-google-docs.html" target="_blank">blog post</a>. Google says these are "high-quality, visually modern designs" that can be useful in a variety of situations, with specialized options for enterprise and education users.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-docs-for-android-defaults-to-paginated-mode">pageless templates</a> feature document tabs and placeholder chips, two Google Docs features that were previously available. Document tabs help organize long documents into easily-digestible and navigable sections. Meanwhile, placeholder chips aim to simplify workflows by making it easy to fill in documents with people, dates, files, events, and places.</p><p>Aside from document tabs and placeholder chips, the 40 new templates are outfitted with custom designs, fonts, and structures. Google explains that there are templates for blog posts, press releases, business proposals, and journals, as well as specialized options such as:</p>
<ul><li>A project roadmap, marketing plan, and sales emails for <strong>business users. </strong></li><li>An interview guide, onboarding guide, and training manual for <strong>human resource teams. </strong></li><li>A reading list and class notes templates for <strong>education users. </strong></li></ul>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1308px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:55.66%;"><img id="bZ8pSFE9dHZ2Djo8HmUnnk" name="Google-Docs-New-Templates" alt="Selecting a pageless template in Google Docs." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bZ8pSFE9dHZ2Djo8HmUnnk.png" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1308" height="728" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>There are a few ways to add a template to a new Google Doc, starting with a new <strong>Templates</strong> building block that will appear at the top of a blank document. Alternatively, you can choose a template by navigating through <strong>File > New > From template gallery</strong> in the Google Docs toolbar.</p><p>These new templates are available to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/everything-you-need-know-about-google-workspace-spaces-and-smart-canvas">all Google Workspace users</a>, though it may take some time for them to show up for everyone. Both rapid release and scheduled release domains are starting to see these 40 new templates starting today, but the rollout can take up to 15 days to complete.</p><p>Google says that users can expect "even more high-quality Docs template options in the coming months."</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-docs-adds-40-new-pageless-templates-with-more-coming-soon</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google added new, modern templates to Slides last month — now Google Docs is getting the same treatment.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">tsgrJraKzSdSHA5UjtB6mg</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7toEJcBHissLb7zzLyXyUg.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 23:13:27 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7toEJcBHissLb7zzLyXyUg.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Help me write in Google Docs on Samsung Galaxy Chromebook Plus]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Help me write in Google Docs on Samsung Galaxy Chromebook Plus]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ A 'Year in Search' highlights Google's top trends across AI and shows in 2024 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-37">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google highlighted its "Year in 2024" data for what users searched for the most in Search and AI.</li><li>Circle to Search and Lens were used to "identify items," shop, and translate items and users were the most curious about Benson Boone's song "Beautiful Things."</li><li>The top trending search in 2024 was Copa America while the most searched for movie was Disney's Inside Out 2.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>As the year winds down, Google is taking a look back at what users searched for the most across multiple categories.</p><p>In a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.google/products/search/google-year-in-search-2024/">Keyword post</a>, the company highlighted various top trending searches for various user interests, like AI. Google highlighted what users searched for the most in since the arrival of Circle to Search, as well as Google Lens. The post states users used both tools to translate, shop, and "identify items" in 2024.</p><p>Moreover, the company adds that users usually combined a search with "how to use" when searching for an item visually.</p><p>Google Maps was tossed in, as the post states users looked up information about the Las Vegas Sphere and Italy’s Arena di Verona this year.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-circle-to-search-ai-powered-multisearch-rollout">Circle to Search</a> launched earlier this year alongside the Galaxy S24 series and the Pixel 8 before hitting other phones. Additionally, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-lens-search-ads-video-function-update">Google Lens</a> grabbed some nifty upgrades like the ability for users to record videos.</p><p>Speaking of AI and Search, in Google's main "Year in Search" overview, the company highlighted what songs users hummed to its engine the most.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1066px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.29%;"><img id="TfFvviGDoa6xV5HMhYMpq5" name="google-search-year-in-review-2024-hum-to-search" alt="Google's top search results for users who utilized "Hum to Search" in 2024." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TfFvviGDoa6xV5HMhYMpq5.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1066" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<h2 id="top-trending-search-in-2024-2">Top Trending Search in 2024</h2>
<ol start="1"><li>Copa America</li><li>UEFA European Championship</li><li>ICC Men's T20 World Cup</li><li>India vs England</li><li>Liam Payne</li></ol>
<h2 id="top-trending-movies-in-search-2">Top Trending Movies in Search</h2>
<ol start="1"><li>Inside Out 2</li><li>Deadpool & Wolverine</li><li>Saltburn</li><li>Beetlejuice Beetlejuice</li><li>Dune: Part Two</li></ol>
<h2 id="top-trending-tv-shows-2">Top Trending TV Shows</h2>
<ol start="1"><li>Baby Reindeer</li><li>Fallout</li><li>House of the Dragon</li><li>Heeramandi</li><li>Shōgun</li></ol>
<p>Google's main "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://trends.withgoogle.com/year-in-search/2024/">Year in Search</a>" overview for 2024 continues with the top pieces of news for 2024. According to Google, its data shows that people searched for (in order) the U.S. Election, Excessive Heat, Olympics, Hurricane Milton, and 台風 気象 情報 台風 第 10 号 (Typhoon No. 10 around Japan) the most this year.</p><p>When it came to "People," Google states the top trending searches were Donald Trump, Catherine the Princess of Wales, Kamala Harris, Imane Khelif, and Joe Biden.</p><p>In "Sports," the New York Yankees took the top spot, followed by the Los Angeles Dodgers, Inter Miami CF, Bayer 04 Leverkusen, and the Boston Celtics. And, lastly, in "Gaming," the top trending searches were for Connections, Palworld, Infinite Craft, Sprunki, and Helldivers 2.</p><p>In November, Google detailed its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-play-unveils-its-top-apps-and-games-of-2024">top apps and games</a> via the Play Store for 2024. Partiful took the award for the "Best App of 2024" due to its reinvention of event planning. For mobile gaming, AFK Journey won "Best Game" while Max took the cake for "Best Multi-device App."</p><p>Other worthy mentions include Hoyoverse's Honkai: Star Rail for "Best Ongoing Game," PBS Kids Video for "Best for Cars," and Dragon Rider by Taran Matharu for "Favorite Fantasy" book in 2024.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-a-year-in-search-2024-highlights</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google takes users on a trip through 2024 and its top trending searches. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">FKNdnTnD55xgS68vQZjFb8</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sTgwYjKwGJHWQmc5VLM4G5.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 20:21:20 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sTgwYjKwGJHWQmc5VLM4G5.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google&#039;s &quot;Year in Search 2024.&quot;]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google&#039;s &quot;Year in Search 2024.&quot;]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>