<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 12:34:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ How do I know if my phone is unlocked? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <section class="article__schema-question"><h3>How do I know if my phone is unlocked?</h3><article class="article__schema-answer"><p><strong>Best answer:</strong> You can contact your mobile carrier to check if your phone is unlocked and if it's eligible. You can also insert and use the SIM card to check the phone's settings. If you bought the phone directly from the manufacturer, you can be sure it's unlocked.</p></article></section>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-where-did-you-buy-it-and-how"><span>Where did you buy it, and how?</span></h3>
<p>First and foremost, mobile carriers like AT&T, T-Mobile, and Verizon want to keep you paying monthly for their service. To do this, they offer discounts for those willing to stick around for a couple of years. It&apos;s not uncommon for a carrier to lock a phone until you pay it off to prevent you from taking advantage of a discount and switching carriers.</p><p>While your phone is locked, you won&apos;t be able to use service from another carrier. Luckily, getting your phone unlocked isn&apos;t too hard, and it may even unlock automatically if enough time has passed. Unlocking the phone might take longer than you&apos;d like, but it&apos;ll all be worth it when it is unlocked and accessible with another carrier.</p><p>If you bought your phone from a carrier, the first thing to do is make sure you pay it off. If you were paying it off with a series of payments, you&apos;d need to ensure you have paid the total balance. You haven&apos;t paid the phone off if you see a deduction offset by a bill credit for a phone purchase. Contact customer support for the information if you&apos;re unsure how much your remaining balance is.</p>
<div class='jwplayer__widthsetter'><div class='jwplayer__wrapper'><div id='futr_botr_gAdkYzi4_DN0T9lx0_div' class='future__jwplayer'><div id='botr_gAdkYzi4_DN0T9lx0_div'></div></div></div></div>
<p>Remember that some carriers use buy-one-get-one (BOGO) deals with monthly bill credits to lock customers into a cycle of paying off the phone for the entire term. If you&apos;ve participated in one of these promotions, you still have to pay for the phones, and switching to a new carrier could invalidate the bill credits that were bringing the phone price down.</p><p>Once you pay off the phone, it will either unlock automatically, or you can request an unlock from the carrier. If switching to a new carrier, unlock your phone before leaving your old carrier. You can still get your phone unlocked down the line, but it&apos;s easier to misplace the needed information, and the process could take longer.</p><p>If you bought your phone from Amazon or another online retailer, it would list it as unlocked or carrier-specific. Be sure to choose the unlocked version for your region. International models will more often than not work with U.S. carriers, but you may not have access to all carrier bands, and 5G support may be weaker than that of U.S. models.</p><p>When you buy a phone directly from a manufacturer such as Samsung, Asus, or OnePlus, it is undoubtedly unlocked and ready to use with your new carrier. When you buy the phone from an online retailer such as Amazon, ensure that you choose the unlocked version before heading out to checkout.</p><p>There&apos;s only one foolproof way to check for the rest of the phones: Try it.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-how-to-check-if-your-phone-is-unlocked"><span>How to check if your phone is unlocked</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.38%;"><img id="mgpGEojQQ8UbnD7SKYyzEa" name="sim-card.jpg" alt="SIM card" src="https://dev.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mgpGEojQQ8UbnD7SKYyzEa.jpg" mos="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kZgYyeyEFQwx6LLA8m4gL.jpg" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="451" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div></figure>
<p>You can also try those online services that claim to let you know if your phone is unlocked by providing them with the phone <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-find-imei-number-your-phone">IMEI</a>. While that might be true, these services cost money and are often incorrect. I&apos;ll come right out and say it: <strong>Don&apos;t bother</strong>.</p><p>Instead, you can call your carrier or the carrier/MVNO you&apos;re considering switching. Companies keep a database of IMEI numbers indicating which phones are compatible, unlocked, or blocked. </p><p>You might not have any luck here, though, because the person answering the phone might not be able to give you that information—they either don&apos;t have access to it or aren&apos;t allowed to tell you over the phone. However, it&apos;s worth a try if you can&apos;t access a SIM card from a different company.</p><p>Skipping all that, the easiest way to find out if your phone is unlocked is just to put in a SIM card from another carrier. It doesn&apos;t have to be a SIM card connected to an active account — the phone will try to initiate a connection with any SIM card in place. If you don&apos;t want to buy one or your friend won&apos;t let you use theirs, you can also try one from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/mint-mobile-free-trial">Mint Mobile&apos;s free trial offer</a> and get a SIM card. Some carriers like Google Fi will even send you a SIM for free when you sign up for a plan, and it doesn&apos;t charge you anything until you activate the card. </p><p>The process is as follows:</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="kFACN5bmHy8gmnr78Ejea7" name="galaxy-s9-plus-sim-card-sd-card-slot.jpg" alt="Galaxy S9+ SIM card tray" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kFACN5bmHy8gmnr78Ejea7.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1536" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<ol><li>If possible, make a phone call using your <strong>current</strong> SIM card to check that the phone is working properly. (Call your parents to say "hello"; they'll appreciate it.)<br></li><li>Shut off the phone and remove the SIM card. If you're not sure how to do this, look in the manual or online. If you need a SIM card removal tool, there's usually one stuck to the paperwork in your phone's box. A small paper clip may also work if you can't find the tool. You may also want to give it a <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/what-sim-pin-code-and-how-unlock-sim-card-pin" data-original-url="https://www.androidcentral.com/what-sim-pin-code-and-how-unlock-sim-card-pin">SIM PIN code</a> first so no one can steal and use your old SIM card.<br></li><li>Put the <strong>new</strong> SIM card in your phone and power it back on.<br></li><li>If you're greeted with a dialog box telling you to enter a SIM unlock code, your phone is SIM-locked to the carrier from which it was initially purchased.<br></li><li>If you <strong>don't</strong> see an unlock code prompt, check that it says you have service if you used a valid SIM card. If you do, your phone is probably unlocked. Sometimes, the phone takes a few minutes to configure for a new network, so be patient. Try making another phone call. (Your parents won't mind two calls on the same day.)</li></ol>
<p>You&apos;ll probably get a recorded message with an error code if you can&apos;t call using the new SIM card. You can jot down the code and check online to see why you can&apos;t complete the call so you know if it&apos;s because of a SIM lock or incompatible hardware. A wholly incompatible phone with another network is unlikely nowadays, but it&apos;s worth checking.</p><p>If you don&apos;t have access to another SIM card, you can also take your phone to a carrier store and tell them you&apos;re thinking of switching carriers and want to check if it&apos;s unlocked. Don&apos;t feel bad about telling them you want to switch; they probably hear it constantly. They can help you insert the SIM card and check if the phone is unlocked.</p><p>If your phone <em>is</em> SIM-locked, don&apos;t fret. Carriers will SIM unlock your phone provided you&apos;ve paid the total amount and your account is in good standing. Each carrier has slightly different rules regarding how long you must own the phone and how long your account must be open.</p><p>You may request an unlock directly from your phone&apos;s settings. T-Mobile has <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.t-mobile.com/support/devices/unlock-your-mobile-wireless-device/" target="_blank">a help page</a> dedicated to showing customers how to do this. If your phone doesn&apos;t have this option, you can also download the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.tmobile.grsuapp&hl=en_US" target="_blank">T-Mobile Device Unlocker app for Pixel</a> users. </p><p>AT&T also has an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.att.deviceunlock" target="_blank">unlocker app</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.att.com/deviceunlock/" target="_blank">a website to request unlocks</a>. Depending on your device, the unlocking process might take a little time, so be patient if it doesn&apos;t unlock immediately.</p><p>In many cases, you may need to do nothing at all. Verizon, for example, states that it will <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.verizon.com/support/device-unlocking-policy/">automatically unlock phones 60 days</a> after the purchase. If your Verizon phone hasn&apos;t been unlocked automatically after 60 days, you may need to call customer service to have them submit the unlock request.</p><p>If all that doesn&apos;t work, you can call customer service, and they&apos;ll help you. If you&apos;ve paid the phone off and it hasn&apos;t, no one reports it lost or stolen; you should have no trouble getting it unlocked.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-do-you-need-an-unlocked-phone"><span>Do you need an unlocked phone?</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="8SkcBHGVfWQnKN9dvQNcRo" name="sim-cards-pile-hero-2.jpg" alt="SIM cards" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8SkcBHGVfWQnKN9dvQNcRo.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1536" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Most smartphone owners ask how to check if their phone is unlocked because they plan to switch carriers. You&apos;ve probably seen some ads for prepaid <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-mvno-carrier" data-original-url="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-mvno-carrier">MVNO carriers</a> offering cheaper service than the Big Three. And since they use the same networks as the Big Three, they&apos;ll usually work with just about any unlocked phone.</p><p>We think that&apos;s great because having even more choices isn&apos;t bad. Even if you go with one of the prominent carriers, having the ability to switch <em>whenever</em> you want to one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cell-phone-plans">best cell phone plans</a> puts the power in <em>your</em> hands.</p><p>But no matter which carrier you choose, you&apos;ll need to make sure you have a SIM-unlocked phone first. That means you can use a SIM card from any company without restrictions, so long as the hardware is compatible with the network.</p><p>Most of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a> are available unlocked, but if you&apos;re paying a monthly fee to your carrier for a phone, it&apos;s likely locked. Just be careful not to get trapped into a buy one lease one free agreement, with monthly bill credits that keep you on the carrier for 24 or 36 months. If you can&apos;t pay for the phone outright, you can often set up payment plans with the manufacturer, like Samsung, without getting locked into a carrier.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-switching-to-an-mvno"><span>Switching to an MVNO</span></h3>
<p>Now that you know how to check if your phone is unlocked, your next question should be what to do with your newly freed phone. You should make several important considerations when switching to an MNVO, including checking if your <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/can-i-use-my-current-phone-prepaid-carrier" data-original-url="https://www.androidcentral.com/can-i-use-my-current-phone-prepaid-carrier">phone works with MNVOs</a>.</p><p>If you&apos;ve already decided that&apos;s your path forward, then your next step is choosing an MNVO. Since your phone may be restricted to a single provider, we have round-ups on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-mvnos-use-verizons-network">best Verizon prepaid carriers</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-mvnos-use-t-mobiles-network">best T-Mobile prepaid carriers</a>, and all AT&T prepaid carriers to help you decide.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="5b53279e-53f0-477b-b344-8050862f0f3c">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/br5W6UQe4WbfFJqj7CjuCH.jpg' alt="Pixel 8a render (Green)"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 8a</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="90" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Get the best of Pixel for less</strong></em></p>
<p>With the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-review">Google Pixel 8a</a>, you get all the AI fun without paying the price the bigger versions go for. With this model, you enjoy the Google Tensor G3 chipset and a 6.1-inch AMOLED Actua display with a 2400x1080 resolution. You also get fantastic cameras!</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/how-do-i-know-whether-my-phone-unlocked</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ An unlocked phone is the key to getting service from an alternative carrier. Here's how to check if a phone is unlocked. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">vhqy9ozhADaJVLcmqq31vV</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MjqWdSVW8usF9dHheCSUE7.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 12:15:13 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Samuel Contreras) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MjqWdSVW8usF9dHheCSUE7.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[T-Mobile logo]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[T-Mobile logo]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ WD just rolled out a 32TB HDD, and I can't wait to get my hands on one ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>While SSDs are now affordable enough that all-flash SSDs are a reality, they&apos;re still prohibitively costly if you need to store a lot of data. A good 8TB M.2 SSD will set you back to the tune of $799, whereas a similar-sized NAS HDD can be bought for as low as $179.</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Hardwired</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="5u6gVPowTCuSQ8NJeoktj7" name="lloyd-hardwired.png" caption="" alt="Android Central's LLoyd with a bionic eye" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5u6gVPowTCuSQ8NJeoktj7.png" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">In <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/hardwired">Hardwired</a>, AC Senior Editor Harish Jonnalagadda delves into all things hardware, including phones, audio products, storage servers, and routers.</p></div></div>
<p>Storage manufacturers are continually increasing drive sizes — I tested <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/seagate-exos-x24-24tb-hdd-review">Seagate&apos;s excellent 24TB Exos X24 drive</a> earlier in the year — and the brand <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/30tb-hard-drives-with-hamr-tech-are-now-a-reality-and-im-thrilled">showcased a 30TB drive</a> based on Heat Assisted Magnetic Recording (HAMR), dubbed the Exos Mozaic 3+, delivering 3TB on a single platter. Western Digital is now following suit with the introduction of the Ultrastar DC HC690, which uses a 11-platter design — one more than regular drives.</p><p>The DC HC690 is aimed at data center use, and is based on Shingled Magnetic Recording (SMR). Similar to what Seagate is doing with HAMR, WD has turned to energy-assisted Perpendicular Magnetic Recording (ePMR) to increase areal density on the drive, and while the density isn&apos;t as high as what Seagate is offering — it goes up to 2.91TB/platter — it is considerably higher than the brand&apos;s regular NAS drives.</p><p>The drive is available in a SATA configuration with 6Gb/s bandwidth, or 12Gb/s SAS as well. It&apos;s sold in 30TB and 32TB sizes, spins at 7200rpm, and goes up to 267MB/s during sustained transfers. WD is also rolling out the 24TB and 26TB DC HC590, with these drives using Conventional Magnetic Recording (CMR) in conjunction with ePMR to deliver better density.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="yrJTvEzX6kpGtw6vdssvfK" name="wd-32tb-drive-2.jpg" alt="WD Ultrastar DC HC690 render" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yrJTvEzX6kpGtw6vdssvfK.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Western Digital)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>With both models designed to be used in the data center, it&apos;s unlikely WD will make these drives available in the retail channel. But what&apos;s particularly interesting is that the brand is rolling out a 26TB Gold HDD, and this is available on its website — you <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.westerndigital.com/products/internal-drives/wd-gold-sata-hdd?sku=WD261KRYZ">can pick it up for $715</a>. The CMR drive also uses a 11-platter design, comes with a 512MB cache, 2.5M hours MTBF, and 550TB/year endurance.</p><p>The Gold drive has a density of 2.36TB/platter, and it is a great choice for enthusiasts looking to maximize storage. I&apos;m waiting until 30TB and 32TB drives are available to retail consumers, but in the meantime, 24TB and 26TB drives are a viable alternative if you&apos;re looking to build a homelab that can store just about everything, or need a NAS with scalable storage in a small business environment.</p><p>The 24TB Exos X24 is down to a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Seagate-Exos-Enterprise-Internal-Drive/dp/B0CM293XCL">reasonable $479</a>, and that&apos;s a stellar value when you consider just how much storage you&apos;re getting. With WD joining the fray, we should see additional savings in this area. While NAS enclosures such as the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/terramaster-f8-ssd-plus-review">F8 SSD Plus</a> showcase what&apos;s possible with all-flash servers, I&apos;m still going to turn to HDDs to store massive amounts of data.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="14e85b81-0dda-4aa8-b2ef-ad243c061095">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kKJk4wSChZxvPY3XduRnLH.jpg' alt="Seagate Exos X24"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Seagate 24TB Exos X24 </div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>The 24TB Exos X24 continues to be one of the best choices if you need a NAS-focused drive with massive storage potential. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/wd-just-rolled-out-a-32tb-hdd-and-i-cant-wait-to-get-my-hands-on-one</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ WD has introduced 30TB and 32TB HDDs, and while these are aimed at data centers, the brand is selling a 26TB model to consumers.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">SNSEYQBL2V7xGG7SZnJqka</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vnGXkkHg29zbPNaAzhYspL.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 11:43:30 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vnGXkkHg29zbPNaAzhYspL.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Western Digital]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[WD Ultrastar DC HC690 render]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[WD Ultrastar DC HC690 render]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Oura Ring 4 vs. RingConn Gen 2 Smart Ring: Return of the king? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[         <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="7553edd1-3dab-4370-be20-c78929ff8a84">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fmmqe7BuwR6QsZtCsAUuPR.jpg' alt="The Oura RIng 4 in silver"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Oura Ring 4</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="90" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Setting standards</strong></em></p>
<p>The new Oura Ring 4 boasts an improved design with recessed sensors, comes in more sizes, and gets an extra day of battery life. It promises more accurate data readouts thanks to a new Smart Sensing technology that adapts to how you wear it. Premium features are still behind a paywall though, which many won't be happy with.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Full titanium build</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Recessed sensors for more comfortable fit</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Up to eight days of battery life</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Wider range of sizes</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>New "Smart Sensing" data collection</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Still needs a subscription for vital analysis</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No independent charging case</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>On the heavier side</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="5b5b0bd3-5f6d-4634-bcea-a6c1ed438ac9">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RWzbtZWTBDgrYM5MAV7oma.jpg' alt="RingConn Gen 2 Smart Ring"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">RingConn Gen 2 Smart Ring</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="80" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Unmatched sleep tracking</strong></em></p>
<p>The RingConn Gen 2 Smart Ring delivers proven performance, and advanced sleep tracking with its ability to detect sleep apnea. Plus, you can access the full stats and analysis of your health data withouth having to pay for additional subscription. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Very long battery life</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Great design</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Sleep apnea tracking can be useful</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>No subscription to use all features</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Great app experience</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Sleep apnea monitoring can drain the battery</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No automatic workout tracking</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<p>Oura was the company that helped ignite the smart ring segment, and today we have many others that have joined the fold, including Samsung. Its biggest rival though has got to be RingConn which offers a very compelling product. If you&apos;re trying to decide between the newly launched Oura Ring 4 vs. RingConn Gen 2 Smart Ring, you&apos;ve come to the right place. </p><p>Oura has brought some big changes with the ring 4 like a sleeker design with a more durable finish, more sizes, and a new sensing platform that promises to capture more accurate health data no matter how you wear the ring. It could very well be a great alternative to buying the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-fitness-trackers">best fitness tracker</a>.</p><p>RingConn&apos;s Gen 2 Smart Ring has equally impressive specs and features, including the ability to detect sleep apnea. It&apos;s also cheaper than the Oura Ring 4 which potentially makes it more attractive to first-time smart ring buyers. Let&apos;s break down all the differences between the two so you can better decide which would be right for you.</p>
<h2 id="oura-ring-4-vs-ringconn-gen-2-smart-ring-design-and-pricing-2">Oura Ring 4 vs. RingConn Gen 2 Smart Ring: Design and pricing</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="2VXbzrrwUpGnHjMAUKPQqc" name="Oura-Ring-4-colors-2.jpg" alt="Oura Ring 4 in different colors" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2VXbzrrwUpGnHjMAUKPQqc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4000" height="2250" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Oura)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Oura Ring 4 starts shipping from October 15, starting at $349. This price is only for the Silver and Black colors. The Brushed Silver and Stealth finishes cost $399, while the Gold and Rose Gold finishes are $499. Unlike the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/oura-ring-gen-3-review">Oura Ring Gen 3</a>, the Ring 4 comes in a single style. You get a one-month membership for free at the time of purchase, after which you&apos;ll have to pay $5.99 a month or $69.99 a year for U.S. members. </p><p>The idea of having to pay more to access detailed reports and analysis of your own health data after already paying a premium upfront for the device is not something I&apos;m thrilled about, and I&apos;m sure many others would feel the same. </p><p>The RingConn Gen 2 Smart Ring has a much more palatable starting price of $299, irrespective of the color choice. You only get three finishes though like Future Silver, Matte Black, and Royal Gold. The biggest advantage of RingConn is that you have access to all data that&apos;s monitored, forever, as nothing is hidden behind any subscription.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="VQuvHprXQ8DgxsyN9Mi9V" name="RingConn-Gen-2-smart-ring-review-13.jpg" alt="The RingConn Gen 2 Smart Ring on a finger" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VQuvHprXQ8DgxsyN9Mi9V.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>There&apos;s not a lot of flexibility to differentiate your product from others when designing a smart ring and so, on the surface, the Oura Ring 4 and the RingConn Gen 2 look quite similar. However examine them closer or try them on, and you might notice some big differences. The Oura Ring 4 gets a fully circular design with new recessed interior sensors at just 0.3mm, which means you won&apos;t feel any bumps when you wear it. This should make it a lot more comfortable to wear while carrying heavy items like dumbbells or grocery bags.</p><p>It also gets full titanium layering on the outside and interiors too. The ring 4 now comes in sizes from four to 15, and it has a thickness of around 2.8mm. Depending on the size, it can feel a bit heavy as the weight ranges from 3.3g to 5.2g. It has full water resistance up to a depth of 100m and can be used in a sauna and other water sports, but not diving.</p><p>The RingConn Gen 2 Smart Ring has a mostly circular design too, but the interiors have two protruding divots for the LED sensors and a flat base between them. While this looks like it could be uncomfortable to wear, we found it to be the opposite when we <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/ringconn-gen-2-smart-ring-review">reviewed the Gen 2 Smart Ring</a>. RingConn uses a titanium alloy for the exterior and a medical-grade epoxy for the interior of the ring. The glossy silver model that we tested held up well against scuffs and scratches with everyday use.</p>
<h2 id="oura-ring-4-vs-ringconn-gen-2-smart-ring-features-and-specs-2">Oura Ring 4 vs. RingConn Gen 2 Smart Ring: Features and specs</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="FZ28NkgQNTRR7wXSZsygca" name="Oura-Ring-4-1.jpg" alt="Oura Ring 4" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FZ28NkgQNTRR7wXSZsygca.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4000" height="2250" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Oura)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Oura Ring 4 and the RingConn Gen 2 Smart Ring promise medical-grade accuracy in readings thanks to finely tuned sensors. Both smart rings can do continuous heart rate tracking, sleep tracking, activity monitoring, stress analysis, and cycle tracking for women. Without a subscription to Oura, the app will only show you sleep, readiness, and activity scores. With an active subscription though, you&apos;ll have access to more detailed reports about your sleep, 24/7 heart rate tracking, SpO2 sensing, VO2 Max readings, cycle insights, automatic activity detection, and much more. These reports are vital if you truly wish to make healthy lifestyle changes, but you&apos;ll need to pay extra to get it.</p><p>On the flip side, the RingConn Gen 2 offers most of these premium features for free, since there&apos;s no subscription involved. It goes a step further and even has continuous sleep apnea monitoring. The latter feature did take a big bite out of the ring&apos;s battery life when we tested it, which is something to keep in mind. Smart rings are also not the best for step tracking, although they are getting better. For best accuracy, it&apos;s better to rely on a wrist-based fitness tracker instead.</p><p>One area where the Oura Ring 4 has an advantage is its automatic activity detection and tracking for certain exercises. This is a premium feature but it makes tracking exercises seamless. Unfortunately, any kind of exercise tracking on the RingConn needs to be manually activated, which is just unnecessary added steps.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:42.85%;"><img id="CvwgsfJnCdQadwkN8c4Vx7" name="RingConn-Gen-2-smart-ring-review-hero-21-9.jpg" alt="The RingConn Gen 2 Smart Ring balanced inside its charging case" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CvwgsfJnCdQadwkN8c4Vx7.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="1817" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>One big advantage of the smart rings is the incredible battery life you get compared to any smartwatch. Since there&apos;s no screen to power or LTE network to connect to, a week&apos;s worth of runtime on one charge is not uncommon to see. The RingConn Gen 2 Smart Ring lasts for 10 to 12 days on one charge, which is incredible. You might see a drop if you do sleep apnea tracking, but it should still be more than a week before you&apos;ll need to charge it again. The best part is the charging case that comes with it can easily charge the ring no matter where you are, thanks to the built-in 500mAh battery. There&apos;s also an optional charging dock which can be bought separately. </p><p>The Oura Ring 4 can go for up to eight days (claimed time) on one charge, which is less than RingConn but an improvement over the Ring Gen 3. Sadly, you don&apos;t get a convenient charging case with it but a charging dock with a Type-C to Type-C cable. This means you&apos;ll need to plug it into a power bank or your laptop in order to charge it.</p>

<h2 id="oura-ring-4-vs-ringconn-gen-2-smart-ring-app-integration-2">Oura Ring 4 vs. RingConn Gen 2 Smart Ring: App integration</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="cabCsi8Y5Cvf6VmfGN7a5d" name="RingConn-Gen-2-smart-ring-review-05.jpg" alt="The RingConn Gen 2 Smart Ring app sleep apnea monitoring feature" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/cabCsi8Y5Cvf6VmfGN7a5d.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>We absolutely loved the app experience of the RingConn Gen 2 Smart Ring. Information is laid out in an easy-to-read manner and there are only three main tabs to cycle through, making it easy to navigate. The app also has a great set of widgets on Android, which we found very useful. The Gen 2 is also compatible with iPhone and integrates with Apple Health. On Android though, we only noticed that it worked with Google Fit and not <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-use-google-health-connect">Health Connect</a>, at the time of our review anyway.</p><p>With the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oura-ring-4-launch">launch of the Oura Ring 4</a>, the company also released a redesigned app which is supposed to make navigation a lot easier. This is a welcomed improvement since the app was pretty crowded given the amount of metrics the ring tracks. The new app will have three main views: Today, Vitals, and My Health, so you can quickly jump to the data you need. A neat addition is the Timeline view in the Today tab which gives you a glanceable snapshot of how you&apos;ve fared in the day so far. Oura&apos;s Labs feature is also finally coming to Android. This includes an AI-powered advisor to help interpret the wearer&apos;s health data.</p>
<h2 id="oura-ring-4-vs-ringconn-gen-2-smart-ring-which-should-you-buy-2">Oura Ring 4 vs. RingConn Gen 2 Smart Ring: Which should you buy?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="WHdukSAeXnrUsnJwqbJFRB" name="RingConn-Gen-2-smart-ring-vs-Oura-Ring.jpg" alt="The RingConn Gen 2 Smart Ring and the Oura Ring Gen 3 in hand" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WHdukSAeXnrUsnJwqbJFRB.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>We&apos;re yet to test the Oura Ring 4 and we have little doubt about the company&apos;s ability to deliver on the promised features, especially considering how well the Gen 3 ring performed. But going the Oura route means a committed monthly investment for the subscription if you want to make any sense of all the data it collects. It&apos;s also quite expensive for casual users as prices can go as high as $499 for the premium trims.</p><p>The majority of users should find the RingConn Gen 2 Smart Ring a good enough alternative, and it&apos;s the one I&apos;d recommend to most. It&apos;s more affordable than Oura, there are no subscription fees to get detailed reports and analysis of your data, and it has an amazingly good battery life which even trumps the Ring 4&apos;s claimed number.</p><p>You&apos;ll have to compromise in some places like manually tracking workouts. The sleep apnea feature can drain the battery a fair bit, even though that&apos;s one of its unique features. Overall, with a great app experience, durable design, and handy charge-on-the-go case, the RingConn Gen 2 Smart Ring is truly the one ring to rule them all.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="c611a5b8-788f-42f2-a9ab-2a2758ee01ac">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RWzbtZWTBDgrYM5MAV7oma.jpg' alt="RingConn Gen 2 Smart Ring"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">RingConn Gen 2 Smart Ring</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The best for everyone</strong></em></p>
<p>The RingConn Gen 2 Smart Ring offers a great mix of features, battery life, and price, making it the ideal first smart ring for most people.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="bab20bc0-1f98-473e-a675-5f24278d501d">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nG8MVq445oJMCacip4R7FR.jpg' alt="The Oura RIng 4 in silver"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Oura Ring 4</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>For those serious about fitness</strong></em></p>
<p>The Oura Ring 4 is for the dedicated fitness person who won't mind paying a monthly fee for detailed insights. Plus, the new design, wider range of sizes, and claimed better battery life should be a good upgrade over the Ring Gen 3.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oura-ring-4-vs-ringconn-gen-2-smart-ring</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Oura Ring 4 is the latest entry in the smart ring space and targets the RingConn Gen 2 Smart Ring squarely. If you're shopping for your first smart ring, which path do you choose? ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">C8zDfJ5yaqQX7SoD368aia</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5fUZtXkXsQyBx4L2G3858h.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 09:48:12 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ roydon.cerejo@gmail.com (Roydon Cerejo) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5fUZtXkXsQyBx4L2G3858h.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Oura]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Oura Ring 4]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Oura Ring 4]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Looks like the Galaxy Z Fold 6 'Slim' might just be around the corner ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The Galaxy Z Fold 6 Special Edition is rumored to drop on October 25.</li><li>This model allegedly boasts a super slim profile—only 4.9mm thick when unfolded and 10.6mm when folded.</li><li>Leaker Evan Blass also shared renders showing the back of the phone, which features three raised lenses in a bold camera bump.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Samsung&apos;s rumored slimmer Galaxy Z Fold 6 was expected to drop this month, and a new leak backs that up with fresh details on the Galaxy Z Fold 6 Special Edition&apos;s launch date.</p><p>A report from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.fnnews.com/news/202410141458081323" target="_blank">FNNews</a> says Samsung is set to launch the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Galaxy Z Fold 6</a> Special Edition on October 25 (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.sammobile.com/news/galaxy-z-fold-special-edition-launch-date-leaks/" target="_blank">SamMobile</a>). This timing puts Samsung in a strong spot to take on its Chinese rivals, especially in terms of screen size and slim design, marking a big leap forward for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">foldable smartphones</a>.</p><p>According to the report, the Galaxy Z Fold Special Edition is just 4.9mm thick when unfolded and 10.6mm when folded—definitely an upgrade from the Z Fold 6&apos;s 5.6mm and 12.1mm measurements.</p><p>Back in July, a leak hinted that the Galaxy Z Fold Special Edition could have a folded thickness between 10 and 11 millimeters. The latest report backs this up, adding more weight to the idea that this device will raise the bar for slim foldable phones.</p><p>Furthermore, leaker Evan Blass just shared two renders of the upcoming Galaxy Z Fold 6 "Slim." The image shows off the back of the phone, with three cameras in a bold camera bump. The raised camera module, complete with individual camera rings, adds some thickness, showing how tricky it is to squeeze cameras into such a slim phone.</p><p>The camera setup in the render lines up with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/alleged-galaxy-z-fold-6-special-edition-photo-rumors">past leaks about this device</a>. The rectangular bump makes it stand out compared to the individual cameras on the Galaxy Z Fold 6, giving the render even more believability.</p><p>The camera module sports three raised lenses that look a lot like those on the Galaxy Z Fold 6. But from the side, there’s not much to take in—just a goldish tint and a pretty chunky border around the internal display.</p><p>The second render gives us a look at the slim side of the device. You can see two buttons—likely for the volume and power—set against a textured rose-gold mid-frame.</p><p>Unfortunately, the limited images don’t give us much to dive into. The leaker hasn’t named the exact device in the renders, but there’s a lot of buzz that it’s likely linked to the upcoming Galaxy Z Fold 6 Special Edition, which was rumored to be called the Galaxy Z Fold 6 Slim and aimed at the South Korean market.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/looks-like-the-galaxy-z-fold-6-slim-might-just-be-around-the-corner</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The launch date for the Galaxy Z Fold 6 Special Edition might've slipped out. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">a8WztAQ2SDHn67bwKK39CT</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/55ZQmVwWJDrUhztCxVy7Vo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 06:44:36 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/55ZQmVwWJDrUhztCxVy7Vo.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 on cobblestone road]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 on cobblestone road]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Mobvoi's new TicWatch promises great battery life despite its feature-packed arsenal ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Mobvoi has launched the TicWatch Atlas, a $350 rugged timepiece that offers a wallet-friendly alternative to premium smartwatches from Samsung and Apple without skimping on features.</li><li>It features a tough stainless steel design, sapphire crystal protection for its 1.43-inch display, and a redesigned button layout for easy use.</li><li>Internally, it runs on the Snapdragon W5 Plus Gen 1, has 2GB of RAM, 32GB of storage, and a 628mAh battery.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Mobvoi has just dropped its newest smartwatch, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.mobvoi.com/us/pages/ticwatchatlas" target="_blank">TicWatch Atlas</a>, a rugged timepiece packed with all the features you might need for your next adventure.</p><p>Currently, the rugged smartwatch market is mostly ruled by a few major players. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/apple-watch-ultra-2-review">Apple’s Watch Ultra 2</a> and Samsung’s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-ultra-review">Galaxy Watch Ultra</a> are top contenders, while <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-garmin-smartwatch">Garmin offers a solid lineup</a> that&apos;s perfect for outdoor enthusiasts.</p><p>If the high prices of these options have got you feeling drained, Mobvoi&apos;s TicWatch Atlas is a great alternative. Priced at only $350, this smartwatch is loaded with features and built to last, offering a premium experience without the sky-high cost.</p><p>Building on the legacy of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/mobvoi-ticwatch-pro-5-enduro-review">Pro 5 Enduro</a>, the TicWatch Atlas features a tough stainless steel build for added durability. It also protects its 1.43-inch display with sapphire crystal and has a fresh button layout for easier access.</p><p>Mobvoi claims that this watch is built to military-grade standards, making it tough enough for extreme conditions.</p><p>Following the success of the Pro 5 Enduro, the Atlas brings some impressive upgrades, like Heat Map Tracking to help you spot your favorite workout spots. It also adds a fall detection feature, which can send out an SOS alert to emergency services or a chosen contact if you take a tumble.</p><p>With health and performance at the forefront, the Atlas packs in 24/7 heart rate monitoring, SpO2 tracking, sleep analysis, and solid tools for managing stress.</p><p>Mobvoi also points out that the Atlas can now display key health metrics—like heart rate, calories burned, and VO2 Max—on its secondary ultra-low-power screen before you dive into your workouts.</p><p>Inside, the Atlas shares a lot of specs with its predecessor. It runs on the same Snapdragon W5 Plus Gen 1 wearable platform, comes with 2GB of RAM, and offers 32GB of storage. And the same 628mAh battery is keeping the lights on. Plus, it&apos;s packed with a bunch of integrated AI features.</p><p>With its hefty battery and smart power-saving tech, Mobvoi says the Atlas can go for up to 90 hours in Smart Mode and 45 hours in Essential Mode.</p><p>Unfortunately, the Atlas is running on Wear OS 4, even though <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/wear-os-5">Wear OS 5</a> has been <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-wear-os-5-september-2024-update">out for a few months now</a>. While there’s a chance it could get an update down the line, there’s no set timeline for when that might happen.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/mobvois-new-ticwatch-promises-great-battery-life-despite-its-feature-packed-arsenal</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The TicWatch Atlas is a sturdy smartwatch that packs in advanced features like a heat map and emergency SOS functionality. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">jSxYrXtxCrKHQfC6EZsfoG</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zrwPBu4fn5FUxGnroHbpY8.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 05:23:20 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zrwPBu4fn5FUxGnroHbpY8.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Mobvoi]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Mobvoi Ticwatch Atlas wrapped around the wrist]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Mobvoi Ticwatch Atlas wrapped around the wrist]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Oura Ring 4 vs. Oura Ring Gen 3: Should you upgrade? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[         <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="908cc959-c9fe-4a38-a04e-d6739777651a">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oHoozuCoVnhNr3oLwRUoEJ.jpg' alt="The Oura Ring 4 in Brushed Silver"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Oura Ring 4</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Smarter sensing</strong></em></p>
<p>The Oura Ring 4 builds on the success of its predecessor by adding better sensing technology for improved accuracy and battery life. Plus, the all-titanium build looks quite good in any color.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>All-titanium build</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>8-day battery life</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>12 sizes</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Improved health-monitoring accuracy</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Automatic activity detection (AAD) with HR data</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No Find My Ring for Android</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Only one style</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="1fe97e36-48c9-414f-b501-ee16c91a057f">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LCHHzTfZTFjUWnoU8iewPA.jpg' alt="The Oura Rinbg Gen 3 Horizon in Brushed Titanium"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Oura Ring Gen 3</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Trendsetter</strong></em></p>
<p>The Oura Ring Gen 3 started it all and continues to impress years after it launched. Even with the newer Oura Ring 4, the Gen 3 model is one of the best smart rings on the market, with an impressive array of features and a great app experience.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Two styles</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Great health-tracking features</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Week-long battery</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>AAD is impressive when it works</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Charger looks/feels cheap</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Raised internal sensors may be uncomfortable</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Fewer signal pathways for health monitoring</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No HR data with AAD</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<p>The Oura Ring 4 is the latest and greatest smart ring from the Finnish company that started the wearable craze. However, the Oura Ring Gen 3 was the smart ring that led that trend, thanks to its impressive feature set, battery life, and small size.</p><p>When considering purchasing a smart ring, you&apos;re likely wondering if you should still go for the older Gen 3 or splurge for the newer model. Even if you already own the Oura Ring Gen 3, you may want to know if it&apos;s worth upgrading to the Oura Ring 4 for the extra battery life and other improvements.</p><p>This comparison should help you decide between the two and if it&apos;s worth switching out your Gen 3 for a 4, although the answer isn&apos;t as simple as you may think.</p>
<h2 id="oura-ring-4-vs-oura-ring-gen-3-design-2">Oura Ring 4 vs. Oura Ring Gen 3: Design</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="3KjubLK3oYtu4nr2A66MLb" name="Oura-Ring-4-vs-oura-ring-gen-3-02.jpg" alt="The Oura Ring 4 on the Oura Ring Gen 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3KjubLK3oYtu4nr2A66MLb.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>At first glance, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oura-ring-4-launch">Oura Ring 4</a> doesn&apos;t look all that different from the Oura Ring Gen 3. The newer model takes after the Horizon style of its predecessor, which features a fully circular design, while the older Heritage style has a flatter "top" section. Where the rings differ, however, is in the materials and the sensors.</p><p>Unlike the Gen 3, which has a titanium exterior and an epoxy interior, the Oura Ring 4 has an all-titanium design, which should improve overall durability. In addition, the sensors are now flush with the interior, whereas the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/oura-ring-gen-3-review">Oura Ring Gen 3</a> has three raised bumps where the sensors go. Having them flush should make the ring more comfortable to wear.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4042px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.26%;"><img id="ukXtzTrmgboYMwWzjeSUaC" name="Oura-Ring-4-vs-oura-ring-gen-3-01.jpg" alt="The Oura Ring 4 next to the Oura Ring Gen 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ukXtzTrmgboYMwWzjeSUaC.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4042" height="2274" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While the Heritage style Oura Ring Gen 3 only comes in four different colorways and finishes, the Horizon style has six options, which correspond with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/which-oura-ring-4-color-should-you-buy">Oura Ring 4 color options</a>. That includes black, silver, Brushed Titanium (Brushed Silver for the Oura Ring 4), Stealth, Gold, and Rose Gold. What you pay for the ring will depend on the color you choose, and for the Gen 3, it will also depend on the style. For comparison, the most expensive Oura Ring 4 colors are $50 cheaper than the most expensive Gen 3 colors, although the cheapest model is $50 more expensive.</p><p>Aside from the all-titanium design, the Oura Ring 4 has the same <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/is-the-oura-ring-4-waterproof">waterproof protection</a>, meaning it should be safe at depths up to 100 meters. The Oura Ring 4 is also available in more sizes than its predecessor, and the width has remained the same, although the thickness lies somewhere between the two Gen 3 styles, while the weight has been reduced overall.</p>
<h2 id="oura-ring-4-vs-oura-ring-gen-3-specs-2">Oura Ring 4 vs. Oura Ring Gen 3: Specs</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3921px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.26%;"><img id="biWhAp3K9FyaAfr5zgyZ35" name="Oura-Ring-4-review-14.jpg" alt="The Oura Ring 4 on its charging dock" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/biWhAp3K9FyaAfr5zgyZ35.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3921" height="2206" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Spec-wise, the Oura Ring 4 is actually pretty similar to the Oura Ring 3, with some differences in battery life, size options, and sensor layout (as well as the specific type of sensors.</p>

<h2 id="oura-ring-4-vs-oura-ring-gen-3-health-tracking-2">Oura Ring 4 vs. Oura Ring Gen 3: Health tracking</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="2sq9v3PBhKKwpjmEkYARNX" name="Oura-Ring-4-review-09.jpg" alt="The Oura Ring 4 with the Android Bot figure" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2sq9v3PBhKKwpjmEkYARNX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Both smart rings feature the standard set of health tracking features, including heart rate monitoring, SpO2, heart rate variability (HRV), temperature, and more. The Oura Ring Gen 3 featured superb health tracking features with the help of its sensor array and algorithms. The ring even supports automatic activity detection, meaning it can detect various activities based on your movements. However, its features are somewhat limited, with automatically tracked activities only showing limited information such as calories.</p><p>The Oura Ring 4 improves <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/can-oura-ring-4-automatically-detect-workouts">Automatic Activity Detection</a> by including heart rate data when the ring automatically detects certain activities. You&apos;ll get a graph of your heart rate, your average HR, and a view of your heart rate zones while the activity was being detected, useful information for people seeking a more active lifestyle.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3440px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:79.65%;"><img id="wooFHuUPnNkAZvvXwWLmqU" name="Oura-app-activity-heart-rate-details.jpg" alt="Oura app activity tracking" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wooFHuUPnNkAZvvXwWLmqU.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="3440" height="2740" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>And while the Oura Ring Gen 3 is fairly accurate (although step counting is hit or miss), the Oura Ring 4 should prove more accurate when measuring things like blood oxygen levels. This is thanks to Oura&apos;s new Smart Sensing technology, which takes advantage of the new sensor array on the Oura Ring 4. Instead of static signals, the algorithm can find optimal pathways while on your finger, which can help it remain as accurate as possible, even as the ring shifts around. Oura says this is also aided by the all-titanium build on the new ring, and it has more than double the number of pathways.</p><p>With smart sensing, the Oura Ring 4 should also be able to respond better to people with different finger physiology, meaning users across genders, skin tones, and ages will benefit from better accuracy.</p><p>As a result, the Oura Ring 4 is 30% more accurate with blood oxygen readings than the Oura Ring Gen 3. You&apos;ll also find better heart rate monitoring with fewer gaps throughout the day and overnight.</p>
<h2 id="oura-ring-4-vs-oura-ring-gen-3-which-should-you-buy-2">Oura Ring 4 vs. Oura Ring Gen 3: Which should you buy?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3895px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="8o8EYvaRRYUABGwZ9ZxweF" name="Oura-Ring-4-review-12.jpg" alt="The Oura Ring 4" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8o8EYvaRRYUABGwZ9ZxweF.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3895" height="2191" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Truth be told, both smart rings are at the top of their class. The Oura Ring 4 is obviously the better ring, but the Oura Ring Gen 3 is still no pushover, and both devices easily best other <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/best-smart-rings">competing smart rings</a>. That said, if you had to choose between these two, I would recommend buying the Oura Ring 4, and here&apos;s why:</p><p>The Oura Ring Gen 3 launched in 2021 and has been able to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oura-ring-resilience-metric-tracks-stress-recovery">add plenty of new features</a> to its repertoire, proving that smart rings have the kind of longevity and flexibility that doesn&apos;t require yearly model updates like a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch">smartwatch</a>. However, it&apos;s been a few years already and the Oura Ring Gen 3 is seemingly at the end of the line. Oura says that it will continue to sell the Gen 3 but at a discount, and once stock runs out, that&apos;s it.</p><p>Meanwhile, given what we know about the Gen 3, the newer Oura Ring 4 will likely receive the same treatment, receiving new features while it&apos;s available (and perhaps beyond). So, with the Oura Ring 4 having just launched, this is probably the best time to get one.</p>
<p>However, it&apos;s a little different if you already <em>have</em> the Gen 3. Oura doesn&apos;t offer any upgrade perks or discounts, so there&apos;s no real pathway to "upgrade" your ring besides outright buying a new one. And while that may seem tempting (if you have the money, go for it), you&apos;re probably best sticking with the Gen 3 until it completely dies.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="be8e3f21-36ad-42dd-a851-185e00436b19">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CWZwah2TKycvWKegbiuEsH.jpg' alt="The Oura Ring 4 in Black"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Oura Ring 4</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The lord of the smart rings</strong></em></p>
<p>The Oura Ring 4 is a fantastic smart ring and perhaps the current new best. Not only does it have an improved design and sensor accuracy, but it also has a longer battery life and more available sizes to fit more people.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="39c9872b-599c-4400-8d32-b541d24e259e">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pxSbe7Q7pa4NpBK8BN8ryg.jpg' alt="Oura Ring Gen 3 Heritage Black"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Oura Ring Gen 3</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Still a great ring</strong></em></p>
<p>The Oura Ring Gen 3 may be a few years old, but it remains one of the best smart rings on the market and perhaps one of the best health-tracking wearables, thanks to the bevy of sensors and the impressive companion app that continues to add more features.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oura-ring-4-vs-oura-ring-gen-3</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Oura Ring 4 brings quite a few important upgrades over the Oura Ring Gen 3, but is it worth upgrading to? Should new smart ring buyers still consider the older model? ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">x7ZGJjf6uFuzeP2e8c3GRL</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dyceobN6TGnV43AovR3zmN.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 04:26:30 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ derrek.lee@futurenet.com (Derrek Lee) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dyceobN6TGnV43AovR3zmN.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Oura Ring 4 on the Oura Ring Gen 3]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Oura Ring 4 on the Oura Ring Gen 3]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Android 16: Eligible devices, release date, and new features ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>After several months of testing, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a> made it to stable release, and the update is now rolling out to eligible Pixel devices. Google showcased dozens of new features in the beta testing phase, but like previous years, not all features made it to the stable build. Either they&apos;re not fully ready, or Google decided to hold back features until later releases.</p><p>This was the case with the predictive back gesture, which showed up initially in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-13-review">Android 13</a> beta but is only rolling out widely with Android 15. While Android 16 is still a few months away — the initial preview builds should go live at the end of February 2025 — we know a decent amount about the next version of Android.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-which-devices-will-get-android-16"><span>Which devices will get Android 16?</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="usUCsFE8ymUB2rjF9HTzYo" name="android-15-devices-2.jpg" alt="List of devices getting Android 15 beta" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/usUCsFE8ymUB2rjF9HTzYo.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Android 16 will make its way to more devices than just about any other Android version. With most brands now offering at least three Android OS updates to their budget and mid-range phones, Android 16 will be available to most devices launched in the last two years. Budget phones have been ignored for far too long, and the fact that they will get long-term updates is a big deal.</p><p>When it comes to Google&apos;s own devices, all Pixels starting with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-7-pro-review">Pixel 7</a> series will be able to switch to Android 16. That leaves out the Pixel 6, 6 Pro, and all older Pixels, but these devices will continue to get feature updates and security patches. With Google now guaranteeing seven years of software updates — even on the mid-range <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-review">Pixel 8a</a> — updates aren&apos;t going to be a problem in the future.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-what-is-android-16-s-internal-codename"><span>What is Android 16's internal codename?</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="WymQhvqn9KZWMgDvhbDvdg" name="android-15-logo-highlight.jpg" alt="Android 15 logo on Pixel 8" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WymQhvqn9KZWMgDvhbDvdg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google used dessert names with Android versions in the past, and while it doesn&apos;t do so any longer — that ended with Android 10 — it still maintains internal codenames. Android 15 was Vanilla Ice Cream, and with Android 16, you&apos;d assume Google to go with a dessert that starts with the letter W, like waffle.</p><p>Instead, Android 16 has an internal codename dubbed Baklava. Google is changing how it&apos;s assigning the codenames for Android releases, and while it&apos;s still maintaining dessert-based monikers, it effectively started over.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-new-features-coming-to-android-16"><span>New features coming to Android 16</span></h3>
<h2 id="notification-cooldown-turns-down-the-noise-2">Notification cooldown turns down the noise</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="kiuynbZRkJSBsn6cyAv9zg" name="android-15-notifications.jpg" alt="Android 15 notification cooldown" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kiuynbZRkJSBsn6cyAv9zg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Notification cooldown is a great new feature that lowers the volume of incoming notifications when you get successive notifications from within the same app. So if you&apos;re in a group chat and start getting constant notifications, your phone automatically lowers the volume of subsequent notifications. </p><p>What&apos;s great is that you can select this setting for just conversations, or all apps. As someone who doesn&apos;t like getting many notification alerts (I use DND most of the day), this is a great new addition, and one that I will use to good effect.</p>
<h2 id="an-actual-desktop-mode-2">An actual desktop mode</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="oZ6tHCLzssh9ruJPDDVYfZ" name="samsung-galaxy-tab-s9-ultra-dex-desktop.jpg" alt="Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 Ultra on desk in DeX Mode" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oZ6tHCLzssh9ruJPDDVYfZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div></figure>
<p>Samsung has <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-samsung-dex">DeX mode</a> on its high-end devices, but the brand is an outlier in this regard, and most Android devices don&apos;t have a desktop mode. That may change with Android 16; later Android 15 beta builds had a desktop mode with app windows, and while it isn&apos;t available in the stable build, it&apos;s clear that Google is working on enabling a desktop mode in Android.</p><p>Samsung&apos;s feature is still much better; the brand has been tweaking DeX for nearly half a decade now, and it is a mature platform. That said, I&apos;m very excited to see a native desktop mode make its way to Android 16.</p>
<h2 id="limit-charging-to-80-2">Limit charging to 80%</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="JnfckBzVEHyPHreXakGZ2m" name="battery-settings-on-pixel-9-pro-xl.jpg" alt="Battery screen on Google Pixel 9 Pro XL" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JnfckBzVEHyPHreXakGZ2m.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>This feature was available in the Android 15 beta, but there&apos;s no mention of it in the stable release. The charging optimization mode is in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-qpr1-beta-1-begins">Android 15 QPR1 build</a>, so Google will likely roll it out with that update, or push it to the wider Android 16 release.</p><p>As the name suggests, the feature allows you to limit the battery to 80%, prolonging its longevity considerably. While a few manufacturers have this feature in their own skin, it makes to see it baked into Android natively.</p>
<h2 id="audio-sharing-should-be-easier-in-android-16-2">Audio sharing should be easier in Android 16</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="urcipt6frvrTMcHqmQjckW" name="nothing-ear-2-25.jpg" alt="Nothing Ear (2) earbuds review on red background" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/urcipt6frvrTMcHqmQjckW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Another new feature that showed up in initial Android 15 betas but isn&apos;t available in the stable release is the ability to cast music to several Bluetooth devices at the same time. The Audio sharing sub-menu is located within the Connected devices page, and it lets you cast music to more than one Bluetooth device at a time. I really wanted to see this feature in Android 15, but given how buggy it was, it&apos;s clear that Google is pushing it to next year.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-android-16-is-coming-soon"><span>Android 16 is coming soon</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="NMKzfoCA9KYCgfxHqqEUJn" name="android-14-pixel-9-pro-xl-android-15-pixel-9-pro-fold-2.jpg" alt="Android 14 on Google Pixel 9 Pro XL and Android 15 on Pixel 9 Pro Fold" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NMKzfoCA9KYCgfxHqqEUJn.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>We don&apos;t have to wait too long to get an initial preview into Android 16. Google usually rolls out a dev preview in Q1, and while the early builds are buggy and don&apos;t have much in the way of new features, they act as the foundation for further testing.</p><p>Google hasn&apos;t changed its beta program in nearly a decade, and that&apos;s unlikely to be the case next year. That means we should get the public beta builds around May, with a stable release in Q4. Of course, this is all conjecture at this point, and we will know more once Google starts rolling out preview builds of Android 16.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The stable Android 15 build is now hitting Pixels, so it's time to take a look at what's coming to Android next year — this is what we know about Android 16.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">DbUExYMoUNnze3RWQWYyzb</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AxWTrfRYJAJ7DLJEZoxu5g.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 03:19:21 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AxWTrfRYJAJ7DLJEZoxu5g.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android 15 home screen]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android 15 home screen]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Motorola is testing AI that skips words and gets straight to doing what you ask ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Motorola revealed a new AI concept that allows your phone to understand its surroundings and tackle tasks just by having a casual chat.</li><li>Although it's still in the proof-of-concept stage, this technology could learn from your habits and turn natural language into actions, making it feel like you have a personal assistant.</li><li>Motorola is also enhancing other AI features, like Moto AI, which launched with the Motorola Razr Plus 2024 and is gradually expanding in beta testing.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Today at Lenovo&apos;s Tech World 2024 event, Motorola showcased a new AI-powered concept that could turn your phone into a do-it-all device.</p><p>Motorola <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://motorolanews.com/motorola-at-tech-world-2024/" target="_blank">announced</a> that it&apos;s exploring a new project that combines Large Action Models (LAM) with Moto AI’s smarts. This proof-of-concept tech lets your phone pick up on your environment and handle tricky tasks by just chatting with it naturally.</p><p>The company gives a simple example: say, "order me an iced americano," and Moto AI will find a nearby coffee shop, place the order, and let you know when it’s ready. This same feature can also handle your regular tasks like hailing a ride.</p><p>While it’s still in the proof-of-concept phase, this tech could understand your environment, learn from your habits to give personalized responses, and turn natural language into actions all on its own. Essentially, Motorola&apos;s LAMs are like smart assistants that can interact with you in a human-like way using everyday language.</p><p>These features give Motorola&apos;s concept a unique twist compared to Apple and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Google&apos;s AI tools</a>. The LAM technology aims to take action in response to your requests instead of just spitting out text or images.</p><p>On the other hand, Google’s upgraded Gemini digital assistant can handle questions about what’s on your screen and interact with other apps.</p><p>Even though this technology is only a proof of concept for now, Motorola is also pushing forward with other AI-driven features. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-motorola-razr-plus-2024-could-pack-a-game-changing-camera-upgrade">Moto AI</a>, launched alongside the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2024-review">Motorola Razr Plus 2024</a> earlier this year, is gradually expanding its AI features in a beta testing phase.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3488px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="GHUdW3V8ETfSKaSvqyKesj" name="Moto-AI-features-Lenovo-Tech-World-2024-3.jpg" alt="Moto AI features demonstrated on a phone" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GHUdW3V8ETfSKaSvqyKesj.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="3488" height="1962" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4036px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="jQV4BRQTfi8sEMHUzn3s5" name="Moto-AI-LAM-Uber-Lenovo-Tech-World-2024.jpg" alt="Moto AI features demonstrated on a phone" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jQV4BRQTfi8sEMHUzn3s5.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4036" height="2270" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3749px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.26%;"><img id="UrHL9Mb3vp3orerrzXJoc5" name="Moto-AI-LAM-Starbucks-Lenovo-Tech-World-2024-5.jpg" alt="Moto AI features demonstrated on a phone" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/UrHL9Mb3vp3orerrzXJoc5.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="3749" height="2109" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 4 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="LhxZfoegFP7HRBorbm8PG9" name="Moto-AI-Catch-Me-Up-Lenovo-Tech-World-2024-2.jpg" alt="Moto AI features demonstrated on a phone" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LhxZfoegFP7HRBorbm8PG9.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Earlier this year, the company showcased several Moto AI features, including Catch Me Up and Remember This. The Catch Me Up feature helps you quickly catch up on notifications by giving you a prioritized summary, saving you from having to scroll through a long list of missed alerts.</p><p>The Pay Attention feature makes it easy for users to keep track of instructions without having to write them down or record lengthy audio notes. Meanwhile, Remember This lets you save live moments or on-screen info when activated.</p><p>However, there’s no word yet on which devices are included in this beta testing or how participants are chosen. Motorola plans to gradually roll out beta invitations over the year.</p>
<hr>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="fd65a628-6a12-485d-bce2-824e85d2455a">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7WdoQCZMkY7zwYEWmLts6Q.jpg' alt="The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 in Peach Fuzz"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Motorola Razr Plus 2024</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 features one of the largest cover screens on today’s flip phones, giving you plenty of room to use apps without needing to open the device. It also sports a powerful dual 50MP camera for stunning portraits and a sleek vegan leather finish that adds a unique look and feel.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/motorola-is-testing-ai-that-skips-words-and-gets-straight-to-doing-what-you-ask</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Motorola’s proof-of-concept LAM tech lets your phone understand your surroundings in order to tackle tough tasks with just a few words. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Ftn5CPG4qQebCgayj74zTf</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pEASxtK2JCHbPBEaLFXnJ4.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 02:19:31 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pEASxtK2JCHbPBEaLFXnJ4.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A Motorola executive showcasing Moto AI on stage]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A Motorola executive showcasing Moto AI on stage]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Black Friday Google Pixel deals 2024 — early discounts and how to prepare ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The fall season has arrived, which means Black Friday Google Pixel deals are just around the corner. If you&apos;re hoping to grab a new device from one of our favorite OEMs this holiday season, bookmark this page: I&apos;ve designed it to be a one-stop shop for all things Google during the Black Friday and Cyber Monday sales in 2024. </p><p>Of course, Black Friday isn&apos;t until November 29th, so in the meantime, I&apos;m filling this guide with a bunch of helpful shopping advice so you know what to expect when the sales officially go live. I&apos;ll also add a few early deals for folks who want to get their shopping done today.  </p><p>Whether you&apos;re hoping to buy the innovative <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-fold-review">Pixel 9 Pro Fold</a> or the midrange <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-review">Google Pixel 8a</a>, keep reading for everything you need to know about shopping Google Pixel devices during Black Friday 2024. Things change quickly around here, so don&apos;t forget to check back later: I&apos;ll be updating this guide on a regular basis. </p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-today-s-best-deals"><span>Today's best deals</span></h3>
<ul><li><strong>Google Pixel 9:</strong> <a href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9/6810275/"><del>$799</del> <strong>$399, plus $15/month Unlimited at Mint Mobile</strong></a></li><li><strong>Google Pixel Watch 2: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-Watch-Best-Fitbit/dp/B0CCQ4BX4T"><del>$249.99</del> <strong>$199.99 at Amazon</strong></a></li><li><strong>Google Pixel Tablet: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-tablet-11-android-tablet-128gb-wifi-hazel/6578698.p"><del>$399</del> <strong>$319 at Best Buy</strong></a></li><li><strong>Google Pixel 9 Pro XL: </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/buy/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-xl.html"><del>$1,249</del> <strong>FREE with eligible line, trade-in at AT&T</strong></a></li><li><strong>Google Pixel 8a: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-8a-Unlocked-Advanced/dp/B0CYQFJSRF"><del>$499</del> <strong>$449 at Amazon</strong></a></li><li><strong>Google Pixel 7 Pro: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-7-pro-128gb-unlocked-obsidian/6519915.p"><del>$899</del> <strong>$449 w/ activation at Best Buy</strong></a></li></ul>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-faq"><span>FAQ</span></h3>
<h2 id="which-retailer-has-the-best-black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2">Which retailer has the best Black Friday Google Pixel deals?</h2>
<p>It depends on what you&apos;re looking for. If you prefer to buy unlocked phones, you&apos;ll find that retailers like Amazon and Best Buy are more than willing to discount Pixel devices heavily during sale events. </p><p>If you&apos;re okay with making a change to your wireless service or you have a device to trade in, you can expect many carriers to discount their Pixel stock as well. As a matter of fact, there are already plenty of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/mint-mobile-deals-promo-codes">Mint Mobile deals</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/best-verizon-phone-deals-plans">Verizon deals</a> available for the Google Pixel 9 series at this exact moment. </p><p>Last but not least, if you don&apos;t mind a preowned item, Black Friday/Cyber Monday weekend typically presents a unique opportunity to buy refurbished tech on sites like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.backmarket.com/"><strong>BackMarket.com</strong></a>. These devices have been tested and renewed to meet like-new standards, and all items from BackMarket are supported by a one-year warranty. Of course, mileage with refurbished phones may vary, but the site is worth a look while you&apos;re shopping.  </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="A5JUsMmXbpHi5T5WexKYy9" name="google-pixel-9-pro-xl-in-hand-rear.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL in hand" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/A5JUsMmXbpHi5T5WexKYy9.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<h2 id="when-do-black-friday-phone-deals-start-2">When do Black Friday phone deals start?</h2>
<p>Black Friday deals are actually starting to kick off right now, and the best offers will continue to run through November 29th. That being said, the offers on display will continue to get better as we approach the holiday, so keep checking this guide as I add new Pixel discounts. </p>
<h2 id="what-black-friday-google-pixel-deals-can-i-expect-2">What Black Friday Google Pixel deals can I expect?</h2>
<p>Fortunately, Amazon&apos;s recent Prime Day event gives us a good idea of what we can expect as the Black Friday deals go live. During that 48-hour sale, we saw a ton of last-gen Pixel phones score record-breaking discounts, while Google tablets and smartwatches saw similarly tempting price drops. We didn&apos;t see any major discounts on the Pixel 9 series or the Google Pixel Watch 3, however, but that could change by the time Black Friday weekend rolls around. </p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-early-black-friday-deals"><span>Early Black Friday deals</span></h3>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="388fc972-466a-4b83-9d9c-58cb37701dfc" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9/6810275/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:204px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:121.08%;"><img id="Y8nScb7AAtxK4j2d2EnxjV" name="google-pixel-9-render-obsidian.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Y8nScb7AAtxK4j2d2EnxjV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="204" height="247" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Google Pixel 9 128GB: </strong><a href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9/6810275/" data-dimension112="388fc972-466a-4b83-9d9c-58cb37701dfc" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799"><del>$799</del> <strong>$399, plus a year of Unlimited for $15/month at Mint Mobile</strong></a></p>
<p>Buy Google's super-balanced <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-review">Pixel 9</a> alongside a year of the Unlimited plan at Mint Mobile and you'll get 50% off both the flagship phone AND a full year of T-Mobile-powered wireless service. The Google Pixel 9 boasts 12GB of RAM, an elegant design with a 120Hz AMOLED display, and a seven-year software update promise. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9/6810275/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="388fc972-466a-4b83-9d9c-58cb37701dfc" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="d3fe4ae0-3e26-46e3-ac0c-955ef03dc783" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel Watch 2: $249.99" data-dimension48="Google Pixel Watch 2: $249.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CCQFL1XV" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="TybpXTco3ENx84pzphmTFf" name="google-pixel-watch-2-black.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TybpXTco3ENx84pzphmTFf.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1500" height="1500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Google Pixel Watch 2: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-Watch-Best-Fitbit/dp/B0CCQFL1XV" data-dimension112="d3fe4ae0-3e26-46e3-ac0c-955ef03dc783" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel Watch 2: $249.99" data-dimension48="Google Pixel Watch 2: $249.99"><del>$249.99</del> <strong>$197.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>Although it's no longer Google's newest smartwatch, the Pixel Watch 2 remains an excellent choice for most folks, with a sophisticated design, snappy Wear OS performance, and seamless Fitbit integration. It's also currently 21% off at Amazon, weeks before Black Friday. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CCQFL1XV" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="d3fe4ae0-3e26-46e3-ac0c-955ef03dc783" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel Watch 2: $249.99" data-dimension48="Google Pixel Watch 2: $249.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="9545f782-1411-41a6-b6e5-f924eace5909" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel Tablet: $399" data-dimension48="Google Pixel Tablet: $399" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-tablet-11-android-tablet-128gb-wifi-hazel/6578698.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="Fa597SdtCGpg5MdQ2EdNpY" name="google-pixel-tablet-render-no-dock.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Fa597SdtCGpg5MdQ2EdNpY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1500" height="1500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Google Pixel Tablet: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-tablet-11-android-tablet-128gb-wifi-hazel/6578698.p" data-dimension112="9545f782-1411-41a6-b6e5-f924eace5909" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel Tablet: $399" data-dimension48="Google Pixel Tablet: $399"><del>$399</del><strong> $319 at Best Buy</strong></a></p>
<p>Perfect if you're already accustomed to the "Hey Google.." lifestyle, the Pixel Tablet comes with a vibrant 11-inch display, Tensor G2 chipset, and a reliable 7,020mAh battery. Grab the 128GB model (without the charging dock) from Best Buy today and you'll get a straight $80 off your purchase. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-tablet-11-android-tablet-128gb-wifi-hazel/6578698.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="9545f782-1411-41a6-b6e5-f924eace5909" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel Tablet: $399" data-dimension48="Google Pixel Tablet: $399">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="bc7efacd-b28b-41a3-ab3e-4bfe1c0ea779" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL 256GB: $1,249" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL 256GB: $1,249" href="https://www.att.com/buy/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-xl.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="sr66Lm9uCSgvS29MgezixS" name="pixel-9-pro-xl-bg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sr66Lm9uCSgvS29MgezixS.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Google Pixel 9 Pro XL 256GB: </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/buy/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-xl.html" data-dimension112="bc7efacd-b28b-41a3-ab3e-4bfe1c0ea779" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL 256GB: $1,249" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL 256GB: $1,249"><del>$1,249</del><strong> FREE with eligible line, trade-in at AT&T</strong></a></p>
<p>Google surprised everyone this year by adding an "XL" version of the Pro to its flagship lineup, but we're not complaining. The <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-review">Pixel 9 Pro XL</a> boasts a sizeable 6.8-inch 120Hz display with a 5,060mAh battery and the Tensor G4 chipset under the hood, plus you get seven years of software updates guaranteed.</p>
<p>Send any Pixel device to AT&T and add a line with a qualifying unlimited plan and the carrier will hook you up with enough promo credits to make this beast of performance totally free. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.att.com/buy/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-xl.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="bc7efacd-b28b-41a3-ab3e-4bfe1c0ea779" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL 256GB: $1,249" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL 256GB: $1,249">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="8549c9ac-76f1-4166-9a60-9eca2f41ba54" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 8a 128GB: $499" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 8a 128GB: $499" href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-8a-Unlocked-Advanced/dp/B0CYQFJSRF" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1422px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:136.29%;"><img id="LbsKCQsXPgXm2gRXKhkv8R" name="google-pixel-8a-render-front-and-back-bay.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LbsKCQsXPgXm2gRXKhkv8R.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1422" height="1938" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Google Pixel 8a 128GB: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-8a-Unlocked-Advanced/dp/B0CYQFJSRF" data-dimension112="8549c9ac-76f1-4166-9a60-9eca2f41ba54" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 8a 128GB: $499" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 8a 128GB: $499"><del>$499</del><strong> $449 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>Google's latest midrange masterpiece, the Pixel 8a features a flagship-quality camera with the same software promise and Tensor chipset found in the more-expensive Pixel 8 Pro. Grab the phone unlocked from Amazon right now and you'll score a straight $50 discount. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-8a-Unlocked-Advanced/dp/B0CYQFJSRF" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="8549c9ac-76f1-4166-9a60-9eca2f41ba54" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 8a 128GB: $499" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 8a 128GB: $499">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="02483b5e-ab1c-43d6-acea-87b32f99aad8" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$899" data-dimension48="$899" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-7-pro-128gb-unlocked-obsidian/6519915.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:806px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:124.57%;"><img id="CZrGk7amucRBU3dvnrwotG" name="google-pixel-7-pro-render-obsidian.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CZrGk7amucRBU3dvnrwotG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="806" height="1004" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Google Pixel 7 Pro 128GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-7-pro-128gb-unlocked-obsidian/6519915.p" data-dimension112="02483b5e-ab1c-43d6-acea-87b32f99aad8" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$899" data-dimension48="$899"><del>$899</del><strong> $449 w/ activation at Best Buy</strong></a></p>
<p>We once considered the Pixel 7 Pro to be the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phone</a> on the market, and while it's since been supplanted by newer devices, the Pro continues to hold its own in 2024 with outstanding cameras, an efficient Tensor G2 processor, and a large battery that easily lasts a day on a single charge. Buy the phone from Best Buy and activate through your carrier today and you'll enjoy a $450 discount. If you'd rather buy unlocked, you'll still be eligible to receive a sweet $350 off the Pixel 7 Pro. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-7-pro-128gb-unlocked-obsidian/6519915.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="02483b5e-ab1c-43d6-acea-87b32f99aad8" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$899" data-dimension48="$899">View Deal</a></p></div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Black Friday is coming up quick, here's what you need to know about finding Google Pixel deals during the big sales.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">3VBHuMcU94gWHi6y4ZkmNT</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vkCxR4Vu6CQxMomk26Y7z8.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 21:29:01 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vkCxR4Vu6CQxMomk26Y7z8.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold on Home Screen in-hand]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold on Home Screen in-hand]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Comcast's network suffers short-lived but major outage in pockets across the United States ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Comcast's home internet and cable networks experienced massive outages across the United States around 1 pm PT / 4pm ET on October 15.</li><li>Down Detector showed a spike in user complaints at the time, though they seem to be dying down.</li><li>We reached out to Comcast for comment; they responded that their team "is not seeing" the issue.</li></ul>
<p>Some Xfinity by Comcast customers experienced severe internet outages across the United States on Tuesday. While not every customer has been affected, we&apos;ve heard reports of lost or slow internet in many major U.S. hubs.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://downdetector.com/status/xfinity/" target="_blank">Downdetector</a> shows a spike in reports in the last hour, with 68% reporting "landline internet" issues. Some Android Central staffers have personally been affected, reporting problems with their home internet and cable TV; others still have internet and only experienced a brief outage earlier in the day. It may vary by location.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:710px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:62.54%;"><img id="e4m7qZzXDU2379Yfh3nvAJ" name="Comcast-outage-map.jpeg" alt="U.S. map showing Xfinity outages on October 15." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/e4m7qZzXDU2379Yfh3nvAJ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="710" height="444" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Down Detector)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Android Central reached out to Comcast asking for comment on the source of the outage and the timetable for when things will be fixed, as no Xfinity social media has commented on the outage. </p><p><strong>Update: </strong>An Xfinity rep told us that their team is "not seeing" an issue, though it&apos;s possible that the widespread issue was resolved before they <em>could</em> see anything. </p><p>It appears that things have improved since the initial spike in reports, but we&apos;re still seeing reports coming in on Down Detector — simply fewer than before. Some users have told us that their cable has returned but home internet is still down.</p><p>While we&apos;re grateful that the Xfinity issues didn&apos;t last long in most places, we&apos;re curious why they cropped up in the first place, and wish we could have gotten more information on the source of the problem. The Down Detector map showed complaints from New York and San Francisco to Seattle and Houston, but other major cities apparently weren&apos;t affected.</p><p>We also heard of sporadic reports of AT&T Fiber outages on Tuesday.</p><p>This outage arrived just a couple of weeks after the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/carriers/is-verizon-down-for-you-youre-not-alone">major Verizon outage</a> in late September. We wrote at the time that it highlighted the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/verizon-outage-hurricane-helene-showcase-importance-of-satellite-connectivity">importance of satellite backups</a> in case of cellular issues. In this case, the problem is mostly restricted to home internet.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/comcasts-network-has-collapsed-across-the-country-in-major-outage</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Xfinity internet service by Comcast is currently experiencing a major outage. Here's what we know about where it is and when it'll end. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">o82HaEpK8RFW5R6fo9h9hS</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VjV8EjSTCYd4tzAq2Qj6yX.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 21:04:34 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VjV8EjSTCYd4tzAq2Qj6yX.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Comcast]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Comcast official logo]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Comcast official logo]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>