<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 22:07:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ OnePlus 13 sharpens up its camera just in time for its global launch ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The OnePlus 13 has been updated with macro photography, letting you capture super close-ups.</li><li>Users can access the new macro feature by tapping the "little petal" icon in the camera app after updating.</li><li>The system update is rolling out in stages, with all devices expected to get it by November 17.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>The OnePlus 13, fresh off its Chinese launch, just got a new macro feature for its camera through a system update, letting you capture super close-up shots.</p><p>OnePlus announced on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://m.weibo.cn/detail/5100612069101992" target="_blank">Weibo</a> that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-13">OnePlus 13</a> users can now dive into macro photography (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.notebookcheck.net/OnePlus-13-gets-a-new-camera-feature-ahead-of-global-launch.918271.0.html" target="_blank">Notebookcheck</a>). This means users will be able to hit the “little petal” icon (a standard for macro cameras) in the camera app to start capturing all those tiny details.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-13-goes-official-in-china">Released in late October</a>, the OnePlus 13 packs a punch with a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/snapdragon-8-elite">Snapdragon 8 Elite</a> SoC, up to 24GB of RAM, and fast charging at 100W wired and 50W wireless—making it a strong contender in next year's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android smartphone</a> race.</p><p>OnePlus' latest flagship has been exclusive to China, but executives have confirmed a global launch is just around the corner. So, the new macro photography feature is a great addition ahead of its worldwide debut.</p><p>While the exact date for the phone's global unveiling is still under wraps, rumors hint at a January release, possibly alongside other OnePlus models, and likely at a higher price than its predecessor.</p><p>While there may be some regional differences, it’s set to impress on the software side.</p><p>The OnePlus 13, developed with Hasselblad, originally came with a triple-camera setup but didn’t support a macro camera feature. The latest update fixes that.</p><p>While the exact lens for macro shots isn’t specified, the OnePlus 13's Hasselblad-powered camera system packs a punch with a 50MP f/1.6 main sensor, a 50MP 3x telephoto lens, and a 50MP f/2.0 ultra-wide sensor. Plus, it has a 32MP selfie camera for top-notch self-portraits.</p><p>The update is rolling out in stages, with all compatible devices expected to get it by November 17. Users can check manually by going to <strong>Settings </strong>> <strong>System and Updates</strong> > <strong>Software Update</strong> or speed things up by selecting the "Apply for trial" option in the update settings.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-13-sharpens-up-its-camera-just-in-time-for-its-global-launch</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ OnePlus 13's latest update adds a super close-up camera mode. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">YS2CqBYbAukvEQ4rJ3ZoPR</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4QEnsjhSowEc2TZM3xYjhY.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 21:22:49 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4QEnsjhSowEc2TZM3xYjhY.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[OnePlus]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus 13]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus 13]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ T-Mobile seemingly kills the T-Mobile app in favor of T-Life ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>T-Mobile started making changes to its mobile apps in January 2024, rebranding the T-Mobile Tuesdays app as the T-Life app.</li><li>Soon, the T-Mobile app became a clone of the new T-Life app, leading to rumors that the carrier would shutter the original.</li><li>Now, the T-Mobile app is officially removed from the Play Store, and the T-Life app looks to be the future.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>T-Mobile's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/carriers/t-mobile-outage-november-12-2024">network went down earlier this week</a>, but now, its original T-Mobile app may be down for good. The app, which became a clone of the carrier's new T-Life app this summer, was recently unlisted from the Google Play Store (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://tmo.report/2024/11/the-t-mobile-app-is-finally-dead-time-to-start-your-t-life/" target="_blank">The Mobile Report</a>). While it still appears to be working for users, it's not available for new downloads, and it's unclear how long the T-Mobile app will remain functional.</p><p>The "un-carrier" has slowly made sweeping changes to its mobile apps throughout the year. In January 2024, it rebranded the T-Mobile Tuesdays app — originally the place for rewards and promotions — to T-Life. Eventually, more features and functionality came to the T-Life app, including account management and chat support.</p><p>This summer, the T-Mobile app was essentially a duplicate version of the T-Life app. The two applications even shared the same logo. The carrier began marketing the T-Life app as the new "everything app" for the company, and sent emails to some customers that pushed them to switch. As such, it seemed like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/carriers/t-mobile">T-Mobile</a> was moving away from the original app that first launched in 2012.</p><p>Now that the T-Mobile app is unavailable for download, it would appear that the transition is now complete. T-Mobile USA currently has <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/developer?id=T-Mobile+USA" target="_blank">22 apps on the Google Play Store</a>, but the original is not one of them. The app's most recent update came earlier this month, although it's unclear whether it'll receive any more updates — or when the app might stop working entirely.</p><p>Android Central has reached out to T-Mobile about the future of the T-Mobile app, and we will update this story when we hear back.</p><p>For now, it may be finally time to switch to the T-Life app if you use a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-t-mobile-phones">T-Mobile phone</a> and haven't already. All signs point to the former T-Mobile Tuesdays app becoming the so-called "everything app" for the company.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/carriers/t-mobile-officially-kills-the-t-mobile-app-in-favor-of-t-life</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ T-Mobile has seemingly gone all-in on the T-Life app, as the original T-Mobile app is now unavailable. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">gafhMW3kWnM56DFsxhZz2n</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/du63zwPBbYBDFHWBTnwQEF.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 21:14:47 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Carriers]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/du63zwPBbYBDFHWBTnwQEF.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The T-Mobile Logo on a Google Pixel 8 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The T-Mobile Logo on a Google Pixel 8 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Photos drops Partner Sharing support for photos from other Android apps ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>In a recent change, Partner Sharing in the Google Photos app no longer supports photos that originated from a third-party Android app.</li><li>Google confirmed the shift in an update to a support document made sometime in the last month.</li><li>The change seems to also affect unedited screenshots, and Google didn't explain why Partner Sharing now works differently.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Users picked up on a major change to the way Partner Sharing works in Google Photos this month, and now Google confirmed the shift in an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/photos/answer/7378858?hl=en" target="_blank">updated support document</a>. Partner Sharing will no longer automatically share photos that come from "other apps on Android," according to the document. The confirmation was first spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://techissuestoday.com/google-photos-android-share-photos-from-other-apps-with-partner-account/" target="_blank">TechIssuesToday</a>, which noted that the support document was updated sometime in the last month based on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20241008002627/https://support.google.com/photos/answer/7378858" target="_blank">Wayback Machine archives</a>.</p><p>Partner Sharing is a convenient, and automatic, way to share photos with someone you trust, like a family member or significant other. Using this feature, you can choose which photos are automatically shared with your partner. For example, photos can be shared if they include a specific person, or were taken after a specific date.</p><p>Additionally, you can share all photos with a partner if you'd like. Since the feature was introduced in 2017, the <strong>All Photos</strong> option really included every photo, but there are new limitations. Now, there's a disclaimer in the Partner Sharing support document reading: "Tip: Photos from other apps on Android aren't shared with your partner account."</p><p>Reddit users spotted the change about two weeks ago, discovering that certain metadata determines whether a photo is shared or not. Downloads, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-use-the-pixel-screenshots-app-on-the-google-pixel-9">screenshots</a>, and photos from other Android apps won't be sent to another person with Partner Sharing.</p><p>This doesn't change if you alter the photo's origin in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-photos">Google Photos app</a>, like removing the "screenshot" badge. However, screenshots will be sent through Partner Sharing if they've been edited in Google Photos.</p>
<blockquote class="reddit-card"  ><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/googlephotos/comments/1gjyasy/screenshots_not_sharing_through_partner_share">Screenshots not sharing through Partner Share</a> from <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/googlephotos">r/googlephotos</a></blockquote><script async src="//embed.redditmedia.com/widgets/platform.js" charset="UTF-8"></script>
<p>Google hasn't shared the reasoning behind the changes to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-share-your-library-google-photos">Partner Sharing</a>. The move could be to protect user privacy, as some users might want to share their photos but not their downloads, screenshots, or pictures from other apps. With that being said, there are already ways to customize which photos are shared with Partner Sharing, so it's puzzling that Google doesn't give users the option to share photos originating from other apps.</p><p>At the moment, it does not appear that Google is communicating this change directly to users in the Photos app. Though a new <strong>Updates</strong> page in the Photos app now exists for changes like this, Partner Sharing users apparently haven't received a message.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-photos-drops-partner-sharing-support-for-photos-from-other-android-apps</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Partner Sharing lets you instantly share your Google Photos library with someone else, but now it won't work with external photos. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">g6PFRA6HiAuUCoHZ2ExX3R</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/79P3D9KKfz7VCaxGJLh3q7.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 20:27:53 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/79P3D9KKfz7VCaxGJLh3q7.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Photos library tab showing its logo above the favorites and utilities buttons]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Photos library tab showing its logo above the favorites and utilities buttons]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google knows it has a Private Space issue with Wear OS, but there's no fix yet ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google published a new support page to inform users of an ongoing problem between Android 15's Private Space and Wear OS watches.</li><li>Users have reportedly received notifications from apps they've stored within Private Space, which isn't how the feature should function.</li><li>Google recently resumed its Wear OS Pixel Watch updates this week after Wear OS 5 caused devices to seize up.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google's major 2024 Android OS release features enhanced privacy, but the company is aware of a glaring problem.</p><p>The company published <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/wearos/answer/15597337">a support page</a> with information regarding the recently surfaced Private Spaces issues with Wear OS (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/11/13/android-15-private-space-wear-os/">9to5Google</a>). Google reiterates that Private Spaces are meant to hide apps that you don't want others to see. However, it notes that some users with a Wear OS device <em>paired with </em>a Private Space-enabled Android phone are receiving notifications.</p><p>The post states users with a Wear OS watch set up to receive "bridged notifications" face this problem.</p><p>Naturally, such devices are not supposed to receive notifications from apps placed within a Private Space. Google states users might receive an alert from an app if their "private space is unlocked on your phone." Moreover, these notifications could appear with a "work profile" icon even if you don't have a profile on your smartphone.</p><p>Google's highlight post lacks information regarding a potential fix for Wear OS devices and Android 15's Private Spaces. The publication assumes a fix <em>could </em>arrive with a future Wear OS or Android 15 patch. At this time, Google hasn't detailed a fix, meaning another may appear later.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="qcz5qgF2N9bL7o9zBqS9M4" name="Google-Pixel-9-review-08.jpg" alt="The Pixel 9 with the Pixel Watch 2 on top" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qcz5qgF2N9bL7o9zBqS9M4.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>During Android 15's launch, one of the major features highlighted was Google's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-create-private-space-for-your-apps-on-pixel">Private Space</a>. The feature functions like a "digital vault," storing away your sensitive apps that you'd prefer no one else see. Private Space is useful for keeping apps like banking and health separate from the rest of your device. Users can secure the space with a PIN or fingerprint, similar to how you'd lock your phone.</p><p>Unfortunately, Wear OS devices are experiencing a disconnect that defeats the purpose behind hiding these apps in a "private space."</p><p>It's unclear if we are waiting for an update to fix this issue. Google <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/wear-os-5-rollout-resumes-for-all-pixel-watch-models-but-theres-a-caveat">resumed its Wear OS updates</a> for the Pixel Watch this week after taking a break to correct a severe software problem. The latest Wear OS 5 upgrade caused several watches to seize up and stop all (proper) functionality.</p><p>More importantly, that update post featured an advisory: the next major OS update won't arrive until March 2025. While that'll be a lengthy wait, hopefully, we won't have to wait that long for a fix for Android 15's Private Space.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-private-space-wear-os-problems</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google detailed an issue between Android 15's Private Space and Wear OS devices. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">gzrciXitDwWduwFNG4raS6</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/R3Mk6dJu8qh9PLboKDFfiF.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 20:18:32 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/R3Mk6dJu8qh9PLboKDFfiF.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Looking through a Pixel 9 Pro XL Thinborne case at an Android 15 logo on a Pixel 8 Pro&#039;s display]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Looking through a Pixel 9 Pro XL Thinborne case at an Android 15 logo on a Pixel 8 Pro&#039;s display]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Sweet! Amazon's Fire HD 10 tablet is nearly HALF OFF for Black Friday ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Black Friday</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Black Friday Google Pixel deals<br></a>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Black Friday Motorola deals<br></a>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024-early-deals-and-how-to-prepare-for-the-big-sales">Black Friday Samsung deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Black Friday OnePlus deals</a></p></div></div>
<p>Amazon has already launched its first wave of Black Friday deals, including a huge <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Amazon_Fire_HD_10/dp/B0BHZT5S12" target="_blank"><strong>46% off the Amazon Fire HD 10 tablet</strong></a>—so long as you don't mind lockscreen ads.</p><p>This tablet is a great pick for casual users with its decent-looking 10.1-inch HD display, 32GB or 64GB of storage, and a price tag low enough to make justifying your purchase easy. It also features up to 13 hours of battery life, along with dual stereo speakers, Dolby Atmos, and a useful headphone jack that some tablets today don't include.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="49746084-18f5-4253-ad88-c3b2c3ce6e6f" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Amazon Fire HD 10 (2023):" data-dimension48="Amazon Fire HD 10 (2023):" href="https://www.amazon.com/Amazon_Fire_HD_10/dp/B0BHZT5S12" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:876px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:63.13%;"><img id="PoXpg5LKEFPAjy2mxUvEEd" name="amazon-fire-hd-10-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PoXpg5LKEFPAjy2mxUvEEd.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="876" height="553" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Amazon Fire HD 10 (2023):</strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Amazon_Fire_HD_10/dp/B0BHZT5S12" target="_blank" data-dimension112="49746084-18f5-4253-ad88-c3b2c3ce6e6f" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Amazon Fire HD 10 (2023):" data-dimension48="Amazon Fire HD 10 (2023):" data-dimension25=""> <del>$139.99</del> <strong>$74.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p><p>Amazon has launched an early Black Friday discount of almost half off the Fire HD 10 tablet, which is our top pick for the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-kindle-fire-tablet#section-best-tablet-for-sharing">best Amazon tablet to share</a> because of its somewhat large screen.</p><p>The Amazon Fire HD 10 is nothing too special, especially with the Fire HD 11 coming out last year, but it will certainly get the job done. </p><p>You can expect to get up to 13 hours of battery life with the Fire HD 10, along with either 32GB or 64GB of storage. Black Friday discounts are currently being applied to both storage configurations, though not to the version without lockscreen ads. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/Amazon_Fire_HD_10/dp/B0BHZT5S12" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="49746084-18f5-4253-ad88-c3b2c3ce6e6f" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Amazon Fire HD 10 (2023):" data-dimension48="Amazon Fire HD 10 (2023):" data-dimension25="">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>you're looking for something with a long battery life; you don't mind lockscreen ads and just want one of the most affordable tablets there is; you don't expect to need a lot of storage.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>you don't want a tablet with lockscreen advertisements; tablets with a good suite of cameras are a priority for you; you'd rather go with a lighter tablet.</p><p>The 2023 Amazon Fire HD 10 tablet is a great little companion, especially at such a low price point. Users love it for its roughly 13 hours of battery life, its 10.1-inch display, and its ease of use for gaming, video streaming,, and more.</p><p>This particular configuration comes with lockscreen ads, and unfortunately, there isn't a deal available for the non-ad version. Still, both the 32GB and 64GB storage options are around half off right now, making these Fire tablets a great deal compared to their usual price point. Storage can also be expanded up to 1TB with the included microSD port.</p><p>It's worth noting that the Fire HD 10 isn't a lightweight tablet, so if this is something that bothers you, it might be worth looking at other options. For those looking to upgrade, it also may be worth considering the slightly larger and better Fire HD 11 tablet, which was launched last year as a more powerful offering from the company.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/sweet-amazons-fire-hd-10-tablet-is-nearly-half-off-for-black-friday</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A capable Amazon tablet with Black Friday pricing. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">ZTtLPCbp5KRLtHAz8oVqrF</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/foNFDLZDvXLsFbbmWoJ3m9.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 19:45:02 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ zacharydvisconti@gmail.com (Zachary Visconti) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/foNFDLZDvXLsFbbmWoJ3m9.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Amazon Fire HD 10 on a wooden table]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Amazon Fire HD 10 on a wooden table]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Years later, Spotify still says it's working on 'Super Premium' with lossless audio ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Spotify announced plans to offer high-fidelity audio to subscribers way back in 2021.</li><li>According to the company's CEO on a recent earnings call, Spotify is still working on delivering lossless audio.</li><li>Unlike the streamer's competitors, Spotify will ask subscribers to pay more for Hi-Fi as part of a "Super Premium" plan.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/spotify">Spotify</a>, the largest music streaming service in the world, is still running into roadblocks that its competitors passed years ago. On an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/q3-2024-spotify-technology-sa-121935633.html" target="_blank">earnings call</a> recapping the company's third-quarter 2024 financial results, Spotify CEO Daniel Ek reaffirmed that lossless audio is still coming, but didn't provide an exact timeline. The higher-quality subscription tier was first announced in 2021, and has faced significant delays since.</p><p>Tidal, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/apple-music-youtube-music-playlist-transfer">Apple Music</a>, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/amazon-music">Amazon Music</a> already offer high-fidelity audio to subscribers as part of their standard subscription tiers. However, Spotify wants its subscribers to pay extra for the luxury, despite being extremely behind in the lossless audio game. The upgraded tier became known as "Super Premium," and recent comments from Ek suggest this subscription could cost as much as $5 more than Premium.</p><p>Aside from lossless quality, Spotify's boss says that Super Premium will include “a bunch of other things.” More importantly, Ek thinks that Spotify users will pay extra for a Super Premium subscription because, well, they love Spotify.</p><p>"The principle for us is always the same, which is how do we create something that consumers love, but that also delivers value back to creators," Ek said on the earnings call. "And you can go back to vinyl buyers, you can go back to all of these superfans that already exist to look for clues in what some of the things are that they value."</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1999px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="N8YDEEixyqyFevodQ3Ni8L" name="Spotify-hero-android.jpg" alt="Spotify logo on an Android phone" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/N8YDEEixyqyFevodQ3Ni8L.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1999" height="1124" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Despite the delays to CD-quality audio, Spotify is growing beyond its internal projections. The company reported having 640 million monthly active users as of Q3 2024, and revenue up 19% year-over-year. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/spotify">Spotify</a> stock trended upward following the earning's call and financial release, but the Super Premium tier remains a question mark for the company. Can it deliver high-fidelity audio to subscribers, and are there enough Spotify users willing to pay a premium for it?</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/years-later-spotify-still-says-its-working-on-super-premium-with-lossless-audio</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Spotify wants you to pay more for features that are already included by its competitors. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">icTgMsHqEM9YSc74P8qcvQ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WmnvJ73Rpc4DnYjGjRXFhe.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 19:22:29 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WmnvJ73Rpc4DnYjGjRXFhe.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Spotify on the Z Flip 3 and Z Fold 3 with headphones and earbuds next to them]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Spotify on the Z Flip 3 and Z Fold 3 with headphones and earbuds next to them]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung's alleged 'double-folding' phone could feature an inward mechanic ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A report claims Samsung has added a "double-folding phone" to its development plans, which could fold "inward" for durability.</li><li>The phone is suspected to launch with a nine to 10-inch display when unfolded, similar to Huawei's Mate XT.</li><li>A report from September claimed Samsung was moving toward its rollable phone concept shown during CES 2024.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Rumors of a tri-fold or "double-folding" Galaxy device return as a report claims Samsung is rethinking such a device.</p><p>A report by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.etnews.com/20241114000332">ETNews</a> claims Samsung "recently added a double-folding phone to its development lineup" (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/samsung-double-folding-phone-launch-next-year-3499641/">Android Authority</a>). Huawei's release of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/huawei-mate-xt-ultimate-design-launch">the Mate XT</a> is likely a strong catalyst for Samsung as it seeks to debut a similar device. The publication's report states that the Korean OEM's version could fold "inward."</p><p>An alleged insider claims this is done to improve its durability as folding outward would make the phone "vulnerable to drops and impacts."</p><p>Rumors purport its specifications, claiming this double-folding device could offer a display size of nine to 10 inches when fully open. Supposedly, the device will remain similar in size to a "regular" slab phone when collapsed. This seems plausible as the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Galaxy Z Fold 6</a> looks like a regular smartphone when closed, but fully expanding it gives it more of a tablet vibe.</p><p>With this report, the publication's source claims that Samsung's partners "have also begun development projects." Additionally, the company is rumored to have the "release model finalized" by the end of November.</p><p>The post states Samsung could debut this double-folding/"multifold" device in 2025. Allegedly, the company may slip this phone in alongside its annual launch of the Flip and Fold series.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="3EYFwuprUs7PqrG6M32Nif" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Z-Flip-6-flex.jpg" alt="The Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 6 main display folded" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3EYFwuprUs7PqrG6M32Nif.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nick Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>This report goes against Samsung's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-rollable-phone-pursuit-alleged-report">rumored course of action</a> following the Mate XT's launch. In September, rumors claimed the Korean OEM was distancing itself from a device with two hinges in favor of its previously showcased <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-display-foldable-rollable-tech-concepts-ces-2024">rollable concept</a>. The company had filed patents for a tri-fold device in South Korea and the U.S., but the device never came to fruition.</p><p>Speculation suggested the device could arrive with a 12.4-inch display when "rolled out" completely. It was also rumored to feature an under-display selfie camera.</p><p>The report also highlighted Samsung's displeasure with its recent Flip 6 and Fold 6 devices. Those phones had fallen "short of expectations," likely pushing the company to seek other avenues.</p><p>With rumors going back on previous reports, it's best to take this speculation with a grain of salt.</p>
<ul><li> <strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://shop-links.co/link?id=pcmcat1563302848653&publisher_slug=future&exclusive=1&u1=ac-us-4877659664571064743&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Ftop-deals%2Fcell-phone-deals%2Fpcmcat1563302848653.c%3Fid%3Dpcmcat1563302848653&article_name=Samsung%20allegedly%20pursues%20world%27s%20first%20rollable%20following%20Huawei%20tri-fold%20surprise%20%7C%20Android%20Central&article_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.androidcentral.com%2Fphones%2Fsamsung-rollable-phone-pursuit-alleged-report" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1943169/565706/9383?subId1=ac-us-1765500805636878076&sharedId=ac-us&u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fcp%2Fcell-phones%2F1105910%3Fpovid%3Dweb_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://shop-links.co/link?publisher_slug=future&exclusive=1&u1=ac-us-8607079121525878536&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.samsung.com%2Fus%2Fshop%2Fall-deals%2Fcell-phone-deals%2F&article_name=Samsung%20allegedly%20pursues%20world%27s%20first%20rollable%20following%20Huawei%20tri-fold%20surprise%20%7C%20Android%20Central&article_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.androidcentral.com%2Fphones%2Fsamsung-rollable-phone-pursuit-alleged-report" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://target.georiot.com/Proxy.ashx?tsid=169923&GR_URL=https%3A%2F%2Famazon.com%2Fs%3Fk%3Dcell%2Bphone%26crid%3D19CKV7OMEPEMF%26sprefix%3Dcell%2Bphone%252Caps%252C222%26ref%3Dnb_sb_noss_1%26tag%3Dhawk-future-20%26ascsubtag%3Dac-us-5701298781318185433-20" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-100048248-15733793?sid=ac-us-4719302212315575514&url=https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-100048248-15735111?sid=ac-us-1029848184206697789&url=https://www.att.com/" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-double-folding-phone-development-rumor</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A new report claimed Samsung is moving ahead with a "double-folding" device. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">JpxF6Kx3zsdnj5zy3NKDL8</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/U7ci7G9gqtLnMu6gFp796X.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 19:16:55 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/U7ci7G9gqtLnMu6gFp796X.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 with fountain behind]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 with fountain behind]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Samsung Galaxy S25 will be exclusively powered by Snapdragon 8 Elite, leaker claims ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-32">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Typically, Samsung uses a combination of Qualcomm Snapdragon chips and its own Exynos chips.</li><li>A leaker with a reliable track record claims that the entire Galaxy S25 lineup will be powered by Snapdragon 8 Elite, in all markets.</li><li>If true, the Galaxy S25 would only be the third Galaxy S lineup to be exclusively powered by a Qualcomm system-on-a-chip.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Samsung often sells its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">flagship phones</a> with different processors, depending on your region. For example, some versions of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24">Samsung Galaxy S24 series</a> shipped with Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 systems-on-a-chip (SoCs), while others featured the Exynos 2400. This comes with benefits and drawbacks: Snapdragon phones are typically faster, while Exynos handsets are more efficient. Looking ahead to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25">Galaxy S25</a> lineup, one reliable leaker claims that all phones will be Snapdragon-powered, in all markets.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/UniverseIce/status/1856677902869516626" target="_blank">Ice Universe</a>, a leaker with a solid track record on all things Samsung, reiterated their position in a post on X (formerly Twitter). The tipster predicts that every Galaxy S25 model worldwide will have Qualcomm's Snapdragon 8 Elite on the inside, the company's newest SoC.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I reiterate that all versions of the Galaxy S25 series in the world adopt Snapdragon 8 Elite, and will not adopt Exynos.<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1856677902869516626">November 13, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>Snapdragon chips usually beat their Exynos counterparts in performance, but that disparity could be even greater in 2025. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/snapdragon-8-elite">Snapdragon 8 Elite</a> uses Qualcomm's custom Oryon cores, which helped the chipmaker find immense success with its Snapdragon X lineup of laptop-class processors. That, plus prior reports of low yield rates for Samsung's Exynos processors, could explain why the Korean tech giant is going all-in on Snapdragon.</p><p>One <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.hankyung.com/amp/2024101722011" target="_blank">report</a> out of Korea last month said that low yield rates for the Exynos 2500 chipset, expected to power some Galaxy S25 models, forced Samsung to change its plans. Another, more recent <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.newsway.co.kr/news/view?ud=2024110612112748553" target="_blank">report</a> suggests that Samsung Foundry's yield woes haven't improved since then. It claimed Samsung's yield rate for 3nm chips was less than 20%, which is an unsustainable figure.</p><p>Combined, all these rumors and reports point to Ice Universe's claim that the Galaxy S25 will be exclusively Snapdragon-powered being correct. If true, it would only be the third time Samsung didn't use an Exynos chip in a Galaxy S lineup in at least some regions. The last time that happened was when the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s23-review">Galaxy S23</a> series launched with only the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 for Galaxy platform.</p><p>However, the Samsung Galaxy S25 lineup being exclusively powered by Qualcomm's Snapdragon 8 Elite might come with pros and cons. Though the chipset looks to be plenty fast, it's more expensive than its predecessor, leading some to believe the Galaxy S25 could launch with a price hike.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-samsung-galaxy-s25-will-be-exclusively-powered-by-snapdragon-8-elite-leaker-claims</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ If you thought the Samsung Galaxy S25 might be powered by Exynos silicon in your region, this leak might be a pleasant surprise.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">PApidLmQ4mnub3AJuuaAKP</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QQxJUB8kzYcB6dkJT9yBBi.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 18:32:12 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QQxJUB8kzYcB6dkJT9yBBi.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Hands-on with the smaller Samsung Galaxy S24]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Hands-on with the smaller Samsung Galaxy S24]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Dig VR with a Roto Chair is insane ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">AC thVRsday</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="LGmZZrc8DWcxmZm6RRUYbC" name="ac-thvrsday-logo.jpg" caption="" alt="AC thVRsday logo" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LGmZZrc8DWcxmZm6RRUYbC.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">In his <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/ac-thvrsday">weekly column</a>, Android Central Senior Content Producer Nick Sutrich delves into all things VR, from new hardware to new games, upcoming technologies, and so much more.</p></div></div>
<p>One of the things I love most about the Meta Quest platform is its simplicity. It's a console, so the only thing I need to do to play games is put it on my head and start the game. So, it's not often that I try out crazy accessories that add layers of complexity to the experience.</p><p>But the Roto VR Explorer chair is the coolest gaming chair I've ever used and is especially helpful if you suffer from motion sickness when playing VR games. Despite being a veteran VR gamer for the last decade, "smooth turning" in VR games still makes me feel woozy and dizzy, but the Roto VR Explorer chair fixed all that.</p><p>Roto VR Explorer is a made-for-Meta Quest chair that rotates when you turn your head, recreating the feeling of inertia that takes place in your inner ears when you physically move around in real life. It works with all <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-meta-quest-games">Meta Quest games</a> but has special integrations in games like Dig VR. It's pricey at $800, no doubt, but I've never used a piece of immersive equipment that's this easy.</p>

<h2 id="digging-with-authenticity-2">Digging with authenticity</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="DfAYDMzjurwJorCn9omig" name="dig-vr-official-screenshot-01" alt="An official screenshot of Dig VR for Meta Quest 3 showing a yellow digger piling dirt on a tarp" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DfAYDMzjurwJorCn9omig.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Dig VR launches today, November 14, and brings about authentic heavy machinery simulation with a mission structure similar to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/why-are-chores-more-fun-in-vr">Power Wash Simulator</a> or Lawn Mowing Simulator, plus plenty of minigames to keep things fresh.</p><p>Part of the authenticity, at least in my case, is playing the game while sitting in the Roto VR Explorer chair, which wirelessly connects to Dig VR to rotate and vibrate along with the machinery I'm using. It creates one of those all-important moments of immersion that you can only get in VR.</p><p>There's just something ridiculously cool about being in a simulator that moves and shakes at a theme park or arcade, but something even better about it being in your own house. When I moved the digger and felt the chair realistically jerk and turn along with the machinery, I knew I had found something special.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VU2DxXE2HNE" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>Dig VR's controls allow you to use the controller in a more traditional video game way, using dual joysticks to move the rig around and control the boom arm for digging, or opt for the full simulator approach and grab the physical controls inside the cockpit.</p><p>The two levers in the middle move the individual treads underneath the digger, letting you move it around in any direction you want. The top section of the digger is mechanically separate from the bottom portion where the treads are, so you have separate joysticks that can be grabbed and tilted in any direction to spin the cockpit and move the boom arm.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="5ffa25d9-f783-4785-aabf-6de962a72ca3" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Buy now at Meta Horizon store" data-dimension48="Buy now at Meta Horizon store" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1024px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="d9ErC6trJfNNrbiG4TPryP" name="dig-vr-logo" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/d9ErC6trJfNNrbiG4TPryP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1024" height="1024" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>Dig VR is the ultimate digging simulator! Build your business in the town of Diglington, earning money to get bigger and badder diggers so you can complete bigger and badder jobs. Plenty of humor keeps things like, and both casual and serious players will find a home with a myriad of control schemes and options.</p><p><strong>Buy now at </strong><a href="https://www.meta.com/experiences/dig-vr/6128709557192619/" data-dimension112="5ffa25d9-f783-4785-aabf-6de962a72ca3" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Buy now at Meta Horizon store" data-dimension48="Buy now at Meta Horizon store" data-dimension25="">Meta Horizon store</a></p></div>
<p>I'm not usually super into simulation games, but the feeling of authenticity I got from controlling this big digger while sitting in the Roto chair convinced me that I ought to try them more often. I'd need to be in the mood to do so — this game is simulating a job that people usually get paid to do, after all — but carving out my own business in the quaint town of Diglington was surprisingly enjoyable, especially with the Roto chair.</p><p>Of course, if you don't have the chair or don't want to spend the money on it, Dig VR is still a lot of fun and has options to significantly simplify the control scheme to minimize frustration. My son preferred using the joysticks on the controllers, for instance, while I found that locking in-game controls to just wrist rotation made it easiest for me to control the diggers.</p><p>The game has over 70 different customization options for each digger, and you'll get new diggers and tool heads throughout your time in the career mode. If you're not feeling the scored mode, there's also a zen sandbox mode for each level that lets you dig to your heart's content.</p><p>It even has multiplayer, so you can dig in while chatting with friends. Sometimes, you just need a fun activity to get the good conversation flowing, and Dig VR is a strangely ideal way to do this.</p>
<h2 id="i-ve-never-used-a-gaming-chair-like-this-one-2">I've never used a gaming chair like this one</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="VSjPgeTu5LWXQ2JfQabe49" name="roto-vr-explorer-with-a-meta-quest-3-in-the-chair-03" alt="A Meta Quest 3 in a Roto VR Explorer chair" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VSjPgeTu5LWXQ2JfQabe49.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Roto VR Explorer chair, as you might imagine, given its price, isn't just made for Dig VR. Rather, it works with <em>any</em> Meta Quest game. Better yet, there's no configuration involved to get playing. Just attach the Pokeball-looking puck somewhere on your Quest — I found sliding it on the top strap to work best — and turn your head to turn the chair.</p><p>You don't even need to plug anything in since it's totally wireless and operates independently from your Quest. I had actually assumed a manual or some instruction was left out of the box because this felt overly simple! Even the puck is wirelessly charged when placed in the cradle in the base of the chair, ensuring it's both charged and paired with the chair automatically.</p><p>The puck can be connected to your headset via the 3.5mm audio jack to enable rumble, but I've found that I don't care much for haptic motors that use sound to create the effect. It's too reliant on a game's sound effects working perfectly with the speaker and you almost always have to turn music completely off which just kills the vibe for me.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="LrB9ycSuwpSgrFukn8Af29" name="roto-vr-explorer-puck-on-a-meta-quest-3" alt="A Meta Quest 3 with a Roto VR Explorer head tracking puck" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LrB9ycSuwpSgrFukn8Af29.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>That little puck will automatically pair with any <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-earbuds">Bluetooth earbuds or headphones</a>, something that's not usually possible with VR since Bluetooth products have added latency. I used the crazy affordable <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/nothing-cmf-buds-pro-2-announced">CMF Buds Pro 2</a> to test because they have a built-in audio dial on the case.</p><p>While I didn't care for the sound-driven haptics very much, a game like Dig VR with its native integration — just hit "connect to Roto VR Explorer" in the game's menu — will more intelligently use this haptic motor without the extra unneeded vibration that comes from the sound-driven implementation.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="jSVzdrCXyN73g9hm6i3Me8" name="roto-vr-explorer-unboxing" alt="All the pieces in the box of the Roto VR Explorer prior to assembly" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jSVzdrCXyN73g9hm6i3Me8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The chair itself is expertly crafted and well-made, with strong metal parts and connectors that won't bend. Putting it together is a bit like assembling something from IKEA, although it'll take you less time if you're not an idiot like me, who apparently can't read directions.</p><p>A port on the swivel cylinder underneath the chair magnetically connects to the haptic motor, and there's even an ingenious USB-C port on it so you can charge your Quest while you play. This is situated on the back of the column and moves with the chair to ensure you don't get tangled in it.</p><p>The cushions on the chair and back are all quite firm, so they should hold up well over time. The material used to cover the pads is also easily cleanable if you sweat a lot while playing.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="kDkT3eoG2V7LXvEHyTTzy8" name="roto-vr-explorer-haptic-motor-and-chair-back" alt="The strong metal back of the Roto VR Explorer chair and the haptic motor underneath" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kDkT3eoG2V7LXvEHyTTzy8.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="dozNFv2yWGNpSAWz3rXY29" name="roto-vr-explorer-with-a-meta-quest-3-in-the-chair-04" alt="A Meta Quest 3 in a Roto VR Explorer chair" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dozNFv2yWGNpSAWz3rXY29.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="fyRLLeUVDZkymfuvaB4Lz8" name="roto-vr-explorer-made-for-meta" alt="The strong metal back of the Roto VR Explorer chair and the Made for Meta sticker" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fyRLLeUVDZkymfuvaB4Lz8.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 4 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="6XAaMvF2DR3ycSBLcqgLz8" name="roto-vr-explorer-with-a-meta-quest-3-in-the-chair-02" alt="A Meta Quest 3 in a Roto VR Explorer chair" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6XAaMvF2DR3ycSBLcqgLz8.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 5 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="uh6FvJ4SGgtTb7EZv9Wi59" name="roto-vr-explorer-with-a-meta-quest-3-in-the-chair-01" alt="A Meta Quest 3 in a Roto VR Explorer chair" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uh6FvJ4SGgtTb7EZv9Wi59.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>While all of this is very cool, the most important part of the chair is the fact that the physical movement completely fixed the dizziness I feel when using smooth turning in VR. While I've always used snap-turning in VR games to mitigate this issue, smooth turning is far more immersive especially when paired with natural head movements.</p><p>In fact, the Roto VR Explorer worked perfectly with every game I tried. Racing games with smooth turning, like EXO Cars, or even other simulators like Lawn Mowing Simulator, work <em>incredibly</em> well for different reasons.</p><p>EXO Cars is a fast-paced racing game that would usually make me feel a bit dizzy, but the subtle movement the chair makes when turning my head to anticipate turning the car mimics real inertia enough to make it feel comfortable. Lawn Mowing Simulator is much slower but still feels great in the chair for the same reason EXO Cars does.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/acaBo9zV5i4" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>But what about games that don't have you riding in vehicles? Those all work perfectly with the chair, too!</p><p>While I only made a video of me playing <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/batman-arkham-shadow-review">Batman Arkham Shadow</a>, I also played several other games including <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/metro-awakening-review">Metro Awakening</a>, Medieval Dynasty, and even Blade and Sorcery to test out the stability of the chair and its ability to quickly move around.</p><p>What I found was that this is significantly better than any old swivel chair for a number of reasons. First, the heavy steel design ensures the chair stays put even on carpet. There are also wheel locks to keep it in place for other surfaces. If you happen to tip the chair a little bit, an alarm will sound, so you know you need to calm down a bit. I only ever heard this alarm when sitting down in the chair, though.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GP7gYu4a7V4" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>Second, it moves where you look. This meant I stopped using the right stick to artificially turn and, instead, treated movement in the chair more like I was standing. The difference, of course, is that I wasn't using the lower half of my body at all. This is great for folks who need to remain seated for any physical reason or just want to have a more relaxing session.</p><p>Ironically, I found that I enjoyed playing Metro Awakening better while seated in this chair because it eliminated the feeling that I needed to stay physically crouched while sneaking around in the game. Sure, I could use the game's virtual crouch by clicking the thumbstick but where's the fun in that?</p><p>It might be expensive but I've been thoroughly impressed with the Roto VR Explorer chair. It's more than just a boring old swivel chair as it provides the necessary inertial movement to combat motion sickness. You could use your legs to move a swivel chair around but it doesn't register in your brain the same way and it's a lot more work. Might as well just stand if you're going to do this, in my opinion.</p><p>Overall, this chair is incredibly impressive and did exactly what it was designed to do: completely eliminate motion sickness in VR.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="45023869-9aed-4f88-9a28-23697310b617">
            <a href="https://www.rotovr.com/products/roto-vr-explorer" data-model-name="Roto VR Explorer"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.94%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CTfVYzBk6L2GDwUrAKWhNC.jpg' alt="An official render of the Roto VR Explorer gaming chair"></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Roto VR Explorer</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>The ultimate gaming chair is here! The Roto VR Explorer turns with your head to give you full immersion in VR games, eliminating motion sickness and keeping you comfortable for hours. It will even charge your Quest 3 while playing, too!</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/dig-vr-with-roto-chair</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Simulation games on the Meta Quest 3 just hit an all-time high thanks to Dig VR and the Roto VR Explorer chair. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Jpn4jA2VfHBrPnPSdry66b</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/A9LMyr8da82wqNXqfAZtiK.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 18:27:17 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/A9LMyr8da82wqNXqfAZtiK.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Sitting on a Roto VR Explorer chair wearing a Meta Quest 3 playing Dig VR. Grassy field generated by AI. Excavator provided by Adobe Stock.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Sitting on a Roto VR Explorer chair wearing a Meta Quest 3 playing Dig VR. Grassy field generated by AI. Excavator provided by Adobe Stock.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ WhatsApp 'message drafts' are the missing piece Meta is finally rolling out ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-37">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Meta announced that WhatsApp users can expect to see "Message Drafts" roll out on mobile devices today (Nov 14).</li><li>This update will save unfinished/unsent texts in a thread alongside displaying a "Draft" indicator at the top of your Chats view.</li><li>WhatsApp recently rolled out customized Lists and teased the upcoming departure from phone numbers on the platform.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Meta is rolling out an update for WhatsApp, and this feature could be one you've been hoping for.</p><p>According to a press release, the company is launching "Message Drafts" for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/whatsapp">WhatsApp</a> platform. Meta's CEO Mark Zuckerberg spearheaded the announcement today (Nov 14), stating users will soon begin noticing a "draft" indicator on threads for unfinished/unsent messages.</p><p>WhatsApp states these indicators will be displayed in green, as chats will show "Draft" followed by a preview of your message in your list.</p><p>The platform adds that chats with unsent texts will be moved to the top of your view, so you can quickly return and finish. The feature is similar to other texting platforms like Google Messages. Moreover, users can likely expect to see their "drafted" message placed automatically in the writing field after tapping a thread.</p><p>Additionally, the folks at MySmartPrice state that the update has been spotted via the respective app stores on iOS and Android devices. WhatsApp is updating devices with the new "Draft" indicator and functionality alongside several bug/performance fixes.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:618px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:97.09%;"><img id="PHNThhLQtURyprELeAQkmX" name="whatsapp-draft-indicator-chat-thread-example" alt="WhatsApp is rolling out its new "Draft" message indicator and functionality for iOS and Android devices." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PHNThhLQtURyprELeAQkmX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="618" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Meta)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>WhatsApp's "draft messages" arrives a couple of weeks after the platform introduced its new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/whatsapp-expands-chat-filters-with-new-options">custom Lists feature</a>. This update expanded the app's original list of available chat filters with more categories. Meta rolled out tags for chats like local neighborhood, work, and buddies. Moreover, the update lets users get creative and create unique tags. All of this is accessible via the "Chats" screen.</p><p>The app accepts one-on-one threads, as well as group chats with this updated Lists feature.</p><p>Of course, that update might pair well with the app's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/whatsapp-likely-to-have-userames-soon">upcoming username patch</a>. In October, the platform rolled out a patch that let users privately manage stored contacts on other devices in addition to their "primary phone." However, this seems to be a prelude to the platform's plans to ditch the necessity of a phone number on the app in favor of a username.</p><p>That update was teased to come with a synchronization feature, so users can keep their contacts with them on every device.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://shop-links.co/link?id=pcmcat1563302848653&publisher_slug=future&exclusive=1&u1=ac-us-7102081545325758946&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Ftop-deals%2Fcell-phone-deals%2Fpcmcat1563302848653.c%3Fid%3Dpcmcat1563302848653&article_name=WhatsApp%27s%20new%20customization%20feature%20makes%20managing%20your%20chats%20much%20easier%20%7C%20Android%20Central&article_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.androidcentral.com%2Fapps-software%2Fwhatsapp-expands-chat-filters-with-new-options" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1943169/565706/9383?subId1=ac-us-8885073604543608871&sharedId=ac-us&u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fcp%2Fcell-phones%2F1105910%3Fpovid%3Dweb_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://shop-links.co/link?publisher_slug=future&exclusive=1&u1=ac-us-1290573761807999148&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.samsung.com%2Fus%2Fshop%2Fall-deals%2Fcell-phone-deals%2F&article_name=WhatsApp%27s%20new%20customization%20feature%20makes%20managing%20your%20chats%20much%20easier%20%7C%20Android%20Central&article_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.androidcentral.com%2Fapps-software%2Fwhatsapp-expands-chat-filters-with-new-options" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://target.georiot.com/Proxy.ashx?tsid=169923&GR_URL=https%3A%2F%2Famazon.com%2Fs%3Fk%3Dcell%2Bphone%26crid%3D19CKV7OMEPEMF%26sprefix%3Dcell%2Bphone%252Caps%252C222%26ref%3Dnb_sb_noss_1%26tag%3Dhawk-future-20%26ascsubtag%3Dac-us-1395577802481583313-20" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-100048248-15733793?sid=ac-us-1197526787989430813&url=https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-100048248-15735111?sid=ac-us-6801254833807500051&url=https://www.att.com/" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/meta-whatsapp-message-drafts-rollout</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Meta detailed the launch of "message drafts" for WhatsApp. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">b5N2KPj4B4F7FFrZvBzJBm</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Q68itx8GJ2hFAbk7rEBTSc.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 18:17:39 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Q68itx8GJ2hFAbk7rEBTSc.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Meta]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Meta rolls out its &quot;Message Draft&quot; feature for WhatsApp.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Meta rolls out its &quot;Message Draft&quot; feature for WhatsApp.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>