<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 01:16:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ What the heck is going on at TSMC? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-tensor-g5-chip-testing-preparations">TSMC</a> is the most important tech company of them all. It may not be the wealthiest or the most recognizable, but the company manufactures the parts that make most of your tech stuff possible. TSMC is the company that makes chips for Apple, Qualcomm, and almost everyone else.</p><p>It's not the company that designs the chips or figures out ways to make them better. It literally is the company that turns silicon wafers and rare metals into processors, and it's found itself smack dab in the middle of the U.S. fight with China.</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Android & Chill</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="6okfEqHJFPcbznZSbSNW3n" name="android-n-chill.JPG" caption="" alt="Android Central mascot" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6okfEqHJFPcbznZSbSNW3n.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Future)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">One of the web's longest-running tech columns, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/android-and-chill">Android & Chill</a> is your Saturday discussion of Android, Google, and all things tech.</p></div></div>
<p>To begin with, it appears that TSMC (Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co.) didn't do anything wrong and is the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/29/business/tsmc-huawei-computer-chips.html">victim of some sort of tech component fraud</a>. In any case, some of the parts it manufactures have been found in Huawei's Ascend 910B AI accelerator, which is something that the U.S. "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/huawei-devices-are-losing-support-for-android-apps-heres-why-its-a-good-thing">forbids</a>." These chips are officially made by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/smic-everything-you-need-know">China-based SMIC</a> (Semiconductor Manufacturing International Corp), but it's been reported that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://asiatimes.com/2024/06/low-yield-for-smic-huawei-nvidia-knockoff-so-what/">the company is unable to meet demand</a>.</p><p>A different client <strong>not</strong> under U.S. sanctions apparently bought the parts and supplied them to Huawei without TSMC's knowledge. TSMC discovered the issue and self-reported to both the Tawainese government and the U.S. Department of Commerce on October 11.</p><p>The U.S. can't do anything directly to any company that is not inside the country, but what it can do may be worse — it can forbid any company that wants to do business inside the United States from supplying anything, real goods or technology included, to a sanctioned entity like Huawei. That means it can tell Apple not to use TSMC, and it can tell Qualcomm that if it wants to sell products to U.S. customers, it can't deal with TSMC either, due to any perceived business between TSMC and Huawei. It's effectively a death sentence.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:61.88%;"><img id="Bv65j4HeYum7Ej3M5ADmhP" name="snapdragon-888-module.jpg" alt="Qualcomm Snapdragon 888" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Bv65j4HeYum7Ej3M5ADmhP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="495" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Source: Qualcomm)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>At first, it sounded like TSMC was in hot water, but that doesn't appear to be the case. Either way, the company has to withstand an investigation by the US Commerce Department’s Bureau of Industry and Security, which will be forced to report the findings to the U.S. Congress. That's something we shouldn't wish on our worst enemies.</p><p>It's good that TSMC is not only clear of any wrongdoing but also did the right thing even though it knew what was going to happen. Not all giant corporations would do the same. It's even more important to us that we won't see sanctions against TSMC, which would wreck the tech landscape.</p>
<p>I know we all hate it when I use Apple as an example, but it's the easy way to demonstrate what I mean, so I'm going with it.</p><p>Apple has TSMC make 100% (effectively) of the chips inside every product it sells that use <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apple-m1-chip-helping-apple-expand-its-brand-lock">Apple's in-house processors</a>. That means with every iPhone, iPad, Mac, etc., TSMC has to continue to increase its manufacturing capacity in order to meet demand from Apple and its other clients, so business is booming.</p><p>Now imagine all those products without anyone to build the chips that power them. The big companies like Apple and Samsung, who can manufacture their own <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/all-new-cortex-x-exynos-chip-will-supercharge-industry">Exynos chips</a>, would survive after a dismal year or two, but the Motorolas and OnePluses of the world would cease to exist if TSMC went "offline" like this and they were unable to get new products built until an alternative was found.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="C2Fb9YHDByQRHztHsMAQsk" name="exynos-generic.jpg" alt="Samsung Exynos processor" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/C2Fb9YHDByQRHztHsMAQsk.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Source: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>That's a big part of the problem; there is no real alternative. There are other foundries — TSMC does not exist in a bubble — but none have the capacity or technology to match TSMC. That's why Apple, Qualcomm, Intel, and everyone else use them. They build a superior product when it comes to yield and die size, and that's what chip companies need.</p>
<p>I've been following this story for a week or so, and at first, I was concerned. The U.S. has an election coming up (as if you haven't noticed), and there is no telling how a Trump administration Commerce Department would react should he win. If sanctions were placed against TSMC similar to what Huawei is dealing with, the tech landscape would be ruined. Thankfully, the full story isn't so bleak.</p><p>TSMC will have to deal with a few million miles of U.S. government red tape, members of Congress will huff and puff to show their <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/a-tiktok-ban-isnt-about-privacy-its-about-politics">disdain for all things China</a>, and it should remain business as usual when it comes to having access to the products we love to use.</p><p>It just goes to show that good things can happen when a company does the right thing instead of trying to hide evidence and delete messages, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.cnn.com/2023/03/29/tech/judge-google-deleted-chat-logs-antitrust-case/index.html">right Google</a>?</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/tsmc-us-investigation-breakdown</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ TSMC got caught up in the U.S. battle with China and it appears to have done nothing wrong. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">T7GaJLzshtRR84t7ZgrtQG</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FQFii5BwHLdxcL48JME658.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FQFii5BwHLdxcL48JME658.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tsmc.com/english&quot;&gt;Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co., Ltd&lt;/a&gt;]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[TSMC logo]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[TSMC logo]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ News Weekly: Samsung teases an exciting 2025, Google Maps upgrades, ChatGPT Search, and more ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">News Weekly</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="h7AVxNX2TSFH3rYKHd2Vw" name="lloyd-news-weekly.jpg" caption="" alt="News Weekly Logo" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/h7AVxNX2TSFH3rYKHd2Vw.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text"><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/news-weekly">News Weekly</a> is our column where we highlight and summarize some of the week's top stories so you can catch up on the latest tech news.</p></div></div>
<p>This is Android Central's News Weekly, your go-to source for a concise roundup of the week's most significant tech stories. This is where we delve into the top headlines that provide the latest developments and innovations contributing to the digital landscape.</p><p>This week, Samsung's earnings reveal its plans for 2025, Google Maps is getting better at navigation, OpenAI launches its Google Search competitor, the OnePlus 13 is official in China, and you can now buy a Certified refurbished Pixel phone.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="samsung-s-2025-a-cheaper-foldable-and-xr-glasses-2">Samsung's 2025: A cheaper foldable and XR glasses?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.30%;"><img id="tSPmQJ5Y3RC35cJQJc2VJF" name="samsung-galaxy-glass-vision-pro-mockup.jpg" alt="A color-inverted version of the Apple Vision Pro with the Samsung Galaxy logo overlayed on top" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tSPmQJ5Y3RC35cJQJc2VJF.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1153" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Samsung / Apple / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Read more <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-confirms-galaxy-s25-teases-cheaper-foldable-xr-device-2025">here</a>.</p><p>Big tech earnings began this week, and Samsung announced its quarterly report on Thursday. While these can be kind of boring, sometimes interesting details can arise from them regarding a company's near-term plans. Samsung's summary of its Q3 2024 financial report highlighted its various businesses and gave us a glimpse into its plans for 2025 regarding phones, XR, and more.</p><p>Unsurprisingly, the company plans to launch the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25">Galaxy S25</a> in the first half of 2025. If we go by last year's schedule, we can expect the phone to launch in January, along with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-confirms-one-ui-7-wont-hit-beta-until-end-of-this-year">stable One UI 7 update</a>. However, that may not be the only exciting phone coming next year, as Samsung seemingly teased a cheaper foldable could be in the works to help promote adoption and offer competitively priced devices. Samsung has previously <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-says-it-has-no-plans-to-make-a-cheaper-foldable-but-why">dismissed the idea of a cheaper foldable</a>, so we hope the company provides.</p><p>Finally, Samsung made a small mention of "XR devices" and its desire for the Samsung Health platform to take advantage of what we can assume will be <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/samsung-glasses">Samsung Glasses</a>, along with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-ring-review">Galaxy Ring</a>.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="google-maps-gets-upgrades-you-ll-care-about-2">Google Maps gets upgrades you'll care about</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="bcBCV2Uj36SakRZSbV2wGm" name="Google-Maps-enhanced-navigation-lane-guidance" alt="A large demo screen showing the new Google Maps "enhanced navigation" lane feature" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bcBCV2Uj36SakRZSbV2wGm.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Read more <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/game-changing-google-maps-enhanced-navigation-update-arrives-next-month">here</a>.</p><p>A decade after Google Maps started guiding users to the correct lane during navigation, the company is now making it even easier to see which lane you should be in. With an update to Google Maps coming to Android phones and iPhones this month, users will be able to clearly see which lane they need to be in and when, thanks to a zoomed-in view.</p><p>This will initially be available in 30 cities in the U.S., but Google plans to eventually expand the feature outside North America as well as to Android Auto and Carplay.</p><p>Gemini is also getting some Maps integration and can <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/you-can-now-ask-google-maps-for-spot-and-activity-ideas-thanks-to-gemini">provide ideas for activities</a>, showing users various review summaries of places to figure out the vibe. There are a ton of other updates as well, such as help with parking, navigation to places from where you've parked, expanded user reports, and more, which you should start to see rolling out through November.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="chatgpt-is-moving-in-on-google-s-territory-2">ChatGPT is moving in on Google's territory</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1666px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="DQerZJ88mwuGHLyDbPsqkM" name="openai-chatgpt-search-text-box-button" alt="OpenAI rolls out ChatGPT Search to a limited number of users before expanding." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DQerZJ88mwuGHLyDbPsqkM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1666" height="937" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OpenAI)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Read more <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/openai-chatgpt-search-feature-rollout">here</a>.</p><p>OpenAI's ChatGPT changed the game with generative AI to the point where many saw that Google was playing catch-up with the company. Now, OpenAI is playing catch-up with Google with its latest effort: ChatGPT search.</p><p>While you can still converse with ChatGPT naturally to get answers to queries, ChatGPT search will scour the web and display relevant results to users. This can happen within a chat, or users can manually begin a search, as a dedicated button will be integrated into the chat UI, making it a secondary component.</p><p>Furthermore, ChatGPT will make it easy to access sources, with links just under the results and accessible via a Sources bar on the side that you can open with just a click.</p><p>OpenAI says this will initially be available on the web and its apps for certain users, such as ChatGPT Plus and Team users, as well as those on the SearchGPT waitlist, while all free users will eventually have access to the feature.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-oneplus-13-looks-like-the-phone-to-beat-2">The OnePlus 13 looks like the phone to beat</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="XSzAZDXTpRYXADiJvSPikh" name="OnePlus-13-launch-teaser.jpg" alt="OnePlus 13 launch tease" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XSzAZDXTpRYXADiJvSPikh.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OnePlus)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Read more <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-13-goes-official-in-china">here</a>.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-13">OnePlus 13</a> is officially here, although not for everyone. The phone has launched in China, with a global launch expected later this year or at the top of 2025, but this initial launch gives us a full look at the phone and what we can expect when it comes to the rest of the world.</p><p>The OnePlus 13 features a mostly flat 6.8-inch 2K OLED display that has a slight curve on all sides. The display has a 120Hz refresh rate and is incredibly bright, with a 4500 nit peak. On the back is a triple camera setup consisting of three 50MP cameras, including a 120-degree ultrawide and 3x telephoto lens.</p><p>The phone runs <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/i-used-oxygenos-15-for-a-week-these-are-my-favorite-features">OxygenOS 15</a> based on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-review">Android 15</a>, meaning you'll have some of the latest features like Circle to Search and more.</p><p>Powering everything is Qualcomm's new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/snapdragon-8-elite">Snapdragon 8 Elite</a> and up to 24GB of RAM, meaning the phone is well equipped for the AI era and will have plenty of power. And keeping the lights on is a massive 6,000mAh battery that supports 100W wired charging and 50W wireless charging. There is magnetic charging, but only if you use a case.</p><p>The phone is available now for preorder in China, but we'll be on the lookout for a global launch.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="discounted-pixels-2">Discounted Pixels</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="y93H3D4cqy23Y9spCfaLyJ" name="google-pixel-7-pro-review-7.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 7 Pro back view straight on angle against green background" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/y93H3D4cqy23Y9spCfaLyJ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div></figure>
<p>Read more <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-certified-refurbished-pixel-program-detailed">here</a>.</p><p>Google has finally launched a Certified Refurbished program where it sells Pixel phones at a discount. These are fully inspected, with Google checking the battery, housing, and screens "for any imperfections" and using "authentic Google parts" to repair them if and when needed.</p><p>The Certified Refurbished program consists of the Pixel 6 and newer devices, with the phones discounted as much as 40% off and still getting the same one-year warranty as a new Pixel. Google also says the devices will feature the latest Android software, although it's important to note that as of October 2024, support for OS upgrades on the Pixel 6 and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-pixel-6-pro-review">Pixel 6 Pro</a> has <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-6-android-15-update-upgrade-decision">officially ended</a>, meaning the devices will only receive security updates until 2026.</p><p>Google isn't the first to offer such a program, with Samsung continuously adding Galaxy phones to its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-s22-series-certified-re-newed">Certified Renewed program</a>. Still, it's good to see Google making the effort to bring more sustainable options, even if we <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-certified-refurbished-prices-are-uncompetitive">question the pricing of these devices</a>.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="more-stories-this-week-2">More stories this week</h2>
<p>Those are some of the biggest stories from this week. Meanwhile, here are some other stories that are worth catching up on:</p>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-galaxy-watch-6-series-get-stable-one-ui-6-watch-wear-os-5">Samsung wraps up the One UI 6 Watch beta, drops the stable version for the Galaxy Watch 6</a></li><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/the-future-of-googles-pixel-watches-is-looking-mighty-powerful">The future of Google's Pixel Watches is looking mighty powerful</a></li><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsungs-android-15-update-gets-an-up-close-reveal-in-this-one-ui-7-hands-on-video">Samsung's Android 15 update gets an up-close reveal in this One UI 7 hands-on video</a></li><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-open-2-camera-charging-leaks">The OnePlus Open 2 could get the one feature we wish its predecessor had</a></li><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-series-color-options-tipped">Galaxy S25 colors leak along with some underwhelming screen specs</a></li><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini-2-dot-0-likely-to-launch-in-december-2024">Google is reportedly launching a new Gemini model in December</a></li><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/pixel-tablet-3-second-usb-c-port-desktop-rumor">Pixel Tablet 3 rumor makes it sound like a more useful laptop replacement</a></li><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9a-battery-capacity-pro-xl-leak">Latest Google Pixel 9a leak says it might strive for Pro XL power levels</a></li><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-next-gen-pro-rugged-devices-early-leak">Early leak claims Samsung is working on a couple of rugged Pro models</a></li><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-reportedly-considers-new-phone-brand-separate-from-galaxy">Samsung reportedly considers dropping 'Galaxy' brand for some devices, but the move might not go how it thinks</a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/news-weekly-november-2-2024</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung teases an exciting 2025, Google Maps gets even better, Google Search gets some competition with ChatGPT Search, and more. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">QogD3G7G3mQ8dfPMJWbSvW</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hXWgyEfPvQgs4vgXNzLxwM.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ derrek.lee@futurenet.com (Derrek Lee) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hXWgyEfPvQgs4vgXNzLxwM.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Samsung]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Z Fold Special Edition promo render]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Z Fold Special Edition promo render]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ MediaTek's Dimensity 9400 is the biggest challenger to Qualcomm yet ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>MediaTek has a sizeable presence in the budget and mid-range segments on the back of strong releases, but it struggled to make progress in the high-end category. Even until two years ago, most Android phones were powered by the Snapdragon 8 platform, with Qualcomm effectively monopolizing this tier.</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Hardwired</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="5u6gVPowTCuSQ8NJeoktj7" name="lloyd-hardwired.png" caption="" alt="Android Central's LLoyd with a bionic eye" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5u6gVPowTCuSQ8NJeoktj7.png" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">In <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/hardwired"> Hardwired </a>, AC Senior Editor Harish Jonnalagadda delves into all things hardware, including phones, audio products, storage servers, and routers.</p></div></div>
<p>That dynamic is changing slowly; MediaTek was able to secure key design wins with the Dimensity 9200 and 9300 in the last two years, giving it a much-needed foothold in this lucrative segment. The fact that it was able to outmuscle Qualcomm to do so is all the more impressive.</p><p>A part of this has to do with the hardware itself; while Qualcomm is just now starting to use performance cores throughout in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/snapdragon-8-elite">Snapdragon 8 Elite</a>, MediaTek has been at it for over 12 months, with both the Dimensity 9300/9300+ and 9400 powered entirely by performance cores.</p><p>Doing so allows MediaTek-powered devices to deliver better multi-core results, and that has been the case in my testing. Phones featuring the Dimensity 9300/9300+ — like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/vivo-x100-pro-review">Vivo X100 Pro</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/xiaomi-14t-pro-review">Xiaomi 14T Pro</a> — have among the highest scores in Geekbench&apos;s multi-core workloads, and while they still don&apos;t quite measure up to the A18 Pro in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/apple-iphone-16-pro-max-review">iPhone 16 Pro Max</a>, they&apos;re better than anything else available on Android.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="CaaCNuVU5JpKFQi4tnvxyk" name="x200.jpg" alt="Vivo X200 launch render" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CaaCNuVU5JpKFQi4tnvxyk.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Vivo)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The biggest endorsement for MediaTek&apos;s efforts in this segment is by Samsung, which is using the Dimensity 9300+ exclusively on its Galaxy Tab S10 series tablets globally. Sure, Samsung&apos;s high-end tablets don&apos;t rack up anywhere as many sales as the brand&apos;s Galaxy S24 series, but the fact that the manufacturer went with MediaTek hardware in all regions — including North America — is a vote of confidence.</p><p>It&apos;s a similar story with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/mediatek-announces-dimensity-9400-flagship-chip">Dimensity 9400</a>, MediaTek&apos;s answer to the Snapdragon 8 Elite. The Dimensity 9400 uses the latest Cortex X925 core alongside Cortex X4 and A720 cores, and it is powering OPPO&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-wait-is-over-oppos-find-x8-and-x8-pro-are-launching-globally">Find X8</a> and 8 Pro as well as Vivo&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/vivo-takes-things-to-a-whole-new-level-with-the-x200-series">X200 devices</a>.</p><p>Although these devices don&apos;t have a huge presence in western markets yet, they sell in the millions in China, and OPPO and Vivo are making some progress in the high-end category in countries like India.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="hyet8kTDnvDvroVXqHRHoQ" name="vivo-x100-ultra-26.jpg" alt="Vivo X100 Ultra review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hyet8kTDnvDvroVXqHRHoQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>As to why a phone manufacturer would use MediaTek instead of Qualcomm, cost is likely a factor in the consideration, but most brands I talked to mention customizability as a big differentiator. MediaTek offers the ability to tailor its Dimensity platform to particular devices, and OnePlus used this to good effect in its mid-range devices in recent years.</p><p>Rivalry is a good thing in this industry, and while Qualcomm is still the dominant brand, it&apos;s good to see MediaTek offering a platform that can hold its own. Vivo&apos;s X100 Pro is one of my favorite phones of 2024, and it is just as performant as the dozens of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-3">Snapdragon 8 Gen 3</a>-powered devices I used over the course of the year.</p><p>With Qualcomm going back to fully-custom designs after nearly a decade, it will be interesting to see how the Dimensity 9400 — which has Arm&apos;s latest cores — holds up in real-world usage against Qualcomm. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/mediateks-dimensity-9400-is-the-biggest-challenger-to-qualcomm-yet</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ MediaTek is doing all the right things lately, and the Dimensity 9400 has secured meaningful design wins.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">dNQCCCBnC2kcTCS5k7ECok</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/B2Lfg9W8t2RrnoM5U2Bcre.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 06:58:53 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/B2Lfg9W8t2RrnoM5U2Bcre.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Mediatek logo at MWC 2024]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Mediatek logo at MWC 2024]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Our favorite phone of 2024 just quietly returned to its lowest price EVER, weeks before Black Friday ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Well, I <em>was </em>about to call it a day, but I just came across an early Black Friday deal at Best Buy that has stopped me dead in my tracks. The OnePlus 12, one of our favorite Android phones on the market today, is currently sitting on the retailer&apos;s site with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oneplus-12-256gb-unlocked-silky-black/6570636.p"><strong>a whopping $150 discount</strong></a>. That&apos;s the same price drop that we saw during Amazon&apos;s Prime Day sale in October, and we&apos;re still almost a month away from Black Friday! </p><p>True, the discount comes in the wake of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-13">OnePlus 13 reveal</a> in China a few days ago, but since there&apos;s no global release date for that phone yet, this is the best that OnePlus currently has to offer at well below the retail price. No trade-in required, no strings attached. </p>
<h2 id="the-apos-gorgeous-apos-oneplus-12-has-returned-to-its-prime-day-price-2">The &apos;gorgeous&apos; OnePlus 12 has returned to its Prime Day price</h2>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="7d393108-04a3-4e09-bd2f-f8b074e8f043" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799.99" data-dimension48="$799.99" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oneplus-12-256gb-unlocked-silky-black/6570636.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:546px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:117.22%;"><img id="WpApNUoUctCEufrWszeWw8" name="oneplus-12-render-black.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WpApNUoUctCEufrWszeWw8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="546" height="640" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>OnePlus 12 256GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oneplus-12-256gb-unlocked-silky-black/6570636.p" data-dimension112="7d393108-04a3-4e09-bd2f-f8b074e8f043" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799.99" data-dimension48="$799.99"><del>$799.99</del> <strong>$649.99 at Best Buy</strong></a></p>
<p>Here at Android Central, it's no secret that we're massive fans of the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12-review">OnePlus 12</a>. While the eye-catching flagship may lack some of the AI features found in its Samsung and Google counterparts, the OnePlus 12 is a champ where it counts. You get lightning-fast Snapdragon performance straight out of the box, plus a vibrant AMOLED 120Hz display, a two-day battery, and some of the best camera tech you'll ever use. </p>
<p><strong>Price comparison: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CQ5MYYZL">Amazon - $649.99</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oneplus-12-256gb-unlocked-silky-black/6570636.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="7d393108-04a3-4e09-bd2f-f8b074e8f043" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799.99" data-dimension48="$799.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/top-deals"><em><strong>See Best Buy's full list of early Black Friday deals</strong></em></a></li></ul>
<p>The OnePlus 12 earned the top spot in our list of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a> of 2024, not because it&apos;s the most powerful or innovative device that we&apos;ve ever used, but because it has the perfect balance of elegant, sophisticated design with butter-smooth performance and a price tag that won&apos;t demolish your bank account. After all, there&apos;s a good reason why so many folks compare the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12-vs-samsung-galaxy-s24">OnePlus 12 with the Samsung Galaxy S24</a> when shopping for a new smartphone. </p><p>While you&apos;ll miss out on some of those fancy AI features that other brands have been prioritizing lately, with the OnePlus 12 you&apos;re getting a phone that&apos;s simply great at being a phone. If all you need is a stylish device with great battery life, fast performance, and awesome camera software, then the OnePlus 12 is a great deal — <em>especially </em>when you compare it with an early Black Friday discount at Best Buy. </p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/our-favorite-phone-of-2024-just-quietly-returned-to-its-lowest-price-ever-weeks-before-black-friday</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Best Buy has randomly decided to slash $150 off the OnePlus 12, returning the beloved flagship to its lowest ever price.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">uFoM7E4Diuzm7zK7ahrbDB</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5YihoisE3ixZ3LsaxmhxfG.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 22:12:19 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5YihoisE3ixZ3LsaxmhxfG.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus 12 camera island with light reflection]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus 12 camera island with light reflection]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Gemini can adjust your smart home accessories with Google Home integration ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google is starting to roll out a slew of new Gemini extensions, including the Google Home app.</li><li>Users enrolled in the Public Preview for Google Home should start seeing the integration in the Gemini app for Android this week, with a gradual rollout over the next few weeks.</li><li>You'll be able to ask Gemini to make changes to your Home in natural language, and the Gemini extension will replace the Google Assistant.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Gemini is on a path to replace the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-assistant">Google Assistant</a>, and it's about to gain crucial functionality once reserved for Assistant. Soon, users will be able to control their smart home with a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-home">Google Home</a> extension in the Gemini app. It's rolling out now for users enrolled in the Public Preview for Google Home on Android, and the gradual rollout will continue over the coming weeks.</p><p>After you gain access to the new Google Home extension, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-gemini-app-android">Gemini</a> will be able to use this newfound integration to control your smart home without needing to invoke the Google Assistant. The extension can activate scenes, change the status of connected accessories, and more. What's different about using Gemini for these purposes instead of Assistant? You can use natural language to get things done instead of using specific word choice.</p><p>Specifically, Google explains that telling <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini</a> the phrase "the sun is too bright in the living room" will result in the AI assistant closing the smart window blinds in your home. The company also gives an example of using "help me clean up the kitchen" to start a robot vacuum.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="4sUeciYBZHaLoMa5KiYw7h" name="google-pixel-9-pro-fold-review-20.jpg" alt="Gemini response on Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4sUeciYBZHaLoMa5KiYw7h.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2500" height="1406" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>To try out these new features, open the <strong>Google Home app</strong> on your Android device. Tap the <strong>Settings</strong> button, then select <strong>Public Preview</strong>. From there, press <strong>Join Public Preview</strong> to enroll your account. You should soon gain access to the Google Home extension for Gemini.</p><p>There are a few limitations to note, though. It's only available on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phones</a> and is restricted to English prompts. Additionally, Gemini can't control smart security devices, such as gates, cameras, locks, doors, and garage doors. On devices that don't have Gemini, like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/nest-audio-review">Nest smart speakers</a> and displays, you'll still be using Google Assistant.</p><p>You can try the Google Home extension in the Gemini app today if you're enrolled in the early preview, and a wider release is likely to follow in the future.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="ee2fde27-a921-40c8-ae21-b1672448b297">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/B22jKfVHKzg8nbRGgwTHSP.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro official render - Rose Quartz - Front and Back"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 Pro</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Pixel power</strong></em></p><p>The Google Pixel 9 Pro is equipped with a powerful Tensor chip, allowing it to handle fun and useful AI features on-device. Gemini is also included, allowing you to control your smart devices or have full-on conversations for a bit of inspiration.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/gemini-google-home-integration-public-preview-rollout</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ You can now try out the Google Home extension in the Gemini app as the functionality enters Public Preview. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">zZpCLWEnK2tWThRJzgzWjL</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MEypxaySVNEaqavKxefoBf.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 21:33:48 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MEypxaySVNEaqavKxefoBf.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Home integration in the Gemini app for Android. ]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Home integration in the Gemini app for Android. ]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ When it comes to Canada's Online News Act, Google wins even when it's losing ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The Canadian Radio-television and Telecommunications Commission (CRTC) has <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://nmc-mic.ca/2024/10/29/google-receives-five-year-exemption-from-crtc/">granted Google a five-year exemption</a> through the country's Online News Act. Google has agreed to pay CAD 100 million yearly to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://cjc-ccj.ca/en/">Canadian Journalism Collective</a> (CJC), a federally incorporated nonprofit organization created to distribute funds allocated under the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-response-canada-bill-c-18">Online News Act</a>. The CRTC also stipulated that additional news outlets be allowed to join CJC to qualify for funds.</p><p>If you're not a Canadian let me help this make some more sense. Canada passed the Online News Act to force companies like Google or Meta—which use small portions of news articles in search results—to negotiate a fair price for the use of these snippets. The CRTC <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://crtc.gc.ca/eng/archive/2024/2024-262.htm">has decided</a> that Google will pay CAD 100 million per year to the CJC which will then disperse funds to news organizations affected by Google's use.</p><p>It seems that being plagued by bureaucracy is not exclusive to the U.S.</p>
<p>I'm not a fan of laws like Canada's Online News Act. I can tell you from experience that becoming featured by a company like Google is 100% a net positive, even if the company used a small portion of your text in a snippet or AI summary. In my opinion, as long as Google links back to the source (it does) anyone interested in reading more than a headline will follow through to the original source.</p><p>Regardless of how I feel about these types of laws, it is the law in Canada, and companies like Google, Apple, and Meta who aggregate and disseminate news summaries are bound by it. Other countries have similar laws.</p><p>I'll also assume that these laws are in place because government bodies like the CRTC believe they serve the interests of the citizens they are charged with serving. Forget about partisanship or left versus right for a moment; federal agencies are supposed to look out for our best interests regardless of where we live.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2047px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="Rk48GXqLxWCgSRaHtwd2o5" name="West_Block_Temp_House_of_Commons,_2022.jpg" alt="Canada's House of Commons" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Rk48GXqLxWCgSRaHtwd2o5.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2047" height="1151" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Hutima - Own work, CC BY-SA 4.0)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Then there is the reality. Laws like Canada's Online News Act are designed to prop up an industry that's currently struggling by having companies that are struggling less provide funding. If part of the reason for the decline is that Google and Meta are "stealing" the synopsis of an article for their aggregation feed, that's fine. Google and Meta should compensate news organizations that provide the content from which they make a huge profit. My opinion that one could leverage being featured by Google or Meta in a lucrative way doesn't matter because I am not a government official.</p><p>It's the CRTC's job to assist news organizations, too. A news outlet is not a citizen, but there should be a government agency that ensures things are done fairly by both sides. The Canadian government has a responsibility not to let Canadian news organizations die. And no, that's not socialism; a government serving the interests of business is the opposite, so save your comment.</p><p>I ask you then, was CAD 100 million enough? Is that number going to keep Canada's news industry alive in times when Google and other tech companies "steal" their content for financial gain? To Google, 100 million Canadian dollars is a laughable amount. Google <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/alphabet-q3-2024-earnings">"earns" that much without even trying</a>.</p><p>This is why I dislike these types of laws. Google should be forced to allow companies to opt out of its search and news services until it has reached an agreement with each individual organization. A smaller company may only be "worth" paying $200,000 a year to use its content, while a large company like the NYT or Washington Post can negotiate for more. Having a lump sum paid out through yet another government body is another way Google wins even when it has lost.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-canada-online-news-act-exemption</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google is getting off easy this time. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Z4XuMAWHHGRboRLVgnj533</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZtjXaaHyTYrAT4dTbChrFe.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 21:15:43 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZtjXaaHyTYrAT4dTbChrFe.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A Google sign at the Mountain View Google campus.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A Google sign at the Mountain View Google campus.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Messages might give its read receipts a new home and design ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Users on Reddit reported new read receipt indicators for RCS chats in Google Messages and an APK teardown provided more insight.</li><li>Per the teardown, Google is testing a change in Messages that moves those sent/delivered indicators inside the bubble with your text.</li><li>A Reddit user discovered that you'd have to press and hold a message and drag it to view the time it was sent.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google is reportedly developing a redesign for its RCS text indicators in Messages.</p><p>The company is developing a (type of) "in-line" read receipt notification for its RCS-enabled chats. Users on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GoogleMessages/comments/1ggwf3f/google_messages_read_receipt_ui_changed_for_me/">Reddit have reported</a> these new indicators on their devices while in the Google Messages beta (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/google-messages-read-receipt-rollout-3496172/">Android Authority</a>). More importantly, the publication conducted an APK dive of the recent beta version (messages.android_20241029_00_RC00)</p><p>From screenshots shared on Reddit to the publication's teardown, these new indicators will occupy the right-most corner of your text bubble.</p><p>Further digging shows that the animations have changed, too. According to the post, sending a message is accompanied by an ellipsis (three dots) before turning into a single check mark. A second check mark — or part of it — appears against the first, showing that the message has been sent and delivered successfully.</p><p>These new receipt indicators are (potentially) always present in the text thread no matter the number of messages. This contrasts how Messages is currently where the most recently sent text displays its RCS sent/delivered indicators. Additionally, a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GoogleMessages/comments/1ggwf3f/comment/lut1874/?utm_source=share&utm_medium=web3x&utm_name=web3xcss&utm_term=1&utm_content=share_button">user on Reddit</a> in the beta states Google changed how you can see the time of a text.</p><p>The user states users must "hold and pull the screen to see the time the message came/sent." After, the app will automatically drop the text to cover those extra details.</p>
<blockquote class="reddit-card"  ><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GoogleMessages/comments/1ggwf3f/google_messages_read_receipt_ui_changed_for_me">Google messages Read receipt u.i changed for me.</a> from <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GoogleMessages">r/GoogleMessages</a></blockquote><script async src="//embed.redditmedia.com/widgets/platform.js" charset="UTF-8"></script>
<p>As the test expands to more users, it's unclear when Google will roll this out. Reports of these revamped indicators were posted recently, so the company will likely wait a while for feedback/testing before pushing it to everyone.</p><p>It's worth remembering that Google Messages used to (digitally) say "Sending..." and "Sent" when texting others. That changed last year when the company introduced <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-messages-new-read-receipts">the new checkmarks</a> we've become accustomed to seeing in the app. With this change looming, Google moves them from beneath your message, beside the time, to inside the bubble with your text.</p><p>Aside from your texts, it was reported recently that Google Messages could receive extra privacy options through <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-messages-adding-profile-discovery-privacy-feature">Profile Discovery</a>. Such options include showing your name and profile icon to "people you message," "only contacts," or "no one." These additions were discovered on the setup screen for the Messages app.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-messages-read-receipts-placement-redesign-spotted</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google was spotted testing a new style of read receipt for its chats in Messages. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">FxAaToBtyjHwtGeG3USdsF</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qmjZ9Buznno9fFnNqySv5V.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 19:38:59 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qmjZ9Buznno9fFnNqySv5V.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nick Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Messages on Pixel 6 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Messages on Pixel 6 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Get ready — Google's Android 15 QPR2 Beta 1 is on its way ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google prepares Pixel testers for its upcoming Android 15 QPR2 Beta 1.</li><li>The company states this build is intended to run through Q1 2025 as it will be its March 2025 feature drop.</li><li>Android 15 QPR1 Beta 3 dropped last week with system crash fixes, but Google recently confirmed Android 16 will debut in Q2 2025.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google is alerting all interested Pixel testers about its next QPR test for Android 15.</p><p>The company <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/android_beta/comments/1ggq2he/android_15_qpr2_beta_around_the_corner/">took to Reddit</a> to announce the upcoming start of the Android 15 QPR2 Beta 1. Google states this next beta will "build on top of" the Android 15 QPR1 release, which is expected to hit devices in December. If you are an enrolled Pixel tester through Google's program, the company detailed steps for those willing to stay or those looking to exit.</p><p>Google states any enrolled tester who'd rather receive the stable QPR1 feature drop must "opt out of the program." To avoid a complete data wipe on your Pixel, the post recommends that users follow the remaining steps:</p>
<ul><li>Ignore/don’t apply the downgrade OTA update.The OTA message will have ‘Downgrade’ in the description. Opting out will not cause a data wipe as long as you <strong>don’t</strong> apply the downgrade OTA update. </li><li>If your device is offered the Android 15 QPR2 Beta 1 update, <strong>don’t</strong> install the update. Instead, first <a href="https://www.google.com/android/beta#devices" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>opt out of the program</u></a>, ignore/don’t apply the downgrade OTA update.</li><li>Wait for the final public stable release of Android 15 QPR1 (AP4A), which is coming in December.</li></ul>
<blockquote class="reddit-card"  ><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/android_beta/comments/1ggq2he/android_15_qpr2_beta_around_the_corner">Android 15 QPR2 Beta around the corner!</a> from <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/android_beta">r/android_beta</a></blockquote><script async src="//embed.redditmedia.com/widgets/platform.js" charset="UTF-8"></script>
<p>For those looking to stay, Google states the Android 15 QPR2 Beta 1 will be automatically downloaded (likely as an OTA update) once it arrives. The post adds that this next QPR build is intended to be the March 2025 feature drop. Additionally, Google estimates that Android 15 QPR2 will conclude sometime during Q1 2025.</p><p>Aside from "kicking off soon," Google did not give a specific date for the start of QPR2 Beta 1. However, with QPR1 confirmed to roll out in December, perhaps we're looking at a launch in January for the next one, but we'll have to wait and see for an official post.</p><p>The company rolled out <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-qpr1-beta-3-bluetooth-foldable-update">Android 15 QPR1 Beta 3</a> last week, and that patch was full of fixes for system crashes. It arrived a little later than what testers (us included) expected. Regardless, the update also provided a blank screen fix for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-fold-review">Google's foldable phones</a> that occurred when users unfolded the device.</p><p>More importantly, Google's confirmed timeline for QPR2 Beta 1 might signal the end of Android 15's beta cycle. The company dropped a major <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-play-store-gemini-android-studio-sdk-updates">Android SDK</a> update yesterday (Oct 31) and with it came confirmation of Android 16 in Q2 2025. Considering Q1 runs from January to March, Android 15's testing might not go further than that. A Q2 launch for Android 16 gives us April through June to play with as we might see a beta or two before its launch.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-teases-upcoming-android-15-qpr-2-beta-1</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google informed users of its upcoming Android 15 QPR2 Beta 1. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">nJrWdMPjf68Kjb3jRYHgJo</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WymQhvqn9KZWMgDvhbDvdg.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 18:49:27 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WymQhvqn9KZWMgDvhbDvdg.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android 15 logo on Pixel 8]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android 15 logo on Pixel 8]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ It's time for Samsung to step up its support game ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Samsung recently announced <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-is-expanding-its-brick-and-mortar-repair-network-across-the-us">a new partnership with Assurant</a> that will bring 300 new places to have your Galaxy product repaired. That's good news, and any move toward more and better customer service after the sale is great to see. But Samsung can do so much better.</p><p>Nine months of every year, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/samsungs-market-share-europe-jumped-over-40-q2-2019">Samsung is the largest electronics retailer in the world</a>; second-place Apple can only best its numbers the month after a new iPhone is announced. Samsung is the world's biggest consumer electronics manufacturer. There is no reason it shouldn't offer the best customer service, too.</p>

<p>There is an easy-to-follow formula here; if you guessed the Apple Store, you're right. You might not want to read this, but Samsung could build just a few models of Galaxy phones and sell support contracts that include friendly, helpful people employed by the company in a Galaxy store who are trained to fix any issue. If you have trouble with your Galaxy phone, watch, tablet, laptop, or earbuds, bring them to the nearest one and get them fixed or replaced while waiting. This works in the West, and we know it works because we can see it.</p><p>Samsung could continue to offer its full portfolio of products without the Galaxy branding for people who aren't looking to spend $1,000 or more instead of considering a new "luxury" brand name like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-reportedly-considers-new-phone-brand-separate-from-galaxy" target="_blank">it is rumored to be doing</a>. This would let the Galaxy name mean more, not less.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4160px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="rdaihAGj8bCoYZiWRNS8RQ" name="apple-store-new-york.jpg" alt="Apple Store in NYC" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rdaihAGj8bCoYZiWRNS8RQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4160" height="2340" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Many people think Samsung builds some of the finest consumer electronics available. I'm one of them. The materials, build quality, fit and finish, and overall package of a Samsung phone or tablet are second to none. The company is taking the time and resources to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-one-ui-6">improve its software offerings</a> and has turned itself around from being a laughing stock just a few years ago to building something people love. The next logical move is to treat its customers to the same A+ level of support, and one way to do that is by opening more physical stores customers could just walk into when they need help.</p><p>Samsung has some flagship stores in a few cities in the United States, but my guess is that many of you probably haven't seen a Samsung store or would know where to find one.</p><p>I think it would be a good move and a lucrative one at that. I'll be blunt — "poor" people don't buy <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review">Galaxy S Ultras</a> or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Galaxy Z Folds</a>. Poor people aren't buying <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/apple-iphone-16-pro-max-review">iPhone 16 Pro Max</a> phones, either. You don't have to be rich to afford Samsung's latest and greatest, but you are going to have a certain level of disposable income. If you're reading this, you probably fall into this category.</p><p>With so much invested into a product, paying $10 a month or $100 a year for top-tier support isn't a bad idea. People are <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-is-samsung-care">paying it now</a>, only to be left to deal with over-the-phone support or third-party stores where walking out with a solution an hour later isn't a guarantee. If this idea didn't make money, Apple wouldn't be doing it. Apple doesn't operate any area of its business at a loss.</p>
<p>You may not be willing to pay for this "privilege," but I'll bet plenty of people would. A Galaxy Store in all the places where you would find an Apple store would make perfect sense, and not just big flagship stores in a few big cities across the country. Even smaller stores in malls where there's a good amount of traffic would make sense, and Samsung could even put them right across from Apple stores just to piss them off.</p><p>I'm not trying to claim Samsung could ever have the ... rabid ... fandom that Apple has, where people would line up around the block to buy the new Galaxy phone. I'm saying that isn't what keeps an Apple Store profitable; product sales and paid customer service throughout the year are where the money is. Samsung can try to get its share of that money while offering us the level of customer support we deserve when we pay for it.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/we-need-more-samsung-stores</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung needs to offer the same type of support its biggest competitor does. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">EnEHWWAsbew49vsawntGrD</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/m9nBdBGHXUwKxDeYWdkv6K.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 18:12:39 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/m9nBdBGHXUwKxDeYWdkv6K.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung logo]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung logo]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung's One UI 7 (Android 15) beta might finally be upon us ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Rumors from a tipster on X claim Samsung could start its One UI 7 (Android 15) beta in "another half month," potentially placing us in mid-November.</li><li>Elsewhere, Samsung has reportedly created the Public Beta forum pages for the Galaxy S24 and S23 series devices.</li><li>The major OS upgrade will debut with the Galaxy S25 series and a recent major leak showcased new parental and AI features.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Rumors are floating around that we're (finally) approaching the start of Samsung's Android 15 beta.</p><p>Well-known X tipster <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/UniverseIce/status/1852158438484382194">Ice Universe</a> claims that Samsung is preparing to launch its One UI 7 (Android 15) beta later in November (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/11/01/samsung-galaxy-android-15-beta-november/">9to5Google</a>). The tipster's post reads, "it will take another half month before Beta starts." As others on X have started to guess, that <em>could </em>put us around mid-November (fingers crossed).</p><p>While this might seem too good to be true, another tipster spotted more evidence.</p><p>Another tipster, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/tarunvats33/status/1852000525635539307">Tarun Vats</a>, discovered Samsung's official One UI 7 beta forum pages have started appearing. Samsung has placed forum pages for the Galaxy S24 and S23 series under its "One UI Beta Program" tag. Users chimed in, asking questions about specifics such as the timing for each Galaxy model. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/tarunvats33/status/1852002041792430157">Vats states</a> they "don't think" the One UI 7 beta will begin simultaneously for the S24 and the S23.</p><p>It's unclear how much of an increased delay the past-gen series could see if this proves true. Additionally, Vats states these forum pages have appeared on Samsung's U.S. community forums, furthering suspicions behind an upcoming Public Beta start for One UI 7.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Breaking News 💥One UI 7 beta for the Galaxy S24/S23 series is confirmed, as the Beta forum page has been created for it.Repost 🔁#OneUI7 #GalaxyS24 #GalaxyS23 #Samsung pic.twitter.com/0RFTHRS9Yn<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1852000525635539307">October 31, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>With Samsung's forum pages reportedly created for the S24 and S23 series, the company might hit that "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-plans-one-ui-7-public-beta">later this year</a>" estimation for the beta. Samsung's Sally Hyesoon Jeong appeared at SDC 2024 where they stated users could "preview" the software in an upcoming beta. While a test period for developers was confirmed, regular users will have a chance once a "schedule is confirmed" by Samsung.</p><p>Seeing how the rumors have progressed, perhaps there's hope that a confirmed schedule will be shared soon.</p><p>Samsung's One UI 7 experienced a more substantial delay than we expected. While the update isn't expected until next year <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-confirms-one-ui-7-wont-hit-beta-until-end-of-this-year">with the Galaxy S25 series</a>, the company demoed the software <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-one-ui-7-changes-teased-sdc-2024">during SDC 2024</a>. The major OS upgrade was shown off on a Galaxy S24 Ultra, shedding light on a change: the separation of its notification and Quick Settings panels. It seems users may have to swipe on the left or right side of their device to access either panel.</p><p>That demo also clued us into the Apple-like vibes Samsung is pushing for with One UI 7 and its UI changes. However, 9to5 highlights Samsung's next <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.sdc-korea.com/">SDC event in Korea</a> on November 21. There's a chance that we'll either hear more about One UI 7 there or, perhaps, that'll kick off its beta.</p><p>More recently, a massive One UI 7 leak surfaced, showing Samsung's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/huge-one-ui-7-samsung-parent-ai-features-leak">parental and AI-focused features</a>. It seems parents will have more built-in ways of protecting their children from harmful online content on their Galaxy devices. Samsung isn't letting go of AI advancements as the leak showed One UI 7 may incorporate Circle to Search and tools to enhance photography.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-one-ui-7-android-15-beta-impending-arrival</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ After official forum pages were discovered, Samsung was rumored to be coming up on its One UI 7 beta start. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">oadLwTQ7Me8Xi9waCxDb8e</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yFmLhsbp8G89X6TVQ6Twh5.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 17:35:42 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yFmLhsbp8G89X6TVQ6Twh5.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Galaxy S24 family including the smaller Galaxy S24, larger Galaxy S24 Plus, and premium Galaxy S24 Ultra]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Galaxy S24 family including the smaller Galaxy S24, larger Galaxy S24 Plus, and premium Galaxy S24 Ultra]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>