<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 16:33:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ AT&T's massive data breach exposed millions of customer data files on the dark web ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Data belonging to 73 million accounts, including current and former AT&T customers, was found on the dark web.</li><li>The leaked data include sensitive information like full names, contact details, and social security numbers, except for personal financial details and call history.</li><li>AT&T stated that there is no evidence of unauthorized access to its systems, which resulted in the extraction of the data set.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>AT&T has confirmed that it was hit by a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/carriers/atandt-data-breach-affects-9-million-customers">huge data breach</a>, affecting the personal information of 73 million current and former customers.</p><p>The US telco giant admitted in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://about.att.com/story/2024/addressing-data-set-released-on-dark-web.html" target="_blank">blog post</a> that over 7.6 million current customers and 65.4 million former customers had their data floating around on the dark web due to the data leak.</p><p>For the active customers impacted, the company has gone ahead and reset their security passcodes. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/5g-att-wireless">AT&T</a> mentioned that the leaked data might include full names, email addresses, mailing addresses, phone numbers, social security numbers, birthdates, AT&T account numbers, and passcodes.</p><p>AT&T acknowledged the data leak after <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/03/30/att-reset-account-passcodes-customer-data/" target="_blank">TechCrunch</a> tipped it off about the vulnerability in its encrypted passcodes. These passcodes, usually four-digit numerical PINs, are used for security during phone calls with company support or in-store verification.</p><p>According to AT&T, the data was posted on the dark web about two weeks ago. The company stated that it seems to be from 2019 or earlier. AT&T also said it&apos;s not sure if the information in those fields came from AT&T directly or from one of its vendors.</p><p>Fortunately, it doesn&apos;t include personal financial details or call history. AT&T is contacting affected customers via email or letter to inform them about the data involved and what steps they&apos;re taking to help them out.</p><p>"AT&T does not have evidence of unauthorized access to its systems resulting in exfiltration of the data set," the company said.</p><p>The data breach came to light when a hacker shared a small sample of the leaked data back in 2021. Then, two weeks ago, a data seller put up details of all 73 million compromised accounts on a cybercrime forum. Customers confirmed that the information was theirs. This marks the first time AT&T has formally recognized the data breach.</p><p>AT&T has created an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.att.com/support/article/my-account/000101995?bypasscache=1/?source=EPcc000000000000U" target="_blank">FAQ page</a> and recommends customers set up free fraud alerts from credit bureaus like Equifax, Experian, and TransUnion. It&apos;s also collaborating with external cybersecurity experts to look into the matter.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/carriers/73-million-atandt-accounts-leaked</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ AT&T is investigating a massive data leak that affected account details of current and former customers. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">aANhYzgbtFssCNHwoPGPRi</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RTNV7SdPpQbEd2EAcnjfWD.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 16:31:08 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Carriers]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RTNV7SdPpQbEd2EAcnjfWD.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[AT&amp;T storefront]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[AT&amp;T storefront]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ WhatsApp redesigns few features for better aesthetic and navigation ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>WhatsApp wants to make your thumb work less with the new update.</li><li>The navigation tools have now been moved to the bottom to make it more accessible.</li><li>The popular green hue across the app is also being replaced with white.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>If you are an Android WhatsApp user, you may have spotted changes on the messaging platform&apos;s home screen.</p><p>WhatsApp confirmed the changes via its X account over the weekend, which involves moving things a bit for easier access. With the new update, the Communities, Chats, Status, and Calls tabs that usually sit at the top of WhatsApp’s main screen have been moved to the bottom. The navigation tools have also been rearranged.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">android friends, we moved some things around to make it easier to access what you need, when you need it meet your new navigation tools 🤝 closer to your thumbs and easy on the eyes pic.twitter.com/CqLvZf9meo<a href="https://twitter.com/WhatsApp/status/1773427349532430714">March 28, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>The popular green hue associated with the navigation above tools was replaced with the white hue complementing the chat screen. The top part features the QR code scanner, camera icon, search icon, and overflow menu button, which also appear white.</p><p>WhatsApp says the new navigation tools are being moved to the bottom to make access more effortless, “closer to your thumbs and easy on the eyes.”</p><p>Users who want to see the new changes must be on WhatsApp’s latest <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.whatsapp&hl=en&gl=US"><strong>2.24.6.77 version</strong></a> on Google Play Store. The app’s “what’s new” section indicates the rollout of the new navigation tools, which is seen with the new update along with the “screen sharing during video calls now supports sharing audio too” feature. However, users are expected to see the changes in the coming weeks.</p>
<p>WhatsApp on iOS has implemented the navigation bar change a long time ago, and it is encouraging to see <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phone</a> users adopting the same aesthetic. </p><p>The Meta-owned messaging platform has been trying to stay relevant with the competition and has constantly made nifty new changes over the past few months. Recently, WhatsApp was found to be adding a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/whatsapp-to-add-one-minute-video-status-updates">new feature</a> that lets users post up to one-minute-long videos as status updates, which was previously limited to 30 seconds. The ability is quite similar to what we are used to on Instagram.  </p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/whatsapp-moves-navigation-tools-to-bottom</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ WhatsApp is constantly making and testing changes to its app over the past few months; a new one now wants to make it more accessible. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">kgpr9camzMci9YBPd23dWL</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TvZiRZSruCSJMJF38W3JoS.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 14:26:50 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TvZiRZSruCSJMJF38W3JoS.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[WhatsApp logo on an Android phone]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[WhatsApp logo on an Android phone]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ YouTube wants to show you Shorts in more places on the web ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>After recently announcing YouTube Shorts nets over 70B daily views, YouTube is testing  Shorts in the recommended sidebar. </li><li>YouTube Shorts have started to appear in the recommended sidebar on the web for a limited number of accounts in the form of a carousel. </li><li>The new Shorts carousel takes up about two to three times the space of a typical YouTube video in the sidebar and can show up to three videos at once. </li></ul>
<hr>
<p>YouTube celebrated the success of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-shorts-remix-music-video-rollout">YouTube Shorts</a> last week, sharing that Shorts get over 70 billion views per day in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.youtube/inside-youtube/shorts-revenue-sharing-update/" target="_blank">blog post</a>. YouTube might be trying to continue that growth by putting Shorts in new places, because it is testing a Shorts carousel in YouTube&apos;s recommended sidebar on the web. For some accounts, YouTube is showing up to three Shorts at a time in the sidebar instead of regular videos, as spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidpolice.com/youtube-testing-new-shorts-carousel-placement-web/" target="_blank">Android Police</a>. </p><p>The feature is far from widely available, and it may be limited to certain accounts in its early stages. Android Central tested YouTube on a few different devices, browsers, and YouTube accounts but hasn&apos;t spotted the Shorts carousel yet. In fact, Android Police was only able to spot the carousel on one of its writers&apos; accounts. The expansion of Shorts to YouTube&apos;s recommended sidebar could be a small test and nothing more, so you might not ever end up seeing it. </p><p>The new version of YouTube recommended shows one traditional video at the top of the list. Under that is the Shorts carousel, which displays up to three videos at a time. Since Shorts are obviously taller, they take up the space of about two or three horizontal videos. This has the potential to be visually jarring because the Shorts carousel is much larger than the horizontal videos. </p><p>It&apos;s easy to ignore the sidebar when it is composed of many smaller videos. Still, when the Shorts carousel is much closer to the size of the currently playing video, that becomes more difficult. Perhaps that is the goal, and YouTube wants users to stop watching the now-playing video in favor of YouTube Shorts.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="wnGHXbATC9VGxp8ArJ83fg" name="YouTube-Shorts-Carousel-Android-Police.jpg" alt="The new YouTube Shorts carousel on the web." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wnGHXbATC9VGxp8ArJ83fg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Police)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>There doesn&apos;t appear to be a way to hide the Shorts carousel as of now. Entering theater mode doesn&apos;t completely remove the carousel. Instead, it simply moves it down under the widescreen video player. However, using theater mode does make the Shorts carousel less distracting, for what it&apos;s worth. </p><p>A handful of social media companies are racing to win the vertical video space, and competition is fiercer than ever. As a potential TikTok ban takes shape in the U.S., alternatives like YouTube Shorts or Instagram Reels have the chance to snap up market share. </p><p>If you have the new YouTube Shorts carousel, you&apos;ll start seeing vertical videos in the recommended sidebar while watching regular YouTube videos. If not, you&apos;ll have to wait and see whether this UI element rolls out more widely. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-wants-to-show-you-shorts-in-more-places-on-the-web</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ YouTube is testing showing Shorts in the recommended sidebar in a small carousel, but it's only available for a limited number of users.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">DrJdfuMZZK4JtvjnBx7ijJ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oU5namDbUAVCZENPFa4Wrf.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 14:00:21 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oU5namDbUAVCZENPFa4Wrf.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[YouTube Shorts logo on a mobile phone]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[YouTube Shorts logo on a mobile phone]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ How to use Astrophotography mode on a Pixel ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Thanks to Astrophotography mode, you can get that perfect shot of the night sky without buying expensive photography cameras. You can skip the part where you must adjust the exposure, ISO, and other necessary settings by following the steps in this guide. Then, you can enjoy those fantastic night sky pictures. Keep reading to see how to use this helpful feature and remember the do&apos;s and don&apos;ts when using Astrophotography mode.</p>
<h2 id="astrophotography-mode-best-practices-2">Astrophotography mode: Best practices</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="HATWYPka9hCNg9ZSsZvzVm" name="Google-Pixel-7-Pro-hazel-taking-photo-camera-02.jpg" alt="Taking a photo with the Google Pixel 7 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HATWYPka9hCNg9ZSsZvzVm.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Taking the best pictures with Astrophotography mode involves more than just going to your backyard and snapping a few photos. You can use a phone tripod to get your desired angle and avoid unwanted movements to get the best shots. Winds can also cause your phone to move, making your images blurred on a windy day. So, to protect your PIxel from the winds, you can put it against a stable surface or protect it from the wind somehow.</p><p>It&apos;s best to avoid the city lights and have a clear sky, so the darker and clearer the sky, the better. Using a light pollution app will also be of great help. Remember to reduce the screen brightness and turn on the dark theme option to reduce light pollution. You can use the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-weather-apps-android">best weather apps for Android</a> to know what day you can head out. If you can&apos;t get too far out, one crucial thing to remember is to prevent the light from getting into the frame.</p><p>It&apos;s also best to use a timer since even the slightest movements can affect the result. You can choose between three and ten seconds when you open the <strong>camera app > Go to Night Sight > Settings</strong> and choose a time option. It&apos;s best to select the three-second option. You can also use your smartwatch to control your phone&apos;s camera. You must install the camera app on your smartwatch and the Pixel for this to work.</p><p>Since you will be away from a wall socket, taking a power bank with you is also a good idea. We suggest the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/sharge-shargeek-170-power-bank-review">SHARGE Shargeek 170 power bank</a> or others that fall into the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-battery-packs">best portable and power banks</a> category. Waiting for the right time is also important since you should wait 45 to 90 minutes after sunset to get your pictures. If it&apos;s possible to wait for the moon to disappear, even better; that way, you get the darkest sky possible.</p><p>You can also try finding amazing landscapes with your pictures to get the best possible photo.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-use-astrophotography-mode-2">How to use Astrophotography mode</h2>
<p>When you&apos;re done with the setup and ready to use Astrophotography mode:</p><p>1. Open the <strong>camera app</strong>.</p><p>2. Swipe right and choose <strong>Night Sight</strong>. For Astrophotography mode to activate, you have to keep your phone still. You&apos;ll know that your Pixel phone is in Astrophotography mode because the moon icon will turn into stars.</p><p>3. Tap the <strong>star shutter button</strong> and wait for the countdown to finish. The time you see will depend on how dark it is; the darker it is, the longer the countdown will be, but it will be no more than four minutes. You can also stop the countdown early if you don&apos;t have time to wait for it to finish.</p><p>If you cannot see the star shutter button, you can check if the Astrophotography mode option is set to Auto by tapping the settings cog at the bottom left and choosing the auto option.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2160px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:111.11%;"><img id="QCcUCEZXAT8h3KcDtiPBoJ" name="Steps-Enable-Astrophotography-mode-Pixel.jpg" alt="Steps to enable Astrophotography Mode on a Pixel" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QCcUCEZXAT8h3KcDtiPBoJ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="2160" height="2400" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>You can also use the time-lapse feature when using Astrophotography mode. To turn this on, go to the camera app&apos;s settings. The feature is on by default, but here are the steps just in case you turned it off and can&apos;t remember the steps to enable it again. </p><p>1. Tap <strong>More settings</strong>.</p><p>2. Choose the <strong>Advanced option</strong>.</p><p>3. Look for the option to <strong>enable time-lapse for astrophotography</strong> and toggle it on. Whenever you want to turn it off, follow the same steps.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2016px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:111.31%;"><img id="Uac4kcMP6fajChjPUHwmCZ" name="Astrophotography-mode-Pixel-Settings.jpg" alt="Pixel camera settings showing time lapse option" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Uac4kcMP6fajChjPUHwmCZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="2016" height="2244" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nick Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<h2 id="keep-capturing-the-stars-2">Keep capturing the stars</h2>
<p>Whether it&apos;s the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-pro-review">Google Pixel 8 Pro</a> or not, when your Pixel is in Astrophotography mode, it&apos;ll take 16 16-second pictures when the shutter is activated. With the Astro-lapse feature, you get a one-second time-lapse of those gorgeous stars. You can use other fantastic features on your Pixel, such as the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-video-boost-pixel-8-pro">Video Boost on the Pixel 8 Pro</a>. </p><p>You might not get the perfect picture on the first try, but take advantage of the peace your surroundings give you, and hopefully, you&apos;ll get it shortly after. After that, you&apos;ll have a picture you may even use as your wallpaper to remember that amusing image.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block" data-id="19c46cdd-632c-45d9-aa0f-2259936991c0">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GUWyZjgsTsmWu9xWniJ5sb.jpg' alt='google pixel 8 pro square press render'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 8 Pro</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="90" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Cream of the crop</strong></em></p>
<p>Enjoy other Pixel photography features, such as its 50MP primary camera, which has 21% more light sensitivity than its predecessor. The primary camera also comes with Dual Exposure, which gives you sharper videos. You'll also get a selfie camera with autofocus, and you can manually change the shutter speed, ISO, and focus.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-astrophotography-mode-google-pixel</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ With Astrophotography mode, you can seize the moment of that unforgettable night sky with this beginner-friendly guide. Thanks to your Pixel, ensure you don't forget how the night sky looked. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">P48D2qgZkm3WdtdfzbE6WT</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ranYPSWZK7J6rgXNqzhDzh.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 12:00:34 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ judysanhz30@gmail.com (Judy Sanhz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ranYPSWZK7J6rgXNqzhDzh.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Photo of the stars taken from a Google Pixel 8 using astrophotography mode]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Photo of the stars taken from a Google Pixel 8 using astrophotography mode]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Chat is prepping a WhatsApp-like broadcast feature ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google is planning to add support for broadcast messaging, which will make Google Chat more like competitors Slack and WhatsApp. </li><li>The new feature, called "Announcements," will presumably allow users to pick and choose who can send messages in large groups.</li><li>It appears to be similar to Channels on WhatsApp, and could make Google Chat a more feasible option for workplace communication. </li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Broadcast messaging is becoming an increasingly popular way to connect with a large number of users without groups turning into a frenzy. Social media features like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/x-twitter-video-option-spaces-rollout">X (formerly Twitter) Spaces</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/whatsapp-channels-gain-new-features">WhatsApp Channels</a> limit who can speak or chat while allowing select users to communicate with a massive audience. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-chat-voice-messages-mobile-rollout">Google Chat</a> appears to be taking note of these successful features and is preparing one of its own. It&apos;s called "Announcements," and it will make broadcast messaging possible on the platform.</p><p>Longtime Android dissector <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://twitter.com/AssembleDebug/status/1773706508293091413?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1773706508293091413%7Ctwgr%5E9560aac26c6408abeb348856bd54fd0e10101a2d%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.androidpolice.com%2Fgoogle-chat-steal-whatsapp-announcement-channels-feature%2F" target="_blank">AssembleDebug on X</a> gave us our first look at the Announcements feature in Google Chat (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidpolice.com/google-chat-steal-whatsapp-announcement-channels-feature/" target="_blank">Android Police</a>). We don&apos;t know exactly how Announcements will work yet, but we have a good idea. Right now, there is only one type of Google Chat space, and it allows for collaborative groups. With this new feature, Google Chat users will be able to choose whether their space is for collaboration or announcements. </p><p>Collaboration spaces allow Google Chat users to "collaborate on project, plans, or topics [and] easily share files, assign tasks, and organize your conversations by threads." By comparison, the new Announcements spaces will make it possible for Google Chat users to "broadcast and share updates with your group. </p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Google Chat is working on a new "Announcements" feature which will allow you to "Broadcast and share updates with your groups"There isn't much info about it yet.#GappsLeaks #Android pic.twitter.com/gW8leE24kq<a href="https://twitter.com/AssembleDebug/status/1773706508293091413">March 29, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>The new Announcements feature will almost certainly make it possible to limit who can post in a Google Chat space. What&apos;s unclear is whether more than one person can make announcements in an Announcements space or if it&apos;ll be limited to just the creator. Assuming that Google wants to make Google Chat an alternative to current broadcast messaging platforms, it&apos;ll need that level of curation. </p><p>There are a handful of apps and services that Google could be trying to beat with the Announcements feature in Google Chat. Consumer-level apps like WhatsApp, Discord, and Telegram all have similar functionality to Google Chat spaces. Additionally, there are workplace-grade apps such as Slack and Microsoft Teams. Considering that Google has plenty of business-oriented apps in Google Workspace, it wouldn&apos;t be surprising for the company to want to bring everything under one roof.</p><p>Still, we&apos;ll have to wait and see what Google Chat Announcements are really like when they debut and whether people want to use them. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-chat-developing-announcements-feature</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google Chat wants you to share messages with groups easily with a new "Announcements" feature, which is like Channels on WhatsApp.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">DgbNT4dMDx2wU3oyEqquL</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pTFT5tahw4qCHXi2NqSn5M.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 01:00:24 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pTFT5tahw4qCHXi2NqSn5M.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Chat overflow menu on mobile]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Chat overflow menu on mobile]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Next POCO smartphone could draw its power from a Snapdragon 8s Gen 3 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>POCO's next release, the POCO F6, is rumored to include the Snapdragon 8s Gen 3 SoC, positioning it as a strong competitor among Android phones this year.</li><li>Xiaomi's confirmation of a device powered by the Snapdragon 8s Gen 3 SoC aligns with rumors suggesting it will be the POCO F6, offering flagship-like performance at a lower cost.</li><li>Camera details for the POCO F6 hint at a 50MP Sony sensor for the main camera and an 8MP Sony ultra-wide lens.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>A new leak has shed light on the specs of POCO&apos;s next flagship model, boasting a mighty processor, and it&apos;s shaping up to be a solid contender for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">leading Android phones</a> this year.</p><p>POCO is presumably getting ready to roll out its next F-series phone, the POCO F6. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.gizmochina.com/2024/03/17/redmi-note-13-turbo-poco-f6-may-feature-the-new-snapdragon-8s-gen-3-chip/" target="_blank">Rumor</a> has it that this device might also debut as a new Redmi Note model, possibly called the Redmi Note 13 Turbo in China.</p><p>Xiaomi previously confirmed that it will <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-snapdragon-8s-gen-3-announced">release a device powered by the Snapdragon 8s Gen 3 SoC</a>, and a new report from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidheadlines.com/2024/03/poco-f6-camera-processor-specs-leak" target="_blank">Android Headlines</a> suggests this model is the POCO F6.</p><p>The Snapdragon 8s Gen 3 might not match the raw power of the regular <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-3">Snapdragon 8 Gen 3</a>, but it&apos;s pretty close and comes at a lower cost for OEMs. Considering POCO&apos;s strong emphasis on budget-friendly options, this choice shouldn&apos;t come as a big surprise.</p><p>The Xiaomi Civi 4 Pro is the first smartphone to feature the Snapdragon 8s Gen 3 chipset, hitting store shelves in China not too long ago. POCO&apos;s global executive David Liu recently shared via a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://twitter.com/DavidBlueLS/status/1770705943057068190" target="_blank">post on X</a> (formerly Twitter) that a global edition of the Civi 4 Pro will also pack the same processor. This adds weight to the latest rumor about the processor for the upcoming POCO F6.</p><p>This won&apos;t be POCO&apos;s first rodeo with slapping a top-tier processor onto its phones. The Chinese brand has a history of equipping its phones with top-tier chipsets, as seen with the POCO F5 Pro&apos;s Snapdragon 8 Plus Gen 1, while the standard <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/poco-f5-and-f5-pro-announcementhttps://www.androidcentral.com/phones/poco-f5-review">POCO F5</a> had the Snapdragon 7 Plus Gen 2.</p><p>However, it&apos;s still up in the air whether we&apos;ll see a Pro edition of the POCO F6 series running on the beefier Snapdragon 8 Gen 3.</p><p>Turning our attention to the rear of the phone, the main camera is said to sport a 50MP Sony sensor, accompanied by an 8MP Sony ultra-wide lens. There&apos;s talk of a third camera, similar to the macro lens in the Poco F5, but details on that for the F6 are still under wraps.</p><p>The global launch of the POCO F6 is expected to take place in April or May, following the introduction of its Redmi counterpart in China, expected in early April.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/poco-f6-specs-may-have-leaked</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Specs of the POCO F6 may have leaked, and it might shake things up with the big boys this year. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">nWjcchvt4QSSs4tyMCxMZi</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DJkc46ho3dVwrkqEBpz73M.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 19:35:30 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DJkc46ho3dVwrkqEBpz73M.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Poco F5 back panel showing the Poco logo]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Poco F5 back panel showing the Poco logo]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google confirms it's still working to support your old Nest cameras in Google Home ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>In a recent Reddit AMA, one of Google's product managers for Google Home and Nest confirmed that the company is still trying to support old Nest cameras in Google Home.</li><li>Google cited the difficulties of supporting devices that were released as far back as 2015 with new software.</li><li>Still, the product manager said that Google is committed to adding support for these older cameras. </li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Itching for your older Nest cameras to be supported in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-home-app-2023-availability">Google Home app</a>? While there&apos;s still time to wait, you can rest assured that Google is working on supporting Nest cameras in Google Home. In a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/google-home-team-ama-reddit-recap">recent AMA on Reddit</a>, members of the Google Home and Nest software team answered a variety of questions directly from users. At least a few users asked about older Nest cameras getting software support, and Google responded. </p><p>"On it – we&apos;re working on bringing support for older generation Nest cameras to the Google Home app," said one of Google&apos;s product managers for Google Home and Nest, identified as Emily. "Stay tuned!"</p><p>That doesn&apos;t give us anything as far as a timeline for support, but it may be helpful for Nest users to know that support is still in the works. Right now, if you use a blend of Google Home and Nest products, your devices may be split between the Google Home and Nest apps. This isn&apos;t a great user experience, but it&apos;s something that Google is actively trying to fix. </p>
<blockquote class="reddit-card"  ><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/googlehome/comments/1bpxro1/comment/kx01ddc">Comment</a> from <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/googlehome">r/googlehome</a></blockquote><script async src="//embed.redditmedia.com/widgets/platform.js" charset="UTF-8"></script>
<p>The product manager noted the difficulties that come with supporting Nest cameras that may be nearly a decade old. The first Nest Cam was revealed in June 2015, followed by the Nest Cam Outdoor in July 2016. </p><p>"Updating firmware and software of older devices - some of which were launched back in 2015 - is a significant technical challenge that we’re committed to doing," Emily wrote.</p><p>However, some of these older cameras already work in the Google Home app. Last year, Google added <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/new-google-home-app-nest-cam-indoor">support for the Nest Cam Indoor and Nest Cam Outdoor</a> in Google Home. Users could port their cameras from the Nest app to the Google Home app with relative easy, and go back to Nest if they didn&apos;t like the new experience. Select older Nest cameras were still unsupported, though. </p><p>The comments from Google&apos;s product manager are interesting because the company has already overcome the hurdle of supporting its oldest cameras. The camera from 2015 referenced in the Reddit comment is the Nest Cam Indoor, which is supported in Google Home. The Nest Cam Outdoor, the company&apos;s second-oldest camera, is supported as well. </p><p>Newer cameras, like the Nest Cam IQ from 2017 and the Nest Hello Doorbell from 2018, are the ones that remain unsupported. </p><p>Aside from a few exceptions, Google&apos;s long-term goal is to support all Nest products with Google Home. While the process is moving somewhat slowly, Google has reiterated that it is still ongoing. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/google-home-older-nest-cam-support-coming</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google bought Nest years ago, and is trying its best to phase out the Nest app in favor of Google Home. But some old cameras are still unsupported, and the company is still aiming to fix that.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">AD36VkqCbsJducLLArJCY6</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vNTQGfw3LDKjVen44Kbgt5.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 19:34:54 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Smart Home]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vNTQGfw3LDKjVen44Kbgt5.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Nest Cam Indoor (1st Gen) with its box in the background]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Nest Cam Indoor (1st Gen) with its box in the background]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ New Motorola Edge 50 Ultra leak reveals an attractive flagship ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-32">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Motorola has an Ultra model in the pipeline in its Edge 50 series.</li><li>The renders and some marketing teasers of the Edge 50 Ultra have leaked.</li><li>The launch of the device is expected alongside the Edge 50 Pro and the Edge 50 Fusion in April.</li><li>The device is expected to be powered with the latest Snapdragon 8s Gen 3 SoC.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Motorola is gearing up for its Edge 50 series launch in multiple regions in the early first week of April. The Ultra model has shown up online through a couple of leaks ahead of the launch.</p><p>The upcoming Edge 50 series will likely have at least three models in the lot, with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-edge-50-pro-launching-on-april-3-2024">Motorola Edge 50 Pro</a> and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-edge-50-fusion-launch-april-3-2024">Edge 50 Fusion</a> models already appearing — thanks to some confirmation from the company and a few renders here and there. However, a new leak from Evan Blass and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidheadlines.com/2024/03/exclusive-leak-motorola-edge-50-ultra.html">Android Headlines</a> showcases the upcoming Edge 50 Ultra in all its glory.</p>
<p>Blass has <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1774263867872285030">posted multiple videos</a> of what appears to be the Edge 50 Ultra&apos;s marketing material ahead of its release on X. The first one in the lot confirms the slightly curved display accompanied by very minimal bezels and a thinner middle frame. </p><p>The design reminds us of the older Galaxy S10 series at first glance. On the back, however, it sports a textured finish, and the protruding camera housing blends into the rear frame seamlessly, mirroring the company&apos;s updated design language as seen on phones like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/moto-g-power-5g-2024-review">Moto G 5G 2024</a>.</p><p>The housing in the back features three cameras, and a selfie shooter is spotted on the punch-hole display on the front. The second teaser from Blass highlights the Edge 50 Ultra&apos;s beautiful bright display alongside the device&apos;s stereo speaker setup — as speaker grilles can be seen on the top and bottom panes of the Ultra phone. </p><p>The other three videos, however, indicate that the device will have solid display protection, water resistance, and some skin tone enhancements, the latter of which is expected to be a significant camera feature on the Edge 50 Ultra. The triple camera setup will allegedly include a 50MP primary accompanied by a periscopic lens, a secondary camera, and a laser autofocus between the sensors. </p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="JRFw9yUdKJVe3uhvRBXy4d" name="motorola-edge-50-ultra-render-03.jpeg" alt="Motorola Edge 50 Ultra render" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JRFw9yUdKJVe3uhvRBXy4d.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="GmsVN3zjABLsaT2LQJ6DUc" name="motorola-edge-50-ultra-render-02.jpeg" alt="Motorola Edge 50 Ultra render" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GmsVN3zjABLsaT2LQJ6DUc.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="shCtkTbwQFbfqU7DKK5tMc" name="motorola-edge-50-ultra-render-01.jpeg" alt="Motorola Edge 50 Ultra render" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/shCtkTbwQFbfqU7DKK5tMc.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Meanwhile, Android Headlines also shared the Motorola Edge 50 Ultra renders that reveal some high-quality images of the device showcasing from all angles. The Ultra is expected to sport in three colorways: Peach Fuzz, Black, and Light Beige. The first two will likely have a vegan leather finish, and the Light Beige will be seen in some textured finish. </p><p>According to Android Headlines, the Motorola Edge 50 Ultra will be powered by the latest Qualcomm <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-snapdragon-8s-gen-3-announced">Snapdragon 8s Gen 3</a> SoC that sits right under the flagship <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-3-launch">Snapdragon 8 Gen 3</a>, powering most <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phones</a> this year. This could point to a reasonably priced flagship from Motorola as well as a new AI focus.</p><p>The device is expected to be announced in April alongside the other models, with speculation pointing to April 3, 2024, when the Edge 50 Pro is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://twitter.com/motorolaindia/status/1771786525254045866">set to launch with a new Hello UI</a> for Android 14. This is also partly based on the date seen on the home screen (although this date appears on most <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-motorola-phones">Motorola phone</a> renders, so take that with a grain of salt). Additionally, the availability of regions may vary, and the Edge 50 Ultra is also expected to be named the X50 Ultra in some regions. </p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-edge-50-ultra-leak</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Motorola is having an exciting launch in the early week of April as not one but three models are expected. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">WbXzLCcWW7gXAjPbc6izqR</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/scHcPa5APSzZHX7Hc27apc.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 19:22:23 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/scHcPa5APSzZHX7Hc27apc.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Headlines]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Motorola Edge 50 Ultra render]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Motorola Edge 50 Ultra render]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Garmin adds a ton of new features and bug fixes in latest beta ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-37">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Garmin has released a beta update (version 17.10) for several smartwatches, introducing numerous changes.</li><li>The beta is available for models like the Fenix 7/7 Pro, Fenix 7s/7s Pro, Fenix 7x/7x Pro, Epix/Epix Pro Gen 2 (in various sizes), Enduro 2, MARQ Gen 2, and Quatix 7.</li><li>Notably, the beta temporarily disables the ECG feature on the Fenix 7 series.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Garmin has released a fresh beta update for a bunch of its smartwatches, packing in loads of changes.</p><p>The smartwatch maker <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://forums.garmin.com/beta-program/fenix-7-series/f/announcements/365294/beta-version-17-10---check-for-updates-only" target="_blank">announced</a> that beta version 17.10 is up for grabs for a bunch of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-garmin-smartwatchhttps://www.androidcentral.com/best-garmin-smartwatch">Garmin watches</a> like the Fenix 7/7 Pro, Fenix 7s/7s Pro, Fenix 7x/7x Pro, Epix/Epix Pro Gen 2 (in 42mm / 47mm / 51mm sizes), Enduro 2, MARQ Gen 2, and Quatix 7 (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.notebookcheck.net/Garmin-adds-dozens-of-new-features-and-bug-fixes-to-current-flagship-smartwatches-with-new-update.820399.0.html" target="_blank">NotebookCheck</a>). But if you&apos;re rocking a Garmin MARQ Aviator Gen 2 or Tactix 7, you&apos;re not in on the beta party.</p><p>Garmin has dropped a hefty changelog for version 17.10 beta, packed with tons of fresh features and some tweaks to make things better.</p>
<ul><li>Added ability to find a lost phone during an activity with GPS.</li><li>Added Applied Ballistics Wind Mode (Tactix only).</li><li>Added Indoor Walk activity.</li><li>Added Messenger App.</li><li>Added Recovery Advisor as an option in Morning Report and glances.</li><li>Added self evaluation to more activity types.</li><li>Fixed battery saver mode being allowed as a power mode name.</li><li>Fixed incorrect DSW on watch face.</li><li>Fixed issue causing the cadence flashlight to enable incorrectly when in an activity resume later state.</li><li>Fixed issue with ski run count in the Last Sport glance.</li><li>Fixed issue with the altimeter glance when in large font mode.</li><li>Fixed issues with Morning Report workouts page.</li><li>Fixed issues with some watch face data fields.</li><li>Fixed potential issue causing the touchscreen to not fully function after a display wakeup.</li><li>Fixed potential issue with the weather map overlay.</li><li>Fixed potential shutdown in morning report.</li><li>Fixed potential shutdown in the body battery widget when viewing near midnight.</li><li>Fixed potential shutdown when loading activity history with auto lock enabled.</li><li>Improved access to additional characters on the touch keyboard by adding a press and hold option to some keys.</li><li>Improved find my phone alert prompt UI.</li><li>Renamed Climb sport to Mountaineering.</li></ul>
<p>However, Garmin mentions that this beta will turn off the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/how-to-use-garmin-ecg-app">ECG (electrocardiogram) feature</a> in the Fenix 7 series. So, if you&apos;re all about those regular ECG checks, you might want to skip this update.</p><p>Nevertheless, according to Garmin, once this beta hits its final stage right before the official release, ECG functionality should come back online for the Fenix 7 series. The company assures us that ECG should function normally on other compatible models.</p><p>If you&apos;re part of Garmin&apos;s public beta program, you can snag version 17.10 beta by heading to <strong>Menu</strong> > <strong>System</strong> > <strong>Software Update</strong> and hitting <strong>Check For Updates</strong> on your watch.</p><p>Keep your eyes peeled towards the end of the public beta cycle because Garmin plans to start sending out beta updates through normal methods via OTA updates.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-adds-a-ton-of-new-features-and-bug-fixes</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Garmin just loaded its top smartwatches with a ton of new features and bug fixes in a new update. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">AtSBdwBkAQ66xpiT4pGboi</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gXzmbaMimETrWfx8HYe5pf.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 15:56:59 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gXzmbaMimETrWfx8HYe5pf.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Garmin]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Garmin Enduro 2 displaying different exercises on the watch screen]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Garmin Enduro 2 displaying different exercises on the watch screen]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ These are my favorite running and step-counting apps to keep me motivated ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Sunday Runday</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="rV2GgqHS9nqccNipGMkWqB" name="lloyd-break-dancing.jpg" caption="" alt="Lloyd, the Android Central mascot, break-dancing" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rV2GgqHS9nqccNipGMkWqB.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">In this <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/sunday-runday">weekly column</a>, Android Central Wearables Editor Michael Hicks talks about the world of wearables, apps, and fitness tech related to running and health, in his quest to get faster and more fit.</p></div></div>
<p>My high school running coach told me that music was a crutch. Well, I may as well have a broken leg, because even though I run or walk every day to stay fit and train for races, I couldn&apos;t do so without the best running apps or best step-counting apps motivating me to get out the door.</p><p>My coach never explained how adult responsibilities, a 40-hour workweek, and the temptation of video games would make finding the time and drive for running really difficult! When it comes to running that first 5K or hitting PR pace on a half marathon — which I did this month, proud to say — you&apos;ll want to find an app that inspires or shames you into ignoring other temptations and working out regularly.</p><p>Below, I&apos;ll focus on the running and step-tracking apps I use (or have used and enjoyed) that provide audio motivation, training planning (and shaming), social motivation, and everything else you need to improve as a runner, or simply to get healthier by walking enough steps every day.</p>
<h2 id="my-favorite-audio-motivation-apps-2">My favorite audio motivation apps</h2>
<p>I&apos;ll start with the obvious: A good music playlist is the difference between getting into the zone and feeling demoralized by your ragged, panting breath during hard runs. I&apos;m not going to advocate for a specific <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-streaming-music-apps-android">music streaming app</a>, but most of the big ones have curated workout playlists matched to specific heart rates or genres.</p><p>A running coach might tell you <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/the-running-blog/2013/mar/13/running-with-music-for-against" target="_blank">not to rely on music</a>, but I think it&apos;s fine if you use it safely — try bone conduction or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/earbuds/best-open-ear-earbuds">open-ear headphones</a> like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/shokz-openfit-review">Shokz OpenFit</a> so you hear your surroundings — and don&apos;t overtrain to match up-tempo songs. I try to curate my own hours-long playlists for different race lengths or training types, so I have a comfortable familiarity with what&apos;s coming instead of being thrown off by new, popular songs that aren&apos;t my cup of tea.</p><p>Beyond music, you might be surprised to learn that Audible is one of my most-used running companions. Whenever I&apos;m marathon training and upping my mileage, the daily hours on the trail can get dull after a while, and I use the time to sink into old favorites that will entertain but not distract. My Wheel of Time series re-listen has carried me through dozens of runs and post-run walks.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="GddrAViUHdPdpBZJD2au5c" name="marvel-move-promo-image.jpeg" alt="A promo image for ZRX's Marvel Move, showing famous Marvel heroes like Thor, the Hulk, Wolverine, Storm, Groot, Captain Marvel, Scarlet Witch, and Doctor Strange." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GddrAViUHdPdpBZJD2au5c.jpeg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: ZRX / Marvel)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>You can&apos;t go wrong with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/how-zombies-run-marvel-move-helped-me-hit-personal-best">Zombies, Run! and Marvel Move</a>. The decade-old app began with a simple premise — if you slow down, virtual zombies would scare you back on pace or "eat" you if you failed — but has added hundreds of audio-drama missions about post-apocalyptic survival as a runner. </p><p>More recently, they licensed Marvel missions where you&apos;re teamed up with Thor and Loki, the X-Men, and other popular heroes. I love using these missions for hard-paced tempo and track runs; while Audible is relaxing but can be distracting, these missions come in short bursts of entertainment that keep you in the zone, but don&apos;t overstay their welcome before switching back to your music. </p><p>Otherwise, if you&apos;re looking for more traditional audio coaching, I&apos;m not as familiar with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-couch-5k-apps">couch-to-5K apps</a> out there because I&apos;ve been running 5K+ for a couple of decades, but I&apos;ve heard very good things about <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://aaptiv.com/" target="_blank">Aaptiv&apos;s personalized coaching cues</a>.</p>
<h2 id="my-favorite-training-and-walking-apps-2">My favorite training and walking apps</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="dkaTFqngwaK6qVmVNPZkJd" name="Fitbit-Charge-6-hourly-activity.jpeg" alt="The hourly activity widget on the Fitbit Charge 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dkaTFqngwaK6qVmVNPZkJd.jpeg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>All the music and coaching apps above motivate you once you&apos;ve already decided to run. But for those exhausted days where slacking off sounds more appealing? You&apos;ll need some kind of positive (or negative) reinforcement to force yourself to gear up and step outside, whether for running or walking.</p><p>I&apos;m a fan of tracking systems like Fitbit&apos;s Active Zone Minutes or Garmin&apos;s Intensity Minutes, which give you a weekly goal to hit and a recommended daily workout, but take context into account and tell you to rest if you&apos;re physically exhausted. For comparison, a daily ring-closing system like Apple&apos;s or Samsung&apos;s will tell you to work out for 30 minutes without fail, even the day after a marathon, which makes me want to ignore it.</p><p>More specifically, I like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/stand-alerts-will-save-your-life-but-most-watch-brands-get-them-wrong">Fitbit&apos;s hourly move reminders</a>, which stop me from being too stiff and sedentary throughout the day. With Garmin, I use its watches&apos; daily suggested workouts to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/how-i-boosted-my-vo2-max-score-on-my-garmin-watch">boost my VO2 Max</a>, or my body&apos;s ability to convert oxygen into energy. I didn&apos;t like seeing my VO2 Max dipping low during the pandemic, so I followed its suggestions for track workouts and low aerobic runs until I had climbed five points from "Good" to "Excellent" for my age.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="NwYJLboggNAMCiwv4o72EV" name="Garmin-VO2-Max-chart.jpeg" alt="A VO2 Max chart on the Garmin Forerunner 965, showing a steady climb and a score of 49." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NwYJLboggNAMCiwv4o72EV.jpeg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Unfortunately, you need a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/which-garmin-forerunner-model-right-me">Garmin Forerunner watch</a> or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-fitbit">Fitbit tracker</a> to access these tools, and I want to focus on apps that anyone can use for motivation, regardless of which fitness watch you own. </p><p>I make a point to go out daily, whether for walks or runs, to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/i-walked-10000-steps-a-day-for-one-month">hit 10,000 steps a day</a> (or close to it). Sometimes, I&apos;ll feel too tired to run, but after starting a walk, I&apos;ll realize I <em>do</em> have enough energy. If I don&apos;t, I look to apps like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/fantasy-hike/id1557127861" target="_blank">Fantasy Hike</a> — a copyright-safe quest to walk to Mount <del>Doom</del> Fire like the Fellowship of the Ring — that make every step and mile feel meaningful, even if I&apos;m not running. I just wish it wasn&apos;t iOS-exclusive.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1056px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="8mb7FLB6qWk4nwFeAwnHya" name="Fantasy-Hike-promo-image.jpeg" alt=""Fantasy Hike: Walk to Mount Fire" promotional image on the Forge7 website for the walking app." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8mb7FLB6qWk4nwFeAwnHya.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1056" height="594" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Forge7)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.walkthedistance&hl=en_US&gl=US" target="_blank">Walk the Distance</a> doesn&apos;t have the fantasy hook, but the premise of adding up your miles and steps to have you virtually hike the Appalachian Trail and compete with other hikers should give Android and iOS users some nice motivation. </p><p>The same goes with cute apps like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.nianticlabs.pikmin&hl=en_US&gl=US" target="_blank">Pikmin Bloom</a>, where more steps equals more Pikmin companions in your team, or more general goal-setting apps like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.finch.finch&hl=en_US&gl=US" target="_blank">Finch</a> where you can take care of your pet by taking care of yourself. </p><p>Otherwise, I&apos;d say don&apos;t be afraid to go lo-fi for your training tracking. This year, I&apos;m using a Google doc to log how many runs, miles, and steps I&apos;ve completed per month to see if I&apos;m on track to hit my yearly goals. Not everything <em>needs</em> to go through a specific app!</p>
<h2 id="my-favorite-social-training-apps-2">My favorite social training apps</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3200px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="A3RqLHv9Ssu2dU4mCznxLY" name="strava-live-segments.jpeg" alt="Strava app showing Live Segment records" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/A3RqLHv9Ssu2dU4mCznxLY.jpeg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3200" height="1800" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It&apos;s hard to recommend any of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-running-apps-android">best running apps</a> because (A) they&apos;re all quite similar in what they offer, and (B) which you pick will depend on which app your fellow runners or walkers use. </p><p>Strava, MapMyRun, Runkeeper, Nike Run Club, and the rest have their strengths with community maps, live segments, leaderboards, coaching, running clubs, and so on. But it&apos;ll be a lonely experience if you pick the wrong app, so I&apos;d say wait to join your local in-person running club and see what they use.</p><p>I like Strava&apos;s focus on segments, which has you competing with local runners in both pace and number of times completed. I&apos;ve battled to be the local legend at the nearest track with a few other runners, for example, and I like competing against others (and myself) on the segments within my favorite running routes, since Strava has a partnership with Garmin to show Live Segments on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-forerunner-965-review">Forerunner 965</a>.</p>
<hr>
<p>I can&apos;t say for certain which app will work best for you. Some people need competition with friends (or strangers), while others prefer a game or fantasy scenario that makes every mile feel more meaningful. Beginner runners may need more in-depth coaching, while veteran runners will want AI-based training plans like Garmin Coach based on their fitness level.</p><p>What matters, in my mind, is that you need to find a concrete, positive goal. Simply telling yourself to walk or run every day will inevitably lead to you losing motivation or overtraining until you hurt yourself. </p><p>But if you&apos;re racing your loved ones to Mordor while working through your audiobook or podcast backlog, you&apos;re setting yourself up to succeed! Or for more serious runners, aiming for concrete fitness goals — like the most miles in your Strava group or a significant VO2 Max boost — is more likely to succeed than just trying to run hard every single day.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/my-favorite-running-and-walking-apps-for-motivation</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Whether you're looking for motivation to run your first 5K, hit a marathon PR pace, or just to walk enough steps every day to stay healthy, these are the apps I'd recommend. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">jPurJ8QXoQdySmvabwGbJ6</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/b9AuNgniECpxjapT9pxmNg.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 15:00:16 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/b9AuNgniECpxjapT9pxmNg.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Forge7]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Screenshots of the Fantasy Hike app]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Screenshots of the Fantasy Hike app]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>