<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 17:34:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Motorola Moto AI: Features, availability, and how to sign up for the beta ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Motorola is the latest Android OEM to dive into the AI space with its own collection of features that fall into its Moto AI suite. While these aren't the first AI features launched by Motorola, these new features under the Moto AI suite aim to help users navigate their lives by improving images and remembering/summarizing content on their devices.</p><p>Motorola phones have access to some of the best Google AI features like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-use-magic-editor-on-the-pixel-8">Magic Editor</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-circle-to-search">Circle to Search</a>, but Moto AI is the company's own take on some popular features specific to Motorola phones. The features are actually built using Google's AI, including Google Cloud Vertex AI, Gemini, and Imagen, thanks to a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/motorola-and-google-cloud-bring-generative-ai-to-new-razr-family-of-smartphones-302181887.html">multi-year partnership</a> between the two companies.</p><p>After teasing new features earlier this year, the Moto AI suite was <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/moto-ai-open-beta-program">released in beta</a> on select devices in November 2024. Users can test out the latest features and provide Motorola with feedback to help the company improve its AI efforts.</p><p>Here's everything you need to know about the new Moto AI suite, including the various features and available devices.</p>

<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-moto-ai-availability"><span>Moto AI: Availability</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="o5sMvGSFcxEQa2ffzxpYrP" name="Motorola-Razr-Plus-2024-review-19.jpg" alt="The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 main display" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/o5sMvGSFcxEQa2ffzxpYrP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While some Moto AI features are widely available across <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-motorola-phones">Motorola phones</a>, the select capabilities part of the Moto AI suite are only available on select devices. As of November 2024, the suite is available for beta testing on the following smartphones:</p>
<ul><li><strong>Motorola Edge 50 Ultra</strong></li><li><strong>Motorola Razr Plus 2024</strong>/<strong>Razr 50 Ultra</strong></li><li><strong>Motorola Razr 2024</strong>/<strong>Razr 50</strong></li></ul>
<p>Motorola has not said if it will expand the availability of these features to more devices, although we can likely expect them on future models.</p><p>While the beta program is available globally, Moto AI features are only available in English, Spanish, and Portuguese.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-moto-ai-features"><span>Moto AI: Features</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4156px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.26%;"><img id="pEASxtK2JCHbPBEaLFXnJ4" name="Moto-AI-Lenovo-Tech-World-2024.jpg" alt="A Motorola executive showcasing Moto AI on stage" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pEASxtK2JCHbPBEaLFXnJ4.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4156" height="2338" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Similar to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-galaxy-ai">Galaxy AI</a>, Moto AI is the backbone of a number of features found on Motorola phones. Some of these features are already available on some devices in an official capacity, including the following:</p>
<ul><li><strong>Magic Canvas</strong>: Lets users create images using a text-to-image generator that can be used as wallpapers.</li><li><strong>Style Sync</strong>: Generates a pattern that matches the color and style of images you take or upload.</li></ul>
<p>Moto AI also encompasses features used to enhance image capture on select devices. It powers the Photo Enhancement Engine on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2024-review">Razr Plus 2024</a>, which improves photos by preserving RAW image data when enhancing an image after it's taken. It also improves stabilization and optimizes shutter speed for features like Action Shot, which allows users to take photos of fast-moving subjects with greater clarity.</p><p><u><strong>Moto AI beta features</strong></u></p>
<ul><li><strong>Catch Me Up</strong>: Moto AI will summarize missed calls and messages from <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-text-messaging-apps">messaging apps</a> like Google Messages, WhatsApp, Telegram, and more so that you can quickly understand the gist of what's happening in conversations you may have missed.</li><li><strong>Remember This</strong>: Save screenshots, notes, and images to your Journal with AI-generated summaries and object recognition technology so that you can recall them later.</li><li><strong>Pay Attention</strong>: Records conversations, then transcribes and summarizes them.</li></ul>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="LhxZfoegFP7HRBorbm8PG9" name="Moto-AI-Catch-Me-Up-Lenovo-Tech-World-2024-2.jpg" alt="Moto AI features demonstrated on a phone" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LhxZfoegFP7HRBorbm8PG9.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<ul><li><strong>Journal</strong>: Where content from Remember this and Pay Attention is saved. The Journal is accessible via the app drawer and syncs to Google Drive.</li><li><strong>Search Bar</strong>: Accessible via the app tray, floating bubble, or Quick Launch. Can be used to answer questions, access the Journal, and search the web. It can also be used to provide quick access to Moto AI features.</li><li><strong>App Tray</strong>: Receives a redesign with three sections: Apps, Newsfeed, and Journal.</li></ul>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1050px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:29.62%;"><img id="cqZmprwQ6tLJt8oHMkW744" name="Moto-AI-search-bar" alt="Moto AI search bar" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/cqZmprwQ6tLJt8oHMkW744.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1050" height="311" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>As far as data and privacy, Motorola states that your personal data is saved on-device, but some of it may be shared with the cloud and "into an LLM," noting that the data is encrypted. Here, it will be processed to help generate summaries and descriptions, which will be sent back to the device where it is stored locally, privately, and securely.</p><p>Motorola ensures that the data is not saved in the cloud after it's processed and that it "will only retain your personal information as long as necessary to achieve proper performance of the product or service or other compelling purposes, and to securely delete personal data when those purposes of use have been satisfied."</p><p>You can visit Motorola's device <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://help.motorola.com/hc/apps/privacy/motoai/en-us/">Privacy Statement</a> for more details.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-moto-ai-large-action-model"><span>Moto AI: Large Action Model</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4036px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="jQV4BRQTfi8sEMHUzn3s5" name="Moto-AI-LAM-Uber-Lenovo-Tech-World-2024.jpg" alt="Moto AI features demonstrated on a phone" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jQV4BRQTfi8sEMHUzn3s5.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4036" height="2270" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In addition to the Moto AI features currently available, Motorola has also shown off its concept for what it's calling a "Large Action Model" or LAM. As <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/motorola-is-testing-ai-that-skips-words-and-gets-straight-to-doing-what-you-ask">demonstrated at Lenovo Tech World 2024</a>, the LAM learns a user's behavior and preferences so that it can perform actions with very little input from the user.</p><p>For example, when prompted to order a coffee, the LAM will automatically locate a nearby coffee shop and go through the motions of ordering your preferred drink. The only input from the user will be to confirm the order. You can also prompt the LAM by telling it where you want to go, and it will order an Uber.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aDNuOvoXdww" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>For now, the LAM is just a proof of concept, and Motorola has not disclosed if or when it will launch on devices. Like the new suite of Moto AI features, we can probably expect this to land in beta before becoming more widely available.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-moto-ai-how-to-sign-up-for-the-beta"><span>Moto AI: How to sign up for the beta</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="95fQ6xFnWxGoi2jd75m5QQ" name="Motorola-logo-wide.jpg" alt="Motorola logo" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/95fQ6xFnWxGoi2jd75m5QQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>For anyone with an eligible Motorola phone, you can sign up for the Moto AI beta via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.motorola.com/us/moto-ai">Motorola's website</a>. You can also visit the Google Play Store and enroll in the beta via the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.motorola.uxcore&hl=en_US">Moto AI Play Store page</a>.</p><p>1. Search "<strong>Moto AI</strong>" on the Google Play Store.</p><p>2. Scroll down and tap <strong>Join</strong>. Then confirm you want to enter the beta program by tapping <strong>Join</strong> again.</p><p>3. Wait as you're enrolled. Once you finish enrolling, you may have to <strong>update Moto AI (Beta)</strong> on the Play Store.</p>
<p>After Moto AI is updated, you'll be prompted to take a tour of the new features when you open the app tray. You will also find the Moto AI option in the settings menu for making changes to the search bar, smart tabs, and more. <strong>Note</strong>: You may have to log into your Moto Account to use the Moto AI features. You can do so in the settings menu.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/motorola-moto-ai</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Motorola's Moto AI is expanding with a suite of new features available now for beta testing. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">4BFNDnnMc2uGWE2xzD59DZ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GHUdW3V8ETfSKaSvqyKesj.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 17:19:48 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ derrek.lee@futurenet.com (Derrek Lee) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GHUdW3V8ETfSKaSvqyKesj.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Moto AI features demonstrated on a phone]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Moto AI features demonstrated on a phone]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Android XR is a new OS built with Gemini and made for VR, AR headsets and glasses ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google and Samsung partnered to create a new version of Android, called Android XR, that will power a new generation of extended-reality wearables.</li><li>Android XR is launching today as a developer preview, and the first hardware products powered by the new OS are set to launch in 2025.</li><li>Samsung will make the first headset powered by Android XR, condemned Project Moohan, next year.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Three years ago, Google and Samsung teamed up to build a new software platform for wearables: <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/wear-os-5">Wear OS</a>. Now, the developer of Android and the largest Android manufacturer are joining forces once again to build a new operating system from the ground up. It's called Android XR, and with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini</a> at the core, Google and Samsung think it'll be the foundation for the next generation of extended-reality wearables.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.google/products/android/android-xr" target="_blank">Android XR</a> is available starting today, Dec. 12, as a developer preview. While the first hardware product running Android XR won't be available to consumers until next year, developers are getting an early look at the latest version of Android. The Android XR developer preview supports dev tools like ARCore, Android Studio, Jetpack Compose, Unity, and OpenXR. Additionally, since the Android XR SDK is built on the foundation of Android, most apps on the Google Play Store will be automatically available on Android XR.</p><p>Android Studio and the Android XR Emulator will give developers a head start on building for the upcoming platform. Google and Samsung, entering the XR market relatively late, likely want to avoid the struggles Apple faced when it launched visionOS earlier this year. It only had 600 native apps available when visionOS debuted. The Android XR developer preview could help the companies avoid growing pains, but wanting developers to build for an unknown platform with many hardware unknowns could prove to be a tall ask.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:5120px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:52.73%;"><img id="GDvSEctRTR7cSxxZmNyABX" name="Samsung-Project-Moohan-Side-render" alt="An official product render of Samsung's Project Moohan VR headset" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GDvSEctRTR7cSxxZmNyABX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="5120" height="2700" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Samsung)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The operating system will first debut on mixed-reality headset, and Samsung will be the first manufacturer to ship an Android XR device. It's codenamed Project Moohan, and bears a striking resemblance to another expensive headset. Android XR headsets, like Project Moohan, will provide both immersive experiences and extended-reality experiences. For example, you might watch a movie completely immersed, and later use an Android XR headset to interact with your real-world environment with Gemini.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.20%;"><img id="DRPgjWYXCq5R2PqDAfeiqD" name="Glasses_Translate-google-android-xr" alt="Translating a sign using smart glasses powered by Android XR" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DRPgjWYXCq5R2PqDAfeiqD.gif" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="500" height="281" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Eventually, the multimodal interaction provided by Gemini in Android XR will be available in a glasses form factor. Google says it wants glasses to be available for "all-day help," and crucially, hopes to build an ecosystem of "stylish, comfortable glasses you'll love to wear every day and that work seamlessly with your other Android devices."</p><p>Google has a pair of prototype glasses in the works, and some people outside the company will soon get the privilege of trying them out. The company announced <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/googles-latest-ai-model-gemini-2-0-is-here-to-usher-in-the-agentic-era">Gemini 2.0</a> a day prior, and with it <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/google-project-astra-ar-waitlist-opens-trusted-testers">the Project Astra trusted tester program</a>. There's a Google Form for users to sign up for a waitlist, and as part of the form, Google asks if you're interested in "using prototype glasses."</p><p>If these prototype smart glasses are anything like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-orion-hands-on">Meta Orion</a>, they could be far out from a public release. Additionally, they might not be released at all — part of the Android XR platform is building up an ecosystem of hardware products with partners like Samsung, Qualcomm, Lynx, Sony, and XREAL. Google might not end up being the one to release a headset or glasses, but it'll certainly be the steward of Android XR.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="H6v9tA3m9Tq5TSncqyvWiG" name="android-xr-smart-glasses-concept-01" alt="A lifestyle image showing off a prototype pair of smart glasses powered by Android XR" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/H6v9tA3m9Tq5TSncqyvWiG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>For now, Android XR is just a preview of what the next Android platform might become. If Google and Samsung succeed, Android XR could become a vibrant ecosystem like Wear OS and Android Auto before it. We'll learn more about Android XR hardware in 2025, and you can learn more about the OS for yourself <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://android.com/xr" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/android-xr-announcement</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google and Samsung want to have their Wear OS moment one more time — only this time, for XR hardware.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">sjaCZEtLv6NKPVMjsnUd5k</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hhYsUHQUEi6pmBmLM9hunL.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hhYsUHQUEi6pmBmLM9hunL.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[An Android XR graphic from Google.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[An Android XR graphic from Google.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Android XR is the most exciting new version of Android in years ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>When was the last time you were excited about a new version of Android? Even as a smartphone reviewer, I'll admit it's been a while for me, as well, and the current thought is that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/android-16-and-17-may-not-come-with-fantastic-new-features-heres-why">Android 16 and 17</a> might not change that much.</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">AC thVRsday</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="LGmZZrc8DWcxmZm6RRUYbC" name="ac-thvrsday-logo.jpg" caption="" alt="AC thVRsday logo" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LGmZZrc8DWcxmZm6RRUYbC.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">In his <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/ac-thvrsday">weekly column</a>, Android Central Senior Content Producer Nick Sutrich delves into all things VR, from new hardware to new games, upcoming technologies, and so much more.</p></div></div>
<p>Enter <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/android-xr-announcement">Android XR</a>, the first new version of Android made for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini</a> era. Google says it's built with Gemini at the core, enabling a brand new type of user interface that's driven entirely by the way you interact with Google's multimodal AI.</p><p>As you might have guessed, the XR in Android XR isn't some weird Roman numeral moniker. Rather, it stands for e<strong>X</strong>tended <strong>R</strong>eality and is a new spinoff of Android built to unify XR products — mainly smart glasses and VR headsets — under a new set of standards and tools. It's exactly how Android Auto is built for car infotainment systems, and Wear OS is built for smartwatches.</p><p>It's a huge opportunity for Google to take the reigns and bring technologies together that, so far, are all very different and often feature messy experiences. But is it too little too late for Google to be doing this? The company thinks otherwise, and Gemini is here to prove it.</p>
<h2 id="changing-the-ux-paradigm-again-2">Changing the UX paradigm...again</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="b8LPWcVz3R46fgHnxagqGF" name="android-xr-video-player-ui" alt="A look at the video player UI of Android XR running on a Samsung Project Moohan headset in mixed reality" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/b8LPWcVz3R46fgHnxagqGF.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The field of XR is still exciting despite having popular consumer products on the market for a solid decade. Many of the existing UI design paradigms don't feel great in VR — using your laser pointer to select things just feels lazy — but UX designers have made significant headway on this portion of the experience in the last few years with things like hand tracking and eye tracking.</p><p>However, Google says a third method is required for truly natural and seamless interaction between the real and virtual worlds: an AI assistant. This is no secret since a multimodal AI assistant is exactly what <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/the-ray-ban-meta-smart-glasses-are-my-gadget-of-the-year-but-ill-never-wear-them-again">makes Ray-Ban Meta smart glasses so special</a>.</p><p>Meta even launched its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-news-recap-july-26-2024">Meta AI assistant on Meta Quest headsets</a> this summer, but Google aims to take this concept even further than Meta has, utilizing full hand tracking, eye tracking, and the voice assistant to make the UI feel as natural as possible.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>Google is unlocking the full power of Gemini by giving it the ability to see and hear the world around it, delivering context to you in a potential smart glasses form factor.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>In one example, Google showed us a prototype pair of AR glasses that have a small screen in the lens, not too dissimilar to what the company launched with Google Glass in 2014. The big difference is that, with Gemini built in, the person wearing the glasses was able to have a conversation with the AI that helped them navigate a busy street without staring at their phone.</p><p>Gemini's full capabilities become unlocked with a product like this because it can see through the cameras on the glasses, hear your voice, and interact with you as if it were a human instead of a bunch of icons on a display. It takes the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-maps-can-now-determine-your-precise-location-using-live-view-ar">existing AR features of Google Maps</a> and makes them make sense.</p><p>Holding up your phone and looking "through" its screen is fine enough, I suppose, but it also invites criminals to snatch your phone and is generally just kind of awkward. Whether it works as well as <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-orion-hands-on">Meta's Orion prototype</a> is anyone's best guess, but they sure do look nice.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.20%;"><img id="DRPgjWYXCq5R2PqDAfeiqD" name="Glasses_Translate-google-android-xr" alt="Translating a sign using smart glasses powered by Android XR" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DRPgjWYXCq5R2PqDAfeiqD.gif" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="500" height="281" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<figure><blockquote><p>Talking to Gemini in Android XR is more like talking to a person rather than a digital assistant because the answers aren't generic. They're extremely specific to what you're doing and what you need in the moment because it can hear and see what you see and hear.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>It's an upgrade over what's currently provided on Ray-Ban Meta Smart Glasses because a screen is involved, allowing Gemini and Android XR to overlay virtual elements onto the real world.</p><p>On the VR side of the house, Android XR will enable more natural interactions with the virtual world as well as the real one, as seen in the previous example. This second example showed a person wearing a prototype Samsung VR headset (called Project Moohan) while watching YouTube.</p><p>Project Moohan is equipped with a Snapdragon XR2 Plus Gen 2 — that's a step up from the Snapdragon XR2 Gen 2 in the Quest 3 and 3S — and is set to debut in 2025 "with more devices to follow," per Qualcomm. It also looks incredibly sleek, giving off vibes from the über-expensive <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/apple-vision-pro-launch-sales-success">Apple Vision Pro</a> rather than Meta's more affordable Quest series.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:5120px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:52.73%;"><img id="GDvSEctRTR7cSxxZmNyABX" name="Samsung-Project-Moohan-Side-render" alt="An official product render of Samsung's Project Moohan VR headset" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GDvSEctRTR7cSxxZmNyABX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="5120" height="2700" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Samsung)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The headset itself isn't the notable thing in this example, although it is Samsung's first VR headset since its HMD Odyssey headset in 2017. Rather, the way this person was interacting with the content onscreen was game-changing. Gemini is able to see and understand what's happening onscreen, meaning you can ask it <em>anything</em> and get a context-sensitive response.</p><p>Again, this is more like talking to a person rather than a digital assistant because the answers aren't generic. They're extremely specific to what you're doing and what you need at the moment.</p>
<h2 id="but-what-about-google-2">But what about Google?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="Ynuoir6wBUdePdHywfUwfG" name="android-xr-smart-glasses-concept-02" alt="A lifestyle image showing off a prototype pair of smart glasses powered by Android XR" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Ynuoir6wBUdePdHywfUwfG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In this case, Google has some very good and some very bad things going for it. Let's get the bad out of the way first: Google has a bad habit of starting cool projects only to drop them a year or two later. The list of projects that have ended up like this is endless, and the problem is that several major AR/VR projects are included in that list. Google Daydream and Google Glass are chief among them.</p><p>Google beat Meta to the punch with a standalone VR headset it made in partnership with Lenovo, only to stop supporting it shortly after launch. The company told us it's been at the heart of XR development all along — and that's certainly true with these developments, Google Cardboard, AR Core, etc. — but people have lost faith in Google side projects like this because of failures like Stadia and others.</p><p>Nothing in the company's presentation told me that this could potentially be any different. If it does well, Android XR will go on to become like Wear OS and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/android-auto-review">Android Auto</a>, two extremely successful Android spinoff platforms that are used by millions of users every day. If it doesn't meet some internal goal within a year or two, who knows what'll happen, although we can all guess based on history.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="H6v9tA3m9Tq5TSncqyvWiG" name="android-xr-smart-glasses-concept-01" alt="A lifestyle image showing off a prototype pair of smart glasses powered by Android XR" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/H6v9tA3m9Tq5TSncqyvWiG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Meanwhile, Meta has charged through despite the investment into XR costing billions, and it has at least partially paid off because the company is the king of the entire umbrella category. The Meta Quest is by far the best-selling family of VR products ever, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/ray-ban-meta-smart-glasses-review">Ray-Ban Meta Smart Glasses</a> have blown the lid off the smart glasses market to pave the way to successful form factors and adoption.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>If it does well, Android XR will go on to become like Wear OS and Android Auto, two extremely successful Android spinoff platforms that are used by millions of users everyday. If it doesn't meet some internal goal within a year or two, who knows what'll happen, although we can all guess based on history.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>But Meta isn't exactly loved by people, not just because of its Facebook lineage but because of its handling of developer relations over the years. Meta <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/sherlocking-what-happens-when-big-tech-steals-your-ideas">has shamelessly Sherlocked</a> features from developers over the years — something Google, Apple, Microsoft, and basically every other big tech company is also guilty of — but it has also alienated developers who have nowhere else to turn to since Meta owns the VR market with an 80% market share.</p><p>Recent changes to the Meta Quest store have buried developers underneath a swath of cheap Gorilla Tag clones and promotion for Meta's own Horizon Worlds metaverse platform instead of propping up paid games that used to see more promotion on the digital storefront.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>I've talked to many VR developers who are happy with the success they've seen from the Quest platform in the past but have been unhappy with how things have changed this year. It's these very people who can build apps for Google's new Android XR platform and potentially give it a win over Meta's Horizon OS .</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>This is where Google can improve and even win developers over with a new way of doing business. I've talked to many VR developers who are happy with the success they've seen from the Quest platform in the past but have been unhappy with how things have changed this year. It's these very people who can build apps for Google's new Android XR platform and potentially give it a win over <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/quest-developers-are-nervous-about-meta-horizon-os">Meta's Horizon OS</a>.</p><p>In fact, Google and Qualcomm have been working with the folks over at Unity to provide full Android XR support in Unity 6, making it easier for developers to port their existing (and upcoming) games to Android XR with fairly minimal effort.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.20%;"><img id="4RfgxtFQxgSCTz5o6LSq3j" name="Headset_GooglePhotos-project-moohan-android-xr" alt="Running Google Photos in mixed reality on Samsung Project Moohan, powered by Android XR" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4RfgxtFQxgSCTz5o6LSq3j.gif" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="500" height="281" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The biggest issue is that this Android XR announcement doesn't come with any hardware commitments. Instead, today's announcement teases Samsung and Qualcomm hardware partnerships — Google likens this to rebuilding Wear OS with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/samsung-galaxy-watch-4-review">Galaxy Watch 4</a> — but without a specific price and date for a product, it's hard to feel like Google is in this to win it.</p><p>Qualcomm and Google say they're working with Lynx, Sony, and Xreal to deliver more products in 2025, though, so it's possible that something actually will come of this whole effort this time around.</p><p>I'd like to have faith that Google and Samsung could pull this off — the bones of Android XR are sounding <em>extremely </em>promising — but Google's history of abandoned projects makes me more worried than hopeful right now. Stadia was a sort of self-fulfilling prophecy and I'm just not sure I'm ready to go through another one of those again.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/android-xr-is-the-most-exciting-new-version-of-android-in-years</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Android XR is the first version of Android built with Gemini at its core, delivering new UI experiences to upcoming XR devices. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">E78xEJTeJ4REgFsdsAqM7L</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4Qsc8c6zs55VDymeeddShN.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4Qsc8c6zs55VDymeeddShN.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android XR in starry space above a planetary horizon]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android XR in starry space above a planetary horizon]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung's new One UI 7 beta killed a handy lock screen feature ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The lock screen widget carousel, which let users tap the clock to access full-sized widgets, is missing in the latest One UI 7 beta.</li><li>The lock screen now only supports mini widgets below the clock, but Good Lock’s LockStar module still allows full customization.</li><li>While Samsung pulls back, Google is going the other way, with Android 15 QPR1 and QPR2 keeping full-sized lock screen widgets, at least on tablets.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>While Samsung added more lock screen customization in the first One UI 7.0 beta, the company may have removed the widgets carousel, with no word on its return.</p><p>Samsung’s delayed Android 15-based One UI 7 beta <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsungs-first-one-ui-7-beta-is-available-now-public-release-set-for-early-2025">finally made its way to the Galaxy S24 series last week</a>, and it’s packing some solid updates. One of the big ones is the long-awaited vertical app drawer, replacing the old horizontal layout and making things feel much smoother and easier to navigate. On top of that, One UI 7 introduces the Now Bar to keep track of live activities, plus a revamped Quick Settings panel that's now separate from the notification shade.</p><p>Even with all the new upgrades, One UI 7 appears to be saying goodbye to the lock screen widget carousel. Users could tap the lock screen clock to access a carousel with full-sized widgets in previous versions. But with One UI 7, it looks like that feature is being dropped.</p><p>A Reddit user recently spotted, as reported by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/one-ui-7-widget-carousel-3507162/" target="_blank">Android Authority</a>, that the lock screen widget carousel is missing from the latest One UI 7 beta. If this sticks around in the final release, Samsung’s One UI will align even more with Google’s Android, which stopped supporting native lock screen widgets back with Android 5.0.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:369px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:216.80%;"><img id="7KfEai4jciv5CzbFUVtPCg" name="Lock-screen-and-AOD-setting-One-UI-7" alt="Lock screen and AOD settings in One UI 7" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7KfEai4jciv5CzbFUVtPCg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="369" height="800" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In earlier versions of One UI, users could find the lock screen widget carousel settings under <strong>Settings </strong>> <strong>Lock screen and AOD</strong> > <strong>Widgets</strong>, where they could choose full-sized widgets like Weather, Calendar, and Digital Wellbeing. But with the latest One UI 7 beta, this setting is nowhere to be found.</p><p>As a result, the lock screen only shows mini widgets below the clock. For those who enjoy customizing their <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-samsung-phones">Galaxy phone</a>, Good Lock's LockStar module still lets you add any widget to the lock screen.</p><p>While Samsung is pulling back on lock screen widgets with One UI 7, Google is heading in the opposite direction. Android 15 QPR1 brought full-sized lock screen widgets, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/android-15-brings-lock-screen-widgets-back-to-life-on-tablets">they’re sticking around in Android 15 QPR2 for tablets</a>.</p>
<hr>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="4cf4f6be-b51e-4a0e-b206-a053e4e615bf">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pb2Z3cawQkbz5RDcGGfxs3.jpg' alt="samsung galaxy s24 plus square render 2"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>The Galaxy S24 Plus is a top-tier device that combines powerful performance, long-lasting battery life, and an advanced triple-lens camera setup. Running on the latest Android OS, it delivers a premium experience all around.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsungs-new-one-ui-7-beta-killed-a-handy-lock-screen-feature</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A helpful lock screen feature got the cold shoulder from Samsung's One UI 7 beta. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">KTuNfq8F26jzDaJKWppJyQ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/H9uJ5yTZcUC5qbV6eB2BDK.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 12:07:21 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/H9uJ5yTZcUC5qbV6eB2BDK.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ I love Garmin watches, but they could learn a thing or two from Android smartwatches ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Wear OS Weekly</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="o8KRGSTt4mbFxn3wdtWvtU" name="lloyd-wear-os-weekly.jpg" caption="" alt="Android Central mascot Lloyd wearing a Galaxy Watch and Pixel Watch" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/o8KRGSTt4mbFxn3wdtWvtU.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">My new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/wear-os-weekly">weekly column</a> focuses on the state of Wear OS, from new developments and updates to the latest apps and features we want to highlight.</p></div></div>
<p>Garmin watches are popular with fitness enthusiasts who have the patience to sift through its tricky UI, the Labyrinthian Connect app, and the weird IQ spinoff where Garmin hides its best third-party tools.</p><p>It's not especially accessible to people coming from Apple and Android watches with better smarts. While I review most of our <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-garmin-smartwatch">Garmin watches</a>, my colleagues who've tested some models have complained about the high learning curve and unnecessary confusion.</p><p>Last month, I wrote about <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/wear-os-watches-could-learn-a-lot-from-garmin">every feature Wear OS should borrow from Garmin</a>, a long list from downloadable courses and better accessory support to battery life concerns, among other weak points. So, I think it's only fair to turn things around on Garmin: there are areas where it could learn from a brand like Wear OS, which is designed to cater to "mainstream" users and be as accessible as possible.</p><p>Garmin <em>can't</em> offer certain smarts because at least half of its users use iPhones, and Apple will keep blocking other watches from syncing properly until the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.techradar.com/health-fitness/your-android-smartwatch-could-soon-work-much-better-on-iphone-thanks-to-the-eu">EU forces them</a> to open things up. In the meantime, with so many smartwatches adding fitness tools like training load to try and compete with Garmin, it makes sense for Garmin to turn the tables and compete more on smarts.</p>

<h2 id="spread-the-fenix-8-s-offline-assistant-as-fast-as-possible-2">Spread the Fenix 8's offline assistant as fast as possible</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="jUNVoitpCtXTVbsvFDP6oX" name="Garmin-Fenix-8-voice-assistant" alt="The Garmin Fenix 8 showing "Listening" for the new voice assistant" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jUNVoitpCtXTVbsvFDP6oX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-fenix-8-review" target="_blank">Garmin Fenix 8</a> added the brand's first offline voice assistant; you hold down a button, then say a command like "Open Spotify," "Start a Cycling workout," or "Show me my most recent workout," and have it take you where you need to go.</p><p>It's not perfect — it's a little slow, and Garmin needs to keep adding more recognized commands — but it's very useful. So it's a shame that very few Garmin watches have a mic, and the only (somewhat) affordable model (the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-venu-3-review">Garmin Venu 3</a>) only supports passthrough commands to your phone assistant.</p><p>If a $50 <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/amazfit-band-7-review">Amazfit Band 7</a> can afford to pack in a mic for Alexa commands, I think more Garmin watches can fit them in, not just the mainline Venus and Fenixes. And voice commands will help newer users find information before they're familiar with the UI. Google Assistant is a key reason people buy <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wear-os-watch">Wear OS watches</a>, and Garmin needs to make its assistant as widespread.</p>
<h2 id="copy-wear-os-tiles-2">Copy Wear OS tiles</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="cm3nSuJTMJFTvtgbnXPkoC" name="Google-Pixel-Watch-3-weather-tile" alt="The Google Pixel Watch 3 showing the Weather tile, with an hourly forecast for the evening." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/cm3nSuJTMJFTvtgbnXPkoC.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Garmin finally made its UI a little smarter last year by making its apps easier to find and adding a list view that is accessible with the main Start button. It may not have a grid view like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-3-review">Pixel Watch 3</a> or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-7-review">Galaxy Watch 7</a>, but I think that's more about aesthetics than functionality, and Garmin doesn't have as many apps to worry about.</p><p>What would help far more is copying Wear OS's tile view, letting you swipe left and right from Garmin's main watch face to see your favorite graphs or functions.</p><p>Rather than having to swipe down to the compact weather widget, select it, and then scroll down to find the hourly or daily forecast, it'd be nice to swipe right and have a full view of that data immediately. The same goes for flashlight controls or seeing your daily calendar with the suggested/scheduled workout — there are so many functions that require two or three taps every time that Garmin could make them more accessible for those who want to prioritize that data.</p><p>In my case, I find it a bit annoying that to see my acute load or load focus, I have to scroll down to the Training Status widget, then scroll down to the sub-widget and select it. Some graphs have watch face shortcuts, but you're limited if you buy an "S" model with a smaller display and less room for data. Other data like Challenges and monthly mileage require diving into the mobile app.</p><p>If, instead, Garmin took after Wear OS and let you highlight your favorite graphs and app views with a couple of swipes, that would also make things more accessible. Now that more models use AMOLED displays and touchscreens, it's time to take advantage of the extra pixels.</p>
<h2 id="make-lte-an-option-already-2">Make LTE an option already</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3701px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.26%;"><img id="C679DtBoDyMeLTiJWe6W5o" name="samsung-galaxy-watch-vs-apple-watch-ultra-2-1.jpg" alt="Samsung Galaxy Watch Ultra vs. Apple Watch Ultra 2" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/C679DtBoDyMeLTiJWe6W5o.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3701" height="2082" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Plenty of Garmin fans have clamored for this for years. Aside from the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/garmin-forerunner-945-lte-review">Garmin Forerunner 945 LTE</a> — which only used cellular for basic safety check-ins — and the kid-focused <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-bounce-kids-watch-review-the-fun-smartwatch-for-kids">Garmin Bounce LTE</a>, Garmin never lets you pay extra for cellular, even as competing flagship watches like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-ultra-review">Galaxy Watch Ultra</a> or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/apple-watch-ultra-2-review">Apple Watch Ultra 2</a> make it a default.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/i-used-to-want-lte-smartwatch-but-not-anymore">I personally don't care about LTE watches</a> because I'm too cheap to give my carrier more money and almost always have my phone on hand. But being unable to send check-ins, incident detection warnings, or manual SOS because your phone battery died is hard to accept for Garmin fans who'd willingly pay for that peace of mind...but don't want to bother with an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-inreach-messenger-plus-announced">InReach Messenger Plus</a> and a hyper-expensive satellite subscription.</p><p>Fenix and Venu models with the mic/speaker combo should allow for standalone calls or the ability to record voice clips and add them to your next check-in for loved ones to hear.</p>
<h2 id="make-garmin-coach-a-chatbot-health-guru-i-guess-2">Make Garmin Coach a chatbot / health guru (I guess...)</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1440px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="w84scqx35wnfynxVtHD9s4" name="samsung-galaxy-ai-wellness-tips.JPG" alt="Samsung Health mock-up showing new Wellness Tips feature for One UI 6 Watch" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/w84scqx35wnfynxVtHD9s4.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1440" height="810" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Samsung)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Garmin's Firstbeat Analytics and Coaching algorithms make it the brand to beat for training guidance. It's also one of the best for overall data accuracy. Yet when it comes to general health advice or making its data accessible, it's easy to argue that Google and Samsung have recently gained the edge and even some smart rings.</p><p>Samsung only recently added its Energy Score (similar to Body Battery), but it also has new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-galaxy-ai">Galaxy AI</a> Wellness tips; the image above shows how it can track and display trends like changing resting heart rate or dipping body fat.</p><p>Fitbit has always been popular for summarizing your health information in accessible ways, as long as you pay for Premium. A more recent development is its Gemini-based <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/fitbit-labs-insight-explorer-test-gemini-start">Fitbit Insight Explorer</a>: It's an opt-in service that analyzes your steps, Active Zone Minutes, sleep quality, HRV, RHR, and other data, then lets you ask its chatbot questions about your averages, trends, and personal bests.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="saVs5xFzRFWuEhLLsVUrtJ" name="Garmin-Forerunner-965-endurance-score-chart.jpeg" alt="Endurance score on the Garmin Forerunner 965" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/saVs5xFzRFWuEhLLsVUrtJ.jpeg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="caption-text">Garmin has a wealth of data on your fitness progress, but mostly asks you to just trust their numbers and not ask too many questions </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Garmin has a <em>wealth</em> of information it could summarize in weekly or monthly reports, but its "In Focus" widgets show basic weekly trends for things like mileage and load without commentary, and all of its Health graphs are buried a few layers deep in the "More" tab where most people never look.</p><p>Instead, Garmin might highlight promising or negative health trends in its Morning Report; ideally, it could also provide monthly summaries of how your training load, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/how-i-boosted-my-vo2-max-score-on-my-garmin-watch">VO2 Max</a>, and other fitness stats compare to past months. It could recommend changes like more anaerobic workouts or more steps.</p><p>To be honest, I'm not <em>thrilled</em> to imagine Garmin Coach progressing from this silent, data-driven platform to some public-facing chatbot like Amazfit's Zepp Coach. But for all the people who use ChatGPT as their default search engine and knowledge base, they'll find Wear OS watches more accessible because they're starting to go all-in on AI insights, and Garmin might need to find an AI partner to help them compete.</p>
<h2 id="above-all-else-accessibility-is-key-2">Above all else, accessibility is key</h2>
<p>I don't want Garmin to become a carbon copy of Wear OS. Core customers love its watches for their long battery life and wouldn't want to lose that for "smarts" that they don't need. But at the same time, I know plenty of people who <em>want</em> to like Garmin watches but can't get past how dense and complicated everything is.</p><p>If Garmin can use voice commands, pseudo-tiles, and off-device AI processing to help users find health and fitness information, it will have taken some of the best aspects of using the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wear-os-watch">best Wear OS watches</a> while still retaining its identity.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/everything-garmin-watches-should-borrow-from-android-watches</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Even as Samsung and Google play catch-up with Garmin on fitness, Garmin itself could learn a thing or two from Wear OS watches to keep customers happy. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">9iEcH2dUqiZ8e3nAsjd9bL</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sDUkyPb3KgrP2tPDSvYxAj.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wear Os]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sDUkyPb3KgrP2tPDSvYxAj.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Samsung Galaxy Watch Ultra (left), Garmin Fenix 8 (middle), and Google Pixel Watch 3 (right) sitting on a chair.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Samsung Galaxy Watch Ultra (left), Garmin Fenix 8 (middle), and Google Pixel Watch 3 (right) sitting on a chair.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google's CEO blasts Microsoft's AI efforts, says 'they're using someone else's models' ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google CEO Sundar Pichai disputed claims that top AI developers are struggling to innovate on next-generation models.</li><li>Pichai had strong words for a key competitor, Microsoft, challenging the Redmond firm to a side-by-side test "any day, any time."</li><li>The executive also criticized Microsoft's partnership with OpenAI, saying "they're using someone else's models."</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google released its next-generation set of artificial intelligence models, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/googles-latest-ai-model-gemini-2-0-is-here-to-usher-in-the-agentic-era">Gemini 2.0</a>, today alongside <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/google-project-astra-ar-waitlist-opens-trusted-testers">glimpses of longer-term AI projects</a>. But even before the company's ambitious announcements, Google's leader expressed confidence in its AI developments. At the now-concluded <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.nytimes.com/events/dealbook/sessions/sundar-pichai-building-the-future" target="_blank">Dealbook Summit</a>, hosted by the New York Times, Google CEO Sundar Pichai had strong words for his company's competitors, and separately, those critical of AI's future (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.windowscentral.com/software-apps/google-ceo-jab-at-microsoft-ai-efforts-side-by-side-comparison" target="_blank">Windows Central</a>).</p><p>Pichai, who has led Google through a challenging period that included massive layoffs and a shift toward AI, is still confident there is more progress to be made.</p><p>"When you start out quickly scaling up, you can throw more compute and you can make a lot of progress, but you definitely are going to need deeper breakthroughs as we go to the next stage," Pichai said at the Dealbook Summit. "So you can perceive it as there's a wall, or there's some small barriers."</p><p>The chief executive appears to be in agreement with other industry leaders, such as OpenAI's CEO Sam Altman, that AI models aren't hitting a so-called wall. In other words, some skeptics believe that AI development will grind to a halt following significant advancements in 2023 and 2024.</p><p>"I don't subscribe to the wall notion," Pichai said.</p><p>However, that doesn't mean the top boss at Google doesn't expect there to be a slowdown as AI development progresses. "I think the progress is going to get harder when I look at '25," the Google CEO explained. "The low-hanging fruit is gone. The hill is steeper."</p><p>Google is competing with a few notable competitors as it searches for AI breakthroughs, including <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/openai-chatgpt-search-feature-rollout">OpenAI</a>, Anthropic, and Microsoft. Pichai called out one competitor, Microsoft, specifically when Andrew Ross Sorkin revisited Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella's negative comments toward Google from earlier this year.</p><p>"I would love to do a side-by-side comparison of Microsoft's own models and our models any day, any time," Pichai quipped. "They're using someone else's models."</p><p>Pichai is referring to Microsoft's multi-billion-dollar investment in OpenAI, which gives it access to the newest GPT models that power <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/microsoft-copilot-default-assistant-beta-rollout">Microsoft Copilot</a>. Google, meanwhile, uses its in-house Gemini models for its AI services.</p><p>Now, the chief executives at both Google and Microsoft have thrown a bit of shade at one another in 2024. As the AI race heats up, this friendly feud will be yet another storyline to watch.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google/googles-ceo-blasts-microsofts-ai-efforts-says-theyre-using-someone-elses-models</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Sundar Pichai is extremely confident in Google's AI models, and didn't hold back opinions about one of the company's biggest competitors. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">xdw9X9M2Jdz3Asa7ZtdEU8</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hWWeWMrmfVhP3jeUj2ucac.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 21:44:09 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hWWeWMrmfVhP3jeUj2ucac.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A Google sign at the Mountain View Google campus.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A Google sign at the Mountain View Google campus.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Launcher 10 lets you turn an Android phone into a Windows Phone ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A discovery made by Mr. Mobile on YouTube highlighted an app called Launcher 10 that can turn an Android phone into a Windows Phone OS.</li><li>Users will have an "authentic taste" of what it used to be, outfitted with the boxy, rectangular tiles that the Windows Phone software featured.</li><li>Microsoft discontinued Windows Phone in 2017 and even ended service support for its Surface Duo 2 in October 2024.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Remember the old Microsoft Windows Phone software? Well, another person does, too, and there's a program that can get it done.</p><p>As spotted by our friends at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.windowscentral.com/phones/windows-phone/watch-mrmobile-turn-a-samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-into-a-windows-phone">Windows Central</a>, YouTuber <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://youtu.be/_p4RbXLW8aY?si=aLU9Z6On6A2B1BBk&t=160">MrMobile</a>, AKA Michael Fisher, discovered a way to turn an Android phone into a Windows Phone. MrMobile found an app on the Play Store called <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.nfwebdev.launcher10&hl=en_US&pli=1">Launcher 10</a>, which gives users a "very authentic taste" of what once was for Microsoft's smartphone. If you remember the aesthetic of this phone — and Windows 8 by extension — then you know what you're in for.</p><p>Launcher 10 brings back those boxy, square, rectangular icons or "tiles." The app, when selected to be put to use within your settings, turns everything into what the Windows Phone OS used to be.</p><p>Interestingly enough, most of the apps that you're likely to have on your device like Gmail, Spotify, Google Calendar, Photos, and more appear properly through Launcher 10. Some of the app icons on the tiles take on Android's "Themed Icon," which is just an outline of the logo within it filled in with color. Others, like Chrome, feature a colored background with a recognizable logo in the center.</p><p>Another aspect that is very Windows Phone is the notifications. MrMobile gave a brief glimpse at a notification, which retained that Windows flair.</p><p>If you're interested, you can watch MrMobiles' <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_p4RbXLW8aY&t=160s&ab_channel=MrMobile%5BMichaelFisher%5D">full glimpse at Launcher 10</a>. Additionally, the video highlights the app's multitude of customization options to get the right theme. However, MrMobiles delivers a warning to those who will want to go that extra mile with Launcher 10.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_p4RbXLW8aY?start=161" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>For those looking for a bit of nostalgia, Launcher 10 might be the best gift of the season. Microsoft discontinued its Windows Phone OS in 2017. It didn't come without a heavy heart as the company's CEO Satya Nadella told <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.businessinsider.com/microsoft-ceo-satya-nadella-interview-ai-activision-blizzard-axel-springer-2023-10?r=US&IR=T">Business Insider</a> in 2023 "the decision I think a lot of people talk about – and one of the most difficult decisions I made when I became CEO — was our exit of what I'll call the mobile phone as defined then" (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-ceo-admits-giving-up-on-windows-phone-was-one-of-the-most-difficult-decisions-he-made">IGN</a>).</p><p>The Windows Phone OS was in response to what Apple had done with iOS and Google with Android, but it didn't catch on.</p><p>As such, Microsoft bowed out of the software side of mobile phones, but it still had its a phone: the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/surface-duo-announcement">Surface Duo</a> and the Surface Duo 2 foldables. Neither of those devices lasted particularly long as Microsoft detailed the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/microsoft-ends-surface-duo-2-support-with-final-security-update">end of service for the Surface Duo 2</a> this year in October. The device only received one update that took it from Android 11 to Android 12L.</p><p>It seemed that Microsoft was more interested in "streamlining" its Surface ecosystem and there are no plans to return the Duo.</p><p>Despite Microsoft's rocky smartphone and phone OS history, the company has taken strides to improve its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/phone-link-is-looking-more-like-windows-answer-to-apples-airdrop">computer relationship with Android phones</a>. In August, Windows' latest features for Phone Link for OS 10 and 11 rivaled Apple's AirDrop with quicker file sharing between PC and Android. Additionally, the dedicated app makes this even easier (and faster).</p><p>Elsewhere, Microsoft even <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-one-ui-6-1-1-app-mirroring-improved">improved its Link to Windows</a> mirroring experience for Galaxy devices with One UI 6.1.1 that same month.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/launcher-10-android-phone-windows-phone-os-style</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A Youtuber discovered an app that can turn the Android software into the Windows Phone OS. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">HBFXpiVUe2LgPiRppds22f</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XZafwZdCrLnRXNAFjUCGH4.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 20:37:57 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XZafwZdCrLnRXNAFjUCGH4.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[MrMobile / YouTube]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A Galaxy S24 Ultra running Launcher 10, which turns its theme into the Windows Phone version.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A Galaxy S24 Ultra running Launcher 10, which turns its theme into the Windows Phone version.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Galaxy S25 series will allegedly see sporadic price increases, per reports ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung is rumored to increase the price of the Galaxy S25 in South Korea following a higher exchange rate and chip costs from Qualcomm.</li><li>A concrete number wasn't stated; however, the price is expected to be "slightly" higher than the S24 in South Korea.</li><li>In contrast, another report states Samsung's Galaxy S25 series could have the same price in Europe.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Rumors are surfacing, with details that suggest Samsung's next flagships could see a jump in price for some.</p><p>A recent report by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://m.yna.co.kr/amp/view/AKR20241209139300017">Yonhap News</a> (Korean) cites an industry source in saying Samsung's Galaxy S25 series could see a price increase in South Korea (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/12/11/samsung-galaxy-s25-price-leaks/">9to5Google</a>). There is reportedly a "possibility" for such a future regarding the S25 trio. The publication purports that this apparent "outlook" is due to the use of Qualcomm's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-announces-snapdragon-8-elite-chip">Snapdragon 8 Elite</a> SoC in all three devices.</p><p>Its sources supposedly added that another contributing factor is the "predicted" price increase for the latest flagship chip. The company has reportedly raised the prices of its technology by roughly 30% when compared to previous generations and this is suspected to affect Samsung's views on the Galaxy S25 pricing.</p><p>The exchange rate between Samsung and Qualcomm is also another culprit for the potential price increase as it's higher than it has been in the past.</p><p>The publication didn't state an exact number; however, it's suspected to be "slightly" higher than the cost of the S24 on Samsung's home soil.</p><p>Elsewhere, another report spotted by 9to5 from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://winfuture.de/news,147437.html">WinFuture</a> (German) claims that this price increase might not affect <em>every </em>region. The information comes via a retailer leak in the region, which shows that the Galaxy S25 pricing (seemingly) remains the same as the soon-to-be predecessor trio. The post claims that the prices were allegedly the same in Germany, which <em>could </em>mean that the rest of Europe will see the same prices.</p><p>According to the publication, the following leaked prices regard the base versions of the series: Galaxy S25 128GB: 899 euro (~$943), Galaxy S25 Plus 256GB: 1,149 euro (~$1,205), and the Galaxy S25 Ultra 256GB: 1,449 euro (~$1,520).</p><p>Of course, the U.S. pricing estimates here are not one-to-one, meaning these aren't something you should take as a literal. <em>If </em>Samsung raises prices in the U.S. market, these numbers will likely shift to better suit the area. Meanwhile, a potential price increase <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-4-rumored-price-hike-sour">was rumored in late September</a>.</p><p>Shortly before the Snapdragon 8 Elite launched, a tipster claimed that Qualcomm was placing a ~$190 price increase on its new Oryon CPU-based chip. That was roughly a 20% increase over the price of the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 for this latest generation of flagship models. The 3nm process was supposedly "quite expensive," thus the price increase rumors we've continued to hear.</p><p>The 8 Elite delivers powerful improvements over the SD 8 Gen 3, like a 45% boost in performance and a 44% boost in efficiency.</p><p>Samsung is expected to debut its Galaxy S25 series in January 2024 during Galaxy Unpacked. A recent string of rumors states the devices could even adopt <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-s25-qi2-wireless-charging-support-rumors">Qi2 wireless charging</a>, too.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-s25-series-alleged-sporadic-price-increase-rumored</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Galaxy S25 price rumors paint a sporadic picture for its global launch. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">TLwq9sGbVEcRLWPc9cMRFM</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/aW5aJXDvAiQnLpfxNZ3NE3.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 19:51:46 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/aW5aJXDvAiQnLpfxNZ3NE3.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Hands-on with the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Hands-on with the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Meta confirms widespread Whatsapp, Instagram outage, working on a solution as thousands still wait for a fix ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Users reported issues accessing various Meta apps and platforms Wednesday, Dec. 11.</li><li>Meta acknowledged the "technical issue" in a post on X (formerly Twitter).</li><li>Though the company said it was working "as quickly as possible" to restore service, it did not provide a concrete timetable for a fix.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Meta apps, services, and platforms are currently experiencing a widespread outage, the company confirmed in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/Meta/status/1866918000374280593" target="_blank">post</a> on X (formerly Twitter). Users started experiencing issues in the afternoon on Wednesday, Dec. 11, as evidenced by various social media posts on working platforms and by the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://downdetector.com" target="_blank">Downdetector</a> — a site that tracks interruptions to major services. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/instagram">Instagram</a>, Facebook, WhatsApp, Threads, Messenger, and Oculus are a few platforms that appear to be affected by the outage.</p><p>"We’re aware that a technical issue is impacting some users’ ability to access our apps," the company said in the post. "We’re working to get things back to normal as quickly as possible and apologize for any inconvenience."</p><p>The problems can cause some Meta platforms to be inaccessible, load slowly, or show older posts. Multiple members of the Android Central team experienced issues with Meta apps. However, the number of Downdetector reports have slowly decreased over the last hour, indicating that Meta is making progress restoring service.</p><p>"We know there’s a technical issue impacting some people’s ability to access Instagram," the official Instagram account <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/instagram/status/1866920842443337824" target="_blank">posted</a> on X. "We’re working to get things back to normal as quickly as possible and are sorry for any inconvenience."</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">We’re aware that a technical issue is impacting some users’ ability to access our apps. We’re working to get things back to normal as quickly as possible and apologize for any inconvenience.<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1866918000374280593">December 11, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>The issues appear to be extremely widespread, with Downdetector showing over <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://downdetector.com/status/instagram/" target="_blank">70,000 reports of Instagram being unavailable</a> for users today. The situation is worse for Facebook, which has been reported down for over 100,000 users, according to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://downdetector.com/status/facebook/" target="_blank">Downdetector</a>.</p><p>This isn't the first time Meta's services have faced significant service interruptions. In March 2024, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/facebook-and-instagram-down-right-now">nearly all Meta platforms went offline</a> for a brief period.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/facebook-whatsapp-and-instagram-are-down-as-meta-faces-widespread-outage</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Nearly all of Meta's services, including Facebook, WhatsApp, Instagram, Threads, and Messenger, are currently down. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">8gZrEeKKwqezAnkjKr3JrS</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/g7z7GKTRj49D2GHSqfqYkT.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 19:43:59 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/g7z7GKTRj49D2GHSqfqYkT.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nick Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Facebook and Instagram down statuses on downdetector.com]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Facebook and Instagram down statuses on downdetector.com]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google's Project Astra waitlist signups begin with enhanced AR features ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-32">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google announced that it has opened its "trusted testers" waitlist for interested participants for Project Astra, its AR venture.</li><li>The company detailed that users can engage with Project Astra via mobile (Android) and "prototype glasses."</li><li>It seems there will be an experimental Astra app that lets users open their camera or share their screen for quick information on what they see.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google's "vision for the future of AR" is entering an exciting phase today (Dec 11) as it progresses its development.</p><p>Per Google's DeepMind page <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://deepmind.google/technologies/project-astra/">for Project Astra</a>, the company announced that the latest AR venture has opened its "trusted tester" waitlist. The company states those <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScCrFFCFcZ9q_0Ti_a-qkh56W26lysgcArpNiaDDQ8DngG9eg/viewform?utm_source=deepmind.google&utm_medium=referral&utm_campaign=gdm&utm_content=">signing up today</a> (Dec 11) can explore the "future capabilities" of its "universal AI assistant." Signing up will require users to fill out a brief form involving their name, location, age, and Android phone type.</p><p>Additionally, Google will ask if you are interested in "using prototype glasses."</p><p>When it comes to your phone, it seems this early test will see accepted participants downloading a Project Astra Android app. A short demo video shows that users can open the app and activate the camera within it to point at something they're interested in. Google states Astra is "multilingual," meaning users can speak to the AI model in their preferred language and receive information back.</p><p>The demo shows a model asking about a string of Chinese lanterns (in French). Astra responds both vocally and in written text with (hopefully) relevant and useful information about your query.</p><p>Moreover, Google adds that users can "share their screen" with Astra to gain even more assistance.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1050px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:50.19%;"><img id="scrkicTkF2C4mLg9diudmP" name="google-project-astra-enters-signup-phase" alt="Google's Project Astra lets testers point their cameras at items within its app to receive information about it." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/scrkicTkF2C4mLg9diudmP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1050" height="527" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The AI model is said to leverage Google apps like Maps, Lens, and Search to fulfill a user's query. This is reportedly a part of its "enhanced understanding." A <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://deepmind.google/technologies/project-astra/tool-use/">subsequent post</a> shows that Astra is capable of "contextual understanding" for "clear, detailed answers, and it can explain the thinking and context behind" its answers. Moreover, Google has added a memory bank to Astra, meaning the AI <em>should </em>remember key details from your previous encounters.</p><p>This seems like something similar to "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini-saved-info-rollout-detailed">Saved Info</a>" in Gemini, which Google rolled out in mid-November.</p><p>The other side of this sign-up is Google's mention of prototype AR glasses. Its announcement splash page only highlights that Astra can "integrate seamlessly with prototype glasses to see the world as you see it – for an even more immersive and helpful experience."</p><p>We've been expecting AR glasses from Google <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/google-may-have-shown-off-ar-glasses-prototype-at-io-2024">ever since I/O 2024</a> when it showcased Project Astra. The demo showed how interactive and engaged Project Astra is (likely) designed to be. When wearing a pair of AR glasses, the device will "record" your surroundings in real time, so when you ask a question, the AI can answer it.</p><p>It's worth mentioning that Project Astra is an AI routine <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/google-project-starline-astra-ar-glasses">that's built off Gemini</a> to give it that "real person-like" experience during conversations. Google also showed that Astra can remember the location of objects, like where you last set down your AR glasses.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hIIlJt8JERI" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/google-project-astra-ar-waitlist-opens-trusted-testers</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google opens the gates to its trusted tester waitlist for Project Astra. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">9oJhGAtfbfhsmHV6hPSCUc</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AoKqVHdHVKDR67J5V6YHtH.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 18:36:36 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AoKqVHdHVKDR67J5V6YHtH.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google&#039;s Project Astra opens its trusted testers signup.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google&#039;s Project Astra opens its trusted testers signup.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>