<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 20:35:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Motorola Razr Plus 2024 leak details major upgrades as launch reportedly nears ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A substantial Motorola "Razr Plus 2024" leak seemingly spills all that consumers should expect.</li><li>It's suggested that the device could feature a 6.9-inch display with a slightly larger 3.9-inch cover display alongside RAM and battery upgrades.</li><li>These rumors also confirm a pricing leak that speculated Motorola could keep the price of its 2024 model similar to that of its 2023 edition.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Quite a substantial leak has surfaced regarding Motorola&apos;s upcoming flagship foldable smartphone.</p><p>Information has come to light via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.smartprix.com/bytes/exclusive-moto-razr-50-ultra-to-debut-as-razr-2024-in-the-us-check-detailed-specs-and-pricing/">SmartPrix</a> in conjunction with X tipster <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://twitter.com/OnLeaks/status/1789983910014628206">OnLeaks</a>, who state the Moto Razr 50 Ultra will be called the "Motorola Razr Plus 2024" in the U.S. For specifications, the clamshell is rumored to feature a 6.9-inch pOLED display internally, with a larger 3.9-inch cover display over <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-review">its predecessor</a>.</p><p>It seems consumers are still in for a dual camera array, as the publication states that once it launches, a wide 50MP lens could be paired with a 50MP telephoto. The latter is said to offer 2x optical zoom, while its punch-hole selfie camera is rumored to arrive at 32MP.</p><p>Qualcomm&apos;s recent Snapdragon 8s Gen 3 SoC is speculated to power the Moto Razr Plus 2024. This toned-down chip sits right under the flagship SD 8 Gen 3, though it clocks in at 3.0GHz. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review">Android 14, </a>with an array of photo and video features powered by AI, is rumored for the device.</p><p>The leaks suggest other notable upgrades, beginning with the device&apos;s RAM. Supposedly, the Razr Plus 2024 will boast 12GB of RAM alongside 256GB of internal storage. Another improvement is rumored to arrive for its battery, as the tipster states the device could pick up a 4,000mAh battery.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Hey #FutureSquad! Today, I have the complete specs sheet as well as the US pricing of the #Motorola #Razr50Ultra (which will likely be marketed as "Razr+ 2024" in the US) to share with you! 😏On behalf of @Smartprix 👉🏻 https://t.co/7MTNBeLUut pic.twitter.com/IC7CpGnnGc<a href="https://twitter.com/OnLeaks/status/1789983910014628206">May 13, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>The good news here is that the latest leaks suggest that despite the upgrades, the Razr Plus 2024&apos;s price might not change. The device will allegedly hit the market with a $999 price tag, which is the same price that last year&apos;s model launched with, sporting 8GB of RAM and 256GB of storage.</p><p>The post adds that Motorola is gearing up for a June launch for the foldable.</p><p>Last year&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-review">Moto Razr Plus</a> debuted with the same internal display size; however, the latest rumors suggest we&apos;re looking for a slightly larger cover display. The device also debuted with a 3,800mAh battery with 8GB of RAM. With rumors suggesting an upgrade in both areas for (potentially) the same price, it looks like Motorola is staring down stronger competition with Samsung&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-z-flip-6-cover-display-memory-rumors">Flip 6</a>.</p><p>Regarding pricing leaks, we heard three days ago that Motorola could keep its price similar — at least in Europe. It was purported that the device could feature a €1200 price tag, which closely matched what consumers in the region saw last year. With rumors now suggesting the same for the U.S. market, perhaps this rumor bears weight.</p><p>Additionally, the Razr Plus 2024 had a render leak back in January, which makes us think the device&apos;s design <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2024-alleged-leaked-render">might not change</a>.</p>
<ul><li> <strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/major-motorola-razr-plus-2024-specs-leak</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A major Motorola Razr Plus 2024 leak seems to highlight everything consumers can expect this year. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Axbyg6KW32vJ8ajDXqJJdn</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tWMdHCviQDD3WC9UkU3aYL.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 20:32:27 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tWMdHCviQDD3WC9UkU3aYL.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Lock screen clock on the Razr+ cover display]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Lock screen clock on the Razr+ cover display]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google I/O 2024: live blog and everything you need to know ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Can you believe it&apos;s already been an entire year since the last I/O? It&apos;s been a whirlwind and there aren&apos;t any signs of things slowing down. </p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-io-2024">Google I/O 2024</a> is set to kick off in less than 24 hours, and the best part is that you don&apos;t have to be in Mountain View to see what Google has to announce. Although I/O 2024 is an in-person event, the company makes it easy to watch from the comfort of your home. </p><p>We&apos;ve got you covered if you aren&apos;t sure where to start and don&apos;t really know <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-io-2024"><strong>what to expect from I/O 2024</strong></a>!</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-live-stream"><span>Live stream</span></h3>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XEzRZ35urlk" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>


 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/news/live/google-io-2024-live-blog</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google I/O 2024 has arrived, marking the first major event from the company for the year. While much of the event is likely to be focused on AI, we're also expecting to learn more about Android 15, and maybe some other fun stuff. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">tzyhitqfzXDu76jKzL3dnJ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/a9QEqLupB2Q5BJiikjSpPb.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 20:14:39 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ shruti.shekar@futurenet.com (Shruti Shekar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/a9QEqLupB2Q5BJiikjSpPb.jpeg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Giant Google I/O 2023 sign at Shoreline Amphitheatre]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Giant Google I/O 2023 sign at Shoreline Amphitheatre]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Ask Jerry: What is FCC certification, and why do phones need it? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Welcome to Ask Jerry, where we talk about any and all the questions you might have about the smart things in your life. I&apos;m Jerry, and I have spent the better part of my life working with tech. I have a background in engineering and R&D and have been covering Android and Google for the past 15 years. </p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Ask Jerry</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="rbW6k4ZmBUAZL7mR2bMnV6" name="jerrydude-avatar.gif" caption="" alt="Android Avatar of Jerry" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rbW6k4ZmBUAZL7mR2bMnV6.gif" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Future)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">Ask Jerry is a column where we answer your burning Android/tech questions with the help of long-time Android Central editor Jerry Hildenbrand.</p></div></div>
<p>I&apos;m also really good at researching data about everything — that&apos;s a big part of our job here at Android Central — and I love to help people (another big part of our job!). If you have questions about your tech, I&apos;d love to talk about them. </p><p>Email me at askjerryac@gmail.com, and I&apos;ll try to get things sorted out. You can remain anonymous if you like, and we promise we&apos;re not sharing anything we don&apos;t cover here.</p><p>I look forward to hearing from you!</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="what-is-fcc-certification-why-do-we-need-this-2">What is FCC certification? Why do we need this?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="GvBTnuVSjvymoJSWiXyYHo" name="xiaomi-13-pro-5.jpg" alt="Xiaomi 13 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GvBTnuVSjvymoJSWiXyYHo.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Dustin asks:</p><p><em><strong>Why do phone manufacturers like Xiaomi, Oppo, Vivo, IQOO, etc. send their phones to the FCC for approval if they don&apos;t ultimately get released in the US?</strong></em></p><p><em><strong>Thanks!</strong></em></p>
<p>This is a really good question, Dustin, thanks for asking. I think a lot of people will be interested in finding out what <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-reaches-us-fcc-listing">FCC certification</a> is for and, of course, why companies get it even if they have no plans to sell products in the states. I know I was when I got your email!</p><p>As usual, I like to start with the easy answer and get it out of the way:</p>
<p>FCC certification (for phones and other wireless devices) makes sure the equipment doesn&apos;t interfere with other equipment. For approval, a manufacturer has to set specific limits on all radio signals — both intentional and unintentional — that can be sent out. Other tests do things like ensure the amount of radiation from a device isn&apos;t harmful, but the main goal of certification is to make sure a phone can&apos;t do something like mess with other equipment.</p><p>Any phone sold or marketed in the United States must get FCC approval for either commercial (Class A devices) or residential (Class B) use. If a device has the potential to emit radio signals, like for instance a microwave, it requires something similar known as a Supplier&apos;s Declaration of Conformity filed with the FCC.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="87cq28PdnGdmwK7M9aDWa" name="oppo-find-x7-ultra-1.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X7 Ultra review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/87cq28PdnGdmwK7M9aDWa.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Many phone manufacturers will also get FCC approval for devices they don&apos;t intend to sell in the U.S. As Dustin mentioned, it&apos;s common to see Xiaomi (for example) get a phone certified without any intention of selling it here.</p><p>Technically, these devices don&apos;t <em>have</em> to be certified, but doing so is a wise decision. It covers the manufacturer—and you—if you are using one in the U.S., regardless of whether or not it&apos;s sold here.</p>
<p>Thanks to the internet, it&apos;s fairly easy to get your hands on any of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a>, even international ones, no matter where you live. A quick trip to Amazon will get you something like a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Xiaomi-Ultra-256GB-Factory-Unlocked/dp/B0C6QK2QL8">Xiaomi Mi 13 Ultra</a>, and even though it&apos;s a Chinese phone built for the Chinese market, it will work in many places in the States, too.</p><p>Not a lot of people are doing this. There&apos;s no guarantee it will work in your area because of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/carriers/5g">network support</a>, there is no warranty, and buying it is only half the solution; even after the language is set to English or Spanish, much of the phone is still in Mandarin until a different OS is flashed to the device. It&apos;s easier to buy a phone officially sold in the U.S.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="3Jt8Js4udELCrnDmuhKCbn" name="xiaomi-13-ultra-kit-13.jpg" alt="Xiaomi 13 Ultra camera kit assembled" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3Jt8Js4udELCrnDmuhKCbn.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>We aren&apos;t most people. If you read about Android or smartphones on the internet, you&apos;re at least a partial nerd, and that&apos;s not a bad thing 😉. A lot of us would love to have some of these phones, even with the extra hurdles to jump through. I used the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/xiaomi-13-ultra-global-review">Xiaomi Mi 13 Ultra</a> as an example because I would love to have one!</p><p>So, let&apos;s pretend I did shell out the money to import one into my nerdly hands. I certainly want to make sure that it can&apos;t interfere with other devices while I&apos;m using it. Imagine the horror of my phone messing with equipment at a hospital or even causing problems with a TV signal or a Citizen&apos;s Band radio.</p>
<p>This means more than having regrets. You are going to be held financially responsible — the feds take this seriously. So is the manufacturer.</p><p>Xiamoi gets the device FCC certified as a way to cover its own ass, and inadvertently it covers yours, too. the company knows that people with this phone will vacation in the U.S. and that people in the U.S. will buy the product even though it&apos;s not "marketed or sold" in the United States officially.</p>
<p>Government involvement and regulations can be silly, mired in red tape, and often overstep their bounds. In this case, I think what the FCC does — something similar is done in most countries around the world — is a necessary evil. But so is companies getting the certification for products they don&apos;t intend to sell in the U.S.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/ask-jerry-why-is-fcc-certification-necessary</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Have a question about the tech in your life? If so, maybe we can get them answered! ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">pbwECCWjrr9fLGEMNbJ8cg</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HrmCzNcQDgwjg2sArrBf7S.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 20:00:55 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HrmCzNcQDgwjg2sArrBf7S.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android statues]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android statues]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Meta Quest picks up a 'Travel Mode' for in-flight VR content and entertainment ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Meta announced the launch of "Travel Mode" for the Quest 2 and Quest 3.</li><li>Travel Mode is designed to give VR users a chance to enjoy entertainment, games, mediation apps, and more while in-flight.</li><li>Meta also announced its pilot program with Lufthansa, which will give Business Class Suite customers an array of unique content with the Quest 3.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Meta announces a new feature for its Quest devices that might make airline travel a little more enjoyable.</p><p>According to a press release, Meta&apos;s CEO Mark Zuckerberg stated that a "Travel Mode" is on its way to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/oculus-quest-2-review">Quest 2</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-3-review">Quest 3</a> VR headsets. In an accompanying <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.meta.com/blog/quest/travel-mode-lufthansa-airplane-flight-entertainment/">blog post</a>, the new mode turns the headsets into the "ultimate in-flight entertainment device." If Wi-Fi is available for everyone, Meta states the Quest should prompt you to join it while automatically launching its browser to begin browsing and watching videos.</p><p>Meta adds that this Travel Mode should give some folks a more comfortable time getting work done as it creates a private space. Games, meditation apps, and more will become available, as well.</p><p>The post adds that both VR headsets utilize a new Meta algorithm for Travel Mode that helps keep what you see stable. More importantly, a user&apos;s VR viewing pleasure should remain consistent even when gazing out the window.</p><p>The Quest 2 and Quest 3&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.meta.com/help/quest/articles/in-vr-experiences/oculus-features/travel-mode/?intern_source=blog&intern_content=travel-mode-lufthansa-airplane-flight-entertainment">Travel Mode</a> is an opt-in feature. To do so, Meta states users need to hop into <strong>Settings > Experimental features </strong>to get started. Users must restart their Quest after opting into the experimental features. Then, the Travel Mode will appear as a toggleable option in Quick Settings.</p><p>Meta states that both headsets should begin to sense when the user is on a plane automatically and offer to launch Travel Mode. The company plans to add support for trains in the future.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1066px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.29%;"><img id="anF6jfgp38QjFwmVqpzmSE" name="meta-quest-3-travel-mode-browser.jpg" alt="The Meta Quest 3 opening its browser during Travel Mode on a flight." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/anF6jfgp38QjFwmVqpzmSE.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1066" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Meta)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1066px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.29%;"><img id="dkwKkcm9xwpNfps6gzv5oK" name="meta-quest-3-travel-mode-chess-game.jpg" alt="The Meta Quest 3 can play games like chess through Travel Mode." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dkwKkcm9xwpNfps6gzv5oK.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1066" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Meta)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>The other side of this Meta Quest update is the company&apos;s pilot program with Lufthansa. Both companies are preparing to outfit a "select number" of flights packed with Lufthansa Allegris Business Class Suite customers. The goal is to offer a range of "custom" MR content that spans entertainment, travel, wellness, games, and more.</p><p>Meta states that all of this is optimized and should work well with the Quest 3&apos;s Travel Mode capabilities.</p><p>Meta and Lufthansa explain that Business Class Suite customers will soon find an "immersive" cinema experience through the Quest 3 for movies and TV shows. Podcasts should also become more immersive as the device&apos;s VR capabilities and spatial video, alongside "select" 360-degree video content. Additionally, features and content are as follows:</p>
<ul><li>Discover travel destinations from a bird’s-eye view with virtual sightseeing previews before you arrive</li><li>Play interactive games like Connect Four and Chess</li><li>Relax with active meditation exercises or enjoy a passive, lean-back experience</li></ul>
<div class="instagram-embed"><blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned data-instgrm-version="6" style="width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"><p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C66Th4eL4EY/" target="_blank">A post shared by Mark Zuckerberg (@zuck)</a></p><p>A photo posted by  on </p></blockquote></div>
<ul><li> <strong>VR headset deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/searchpage.jsp?st=vr+headset"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=vr+headset"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.newegg.com/Virtual-Reality-Headsets/EventSaleStore/ID-2140595"><u><strong>Newegg</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.meta.com/"><u><strong>Meta</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/virtual-reality/5454301"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a></li></ul>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="cc81267f-a874-4dbf-a46b-35dce7cbebd1">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3YdJhoJWw8jAejG37VJMcQ.jpeg' alt='Meta Quest 3 product render'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Meta Quest 3</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The best VR headset you can buy</strong></em></p>
<p>The Meta Quest 3 truly takes what the company started with the second edition and makes it all better. The headset boasts an impressive visual upgrade and its work with mixed reality has improved. The Quest 3's controllers feel much more comfortable in-hand alongside notable graphic and performance enhancements.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-travel-mode-launch</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Meta launched a new in-flight travel mode for the Quest while debuting a new program for certain airline customers. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Zwf2zhh4hidVRz8esVrbz5</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gxT94FhFKeAWHcZAacuT48.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 18:12:38 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gxT94FhFKeAWHcZAacuT48.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Meta]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[An example of a Meta Quest 3 using Travel Mode and viewing three panels.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[An example of a Meta Quest 3 using Travel Mode and viewing three panels.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Best DACs for Android 2024 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>I was trying to wait to write this roundup until Spotify officially announced their Hi-Res Audio offering, but I’m getting old, and life is short, so here we are. There are DACs in this list for every budget and every level of sophistication. From the casual listener to the enthusiast, (GASP!) even a neophyte “audiophile,” we have something for you here. These are the best DACs for your Android-based audio enjoyment. Whether it’s a tablet, smartphone, or Chromebook, we’ve got you covered.</p><p>To fully experience the enhanced audio qualities these DACs offer your phone or tablet, you’ll need an app like Neturon Player or USB Player Pro (my favorite) to bypass an Android limitation. Google’s OS downsamples USB-C output to 16bit/44.1kHz or CD quality, but with the proper setup, you can unlock the full potential of high-resolution audio. We know that hi-res&apos;s “full potential” is somewhat controversial, but we’ll save that for another article. Let’s dive into these DACs!</p>
<h2 id="the-best-dacs-for-android-2">The best DACs for Android</h2>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="f7107ec7-7a8f-4895-a389-fa87a62d059f">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QWkeaYt7ygXtZ4xgKweAZj.jpg' alt='Apple USB-C to 3.5mm adapter'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Apple USB-C to 3.5mm adapter</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best bang for your buck</strong></em></p>
<p>Yes, this is an Android fan site. No, there are not many super basic dongle DACs available for $9 that offer quality audio output that works for whatever your mobile OS is. All you need is that USB-C port and headphones with a 3.5mm male cable or adapter for your larger connectors and you’re good to go. This one has been around for years and is tried, true, and tested ad nauseam by the snootiest audiophiles on the planet, so it should be good enough for us mere mortals, right? Right.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="e8afb2a6-9541-4fdd-a9f2-154e463a1af8">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/m7LR9kt7Lin3BjoQ4nU4aL.jpg' alt='Fiio KA11 dongle DAC'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">FiiO KA11</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best Apple dongle upgrade</strong></em></p>
<p>If you have some pricey in-ear monitors or over-ear headphones, you may need more power to drive them, and if you’re on a budget, that’s where the excellent FiiO KA11 comes in. It has a neutral sound, no companion app, and if you’re into numbers you should know that the power I spoke of comes in the form of 245mW of power at 16Ω. Available in silver and black, the compact but sturdy metal build means you can toss it in a bag and go without worry. If you find that the Apple dongle requires you to push the audio level to the max with the headphones or IEMs you’re using, the KA11 is the upgrade you need.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="be590afe-1454-4347-a3da-6829aae517f9">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xWEnTHPszSqQH54RecLbQM.jpg' alt='THX Onyx DAC/AMP'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">THX Onyx</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best phone-powered compact MQA DAC</strong></em></p>
<p>THX Onyx is a THX-certified AAA DAC with a high voltage output whose ability to drive headphones and IEMs is immediately noticeable if you’re upgrading from something like the Apple dongle. It’s also certified to play MQA files from Tidal and has a handy set of LEDs so that you know what level of files you’re decoding. The build quality of the metal frame is excellent, and the cable management via magnets is a delightful touch. The sound is warm with a large soundstage, but the device is very efficient with a lower power draw than others in this class. This means it won’t kill your phone’s battery while attached and in use.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="a32ae53d-5246-4aae-b07a-73d2f9a2bd8c">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ntGSZtDHMaYzC4gMyqhkCM.jpg' alt='iFi GO blu DAC/AMP'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">iFi GO blu</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best overall mobile DAC/AMP for Android</strong></em></p>
<p>This DAC/AMP blew my mind the first time I used it with my Sennheiser HD 660S2’s connected to it. It’s self-powered by a 450mAh battery, so it has impressive on-device controlled volume to the 3.5mm SE or 4.4mm balanced outputs. Connect to it via USB-C, or Bluetooth while supporting a variety of Hi-Res Wireless Audio Bluetooth codecs. You'll even have the ability to update to future codecs over the air. Best of all, it has three EQ presets that add warmth, increase the soundstage, or a mix of both via analog circuitry and not DSP. Did I mention that it's one of the best-looking DACs in this roundup?</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="8d29a0f2-c12f-4970-97f5-fed6fb81f9d8">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Gpy5g4NBbsuMGxqgF7D9JM.jpg' alt='Qudelix-5k DAC/AMP'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Qudelix-5k</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best audiophile tinkerer mobile DAC/AMP</strong></em></p>
<p>This DAC/AMP is similar to the iFi GO blu, minus the alluring industrial design, but it makes up for that with a companion app fit for serious audiophiles. There’s a deep set of features in that app, including a fully decked-out parametric EQ. Seriously! Steep learning curve ahead if you’re new to the world of “coloring” your audio, playing with gain, power output and so much more. It'll take time, but if you're into shaping your sound, it's worth it!</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="47d687ac-8be9-4e3f-b481-5dc620943bdd">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MiUEpMb8irJBGMZ5FLirYM.jpg' alt='iFi Zen DAC 3'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">iFi Zen DAC 3</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best travel-friendly desktop DAC/AMP</strong></em></p>
<p>The iFi Zen DAC 3 is the third generation of iFi’s highly lauded, somewhat portable desktop DAC. This is for those of you who want something at home, or to take to the office in your backpack. Connect to your tablet or Chromebook- or Mac, or Windows machines! There’s a Burr-Brown True Native chipset onboard, so file formats are rendered “bit-perfect.” If you have open-back headphones and feel they’re a little light on the bass, TrueBass enhances bass output via analog circuitry, without DSP in the mix. Power it via USB-C, or use 5V DC and get cleaner, more powerful sound reproduction. Being a desktop DAC/AMP, you get 4.4mm balanced and unbalanced 6.3mm and RCA outputs.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="478ae7d2-d3bd-4a8b-8820-49474a0b5cd6">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JzCGe2JXMXSaRJnbsWZJaD.jpg' alt='FiiO K19 Desktop DAC/AMP'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">FiiO K19</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best aspirational premium DAC/AMP</strong></em></p>
<p>The most expensive DAC on the list, FiiO’s K19 is for serious audio lovers! This desktop DAC/AMP features beautiful aluminum honeycomb side paneling, but the attention to detail and connectivity options are what impressed us the most besides the sound. The front has 6.35mm, 4.4mm, 4-pin XLR ports, and a USB-C port. On the rear, you can connect to AC or DC power with a switch to select which one. Also on the rear are 3-pin XLRs, RCA ports with dust covers, optical in/out, coaxial in/out, and USB-C in. You can even use the K19 with TVs and gaming consoles thanks to the HDMI in and HDMI ARC out ports. The bundled IR remote control is a nice touch, but you can also access all of the features via the FiiO Control app.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="e529da80-4e2a-4910-a113-92d47ac50369">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JWwt6hvYgqFV8jSvLUAXE9.jpg' alt='Shanling M0 Pro'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Shanling M0 Pro</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best multifunctional DAC</strong></em></p>
<p>This relatively inexpensive DAC is unique on this list due to its ability to double as a digital audio player, or DAP. It features a beautiful metal design with a tiny 1.54-inch LCD, and is available in red, green, or black colorways. What makes this such a worthy DAC is its dual ESS chips, allowing for balanced output if you buy the optional 3.5mm to 4.4mm connector. Aside from that you also get a large 650mAh battery capable of 14.5 hours of playback. This DAP/DAC works via Bluetooth and USB-C and has a microSD slot supporting up to 2TB of storage for offline music listening.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="4368a3e3-b2e1-40d8-b2ee-e4872fad9f03">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dJeH3AeqCZqDdBLxJsgpkM.jpg' alt='LG V60 ThinQ 5G'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">LG V60 ThinkQ 5G</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best DAC you hadn't considered</strong></em></p>
<p>Get off my lawn!! I want my LG V60 ThinkQ 5G back! Unlike the majority of today’s phones, this one had a 3.5mm port built-in, AS WELL AS a Quad DAC. You can still find these refurbished and unlocked on Amazon, and you’ll get a competent smartphone that could be your highly capable “iPod Touch” at a price comparable with many of the products on this list. Think about it… you can use WiFi to connect to all of your favorite streaming apps. Use onboard storage for offline music playback. And if you need a backup phone, BOOM! Look no further. It’s like a Swiss Army DAP! You’re welcome.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<ul><li><a href="#main"><strong>Back to the top ^</strong></a></li></ul>
<h2 id="before-you-buy-that-dac-know-this-2">Before you buy that DAC, know this...</h2>
<figure><blockquote><p>Imagine me on a rooftop, shouting; your DAC won’t matter if your headphones or IEMs are trash. Just like you can’t outwork a bad diet in the gym, you can’t outperform poor-performing headphones or IEMs in your DAC purchase. But no worry—we have you covered there as well.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>You can check out Harish’s review of some of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/wired-earbuds-are-making-a-comeback-and-im-excited">best IEMs your hard-earned dollars</a> can buy. Or you can peruse our selection of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones">best wireless headphones</a>, many of which you can connect via 3.5mm cable to one of the DACs on this list. For example, Sennheiser’s Momentum 4s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/do-listeners-really-care-about-hi-res-audio">sound excellent paired with iFi’s GO blu DAC/AMP</a>.</p><p>The next thing you need to know is that pairing a good pair of headphones or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-fa19-review">IEMs</a> with a DAC is like pairing beverages with food; some go better together than others. Part of the fun for some people is the exploration, so you’ll have to try out the headphones that have caught your attention with the DAC you can afford or want to try and see how they sound. Some people will buy a couple DACs at a time and trial things, then return the one they don’t want or sell it. </p><p>One feature I want to take a moment to clarify, if you haven’t had much experience with headphones and DACs is the 4.4mm (or XLR) balanced output. It’s really simple, actually. A DAC with <strong>balanced output</strong> sends signal/power to both the left and right audio channels independently from two separate DAC chips, unlike one with <strong>unbalanced output </strong>(also referred to as &apos;single-ended&apos; or &apos;SE&apos;), which sends power to both left and right channels from a single source. You’ll immediately notice more volume (turn it down when going balanced), and greater bass detail. If you’re in an environment with a lot of electromagnetic interference, you’ll also have less “noise” in your audio. If you have a pair of high-quality headphones that support balanced audio and you have the budget, you should definitely be looking at one of those DACs for Android.</p><p>If your “audiophile” experience isn’t extensive, any item on this list beyond the Apple adapter will be a noticeable upgrade from what you’ve been listening to. So, sit back, relax, press play, and lose yourself in immersive sound.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/best-dacs-for-android</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Expand your auditory experience with this selection of the best DACs for Android. We have something for you, no matter your budget or level of sophistication! ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">2vAgeTVxqf8vPNLkC45qLe</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JMjf7YoZZbGgYyMJSPmexL.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 17:55:44 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ klpmediallc@gmail.com (Tshaka Armstrong) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JMjf7YoZZbGgYyMJSPmexL.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[iFi]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[iFi GO blu DAC/AMP lifestyle]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[iFi GO blu DAC/AMP lifestyle]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google is bringing Project Starline's 3D video calls to everyone in 2025 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google wants to enhance the video conferencing experience by integrating Project Starline with popular platforms like Google Meet and Zoom.</li><li>Teaming up with HP, Google plans to launch its 3D video call platform in 2025.</li><li>Project Starline introduces a teleconferencing solution that projects lifelike 3D models of participants, replicating gestures and expressions, thus simulating an in-person experience.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google is working on bringing its Project Starline solution to everyday platforms like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/top-10-google-meet-tips-and-tricks-you-need-know">Google Meet</a> and Zoom for a more lifelike video conferencing experience.</p><p>The company <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.google/technology/research/google-project-starline-hp-partnership/" target="_blank">announced</a> that it is partnering with HP to bring the 3D video call platform to market in 2025. Plus, it is working on making it compatible with your <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-video-conference-software">favorite video conferencing services</a> so you can ditch the flat screen.</p><p>In 2021, Google started working on Project Starline, a teleconferencing setup where you see a 3D model of the person you&apos;re talking to, complete with all their gestures and expressions, making it feel like you&apos;re actually in the same room. It&apos;s designed for businesses for now, but it&apos;s definitely a glimpse into the future of video chat.</p><p>At last year&apos;s I/O conference, Google <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-project-starline-new-prototype-2023">revealed a prototype that&apos;s way smaller and sleeker</a> compared to the original bulky booth-like design. Instead of a booth, the new version is more like a digital whiteboard. It&apos;s got just a few cameras around the screen, but it used AI to work out the depth, giving it that 3D feel.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NGPyOHKWLFQ" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>After years of tinkering, Google is finally bringing Project Starline out of the lab and into the real world.</p><p>Google mentioned that after clocking in thousands of hours of testing across Google offices and with business partners, it discovered that meetings in Starline feel more like being physically together than just your usual video calls.</p><p>The Mountain View-based company points out that this results in people paying better attention, remembering things easier, and feeling more like they&apos;re in the same room, not miles apart. In Starline, folks behave as if they&apos;re right there in the same room, not separated by thousands of miles, according to the company.</p><p>No pricing details are available yet, but it&apos;s likely that bigger companies with the cash and room to spare will be the first to dive in. Google has promised to make Project Starline cheaper and easier to get hold of eventually, but for now, it&apos;s not really meant for personal use.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-is-bringing-project-starlines-3d-video-calls-to-everyone-in-2025</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google's Project Starline is exiting the lab, and it will work with Meet and Zoom. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">QXgWzQGp9XKu3ezp29JCXZ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gTGKsyXAoTaMgfBkZZhKmg.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 16:14:06 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gTGKsyXAoTaMgfBkZZhKmg.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Project Starline video conferencing solution]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Project Starline video conferencing solution]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Best MP3 players 2024 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Listening to high-resolution, and uncompressed audio files is no longer for audiophiles only. Most major music services offer some form of hi-res or lossless, so it&apos;s time you stepped up your gear game to get the most out of the service you&apos;re paying for! Even Spotify is still threatening to offer Hi-Res Audio to its subscribers. We&apos;ll believe that when it finally happens though.</p><p>You&apos;ll need more than your $8 USB-C to 3.5mm Apple dongle (though audiophiles praise it for its cost-to-quality benefit) to fully realize the highs and lows of that high-resolution digital data flow. To that end, we&apos;ve compiled this list of the best digital audio players (DAPs) that support high-resolution audio playback. From affordable, entry-level options to over-the-top aspirational enthusiast favorites, this collection rounds up the best of the best.</p>
<h2 id="step-into-the-world-of-audio-nerds-2">Step into the world of audio nerds</h2>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="fefdd902-3ea9-47a1-bdba-9d49ff791388">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ogJ6KZYFgJ3NX5eZxc6SU4.jpg' alt='FiiO M11 Plus ESS'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">FiiO M11 Plus ESS</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Absurdly good audio</strong></em></p>
<p>FiiO has mastered the art of fine-tuning sound as proven by the superb audio gear made by the brand. The FiiO M11 Plus ESS is top-tier, supporting all the things. You get Android 10 and a 5.5-inch touchscreen interface. It has dual DACs, dual-band WiFi, expandable storage up to 2TB, and 3.5mm/2.5mm/4.4mm outputs. Look forward to lossless audio support, along with LDAC, LHDC, and aptX-HD. The M11 Plus ESS has enough power on tap to drive some of the hungriest headphones.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="c7f5bdb5-d13e-47d6-a1e6-96c35143fb4a">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:99.92%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/c9DisNHnsSzzxioZqtYPNd.jpg' alt='SanDisk Clip Jam'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">SanDisk Clip Jam</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Properly cheap and cheerful</strong></em></p>
<p>If you're not in need of a specialized, uber-expensive MP3 player, then SanDisk is there to save the day. The Clip Jam is an adorable audio player with a tiny footprint. You won't find any fancy codecs and file formats here, but the physical navigational buttons are easy to use while working out and you get 8GB of on-device storage.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="d554ed32-9b2f-4531-874e-693fa3bf26c6">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/P9nREXURrX3dGPN5kWSTg4.jpg' alt='HiBy R3 II'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">HiBy R3 II</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>For the pros on budget</strong></em></p>
<p>The HiBy R3 II fills in the gap without skimping on high-quality sound. This touchscreen MP3 player delivers balanced audio and supports advanced codecs such as UAT and LDAC. You even get Wi-Fi and Bluetooth connectivity, letting you play music from any platform. When you don’t have WiFi, simply place the R3 II into DAC/AMP mode, connect it to your phone, and use it as an external DAC/AMP via USB or Bluetooth.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="2bd1deac-fd28-47ea-af4b-dd9a92bbe9b2">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/aDGNgcTRaNSJSysPLrFqj3.jpg' alt='Astell&Kern KANN Ultra'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Astell&Kern KANN Ultra</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Over-the-top option</strong></em></p>
<p>The Astell&Kern KANN Ultra is ultra aspirational with its four-figure price tag. While audiophiles will argue about what you get here versus a slightly less expensive kit, there seems to be no argument about the high-resolution, lossless audio that makes your mouth water and your eyes sparkle. It has all the ports and technical goodies under the hood to please sound engineers and audiophiles alike.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="be861c19-320a-4cc2-9786-70993d834320">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LpXv25qXFFzdVsPduNC7DA.jpg' alt='HIFI WALKER H2'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">HIFI WALKER H2</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>HQ sound for all</strong></em></p>
<p>The HIFI WALKER H2 costs half as much as the mid-range HiBy player, and we couldn't be happier about it. HIFI trades a touch screen for satisfying physical buttons, a wide assortment of supported audio file formats, DSD playback, and a built-in DAC from Burr-Brown.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="ab8b81b9-0063-4677-ab9c-3febf437bfbf">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vUMGtwKhzadEBMfepMXU45.jpg' alt='Sony NW-A306'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Sony NW-A306 Walkman</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Reliable make</strong></em></p>
<p>The words "Sony" and "Walkman" sure trigger heavy nostalgia. Sony's cassette-tape days may be gone, but the Sony NW-A306 Walkman high-res music player sports impressive features at an amicable cost. It features extensive high-res file support, up to 32-bit/384kHz PCM, MQA, and DSD256 file formats. You also get aptX HD and LDAC codec support. There's only 32GB of storage, and half of that is taken up by Android, but it's expandable up to 2TB via a microSD card.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="31e7008f-2d88-4488-b01d-1bf2614108df">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kdNAHwtazrL6ZWZfFLYNv4.jpg' alt='Mighty 3 DAP'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Mighty 3</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>No-frills experience</strong></em></p>
<p>Mighty's adorable little music player is shaped like a cube and has a clip on the back. For the “mature” among you, this is reminiscent of the 6th generation iPod Nano, but without the touchscreen. You can set up the Mighty Vibe 3 in a jiffy using your phone and attach it to your armband for easy access. It can store around a thousand songs and you can sync your Spotify (family or premium only) or Amazon Music libraries with it then enjoy those tunes for up to eight hours on a charge.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="2132aeff-29e8-457f-9d42-64bbab2bf925">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JWwt6hvYgqFV8jSvLUAXE9.jpg' alt='Shanling M0 Pro'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Shanling M0 Pro</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>iPod Nano incarnate</strong></em></p>
<p>Missing the iPod Nano's small form factor coupled with a touch display? The Shanling M0 Pro is the perfect modern alternative. But its size belies its power! Dual ESS DACs for better sound and power than its predecessor, a new 3.5mm connector, and bi-directional Bluetooth are just some of its many features! It's hard to believe such a tiny device can produce such high-quality audio. Our <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/author/harish-jonnalagadda">Harish Jonnalagadda</a> reviewed it and calls the M0 Pro, "<a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/shanling-m0-pro-review">a terrific choice.</a>" 'Nuff said?</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="846b9e8f-041a-4385-b21b-49b95591a7bb">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/z6FoHX9LAqGoPFSLsYrJ6Y.jpg' alt='LG V60 ThinQ 5G'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">LG V60 ThinQ 5G</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Complete package</strong></em></p>
<p>Those of you who don't want to separate your MP3 player and smartphone needs can grab the LG V60 ThinQ 5G. LG's foray into phone making was good while it lasted, giving us gems like the V60 ThinQ that has a DAC built-in. You can plug in a standout pair of wired headphones into the audio port and enjoy high-end sound quality. There's no shortage of storage or music playing platforms it can access. Sadly, you'll be stuck with renewed versions when looking to buy one.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<ul><li><a href="#main"><strong>Back to the top ^</strong></a></li></ul>
<h2 id="rediscovering-the-sound-of-music-2">Rediscovering the sound of music</h2>
<p>Unlike picking the right <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-music-players-android">music player apps for Android,</a> looking for a dedicated digital audio player is a complicated process. A lot of thought goes into the search, especially if you have exposed your ears to high-end audio before. Nonetheless, the devices that we have gathered in this roundup have all the best features that you need. There&apos;s a little something for everyone, in every color, and every price bracket.</p><p>For audiophiles with a keen sense of hearing, the Astell&Kern KANN Ultra is the absolute best audio player. It is powered by the ES9039MPRO Dual DAC chip, it supports a vast range of file formats, and it can deliver hi-res audio for both wired and wireless sound delivery methods. The KANN Ultra features a custom-built OS, so no additional apps or notifications disturb your music-listening bliss. The 128GB of onboard storage is plenty, but you can expand it to 1TB if needed. The one caveat here is the eye-watering asking price - this DAP will cost you as much as a flagship foldable phone, or mid-level gaming laptop. If you can afford it, pair it with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-fa19-review">Fiio FA19 wired in-ear monitor (IEM) earphones</a> and you&apos;ll experience total auditory bliss.</p><p>For lower budgets, the HiBy R3 II and HIFI WALKER H2 are decent options. They both manage to produce similar levels of sound that sound exceptionally good. You&apos;ll enjoy top-notch audio playback without spending smartphone money on either one. On the other hand, if audio codecs, file formats, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/does-my-phone-have-dac-explaining-dacs-and-amps-smartphones-today">DAC & amps</a>, and lossless audio mean nothing to you, then you should stick with basic portable music players such as the Mighty 3 or the SanDisk Clip Jam. If you want even more versatility, grab the LG V60 ThinQ 5G to serve as a phone as well as an MP3 player. It&apos;s one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phone-headphone-jack">best Android phones with a headphone jack</a> and it has a solid DAC built-in.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/audio/best-mp3-players</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ MP3 players might sound like devices from the day of yore. However, audiophiles all agree that high-quality audio demands better gear than your everyday smartphone and earbuds. These are the best digital audio players to deliver the ultimate audio experience. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">JWoTjKfYV4n7LHiMSwJ2iD</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/afeQHovgdtxyB3DU5eCyC4.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 16:01:53 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/afeQHovgdtxyB3DU5eCyC4.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[FiiO]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[FiiO M11 Plus ESS]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[FiiO M11 Plus ESS]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Pixel 8a vs. Samsung Galaxy S23 FE: May the better model win ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[         <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="65afdaf5-0260-4c9d-8b08-50664639c85f">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rkG8MMYwEzPpdaYB6rQ5y9.jpg' alt='Google Pixel 8a in Bay'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 8a</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="80" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The cheaper option</strong></em></p>
<p>The Google Pixel 8a gives you more system and security updates than its competitor but falls behind in some areas. It's still better when it comes to cameras, and as a Pixel, you will always get the latest Google features first. It has the fun AI features in the Big Brother models.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Cheaper</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Fantastic AI features</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Seven years of system updates</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Great battery life</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Brighter screen</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Charges at 18W</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Not available in most global markets</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Less screen protection</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No expandable storage</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No charger</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="71f24e75-981b-4276-81e0-f5e48a2e00ee">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GkVM7Nd5GdbAoLZMSRdDJ.jpg' alt='Samsung Galaxy S23 FE'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S23 FE</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="70" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The faster charging model</strong></em></p>
<p>The Samsung Galaxy S23 FE has a 6.4-inch screen and is available in Cream, Mint, Purple, and Graphite. It has a fancier look than its competitor and offers better screen protection with the Corning Gorilla Glass 5.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Fast processor</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Bigger screen</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Fancy design</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Better screen protection</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Thinner</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>IP68</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No Dolby vision</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Feels heavier</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Inferior main and front-facing camera</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No charger</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No expandable storage</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<p>The Google Pixel 8a vs. Samsung Galaxy S23 FE mid-range battle is here. After comparing the specifications of both phones, you may get a clearer picture of which phone is right for you. The Samsung Galaxy S23 FE has been out for a while, but it still wins in some areas compared to the new Pixel 8a.</p><p>Both <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phones</a> have a lot to offer, but what matters most to you will determine which one you go with. For example, some users will only consider a phone if the camera specifications are good, while others care more about the software. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-and-pixel-8-pro-deals-of-the-month">Pixel phones</a> get the latest Google features first, but is that a solid reason to get the Pixel 8a? We&apos;ll give you a detailed comparison to see where each phone loses and wins, and which is best for your tech needs.</p>
<h2 id="google-pixel-8a-vs-samsung-galaxy-s23-fe-design-2">Google Pixel 8a vs. Samsung Galaxy S23 FE: Design</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="SafYZGr6gUDGsM4VsQ7ooe" name="samsung-galaxy-s23-fe-white-with-mint-case-2.jpg" alt="White Galaxy S23 FE with Mint case" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SafYZGr6gUDGsM4VsQ7ooe.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>You can identify which phone is which by looking at the design. The Google Pixel 8a stands out because the aluminum camera bar runs along the back and has more rounded corners than the previous model, giving it a more elegant look. With this new design, the Pixel 8a looks practically identical to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-review">Pixel 8</a>. The Google Pixel 8a is available in Aloe, Bay, Obsidian, and Porcelain. It also has a matte finish on the back that matches the Pixel 8 and 8 Pro style.</p><p>The Samsung Galaxy S23 FE has three camera modules in the upper left-hand corner without the border that the S21 FE has. It is available in Mint, Purple, Cream, Graphite, Indigo, and Tangerine finishes. Unlike past models, the back of the phone has a glass finish. You also get lovely silver accents in the form of separate camera rings. The aluminum frames have a matte finish and are 30 grams heavier than the previous model, and the bezels are a little thick.</p>
<h2 id="google-pixel-8a-vs-samsung-galaxy-s23-fe-display-2">Google Pixel 8a vs. Samsung Galaxy S23 FE: Display</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="6YAoRENQwue2vYvMhoTHXJ" name="google-pixel-8a-homescreen-01.jpg" alt="The homescreen of the Google Pixel 8a" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6YAoRENQwue2vYvMhoTHXJ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Google Pixel 8a has an improved display this time, but the size is still the same, with a 6.1-inch panel. You can also count on a 120hz OLED panel with a 1080 x 2400 resolution and a middle-hole punch cutout for the selfie camera.</p><p>The display has an optical fingerprint reader and has been bumped to the same Actua display featured on the Pixel 8. The Pixel 8a&apos;s peak brightness is 40% higher than the previous model at 2,000 nits in HDR mode. The layer of Gorilla Glass 3 for protection isn&apos;t as good as its Galaxy competitor. You enjoy features like an Always-on mode and widgets like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-enable-the-new-google-at-a-glance-widget-features">At A Glance</a> and Now Playing on the lock screen.</p><p>The Samsung Galaxy S23 FE features a 6.4-inch Dynamic AMOLED display with a 1080 x 2340 resolution that offers decent sharpness and color accuracy. It also has a 120Hz refresh rate (60Hz when idling) and Gorilla Glass 5, not Victus, like the previous model. The Galaxy S23 FE supports HDR10+ video content, and the brightness is better in this model than the S21 FE. The Galaxy S23 FE isn&apos;t as bright as its Pixel 8a competitor, with a peak brightness of 1,450 nits.</p>
<h2 id="google-pixel-8a-vs-samsung-galaxy-s23-fe-hardware-2">Google Pixel 8a vs. Samsung Galaxy S23 FE: Hardware</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1307px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="xD6xEMJSjzR8eafwDEKwJB" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S23-FE-hero.jpg" alt="The Galaxy S23 FE in all its colors" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xD6xEMJSjzR8eafwDEKwJB.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1307" height="735" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Samsung)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>How long can the Google Pixel 8a last in terms of battery life? With a 4,492mAh battery that supports 18W wired charging and 7.5W wireless charging, the Pixel can last a day. You can stretch that to as long as 72 hours on the extreme battery-saver mode. It has a slightly inferior battery than the Samsung Galaxy S23 FE but a better Tensor G3 chip than last year&apos;s flagships. The cores are new, and they have improved performance. There is no information on the thermal management at this point. It also has a USB Type-C 3.2 port.</p><p>There is no change regarding RAM, you still get the same 8GB memory from last year. You also get UFS 3.1 storage instead of the faster UFS 4.0 storage, which is a shame. The Pixel 8a offers two storage options: 128GB and 256GB, the latter being a first for the Pixel A series. The Pixel 8a shares the exact RAM and storage capacity as its Galaxy S23 FE competitor.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s23-fe-hands-on">Samsung Galaxy S23 FE</a> has a 4,500mAh battery that supports 25W wired and 15W wireless charging. Unfortunately, battery life is middling with about half a day&apos;s worth of usage resulting from a single charge. The phone has a Snapdragon 8 Gen 1 processor that is slightly less powerful than its Pixel competitor. The Samsung model sold outside the United States has an Exynos 2200 processor. Both the Pixel 8a and the Galaxy S23 FE feature stereo speakers.</p>

<h2 id="google-pixel-8a-vs-samsung-galaxy-s23-fe-software-2">Google Pixel 8a vs. Samsung Galaxy S23 FE: Software</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1343px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.22%;"><img id="4RG6RhDNYmhufLzCX5rRjS" name="Google-Pixel-8a-circle-to-search.jpg" alt="Circle to Search on the Pixel 8a" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4RG6RhDNYmhufLzCX5rRjS.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1343" height="755" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google promises seven years of software and security updates with the Pixel 8a and Android 14 out of the box, so you&apos;re sure to get monthly Feature Drops as well as major OS upgrades for quite a while. With this mid-range Pixel, you get a lot of the smart AI features you would see on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-review">Pixel 8</a>. You get Call Assist, Pixel VPN, Magic Eraser Audio, Speech-to-Text, and Gemini.</p><p>The Samsung Galaxy S23 FE comes with Android 13 based on One UI 5.1 but can be upgraded to Android 14 based on One UI 6.1 right away. However, this model doesn&apos;t offer as many updates, as Samsung promises only four years of system updates and five security updates. You also get the same AI experience you would on higher-end models (when updated to One UI 6.1), such as DeX support, Photo Remaster which fixes blurry pictures, and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/how-to-transcribe-and-summarize-using-samsung-notes-on-the-galaxy-s24">Summarize feature</a> which gives a summary of long articles when using the Samsung browser.</p><p>This model also includes Interpreter Mode, which is very helpful whenever you need something translated. Other included features are <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-circle-to-search">Circle to Search</a>, Auto format, Correct spelling, and Translate in Samsung Notes.</p>
<h2 id="google-pixel-8a-vs-samsung-galaxy-s23-fe-which-should-you-buy-2">Google Pixel 8a vs. Samsung Galaxy S23 FE: Which should you buy?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="XJrBJTbAnK5LULvLJybsBG" name="google-pixel-8a-official-lifestyle-obsidian-01.jpg" alt="A person holding an Obsidian Google Pixel 8a" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XJrBJTbAnK5LULvLJybsBG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Samsung Galaxy S23 FE is available now for a starting price of $599, and the Google Pixel 8a starts at $499 in the US. The Pixel 8a is cheaper and has fun AI features you won&apos;t find on the Galaxy S23 FE, so if you&apos;re a selfie enthusiast and always want the latest system updates, the Pixel 8a might sound more appealing.</p><p>But if you&apos;ve always wanted to have the AI features you would see on Samsung&apos;s higher-end Galaxy S models like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review">Galaxy S24 Ultra</a>, and want to flaunt a more elegant-looking phone, then the S23 FE could be your choice. In the end, it always comes down to your preferences and budget.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="e0f11099-5778-4178-b360-774957cd7ba8">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9oC7D3ePxvwxRrtEkU7pf9.jpg' alt='Google Pixel 8a in Porcelain'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 8a</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="80" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Mid-range Pixel</strong></em> </p>
<p>Get in on the fun Pixel fans are enjoying without paying full price with the Google Pixel 8a. You get seven years of system and security updates as well as fantastic cameras. Enjoy the 6.1-inch display with it 2,000 nits of peak brightness and other great specifications.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="730dfc65-4d42-4b4e-aafa-4c190565eab0">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GkVM7Nd5GdbAoLZMSRdDJ.jpg' alt='Samsung Galaxy S23 FE'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S23 FE</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="70" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The elegant Fan Edition phone</strong></em></p>
<p>The Samsung Galaxy S23 FE lets you in on the AI fun you see on the higher-end Galaxy models, despite its humbler price tag. It has a 6.4-inch screen, an improved processor, Vision Booster, better cameras, and IP68 water and dust resistance.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-vs-samsung-galaxy-s23-fe</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Google Pixel 8a vs. Samsung Galaxy S23 FE comparison is here with the launch of the new Pixel. Get the facts that matter without the fluff to help you decide which is best. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">YM2Yamki6tGAFfLDqb3eEW</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Gcs7FVTjvc2HZyLR3qWMnH.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 15:27:27 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ judysanhz30@gmail.com (Judy Sanhz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Gcs7FVTjvc2HZyLR3qWMnH.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Google Pixel 8a in the Bay blue colorway]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Google Pixel 8a in the Bay blue colorway]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Vivo X100 Ultra leak reveals prominent display and camera specs ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Vivo X100 Ultra's manual leak reveals what to expect from the next flagship.</li><li>The device is equipped with a 200MP sensor, two 50MP sensors, and also a 50MP selfie camera.</li><li>The Vivo X100 Ultra will also sport a large 6.78-inch WQHD+ display.</li><li>Meanwhile, the launch is set for May 13 in the Chinese region.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Vivo is preparing for a new launch in the Chinese region on May 13, when we will see the Vivo X100 Ultra next to the Vivo X100s series. Ahead of the release, new information appears, revealing interesting specs of the upcoming flagship.</p><p>Prolific leaker Evan Blass has managed to grab the user manual of the upcoming Vivo X100 Ultra and has shared some of it on X (formerly Twitter). The images reveal the flagship phone&apos;s specs following a blueprint showing the device&apos;s prominent sensors.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">From the Vivo X100 Ultra user manual: pic.twitter.com/nyt6LNlxWD<a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1788926648441508165">May 10, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>Per the shared manual, the Ultra will feature a 50MP selfie shooter and a triple rear camera system comprising a 200MP lens aided by two 50MP sensors. Besides, these rear cameras are also ZEISS-powered. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/vivo-x100-ultra-x100s-series-launch-confirmed">Earlier reports</a> have indicated that one of the 50MP sensors will act as the primary lens, and the 200MP sensor is likely projected as the periscopic lens.</p><p>Furthermore, the upcoming <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">flagship phone</a> will measure 9.23mm in thickness and sport a 6.78-inch WQHD+ display featuring 3200 x 1440 resolution. It is also tipped to have a curved display along the edges. Other parameters from the manual include the device&apos;s 5G connectivity and support for GPS.</p><p>The aforementioned report has also indicated that the device will have a glossier finish at the rear, equip a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-3-launch">Snapdragon 8 Gen 3</a> underneath, and likely sport Black, Titanium, and White color options. The storage variants are believed to be 12GB+256GB, 16GB+512GB, and a whopping 16GB+1TB. The larger variant has its own set of unique parameters like satellite connectivity and is also tipped to be priced at CNY 8499 (~$1,180).</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:337px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:178.04%;"><img id="SHyuLakRyPqV28HiNHz8Tj" name="vivo-x100s-pro-three-colorways-teaser.jpg" alt="A teaser image depicting the three colorways for the upcoming X100s Pro by Vivo." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SHyuLakRyPqV28HiNHz8Tj.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="337" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Vivo / Weibo)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Meanwhile, the X100s series from Vivo, which is launching next to the Ultra on May 13, will sport flat edges and a flat display measuring 6.7 inches. These devices are expected to be powered by MediaTek&apos;s latest <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/mediateks-new-dimensity-9300-chip-brings-higher-clock-speeds-and-better-ai-processing">Dimensity 9300 Plus</a> chipset with higher clock speeds. </p><p>The Vivo X100 Ultra appears to be a promising successor to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/vivo-x100-pro-review">Vivo X100 Pro</a>, which launched in November 2023, followed by a global debut in December 2023. While it turned out to be a greatly designed smartphone with incredible cameras, the successor will likely take things further as it boasts the Ultra badge.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/vivo-x100-ultra-specs-leak</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ After witnessing the Vivo X100 Pro, the company is gearing up to launch its Ultra model next week. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">nrqeWibWC9A3938hyWVk3</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/aaSCTVr5cBrjMMvP9QtARE.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 14:03:55 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/aaSCTVr5cBrjMMvP9QtARE.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Vivo / Weibo]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A teaser video highlighting the upcoming Vivo X100 Ultra.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A teaser video highlighting the upcoming Vivo X100 Ultra.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Pixel 8a initial review: The mid-range camera champ ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>As the Pixel evolves and figures itself out as a brand, Google has been making notable changes and refinements for the better. This year, the Pixel 8a improves on nearly every negative point of last year&apos;s Pixel 7a, and it even makes changes I didn&apos;t expect from a $500 phone.</p><p>With the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-review">Pixel 8</a>, Google rounded the corners and put a matte texture on the back, making for a comfortable phone that consistently looks nice. The Pixel 8a has adopted these same changes and even rounded the corners just a bit more for an almost Galaxy S3-esque "smooth pebble" design. My gosh, if it isn&apos;t the most comfortable phone I&apos;ve held in a long time because of it!</p><p>In addition to that, we&apos;re looking at the same processor in the Pixel 8, the same display as that phone, the same amount and speed of RAM, the same storage speed, the same water resistance rating, and the same powerful AI-driven Tensor G3 processor. It certainly makes you wonder why you would ever need a more expensive Pixel phone, doesn&apos;t it?</p><p>This initial review was conducted after using the phone as my primary phone over the duration of four full days. I&apos;m using the Pixel 8a on T-Mobile&apos;s 5G network, and it runs the latest version of Android 14, which the phone will ship to customers.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-google-pixel-8a-price-and-availability"><span>Google Pixel 8a: Price and availability</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="MgDnr2paYR3zigdkma9DLB" name="google-pixel-8a-lockscreen-01.jpg" alt="The colorful home screen of the Google Pixel 8a under some flowers" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MgDnr2paYR3zigdkma9DLB.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Google Pixel 8a officially launched on May 14, 2024, with a starting retail price of $499 USD / $679 CAD / £499 / Rs 52,999 for the model with 128GB of internal storage. For the first time ever on a Pixel A-series phone, Google is also selling a 256GB storage model for an additional cost. The phone ships in your choice of Obsidian, Porcelain, Bay, and Aloe colorways.</p><p>As you might expect, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/best-google-pixel-8a-deals-how-to-buy">best Google Pixel 8a deals</a> will get you the phone at a reduced price — maybe even free — especially if you have an older phone to trade in.</p><p>The Pixel 8a comes in completely plastic-free packaging.</p><p>These are all the countries where the Google Pixel 8a is launching:</p>
<ul><li>U.S.</li><li>Canada</li><li>Austria</li><li>Belgium</li><li>Czech Republic</li><li>Denmark</li><li>France</li><li>Germany</li><li>Italy</li><li>Ireland</li><li>Netherlands</li><li>Norway</li><li>Poland</li><li>Portugal</li><li>Spain</li><li>Sweden</li><li>Switzerland</li><li>UK</li><li>Australia</li><li>India</li><li>Japan</li><li>Singapore</li><li>Taiwan</li></ul>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-google-pixel-8a-display-and-design"><span>Google Pixel 8a: Display and design</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="jrTjkemnA9qa69RPvqAQvB" name="google-pixel-8a-homescreen-03.jpg" alt="The colorful home screen of the Google Pixel 8a on the stairs" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jrTjkemnA9qa69RPvqAQvB.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Of all the Pixel phone designs over the years, the Google Pixel 8a is my new favorite. It melds the unique camera bar design from the more expensive Pixel 8 series with further rounded corners, and a matte finish back that feels heavenly.</p><p>This is a phone that&apos;s built for human hands and it feels wonderful to use it one-handed, even if the display is a bit big to reach all the edges with one thumb without shifting the phone around. Round corners do a lot for long-term usability and comfort. Sharp corners on phones like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review">Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra</a> are just plain uncomfortable, made even worse because it&apos;s a super heavy phone.</p><p>The Pixel 8a isn&apos;t shockingly light by any measure but it does come in at around 5 grams lighter than last year&apos;s Pixel 7a. At 188g, you&apos;ll feel it in your pocket but it&apos;s not heavy enough to cause finger fatigue if you find yourself holding it for a long time. As actor Chris Evans <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://collider.com/chris-evans-misses-his-iphone-6s-video/">once pointed out</a>, heavy phones often cause pinky finger fatigue.</p>

<p>Beyond the weight and shape, Google is using surprisingly premium materials for most of the phone. The back is still plastic, but it feels less like plastic than ever, thanks to a beautiful, fingerprint-resistant matte finish. I praised Google&apos;s use of a matte finish in my <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-pro-review">Pixel 8 Pro review</a>, and this phone feels nearly identical to that.</p><p>There&apos;s a slight hollow feeling if you tap the back when compared to a glass-backed phone like the more expensive Pixel 8 models have, but it doesn&apos;t come off feeling cheap.</p><p>Likewise, the "satin aluminum" frame looks extremely premium, particularly on the Bay blue model I have for review. This part, too, has a matte finish that won&apos;t attract fingerprints and will leave your Pixel 8a looking clean and shiny even after using it for hours.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="LHU5qGpvPUBNcyUSFjK8M4" name="google-pixel-8a-back-bay-08.jpg" alt="The back of the Bay blue Google Pixel 8a" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LHU5qGpvPUBNcyUSFjK8M4.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="5C2GJycwViaKNcc7kiCKMJ" name="google-pixel-8a-camera-bar-bay-02.jpg" alt="The Google Pixel 8a in the Bay blue colorway" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5C2GJycwViaKNcc7kiCKMJ.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.30%;"><img id="cm64GCZLiWFzRYadf3YodH" name="google-pixel-8a-back-bay-04.jpg" alt="The Google Pixel 8a in the Bay blue colorway" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/cm64GCZLiWFzRYadf3YodH.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1153" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>The display has been upgraded yet again this year. The display is spec-for-spec identical to the Pixel 8 in all but one way: it&apos;s not LTPO. That means this 120Hz panel shifts between 60Hz and 120Hz depending on what&apos;s happening on screen, while the  Pixel 8 and Pixel 8 Pro&apos;s displays can smoothly shift between 1Hz and 120Hz. In plain language, the Pixel 8a&apos;s display is slightly less battery-efficient.</p><p>But the rest of the panel is right on the money in most measurements. Google calls it the "Actua display" in reference to its color accuracy, which helps highlight the quality of the camera. It also gets incredibly bright, with a peak brightness of 2000 nits and a peak HDR brightness of 1400 nits.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aoNSYNPbCtE" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>The downside is that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-is-pwm-display-flicker-tips-and-tricks">PWM-sensitive folks</a> are going to find this display incredibly uncomfortable. Like the mainline Pixel series, this uses 240Hz PWM flickering at all brightness levels, quickly turning the display on and off to fool your eyes into thinking it&apos;s bright or dim instead of adjusting voltage like traditional displays and lights.</p><p>This PWM rate is the lowest of any major phone series and is truly awful for any flicker-sensitive person. Google doesn&apos;t offer an anti-flicker or flicker-reduction mode like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12r-review">OnePlus 12R</a> or any OLED-donning Motorola phone, which makes those phone much better options if you&apos;re PWM-sensitive.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-google-pixel-8a-performance-and-battery-life"><span>Google Pixel 8a: Performance and battery life</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="iYiFZ2kfrjYSPRaxDjuh6B" name="google-pixel-8a-homescreen-04.jpg" alt="The colorful home screen of the Google Pixel 8a under some flowers" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/iYiFZ2kfrjYSPRaxDjuh6B.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Google Pixel 8a sports the exact same Google Tensor G3 processor that&apos;s found in the more expensive Pixel 8 and Pixel 8 Pro phones. That means Google was able to pack in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-google-pixel-8a-packs-just-as-much-ai-punch-as-the-standard-pixel-8">the same AI features</a> as those more expensive phones.</p><p>A huge part of that capability is in the Tensor G3&apos;s upgraded NPU capabilities which, according to benchmarks we ran, is nearly 3x faster than the NPU in the Pixel 7a. That NPU, or Neural Processing Unit, is what&apos;s responsible for efficiently running AI routines on-device and ensuring that the phone quickly processes AI-based tasks and also keeps them from needing to be uploaded to a cloud server for privacy reasons.</p><p>Overall performance of the phone, based on benchmarks, is also better than both the Pixel 7a and even the more expensive Pixel 8 Pro. Google said it was able to concoct a new thermal management method, and while the phone still throttles heavily at around 40 degrees Celsius, it takes longer to hit that thermal limit.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:46.53%;"><img id="kJ7BmxdTPQeReiC6dNGHXD" name="google-pixel-8a-vs-pixel-7a-vs-pixel-8-pro-vs-oneplus-12r-burnout-benchmark-01.jpg" alt="Burnout Benchmark results comparing the Google Pixel 7a, Pixel 8a, Pixel 8 Pro, and OnePlus 12R" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kJ7BmxdTPQeReiC6dNGHXD.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="953" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:54.10%;"><img id="d3voxFvW7XAEoAR7HihkLD" name="google-pixel-8a-vs-pixel-7a-vs-pixel-8-pro-vs-oneplus-12r-burnout-benchmark-02.jpg" alt="Burnout Benchmark results comparing the Google Pixel 7a, Pixel 8a, Pixel 8 Pro, and OnePlus 12R" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/d3voxFvW7XAEoAR7HihkLD.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1108" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>However, when compared to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12r-review">OnePlus 12R</a>, our current favorite mid-range phone, the Pixel 8a&apos;s performance is quite lacking. Not only that, but the Pixel 8a&apos;s performance-per-watt is substantially worse than the OnePlus 12R. In plain terms, your battery life is going to drain more quickly on a Pixel 8a than a OnePlus 12R when doing anything that taxes the processor.</p><p>So far, battery life hasn&apos;t been particularly impressive for me. Granted, I have to run the display at 100% brightness all the time to keep headaches at bay, otherwise, the phone&apos;s PWM-laden flickering display makes my head hurt something fierce.</p><p>Our parent company runs lab tests via the Future Labs department, and those test results show that the Pixel 8a gets one hour of <em>better</em> battery life than the Pixel 8 Pro in the battery rundown test at the default 60Hz refresh rate. In other words, if you&apos;re using default settings — 60Hz display, auto brightness — then battery life will be quite excellent.</p><p>I&apos;ll be putting the phone through the rigors over the next few days and weeks to better determine what it&apos;s best at but, for now, early tests show that Google has made important improvements to some of Tensor&apos;s biggest weak points, even if the processor is still slower and less efficient than the competition.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-google-pixel-8a-software"><span>Google Pixel 8a: Software</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="N62Vav8YybD2DRWosnf7bW" name="google-pixel-8a-setting-up-01.jpg" alt="Setting up a Google Pixel 8a" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/N62Vav8YybD2DRWosnf7bW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google&apos;s Pixel software has really come into its own over the years, particularly in the past six months, as Google has added <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-gemini-app-android">Gemini</a> features to the platform. The Pixel 8a sports all the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-google-pixel-8a-packs-just-as-much-ai-punch-as-the-standard-pixel-8">same AI features as the regular Pixel 8</a>, including Magic Eraser, Zoom Enhance, Best Take, Audio Magic Eraser, Circle to Search, and more.</p><p>Not only that but the Pixel 8a is set to receive <strong>seven years</strong> of Android updates, meaning it&apos;ll see Android 21 before the end of its shelf life. It also has a <em>free VPN</em> built-in, something only Pixel phones provide.</p><p>That&apos;s a huge value add for a phone in the $500 price range, as these devices normally don&apos;t have the processing capabilities to be able to pull off impressive AI features like this. It&apos;s a huge win for anyone not wanting to spend flagship money but still get flagship features.</p><p>Of course, this means there&apos;s almost nothing <em>new</em> on the Pixel 8a when compared to the Pixel 8 series. The lone exceptions are the upgraded <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/how-to-use-guided-frame-pixel-7">Guided Frame</a> utility and the improved Family Link parental controls setup.</p><p>Initially, Guided Frame was just used as a way to help vision-impaired users take better photos and selfies. Now, Guided Frame can utilize both front and rear-facing cameras to describe what your phone&apos;s camera is seeing.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1343px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.22%;"><img id="4RG6RhDNYmhufLzCX5rRjS" name="Google-Pixel-8a-circle-to-search.jpg" alt="Circle to Search on the Pixel 8a" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4RG6RhDNYmhufLzCX5rRjS.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1343" height="755" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google also improved Family Link by making the setup process easier and clearer, which goes nicely with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/wear-os-preps-school-time-mode-play-services-update">recent Pixel Watch update</a> that adds School Time and other important parental control functions.</p><p>But under the shiny exterior of AI features and update promises lingers an underlying distrust built up from years of screw-ups on Google&apos;s part. As I said <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/should-you-buy-pixel-8a">last week</a>, the Pixel series has become known for its buggy updates and weird problems.</p><p>Things have slightly improved since the Pixel 6 days, but over the past year alone, we&apos;ve seen monthly updates cause <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-and-8-pro-battery-drain-and-network-issues">battery drain issues</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-second-april-patch-cell-service-rollout">cellular connectivity issues</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-7-6-battery-overheating-issues">overheating issues</a>, and even <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/pixel-6-storage-bug-android-14">a crucial storage bug</a> that made it impossible to use many apps.</p><p>These are just a handful of issues Pixel owners have had to deal with to some degree over the past few years, and it makes me wonder if monthly updates are really worth the issues they seem to create.</p><p>Of course, the flip side to all this is that Pixel phones nearly always get updates before any other phone on the market.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-google-pixel-8a-cameras"><span>Google Pixel 8a: Cameras</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="DcVMw6eFyhqbMozJxyyGkc" name="google-pixel-8a-camera-03.jpg" alt="Taking a picture with the Google Pixel 8a" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DcVMw6eFyhqbMozJxyyGkc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Whenever I review a Pixel phone and compare it to other phones, my thoughts usually begin with, "I wonder how much worse this other phone&apos;s camera is compared to the Pixel."</p><p>Google Pixel phones have long been the pinnacle of mobile photography, and while some other phones <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-camera-review">sometimes beat it</a>, Pixel&apos;s consistently excellent camera performance delivers a reliability factor that can be envied.</p><p>In my testing so far, I can confirm that the Pixel 7a and Pixel 8a&apos;s cameras produce identical results. If nothing, that means you can save some money and get a Pixel 7a while still getting a stellar camera.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:53.71%;"><img id="b4HCRrxB6mvn47fLmuKnwM" name="google-pixel-8a-camera-comparison-01.jpg" alt="Comparing the Google Pixel 8a's camera with the Pixel 7a and OnePlus 12R" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/b4HCRrxB6mvn47fLmuKnwM.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1100" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:53.71%;"><img id="jeUZesGTkrA38FxAqBCEMN" name="google-pixel-8a-camera-comparison-02.jpg" alt="Comparing the Google Pixel 8a's camera with the Pixel 7a and OnePlus 12R" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jeUZesGTkrA38FxAqBCEMN.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1100" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:53.71%;"><img id="xBuGGd8GcGNWmeMEX64tgN" name="google-pixel-8a-camera-comparison-04.jpg" alt="Comparing the Google Pixel 8a's camera with the Pixel 7a and OnePlus 12R" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xBuGGd8GcGNWmeMEX64tgN.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1100" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 4 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:53.71%;"><img id="bMqPiBnLN8A7NuCT6U3q6P" name="google-pixel-8a-camera-comparison-03.jpg" alt="Comparing the Google Pixel 8a's camera with the Pixel 7a and OnePlus 12R" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bMqPiBnLN8A7NuCT6U3q6P.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1100" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 5 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:53.71%;"><img id="5UKatykKwHbovvZUAPtwMP" name="google-pixel-8a-camera-comparison-05.jpg" alt="Comparing the Google Pixel 8a's camera with the Pixel 7a and OnePlus 12R" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5UKatykKwHbovvZUAPtwMP.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1100" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Comparing the Pixel 8a to the OnePlus 12R — another excellent $499 phone — shows that there&apos;s not a <em>huge</em> gap between the two in most shots, but the Pixel 8a definitely wins more often than not. In many cases, the Pixel often gets the exposure mostly correct and ends up pulling out more detail, resulting in a better-looking picture because of it.</p><p>Photos taken on the Pixel 8a exhibit the classic high contrast, color-accurate imagery that Google&apos;s Pixel phones are known for. Pixels are also the best when trying to capture objects in motion — like pets or kids — which means the Pixel 8a is automatically the better choice for parents or folks who love to take lots of photos of their pets.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-google-pixel-8a-the-competition"><span>Google Pixel 8a: The competition</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="jwRWKcGq4Na5HEgi8EY4KP" name="oneplus-12r-3.jpg" alt="OnePlus 12R review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jwRWKcGq4Na5HEgi8EY4KP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>For the price, it&apos;s hard to turn down the Pixel 7a. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/best-pixel-7a-deals">best Pixel 7a deals</a> will get you the phone for $350. Considering that the Pixel 7a is still due for four more Android updates (up to Android 19), this one has quite a bit of life left in it. You&apos;ll also be getting a camera with identical quality capture as the Pixel 8a, although battery life and performance are worse than Google&apos;s latest can provide.</p><p>But if battery life and performance are your chief concern, the OnePlus 12R is the best buy at $500. It has a Snapdragon 8 Gen 2 processor, which is roughly twice as fast as the Tensor G3 in the Pixel 8a for gaming and other graphics-intensive applications. OnePlus doesn&apos;t offer the same level of long-term support or some of the Pixel-exclusive AI features, though, and the camera is not as good as a Pixel.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-google-pixel-8a-should-you-buy-it"><span>Google Pixel 8a: Should you buy it?</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="KEN4R38CamszXthY34ubY4" name="google-pixel-8a-back-bay-09.jpg" alt="The back of the Bay blue Google Pixel 8a" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KEN4R38CamszXthY34ubY4.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>You should buy this if...</strong></p>
<ul><li>You plan to hold on to your phone for years.</li><li>You want the best camera in its class.</li><li>You love Google AI features and Pixel features.</li></ul>
<p><strong>You shouldn&apos;t buy this if...</strong></p>
<ul><li>You're sensitive to flickering lights or PWM-dimmed displays.</li><li>You need the best performance for the price.</li><li>You need fast charging and/or more than 24-hour battery life.</li></ul>
<p>As the price of the Pixel A-series continues to climb in many regions, its value continues to encroach on full flagship-tier phones. There&apos;s also something to be said when the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-and-pixel-8-pro-deals-of-the-month">best Pixel 8 deals</a> can get you a better phone — the regular Pixel 8 — for the same price as the 8a. Not only that, but the OnePlus 12R also retails for $499 and packs a significantly faster and more efficient processor onboard, plus a better display that&apos;s also more eye-friendly.</p><p>But there&apos;s no guarantee that you can snag a Pixel 8 for $499, which means the Pixel 8a is the best buy at the price if long-term updates and camera quality are your top features. Google&apos;s update quality has been a little shaky over the past few years, though, which hangs a cloud over an otherwise impeccable record of update speed.</p><p>For now, I&apos;d personally pick a Pixel 7a over Google&apos;s latest. Sure, it&apos;s only got four more years of Android updates, but I&apos;m not convinced that current Tensor processors will be fast enough to feel snappy for longer than that. At $350, the 7a is an unbeatable deal with camera quality that matches the 8a, even if it doesn&apos;t have as many AI features.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-review</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Google Pixel 8a is an impressive mid-range phone with flagship-level dreams, sporting an excellent camera and all the great AI features of more expensive Pixels. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Y2Ucetk7zpRFKPy3XQ5Zr4</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CyMBUSJ4RR8zQFWPo9MbXC.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 14:00:10 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nicholas.sutrich@futurenet.com (Nicholas Sutrich) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CyMBUSJ4RR8zQFWPo9MbXC.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A Bay blue Google Pixel 8a on a staircase]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A Bay blue Google Pixel 8a on a staircase]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>