<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 06:16:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Qualcomm reports $10.2B in FY Q4 revenue thanks to strong headset sales, automotive push ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Qualcomm announced its fiscal year Q4 2024 revenue with $10.2 billion for the quarter.</li><li>Mobile chipset sales increased by 12%, while automotive grew an impressive 68% compared to the same quarter in 2023.</li><li>Qualcomm just launched the Snapdragon 8 Elite, which is already landing in new smartphones from Xiaomi, OPPO, OnePlus, and more.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Qualcomm is ending its 2024 fiscal year on a high note, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://investor.qualcomm.com/files/doc_financials/2024/q4/FY2024-4th-Quarter-Earnings-Release.pdf">reporting</a> a 12% growth in Q4 revenue to $10.2 billion. That brings its total 2024 revenue to $39 billion, up 9% compared to fiscal year 2023.</p><p>“We are pleased to conclude the fiscal year with strong results in the fourth quarter, delivering greater than 30% year-over-year growth in EPS,” said Qualcomm CEO Cristiano Amon in a prepared statement.</p><p>“We are excited about our recent product announcements at Snapdragon Summit and Embedded World, as they continue to extend our technology leadership and position us well across Handsets, PC, Automotive and Industrial IoT. We look forward to providing an update on our growth and diversification initiatives at our Investor Day on November 19.”</p><p>Throughout the quarter, Qualcomm saw the launch of several flagship Android phones utilizing its last-gen flagship chipset, including the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-6-review">Galaxy Z Flip 6</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Galaxy Z Fold 6</a>, and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2024-review">Razr Plus 2024</a>. Amazon's first Prime Day sales event also likely contributed to impressive headset sales during the quarter.</p><p>Qualcomm has also pushed heavily in other markets, with its automotive solutions seeing an impressive 68% uptick in revenue and expectations that it will continue to grow in 2025, particularly with the new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/qualcomm-announces-snapdragon-cockpit-elite-ride-elite-for-ai-in-cars">Cockpit Elite</a>. During the earnings call on Wednesday, Amon further highlighted the company's efforts in AR/VR and partnership with Meta, with the recent launch of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-3s-review">Quest 3S</a> seen as an "important milestone in increasing the scale of this opportunity."</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2610px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="rRUXiFcY6iXrsZAHShZKPR" name="Snapdragon-8-Elite-Gaming" alt="A photo showing a gaming phone with the Snapdragon 8 Elite logo hovering above it" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rRUXiFcY6iXrsZAHShZKPR.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2610" height="1468" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Qualcomm)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>With the recently unveiled <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/snapdragon-8-elite">Snapdragon 8 Elite</a>, Qualcomm already feels well-poised for a better 2025, with Android OEMs already unveiling their latest flagship powered by the chip.</p><p>"We are extremely pleased with this Snapdragon 8 Elite design traction with successful launches at Xiaomi, Honor, OPPO, and Vivo," Amon said during the call.</p><p>Qualcomm CFO Akash Palkhiwala noted that this will have a positive impact on the company's FY Q1 revenue. He expects year-over-year headset growth, thanks to "greater than 40% sequential revenue growth from Chinese OEM and the acceleration of flagship Android handset launches," particularly phones adopting the Snapdragon 8 Elite.</p><p>Amon also highlighted upcoming launches from ASUS and Samsung. The latter has been rumored to be considering adopting its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-models-to-opt-for-flagship-exynos-soc-again">Exynos chips for some Galaxy S25 models</a>. That said, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25">Galaxy S25</a> is not expected to launch until Qualcomm's FY Q2, which could help boost sales following the holiday season, although that could also depend on the share of Snapdragon-powered models.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-fy-q4-2024-earnings</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Qualcomm's yearly revenue has increased by 9%, closing in on $40 billion. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">dRBaFkuGMqe69qDWEPs3uf</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TZk2Z8sFDhzmSjwRii4wCS.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 21:56:02 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ derrek.lee@futurenet.com (Derrek Lee) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TZk2Z8sFDhzmSjwRii4wCS.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Qualcomm logo at MWC 2024]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Qualcomm logo at MWC 2024]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Play Protect's new feature tipped to remove the worry about side-loading apps ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The latest APK teardown of the Google Play Protect app has revealed a temporary pause button that could venture soon.</li><li>Users who side-load apps and generally turn off Play Protect to do so can now have a temporary time frame.</li><li>The upcoming feature would enable Play Protect feature after a day even users disable it for side loading of apps.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google Play Protect on Android phones plays a significant role in preventing malicious apps from being installed. According to its latest app findings, the tool might be getting a nifty upgrade for additional security.</p><p>Folks at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/google-play-protect-pause-3496795/">Android Authority</a> have managed to perform an APK investigation of the Google Play Store app version <strong>43.4.23-31</strong>, which revealed interesting changes coming to the app.</p><p>For starters, Play Protect is essential to safe-check Android apps that are being installed on your phones. However, while side-loading apps, it needs to be disabled momentarily as it can obstruct the third-party app installation.</p>
<p>Users can turn on Play Protect through their phone settings after installing the side-loaded apps. However, those who tend to forget might be at risk from malicious apps that can unknowingly get installed and cause problems. To fix this, the latest APK findings reveal that Google might be bringing a temporary pause option for the Play Protect feature on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phones</a>.</p><p>Per the screenshot shared by the publication, the Google Play Protect feature now has a new “Pause” button right next to “Turn off,” which was the only option for users earlier. Once the feature rolls out, it would likely be very handy for users to enable this option, who often install third-party or side-load apps without worrying about malware getting installed later.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:270px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:222.22%;"><img id="ptoC58i7RyvUUZVbwnq7Kc" name="New-Pause-Play-Protect-button" alt="Google Play Protect Pause button" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ptoC58i7RyvUUZVbwnq7Kc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="270" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>“When paused, Play Protect will no longer scan apps available outside of Google Play for malware. Play Protect will automatically turn on again the next day.”</p><p>It is still unclear if the timeframe for pausing the feature will increase later, yet having an option is still a plus, to say the least. Since it is found in the testing phase, the rollout might be soon for all Android devices, or the company could entirely skip it, as pausing the feature even for the suggested timeframe might still put the devices at risk from malicious apps during that period.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-play-protect-could-be-put-on-a-temporary-pause-in-future</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Google Play Protect feature is essential on your Android phone as it blocks malicious apps. The new feature in testing might ease things a bit. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">uRyrZymGHjQa6d9XwRcoae</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JtT6RUBnjWdpzsRzAkLpwS.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 20:52:49 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JtT6RUBnjWdpzsRzAkLpwS.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Pixel 9 Pro XL home page showing icons]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Pixel 9 Pro XL home page showing icons]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Galaxy S25 'Slim' might've made a cameo in an early database listing ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung's Galaxy S25 "Slim" might've appeared in a recent database listing.</li><li>The device is reportedly named "SM-S937U" and the "U" tag may indicate a device aimed at the U.S. market.</li><li>This "slim" variant was rumored to debut in Q2 2025 with a 6.7-inch dynamic AMOLED display and MediaTek's powerful Dimensity 9400 SoC.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Speculation of a "slim" Galaxy S25 continues to swirl as a recent finding might hold enough evidence to solidify its existence.</p><p>The alleged model number of Samsung's rumored Galaxy S25 "Slim" was discovered in a database by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.smartprix.com/bytes/samsungs-mysterious-galaxy-s25-slim-smartphone-officially-spotted-for-first-time/">SmartPrix</a>. According to the publication, the thinner device was supposedly given model number "SM-S937U." This number fits the recent discovery of the Galaxy S25 model names. A <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-plus-discontinued-rumors">previous database listing</a> showcased SM-S931, SM-S936, and SM-S938 for the Galaxy S25, S25 Plus, and S25 Ultra.</p><p>With the model numbers appearing so similar, it seems almost certain that this is the fourth S25 phone we've been hearing about.</p><p>More importantly, the publication notes that this particular number with the "U" tag indicates the U.S. version.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1288px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:24.46%;"><img id="znpXiHZmPezkAwensrfB2e" name="samsung-galaxy-s25-slim-rumored-model-number" alt="The supposed model number of the Galaxy S25 "Slim" has reportedly appeared in a database listing." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/znpXiHZmPezkAwensrfB2e.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1288" height="315" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: SmartPrix)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>A Korean <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/a-slim-galaxy-s25-might-be-samsungs-answer-to-apples-rumored-thin-iphone-17">report surfaced</a> at the beginning of November, doubling down on the chance for a "Galaxy S25 Slim." The device is expected to be "thinner" than the rest of the upcoming S25 cast and battle against Apple's rumored iPhone 17 "Air." It's still too early to tell <em>how </em>thin Samsung's phone will be, but what's clear is that it would need to arrive somewhere under the S24's 7.6mm measurement.</p><p>Additionally, the report claimed Samsung will launch the "Slim" phone in Q2 2025. The flagship trio is expected to drop in January or February, but a Q2 theory for the thinner device could put it anywhere from April to June.</p><p>SmartPrix states that Samsung's past behavior indicates that it typically places new devices (model numbers) in the GSMA database "six to seven months" before release. With that, the rumored Q2 release might be true, but take this with a grain of salt.</p><p>Of course, rumors of a "Slim" instead of a "Galaxy S25 FE" <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/sasmung-galaxy-s25-fe-could-be-called-s25-slim">started in October</a>. It was theorized that Samsung decided to shift gears with branding as it looks to debut a phone with a thinner form factor. Additional rumors state the device could launch with a 6.7-inch dynamic AMOLED display and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/mediateks-dimensity-9400-is-the-biggest-challenger-to-qualcomm-yet">MediaTek Dimensity 9400</a> SoC.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-s25-slim-early-database-listing-appearance</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Galaxy S25 "Slim" reportedly appeared in a database listing. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">2pXYVF5KhSq54VTgz6UR8T</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/G2jTwQ3PkYe4RjaFE8FhMm.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 20:45:56 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/G2jTwQ3PkYe4RjaFE8FhMm.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Looking at the different colorways of the Samsung Galaxy S24]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Looking at the different colorways of the Samsung Galaxy S24]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Some Galaxy S25 models might still opt for an Exynos chip instead of Snapdragon 8 Elite ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung is expected to launch the Galaxy S25 series earlier than the predecessor models.</li><li>New benchmark tests might have given away the Exynos chipset with which some Galaxy S25 models might ship.</li><li>Samsung usually releases its flagship series other than the Ultra model with an Exynos chip in regions like India and Europe — and it is likely to repeat with the Galaxy S25 series.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Samsung is probably gearing up for the Galaxy S25 series release earlier than usual. The devices are expected to be powered by Qualcomm's latest and greatest Snapdragon 8 Elite chip, as has been the tradition at least for the U.S. market.</p><p>Samsung; however, has chosen to bring its Exynos 2400 chipset for the Galaxy S24 models, such as the standard <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-hands-on">S24</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-plus-review">S24 Plus</a>, for regions like India and Europe, while the U.S. models have shipped with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-3-launch">Snapdragon 8 Gen 3</a> across the lineup.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Samsung Galaxy S25+ spotted with Exynos 2500 chipset.So, no Snapdragon 8 Elite for all regions. 🥴🔳 Exynos 2500🍭 Android 15- 12GB RAM#Samsung #GalaxyS25 #S25Plus pic.twitter.com/nbC4aiDmXE<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1853717658207678828">November 5, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>New evidence suggests that Samsung might again opt for the same strategy for the upcoming Galaxy S25 models. A recent benchmark leak indicated that the Samsung Galaxy S25 Plus model runs on an Exynos 2500 SoC. The Geekbench report of the S25 Plus indicates the device scoring 2359 single-core and 8141 multi-core scores.</p><p>The benchmark further confirms that the device features the Android 15 operating system, likely running on the upcoming One UI 7. According to Geekbench, it also has 12GB of RAM. The device has the model number <strong>SM-S936B</strong>. For the uninitiated, the Galaxy S2 Plus has the model number <strong>SM-S9236B </strong>in certain regions.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1406px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.26%;"><img id="MCC9YAmSEdQcicmoGWyhQk" name="samsung-galaxy-s25-plus-stacked-alleged-rendering.jpeg" alt="An alleged rendering of the Galaxy S25 Plus." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MCC9YAmSEdQcicmoGWyhQk.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1406" height="791" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Regarding the chipset, the showcased Exynos chip is a ten-core chip built on 2+5+2+1 architecture with clock speeds of up to 3.30GHz. In comparison, the Galaxy S25 Ultra features the latest Snapdragon chip, which hit early in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-s25-ultra-with-snapdragon-8-gen-4-hits-benchmark">benchmark test</a>, revealing 3069 and 9080 single- and multi-core scores. The Snapdragon chip's clock speeds hit up to 4.19GHz.</p><p>Although these benchmark tests don't significantly indicate the real-life performance of these devices, they will only be gauged after their release. Given the history of Snapdragon versus Exynos, the former has been a viable option in the long run.</p>
<p>Since these benchmark tests indicate that the upcoming Galaxy S25 series is in the testing phase, it still needs to be determined whether Samsung will opt for the Snapdragon chip across all regions or the Exynos chip in select regions.</p><p>X user Jukanlosreve also indicated that the aforementioned Galaxy S25 Plus running on Exynos chips was apparently for testing purposes. On the contrary, the user denotes that all S25 models would be running on the Snapdragon 8 Elite, which is exciting to hear. However, it is recommended that we wait before jumping to conclusions, as the rumored launch is only a couple of months away.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Update: This was for testing purposes. All S25 models use the 8 Elite. https://t.co/G6j6lMYqam<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1853707361229435002">November 5, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-models-to-opt-for-flagship-exynos-soc-again</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung has launched the Galaxy S24 series with an Exynos chip in some regions other than the U.S., and that is likely to happen with the successor models, too. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">5BbWimWS9V7W6Fr2gpz6VA</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yFmLhsbp8G89X6TVQ6Twh5.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 19:58:50 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yFmLhsbp8G89X6TVQ6Twh5.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Galaxy S24 family including the smaller Galaxy S24, larger Galaxy S24 Plus, and premium Galaxy S24 Ultra]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Galaxy S24 family including the smaller Galaxy S24, larger Galaxy S24 Plus, and premium Galaxy S24 Ultra]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Galaxy Ring 2 might not wait as long to reveal these rumored enhancements ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A rumor claims Samsung is preparing to implement a series of additional changes to the Galaxy Ring 2.</li><li>Supposedly, the device could grab an increased battery life, a thinner profile, and "more."</li><li>A recent report highlighted a re-published Samsung Galaxy Ring patent for a "resizing structure" design that could debut for the second model.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Additional rumors surfaced regarding Samsung's next smart ring, which suggests the OEM wants to implement more changes.</p><p>A tipster posted some rumors about the Galaxy Ring 2 <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://m.blog.naver.com/PostView.naver?blogId=yeux1122&logNo=223648855900&proxyReferer=&noTrackingCode=true">on Naver</a> (Korean) claiming the next small wearable will receive several more improvements (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/11/06/samsung-galaxy-ring-2-report/">9to5Google</a>). According to tipster Lanzuk, the next-gen Ring may grab a "longer battery life" than its predecessor.</p><p>The rumors add that Samsung's next model could arrive with an even thinner profile, too. The tipster doesn't purport how thin the Galaxy Ring 2 could be. It's worth reiterating that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-ring-review#section-battery-and-charging">the original model</a> is 7.0mm wide and 2.6mm deep. Samsung's smart ring was the "thinnest on the market" for a time, but the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/ringconn-gen-2-smart-ring-review">RingConn Gen 2</a> arrived shortly after to take that crown at 2mm in depth.</p><p>The tipster then alludes to "more features" as part of Samsung's supposed overhaul/rework of the Galaxy Ring 2.</p><p>What's more, Lanzuk states that Samsung could debut its Galaxy Ring 2 "a bit earlier than originally scheduled." It's uncertain what timeline the company originally had in mind; however, the O.G. device debuted during Unpacked in July.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:699px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:65.81%;"><img id="mvm5TQZNsyfy6b8DFjYtmn" name="samsung-galaxy-ring-2-launch-features-rumored" alt="Rumors about Samsung's supposed Galaxy Ring 2 improvements and a potential launch timeframe." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mvm5TQZNsyfy6b8DFjYtmn.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="699" height="460" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Lanzuk / Naver)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Seeing more battery life on the next Ring would likely aid Samsung's competitive spirit. The original model delivers an 18mAh battery that lasts roughly a week on a full charge. That timeframe is a few days shy of the RingConn Gen 2, which can push 1o to 12 days on a full charge (outshining Oura, too).</p><p>In other news, these (rumored) changes to the Galaxy Ring 2 are interesting, especially after Samsung <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-ring-resizing-patent-discovered">re-published a patent</a>. In late October, the Korean OEM was spotted resurfacing a patent for a "resizing structure" design for the Galaxy Ring. This design was originally published in December 2023, which would've fit well for the O.G. launch, but we didn't get that.</p><p>The design showed a Galaxy Ring with a stretchy, "elastic" and "transformable" inner band that would reshape itself to fit the user's finger. In short, it's a design that would help create a more comfortable Galaxy Ring without Samsung needing to make so many sizes. Instead, Samsung reportedly filed the patent with varying internal structure segment sizes — but the outer shell remained the same.</p><p>There's more that we would hope a "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-ring-2">Galaxy Ring 2</a>" could offer; however, one aspect that would be nice to see improved is its durability. The device's finish was fragile as it would chip and peel easily with slight bumps.</p><p>It's anyone's guess when Samsung could debut this next model. The company debuted the original iteration during its summer Unpacked event in July. The thought of an "earlier" launch could put us in the spring or perhaps sometime in June. As always, we'll have to wait for the official word.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/galaxy-ring-2-new-enhancements-launch-rumored</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Rumors claimed Samsung may implement even more upgrades in its Galaxy Ring 2. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">vAJXx3rt9YHhfh3nzyhhbW</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3sGWcko3E7aG2PnDTK5TxW.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 19:52:47 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3sGWcko3E7aG2PnDTK5TxW.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The gold Samsung Galaxy Ring alongside the Samsung Wearables app]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The gold Samsung Galaxy Ring alongside the Samsung Wearables app]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Pixel 9 series users can expect notable bug fixes with the November security patch ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google Pixel 9, Pixel 9 Pro, 9 Pro XL, and Pixel 9 Pro Fold owners on Verizon get the latest November firmware.</li><li>It brings bug fixes for Bluetooth and zoom issues on the camera, amongst other notable issues.</li><li>The update seems to be sizable, including the latest Android security patch. The wider rollout is expected later this week.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>As we enter November, Google Pixel owners expect a new monthly firmware release, and the company is reportedly releasing it, at least for the Pixel 9 series users on Verizon.</p><p>According to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/11/05/november-2024-pixel-update/">9to5Google</a>, the carrier has detailed what’s coming with the November security update on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-series-hands-on">Pixel 9 series</a>, which is yet to be officially announced by the search giant. Considering the every month release cycle, it naturally happens on a Monday, and it is likely the case this month, too. However, Verizon carrier Pixel 9 owners might be in for an early treat.</p>
<p>The latest security update uses the <strong>AP3A.241105.008</strong> firmware version and the devices included are the Pixel 9, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-review">Pixel 9 Pro, and Pixel 9 Pro XL</a>. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-fold-review">Pixel 9 Pro Fold</a> is also included.</p><p>The publication shared the changelog, which states that the firmware update includes the latest Android security patch. The new software will address the fix for Pixel 9 models facing issues with Bluetooth range in some scenarios.</p><p>Camera issues like tilting when zooming between cameras are believed to be fixed. The latest release also addresses issues that caused white dots to flash and the prevention of not triggering adaptive brightness in certain conditions. The firmware also resolves other touch-related issues, in addition to general improvements and stability across the interface and animations.</p>
<p>On the other hand, 9to5 also notes that changelog entries for the Pixel 6, Pixel 7, and Pixel 8 series include the <strong>AP3A.241105.007</strong> firmware number for the November update. While it doesn’t include any major bug fixes, users can expect the latest Android security patch next to general performance improvements, as aforementioned.</p><p>While the new firmware release is seen on the Verizon-powered Pixel 9 models, other general audiences will likely see the firmware rollout this week or the coming Monday.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-pixel-9-verizon-owners-already-receive-november-2024-firmware</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Other Pixel 6, Pixel 7, and Pixel 8 models also get the latest firmware with general improvements. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">328nqGG5VuozKceRtPMeaA</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DsBa2t3vEyHabPemsFwwK8.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 19:19:51 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DsBa2t3vEyHabPemsFwwK8.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android 15 home page on Pixel 9, Pixel 9 Pro XL, and Pixel 9 Pro Fold]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android 15 home page on Pixel 9, Pixel 9 Pro XL, and Pixel 9 Pro Fold]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ This long Wear OS 5 update delay feels like a sign of what's to come ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Wear OS Weekly</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="o8KRGSTt4mbFxn3wdtWvtU" name="lloyd-wear-os-weekly.jpg" caption="" alt="Android Central mascot Lloyd wearing a Galaxy Watch and Pixel Watch" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/o8KRGSTt4mbFxn3wdtWvtU.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">My new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/wear-os-weekly">weekly column</a> focuses on the state of Wear OS, from new developments and updates to the latest apps and features we want to highlight.</p></div></div>
<p>Wear OS 5 is a subtle but significant improvement for Wear OS watches across brands, with the Pixel Watch 3 and Galaxy Watch 7 showcasing its strengths. But the longer the update takes to arrive on last-gen watches, the more questions it raises about the OS' future.</p><p>Google first added Wear OS 5 to the Pixel Watch 2 and 1 on September 27 before <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/pixel-watch-wear-os-5-problems-force-pause">pausing the rollout</a> after reports of users' watches crashing, with "blank screens" forcing factory resets. The Wear OS team promised a resumed rollout "later this year," adding they would "share additional updates with our community as they become available."</p><p>It's been nearly six weeks since then, with no updates on when "later" will arrive; Samsung <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-galaxy-watch-6-series-get-stable-one-ui-6-watch-wear-os-5">added Wear OS 5 to the Galaxy Watch 6</a> in the interim, beating the stock Wear OS devs to the punch, but it, too, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/11/06/samsung-galaxy-watch-updates-months-behind-wear-os/">hasn't updated its older Galaxy Watches since spring</a>.</p><p>Last week, I contacted a Wear OS team member for new info on the root of the problem and the delay in solving it. In response, they linked to the original <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/googlepixelwatch/thread/301420568">September help page</a>, saying I'd "find what [I] need" there. I didn't, obviously.</p><p>Since Google wouldn't explain the delay, I speculated with my Android Central coworkers. We're guessing the Wear OS devs probably haven't replicated the configuration issue causing these blank screens, so they're stuck waiting to avoid a repeat of crashing watches. It's not that the older watches <em>can't</em> run Wear OS 5, especially since the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-2-review">Pixel Watch 2</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-3-review">Pixel Watch 3</a> largely share the same tech.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="SJjsSKMQGc6UuycG4WeaB7" name="Google-Pixel-Watch-3-nest-cam-live-feed.jpeg" alt="Nest Doorbell live feed on the Pixel Watch 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SJjsSKMQGc6UuycG4WeaB7.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="caption-text">The Nest Cam view on the Pixel Watch 3 with Wear OS 5 </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nick Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Unlike Samsung, which pushed out <em>eight</em> One UI 6 Watch betas on the Galaxy Watch 6 before the stable build arrived for those in the program, Google doesn't offer a Wear OS beta program like it does with the mobile Android OS. Perhaps this incident will convince Google that it's worth exploring for Wear OS 6 to try and catch these issues beforehand and avoid the QA headache of a rolled-back update.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a> took longer than usual to arrive this year, too, but phones have the headroom to implement a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/9-android-15-features-you-should-check-out">ton of new features</a>, while smartwatches use old Arm Cortex cores and settle for a few software tweaks per year.</p><p>With <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://developer.android.com/training/wearables/versions/5">Wear OS 5</a>, you get battery optimization, better content reflow optimized to fit different screen sizes, new "flavors" and goals for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/wear-os-5-blocks-facer-and-makes-watch-faces-boring">Watch Face Format</a>, and a few new features for runners. Specific to the Pixel Watch, you'll see a Nest Cam view, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/google-tv">Google TV</a> controls, a recorder app, and a cam viewfinder mode; older Galaxy Watches will add Energy Scores, a new Quick Panel, universal gestures, and other tweaks.</p><p>I'm not saying Wear OS 3.5 and Wear OS 4 were <em>unimportant</em> updates, but their changes definitely felt more pedestrian. Wear OS 5 helped the Pixel Watch 3 and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-7-review">Galaxy Watch 7</a> have stronger-than-expected battery life compared to the last generation while also adding some juicy exclusives.</p><p>Maybe that's a partial explanation for why customers are having to wait months later than usual for this new update (the number of substantial changes). And that raises its own questions.</p>
<h2 id="wear-os-already-has-a-messy-update-history-2">Wear OS already has a messy update history</h2>
<p>Since Google and Samsung teamed up on Wear OS updates in mid-2021, it's become clear that any OEMs besides these two would struggle to keep up.</p><p>Wear OS 3 arrived in 2021, but it took Fossil until late 2022 to add it, and then another year for Wear OS 3.5 before <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fossil-group-quits-making-smartwatches">abandoning the platform entirely</a>. Mobvoi took until December 2023 to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/mobvoi-wear-os-3-rollout">add Wear OS 3</a>, then <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/mobvoi-wear-os-4-update-ticwatch-pro-5-series">launched Wear OS 4 in September</a>; its newest watches still don't have Google Assistant, even though we <em>assumed</em> the Wear OS 4 update would make it available. Who knows when (or if) they'll get Wear OS 5!</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:720px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="zrwPBu4fn5FUxGnroHbpY8" name="Ticwatch-Atlas.jpg" alt="Mobvoi Ticwatch Atlas wrapped around the wrist" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zrwPBu4fn5FUxGnroHbpY8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="720" height="405" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="caption-text">The new Mobvoi TicWatch Atlas has Wear OS 4. Will it get Wear OS 5? Who knows! </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Mobvoi)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The newest Wear OS partners are OnePlus and Xiaomi. We've yet to test the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/xiaomi-officially-launches-xiaomi-watch-s3-watch-2-and-smart-band-8-pro-worldwide">Xiaomi Watch 2</a> or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/xiaomi-watch-2-pro-official-wear-os-3">Watch 2 Pro</a>, but we know they only just received Wear OS 4 in September 2024, a year behind; as for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oneplus-watch-2-review">OnePlus Watch 2</a>, it's slated to receive Wear OS 5 and 6, but we don't know <em>when</em>.</p><p>We hope OnePlus fans won't have to wait long, but that seems to be the track record for everyone besides Google and Samsung for relatively <em>minor</em> changelogs. Now that Google itself is struggling to update its watches speedily, who knows what that means for its partners trying to add Wear OS 5. Will they need a year or more?</p>
<h2 id="whether-wear-os-updates-get-quicker-or-longer-will-depend-on-hardware-2">Whether Wear OS updates get quicker (or longer) will depend on hardware</h2>
<p>Google promises its Pixel Watches will get three Wear OS updates, while Samsung promises four version updates. Compared to the seven or eight years of updates flagship phones get these days, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch">Android watches</a> get short shrift. Whether that changes will depend a lot on future Wear OS hardware.</p><p>I recently wrote about Google's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/wear-os/upcoming-pixel-watches-could-play-it-safe-and-i-dont-like-it">leaked Pixel Watch chip plans</a> and why it may play it safe with a lesser version of Samsung's Exynos W1000 with Arm cores rather than go all on in open-source RISC-V or try a Snapdragon W5 Gen 2 with Oryon cores.</p><p>If Google chooses Exynos-inspired Tensor hardware, it'll be because Arm cores keep watches priced low, allow Google to control its software roadmap, and make it easier for third parties to stick with the same Wear OS coding that they're familiar with. At the same time, Tensor optimization would keep the status quo, with a limit on what Wear OS watches can do and other OEMs scrambling to stay a year behind Google and Samsung.</p><p>After hearing Qualcomm VP of Wearables Dino Bekis talk about <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/wear-os/qualcomms-next-wear-os-chipset-could-arrive-in-2025">future Wear OS watches</a> with a goal of week-long battery life, more AI and compute capability, and a platform with enough "headroom" to "scale for multiple years," I'll admit that it made me hope for more. But that could come with its own update problems.</p><p>On the plus side, an optimized RISC-V chip or more powerful Snapdragon chip could make future Wear OS updates more substantive, leave room for future updates beyond three years, and give OEMs more headroom to implement their own watch software features instead of having to stay in lesser lockstep behind Google.</p><p>As a negative, more powerful smartwatch chips could make watches more expensive and make it much harder to optimize future Wear OS updates for <em>current</em> hardware — especially if Google chooses the RISC-V route.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="PqXZpoB9SLWbgwNXTMhvZh" name="Google-Pixel-Watch-3-app-drawer" alt="The default app drawer on the Google Pixel Watch 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PqXZpoB9SLWbgwNXTMhvZh.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I don't know what will happen with future <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wear-os-watch">Wear OS watch</a> hardware, and if it'll make this year's messy update a thing of the past or a common occurrence. What I do know is that companies should have greater transparency around delays and glitches like this.</p><p>It's been three months since the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-august-2024-update">August 2024 Wear OS update</a>, and Pixel Watch 1 and 2 users being kept in radio silence after a glitchy annual update will remember this delay when choosing their <em>next</em> watch, whether it's the excellent Pixel Watch 3, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-4">Pixel Watch 4</a>, or a different brand entirely.</p><p>Of course, Samsung (the most obvious alternative) has been lax when it comes to keeping its older watches updated every month. It makes me wonder why Wear OS watches are so difficult to update, both for small and major updates!</p><p>Google may not want headlines saying what went wrong, but not explaining the delay isn't any better. Wear OS updates are already enough of a messy Wild West, and even if you can't provide a timeline, you can at least explain in more detail what went wrong.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/long-wear-os-5-update-delay-feels-like-bad-sign</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ This six-week Wear OS 5 delay on last-gen Pixel Watches isn't that long (yet), but Wear OS has a long history of painful waits for new features. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">b5LsfYRdbK2AwZyFadNiYb</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/UTBgD6CtsrdwzTmveZFbUc.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 19:19:50 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wear Os]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/UTBgD6CtsrdwzTmveZFbUc.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Camera Viewfinder on Pixel Watch 3]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Camera Viewfinder on Pixel Watch 3]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung's major Gen AI Bixby upgrade is here, but it's out of reach ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-32">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung drops a surprise as it launches its promised overhaul for Bixby in an overseas foldable launch.</li><li>The debut brings generative AI features to Bixby, like on-screen translation, better "complex" query understanding, and more.</li><li>Samsung's TM Roh stated the company was aiming for a "late 2024" launch, which has happened for China; however, it's unclear when it'll hit the U.S.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Since Galaxy AI debuted, Samsung has been slowly upgrading its on-device helper, Bixby, but it seems the AI's major overhaul arrived for one overseas market.</p><p>Samsung launched <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.samsung.com.cn/smartphones/samsung-w25/">its next wave of foldables</a> in China: the W25 and the W25 Flip, alternates of the Fold's Special Edition and the Galaxy Z Flip 6. However, as spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.sammobile.com/news/new-samsung-bixby-launched-china/">SamMobile</a>, the Korean OEM's debut included the surprise inclusion of its "next-generation" on-device AI assistant, Bixby.</p><p>From the launch page, Samsung has seemingly stepped up Bixby's ability to understand what the user wants <em>and </em>its content understanding capabilities.</p><p>Regarding the former, the company states its next-gen Bixby can "understand complex user intentions" (machine-translated). This might be similar to what Google did for its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gen-ai-search-upgrades-io-2024">AI Overviews</a>. Samsung states Bixby can "deeply perceive" what a user wants, as well as maintain a sharp understanding through multi-step instructions in "a single sentence."</p><p>Samsung also upgraded Bixby with stronger, more "accurate" on-screen translation capabilities. Mandarin is likely fully supported seeing as these devices launched in the Chinese market. Samsung added that it will expand its language support for Bixby's on-screen translation feature, but a timeline wasn't detailed.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:544px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:110.29%;"><img id="gnmYzM9HLBtSqPUaoHW7KB" name="samsung-bixby-on-screen-translation-capabilities" alt="Bixby's new Gen AI overhaul brings "more accurate" on-screen translation capabilities." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gnmYzM9HLBtSqPUaoHW7KB.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="544" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Samsung)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:556px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:107.91%;"><img id="BbY8ojRms3snbnkaAT6R7F" name="samsung-bixby-complex-query-understanding-example" alt="Samsung states its Gen AI upgraded Bixby can better understand more "complex" multi-step queries." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BbY8ojRms3snbnkaAT6R7F.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="556" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Samsung)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Bixby's content understanding capabilities extend to videos, too. According to Samsung, Bixby can "cleverly integrate text and video" from online sources. The company states this should give users better context about places they may travel to.</p><p>Lastly, the Gen AI upgrades bring "office document generation." The OEM states Bixby can generate Word, PowerPoint, and "other documents based on user needs."</p><p>In July, Samsung <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-bixby-gen-ai-overhual-confirmed">confirmed</a> that a major overhaul of its on-device assistant Bixby was inbound. The company's Head of Mobile Business, TM Roh, stated that such advancements with its AI are a "driver" for consumer interest and "convenience." The upgrade was centered around funneling generative AI features into its assistant, which were <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-teases-generative-ai-plans-bixby">previously rumored</a> to have been influenced by ChatGPT.</p><p>Roh stated that Samsung was interested in debuting such advancements "later in 2024" and it seems to have hit that estimation. There's no telling when other markets, such as the U.S., could see this upgraded Gen AI version of Bixby. It's possible that it could drop alongside the Galaxy S25 series next year with One UI 7, but we're just speculating.</p><p>Currently, Galaxy S24 users can mess with a smaller update to Bixby, which brought <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-galaxy-ai-bixby-integration-announced">hands-free capabilities</a> to the AI. Samsung highlighted such features in February, stating users can leverage Live Translate, Spelling Correction, Webpage Summaries, and File organization without lifting a finger. Users can initiate their hands-free experience with "Hi Bixby..."</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-major-gen-ai-bixby-rework-arrives</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung was spotted debuting its next-gen Bixby assistant in an overseas launch. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">txKDD2NsssqfrRuB8GASVe</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dmS8YZtoEgXaPisbPM8ajK.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 18:51:23 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dmS8YZtoEgXaPisbPM8ajK.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Bixby Voice on the Galaxy S20 Ultra]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Bixby Voice on the Galaxy S20 Ultra]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ What is 5G RedCap and do you need to rush out and buy into it? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>You might have heard T-Mobile and TCL telling us about the new 5G RedCap device being offered. It's the first of its kind, and it can be used to bring a 5G connection to almost any device with a USB-C port. In the large picture of a connected world, it's pretty important.</p><p>Most people see something like this and immediately wonder if it's something they need. Like a lot of things, RedCap devices like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.t-mobile.com/news/devices/tcl-and-t-mobile-launch-first-5g-redcap-device">TCL LINKPORT IK511</a> are built for people who already know they need it because it's either the best solution or the only solution.</p>
<p>It's not the only way RedCap will come to the market; it's just the first way. One day we will probably see things like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch">a wearable</a> built using RedCap tech for its 5G connection (<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.qualcomm.com/news/onq/2022/07/what-is-5g-nr-light--a-k-a--redcap--and-how-will-it-accelerate-t">Qualcomm is already working on it</a>) via the internal hardware of the device itself. For now, though, RedCap probably isn't something you need to buy into.</p><p>So, what exactly is it?</p>
<p>I love <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://iot.telenor.com/technologies/connectivity/5g-redcap/">Telnor's</a> overview of the technology because it's a just-the-facts synopsis:</p><p><em>5G RedCap is a new 5G standard that is designed to address the use cases in between the high speed Enhanced mobile broadband (eMBB), the ultra-reliable low latency communications (uRLLC) and the low throughput and battery efficient Massive Machine-Type Communication (mMTC) technologies. 5G RedCap is well-suited for a wide range of IoT applications and will probably play an important role in future IoT deployments. For the time being, LTE Cat 1 and Cat 4 are the most suitable for those IoT scenarios.</em></p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="Yd5RHWuQ63Esx88oCRWoqh" name="Google-Pixel-Watch-3-front-view" alt="A close-up front view of the Google Pixel Watch 3 and a data-rich watch face" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Yd5RHWuQ63Esx88oCRWoqh.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>For most people, this doesn't mean much, but it actually says it all. 5G RedCap is a bridge between the robust 5G deployments we have now and the limited needs of some devices. The clue is in the name, which stands for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.ericsson.com/en/reports-and-papers/white-papers/redcap-expanding-the-5g-device-ecosystem-for-consumers-and-industries">REDuced CAPacity</a> because it can deliver what some devices need without all the extra fluff.</p>
<p>It's built for IoT devices, both consumer and industrial. RedCap is a great solution for a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-security-cameras-store-locally-not-cloud">camera surveillance system</a> guarding your home or a network of sensors that control autonomous loaders at a factory that manufactures cardboard. These sorts of things don't need the full capabilities of an expensive 5G network so planning one out and then spending the money on it isn't very wise. Before RedCap came into the picture, this was the only choice once 4G goes away.</p><p>Here's the meat of the issue for normal people who just like their gadgets—you don't really need to worry about it. If you need a connection for your laptop because you're somewhere with no Wi-Fi, just use your phone instead of buying a dongle from T-Mobile. If you regularly find yourself in this situation, you already know if RedCap is going to work for your needs.</p><p>When RedCap hardware appears inside things like smart rings or cameras, you won't have to do anything to use it. You might save some money, but knowing how companies like to operate, probably not. Making sure it "just works" will be figured out long before you can buy the devices.</p>
<p>The tech is cool, I'm not going to lie. I'm a manufacturing nerd and can think of a million ways this tech could be used on a factory floor, provided it's cheap and someone wants to build the things. I can also see how it would be good for the camera system at Walmart, which has the means to build out a dedicated network to use it right now.</p><p>We're in the hype-building phase, just like we saw for LTE and 5G itself. Once the tech is ready for wide adoption, it will just happen, and you don't have to think about it at all.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/5g-redcap-explained</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ RedCap brings a 5G smart grid anywhere there is network access. It doesn't compete with the Wi-Fi you already have. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">fVhw7b8MJyqysRNdjgdrqL</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PemxwDLThnJXurFg3y6FJB.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PemxwDLThnJXurFg3y6FJB.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[T-Mobile]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[TCL 5G RedCap device attached to a laptop.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[TCL 5G RedCap device attached to a laptop.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung Galaxy S25: What preorder deals can we expect? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Planning to buy a Samsung Galaxy S25 when the phones are (presumably) unveiled in a few months? Well, you're in luck: I created this guide so all of you early birds know where to look when the preorder period finally kicks off.</p><p>If past years are any indication, you can expect Samsung's next flagship lineup to be revealed during a Galaxy Unpacked event in January 2025. We've already begun seeing a bunch of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25">leaks and rumors</a> about the upcoming devices, and while nothing is confirmed just yet, I've been working these events long enough to have a pretty good idea of what you can expect. From trade-in opportunities to free gift cards, keep reading for all of my Galaxy S25 preorder predictions.</p><p>While you're in the neighborhood, you should also go check out my guide to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024-early-deals-and-how-to-prepare-for-the-big-sales">best Samsung Galaxy deals of Black Friday 2024</a> (so far) to see if you can knock out some holiday shopping early.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-preorder-deals-to-expect"><span>Preorder deals to expect</span></h2>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="c5360a88-b631-4b05-8fdf-a2256c3a97d8" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="See top deals at Samsung today" data-dimension48="See top deals at Samsung today" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="B2FuqYxaZUEkHwVmgYdBUT" name="Samsung-Logo.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/B2FuqYxaZUEkHwVmgYdBUT.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="2048" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung: </strong>enhanced trade-in credit, storage upgrades, bundle deals</p><p><strong>My prediction: </strong>unsurprisingly, Samsung is likely to be the first retailer with preorder deals as soon as the Galaxy S25 series is announced. Plan to see loads of accessible trade-in credit with free storage upgrades abound. Preordering at Samsung is also the best way to score exclusive color variants on the S25 series.  </p><p><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/" data-dimension112="c5360a88-b631-4b05-8fdf-a2256c3a97d8" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="See top deals at Samsung today" data-dimension48="See top deals at Samsung today" data-dimension25=""><em><strong>See top deals at Samsung today</strong></em></a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="66abc080-0163-42da-a67f-50fcdde7acf9" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="See Amazon's top deals today" data-dimension48="See Amazon's top deals today" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:153px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="opLCJmgrBwG9SYqG5HZ94" name="amazon-deal.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/opLCJmgrBwG9SYqG5HZ94.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="153" height="153" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Amazon: </strong>free gift cards, storage upgrades</p><p><strong>My prediction: </strong>Amazon is usually a little late to the preorder party when new devices get revealed, but once the phones are added, I expect accompanying gift cards with a value of up to $200, plus twice the storage at no additional cost.</p><p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/deals" data-dimension112="66abc080-0163-42da-a67f-50fcdde7acf9" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="See Amazon's top deals today" data-dimension48="See Amazon's top deals today" data-dimension25=""><em><strong>See Amazon's top deals today</strong></em></a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="7b2a9983-f361-405c-9860-4ddc5b6fd5a1" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="See top deals at Best Buy today" data-dimension48="See top deals at Best Buy today" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:59.00%;"><img id="HDzkHxFGNNvnkYjNkGzePC" name="best-buy-logo.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HDzkHxFGNNvnkYjNkGzePC.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="472" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Best Buy: </strong>free gift cards, storage upgrades</p><p><strong>My prediction: </strong>just like Amazon, Best Buy is likely to accompany its Galaxy S25 preorder deals with retailer gift cards and double the storage for free. The retailer might also throw in some enhanced trade-in credit. </p><p><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/top-deals" data-dimension112="7b2a9983-f361-405c-9860-4ddc5b6fd5a1" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="See top deals at Best Buy today" data-dimension48="See top deals at Best Buy today" data-dimension25=""><em><strong>See top deals at Best Buy today</strong></em></a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="8968e9f4-430d-478e-8e99-e6d088d46f59" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="See all of Verizon's best deals now" data-dimension48="See all of Verizon's best deals now" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3321px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:40.98%;"><img id="HBqRvBgPimq99uDCsr2Mgj" name="Verizon-2024-logo.png" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HBqRvBgPimq99uDCsr2Mgj.png" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3321" height="1361" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Verizon: </strong>enhanced trade-in credit, new line discounts, storage upgrades</p><p><strong>My prediction: </strong>Verizon is usually one of the first retailers to launch preorder deals when new Samsung devices get announced. If my predictions are correct, you can expect to receive some seriously impressive savings when you sign up for an eligible data plan and send the carrier an old or broken device. </p><p>In most cases, it's pretty easy to score the max trade-in credit, but the qualifying unlimited plans can get expensive if you aren't careful. Storage upgrades are common here, as well. </p><p><a href="https://www.verizon.com/deals/" data-dimension112="8968e9f4-430d-478e-8e99-e6d088d46f59" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="See all of Verizon's best deals now" data-dimension48="See all of Verizon's best deals now" data-dimension25=""><em><strong>See all of Verizon's best deals now</strong></em></a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="3ae9400d-c732-41cf-9afa-3d6dd746c821" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="See AT&amp;T's best phone deals today" data-dimension48="See AT&amp;T's best phone deals today" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:49.25%;"><img id="LAej2bTeQvF3C9LXZQrdBg" name="att-logo-reco-transparent.png" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LAej2bTeQvF3C9LXZQrdBg.png" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="394" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>AT&T: </strong>enhanced trade-in credit, new line discounts, storage upgrades</p><p><strong>My prediction: </strong>AT&T is also likely to offer a free storage upgrade and some enhanced trade-in credit when you preorder a Galaxy S25 and send in an old device, regardless of the phone's age or condition. The catch is signing up for the right unlimited plan, but if you can make it work for you, AT&T preorder deals are typically some of the best around. </p><p><a href="https://www.att.com/deals/cell-phone-deals/" data-dimension112="3ae9400d-c732-41cf-9afa-3d6dd746c821" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="See AT&amp;T's best phone deals today" data-dimension48="See AT&amp;T's best phone deals today" data-dimension25=""><em><strong>See AT&T's best phone deals today</strong></em></a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="2957c021-8fe4-4380-8333-668da138289b" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="See Mint Mobile's best deals today" data-dimension48="See Mint Mobile's best deals today" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="cNfSyKCaNDAiPxukdZBSfG" name="mnt mobile square render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/cNfSyKCaNDAiPxukdZBSfG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="500" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Mint Mobile:</strong> discounted phones and wireless when you bundle</p><p><strong>My prediction: </strong>Mint Mobile will probably get involved with Galaxy S25 preorder deals a few days after the Unpacked announcement, but the offers are sure to be worth the wait. </p><p>If past releases are any indication, you can expect the T-Mobile-owned MVNO to slash prices on Galaxy S25 phones when you bundle the purchase of the device with a data plan. The wireless will probably come super cheap too, as Mint is currently offering its popular Unlimited plan for as little as $15 per month. </p><p><a href="https://mintmobile.com/deals/" data-dimension112="2957c021-8fe4-4380-8333-668da138289b" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="See Mint Mobile's best deals today" data-dimension48="See Mint Mobile's best deals today" data-dimension25=""><em><strong>See Mint Mobile's best deals today</strong></em></a></p></div>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-samsung-galaxy-s25-faq"><span>Samsung Galaxy S25 FAQ</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="V5uuKBra5MCkhZteCeYS8f" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-Ultra-using-the-camera-back.jpg" alt="Taking a photo using the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/V5uuKBra5MCkhZteCeYS8f.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<h2 id="when-will-the-samsung-galaxy-s25-come-out-2">When will the Samsung Galaxy S25 come out?</h2>
<p>The Samsung Galaxy S25 series — which is expected to include the new Galaxy S25, Galaxy S25 Plus, and Galaxy S25 Ultra — is likely to be announced during an Unpacked event in January with an official release date later that month.</p><p>This prediction is entirely based on previous rollouts that we've seen from Samsung. The Galaxy S24 lineup, for example, was announced on January 17th, 2024 and subsequently released on January 31st. The Galaxy S23 series, on the other hand, was announced a bit later, with a February 1st, 2023, announcement and a February 17th release date.</p>
<h2 id="how-much-will-the-samsung-galaxy-s25-cost-2">How much will the Samsung Galaxy S25 cost?</h2>
<p>While nothing has been confirmed quite yet, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-4-rumored-price-hike-sour">rumors from earlier this year</a> suggest that the Galaxy S25 series' <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/snapdragon-8-elite">Snapdragon 8 Elite</a> chipset may result in considerably higher price tags than previous Galaxy S phones. While we wait for official news from Samsung, you can speculate a bit by considering the price tags found on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24">Galaxy S24 series</a>.</p><p>The base model Galaxy S24 starts at $799 for the 128GB configuration, while the Galaxy S24 Plus costs $999 with 256GB of storage. The super-powerful Galaxy S24 Ultra is the most expensive of the bunch, with a starting retail price of $1,299 for the 256GB version. If the rumors are true, you can expect all of those prices to go up by $100 or so, which is all the more reason to look for a preorder deal when they become available.</p>

<h2 id="how-do-i-preorder-the-samsung-galaxy-s25-2">How do I preorder the Samsung Galaxy S25?</h2>
<p>You can begin searching for Galaxy S25 preorder deals pretty much as soon as the Samsung Unpacked event kicks off. Start by considering your options: do you have a phone to trade in? Would you rather purchase an unlocked device or shop through your wireless carrier? There are usually a ton of ways to save when new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-samsung-phones">Samsung phones</a> get announced, you just need to find the deal that works best for you. Needless to say, we'll be actively sharing all of the best offers the moment they go live, so bookmark this page if you want to be first in line.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="G2jTwQ3PkYe4RjaFE8FhMm" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-white-back-01.jpg" alt="Looking at the different colorways of the Samsung Galaxy S24" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/G2jTwQ3PkYe4RjaFE8FhMm.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<h2 id="will-the-samsung-galaxy-s24-drop-in-price-2">Will the Samsung Galaxy S24 drop in price?</h2>
<p>Probably! We're already seeing a lot of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/best-samsung-galaxy-s24-deals-of-the-month">Galaxy S24 deals</a> as we approach Black Friday, and while we haven't heard anything about permanent price drops, Samsung phones typically get discounted more regularly when they're no longer current-gen.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-preorder-deals-what-to-expect</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung's new flagship lineup will be unveiled in a few months — here's what we know (so far) about preordering the phones. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">PNz2LZ5sSQ92EC4vrGUwfS</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rE4YGhpZYsVBh7ahzPSyhT.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 12:02:46 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rE4YGhpZYsVBh7ahzPSyhT.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Comparing the camera lens bumps on the Samsung Galaxy S23 Ultra vs S24 Ultra]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Comparing the camera lens bumps on the Samsung Galaxy S23 Ultra vs S24 Ultra]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>