<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 01:51:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Does it matter that the Galaxy Z Fold 6 didn't get the One UI 7 beta? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title"> Beyond the Alphabet</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="74uXEL5FbSyzjPgHM9K6b7" name="lloyd-beyond-the-alphabet2.png" caption="" alt="Android Central's LLoyd with a projection with a Google logo" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/74uXEL5FbSyzjPgHM9K6b7.png" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text"><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/beyond-the-alphabet">Beyond the Alphabet</a> is a weekly column that focuses on the tech world both inside and out of the confines of Mountain View.</p></div></div>
<p>Oh the woes of living on the edge. Earlier this week, Samsung started rolling out the first One UI 7 beta. Naturally, it's first being made available to those that own one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24">Galaxy S24</a> flagship models (sorry, S24 FE.)</p><p>However, when the rumor mill picked up steam leading up to the official announcement, I was hoping to spend my weekend messing around with One UI 7 on the Galaxy Z Fold 6. The announcement came and went, and there was no mention of the Fold 6 being included in the beta program.</p><p>In fact, there wasn't any mention of Samsung's flagship foldable phones at all. Instead, they've just been roped in with the rest of the company's lineup, with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://news.samsung.com/global/samsung-one-ui-7-beta-starts-to-roll-out-in-select-markets">Samsung stating</a> "In line with Samsung’s commitment to extend its OS upgrade policy, the update will gradually roll out to other Galaxy devices."</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="y25BmS6tkpUTKKSGXq4LLD" name="one-ui-7-beta-features-galaxy-s24-ultra" alt="One UI 7 features on the Galaxy S24 Ultra" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/y25BmS6tkpUTKKSGXq4LLD.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Samsung)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I didn't <em>actually</em> expect the Galaxy Z Fold 6 to be included in the One UI 7 beta program. Especially considering how many times <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/dreary-one-ui-7-beta-forum-update">rumors</a> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/one-uis-next-release-is-delayed-and-samsung-wants-it-on-your-tvs-and-appliances">have</a> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-one-ui-7-beta-pushed-back-again">surfaced</a> about Samsung needing to delay the rollout. It's apparent that this isn't just your run-of-the-mill update, as more <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-galaxy-ai">Galaxy AI</a> features are on the way, along with the new "Now Bar" and improved camera controls.</p><p>Obviously, Samsung is going to prioritize its slab phones over foldables, but there's just something that leaves me feeling a bit disappointed.</p><p>We're heading into year 6 of the foldable phone experiment, with Samsung arguably providing the most useful and reliable software experience of them all. So why is it that the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Galaxy Z Fold 6</a> or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-6-review">Flip 6</a> aren't even mentioned in a footnote for being included or next in line?</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1131px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="hXWgyEfPvQgs4vgXNzLxwM" name="samsung-galaxy-z-fold-special-edition-promo-render.jpg" alt="Samsung Galaxy Z Fold Special Edition promo render" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hXWgyEfPvQgs4vgXNzLxwM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1131" height="636" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Samsung)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Yet again, it feels as if foldable phone enjoyers are being treated like second-class citizens who have a first-class budget. Samsung has made it abundantly clear that it is more than willing to ship out the same phone for three years in a row, raking in profits and then apologizing for "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/is-samsung-sorry-for-failing-to-innovate-or-just-sorry-sales-are-down">failing to innovate</a>." Only to release a phone with the changes we've been wanting, but limit it to just one specific region.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">Foldable phones</a> are a niche product category, I get it. And I know that within that niche, there's an even smaller group that would entertain the idea of installing beta software. But here's my counterargument — if I already know that I'm part of an experiment, what makes you think that I wouldn't want to be included in another one?</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4480px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="MLCKfeSHeDZWCUwT9QjhHA" name="Android-16-Pixel9PF" alt="The logo for Android 16 on a Pixel 9 Pro Fold." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MLCKfeSHeDZWCUwT9QjhHA.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4480" height="2520" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Brady Snyder / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It's been more than two years since I wrote about my experiences living in the "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/beta-apps-anonymous">beta lifestyle</a>," but nothing's changed. Well, I take that back. The devices and some of the apps have changed, but everything else I expressed in that article still rings true.</p><p>Some of it definitely has to do with FOMO, as there are some intriguing additions coming to One UI 7. However, there's also a sneaking suspicion that this might be a sign of things to come. Not that Samsung is going to ditch its foldable phones, but that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/delayed-one-ui-7-update-has-me-worried">we might be heading for a rough patch</a> with One UI software updates.</p><p>We've had the stable version of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-review">Android 15</a> since mid-October, yet here we are almost two months later, and there's no clear timeline for when it will come to the Fold. And if Samsung is having this much of an issue already, what does that say for older models like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/i-spent-a-week-with-the-z-fold-5-coming-home">Galaxy Z Fold 5</a> or even the Galaxy S23 Ultra?</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="R58kspU9haSWsVA2tVErqh" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-camera-lenses-01.jpg" alt="Hands-on with the smaller Samsung Galaxy S24" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/R58kspU9haSWsVA2tVErqh.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I was going to just bypass the money argument until I realized that the $850 Galaxy S24 gets a taste before the $1,800 Z Fold 6. Yes, I know that I answered the reason as to why this is the case already, but my point still stands.</p><p>It's not like we're talking about a company with limited budgets and resources that might issue one or two updates, six months after the release. This is Samsung. You know, the company that generated almost $60 BILLION in revenue in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-confirms-galaxy-s25-teases-cheaper-foldable-xr-device-2025">Q3 2024</a>. In my mind, there's really no excuse for any of its flagship phones to be left behind, even if they aren't as popular or selling as well.</p><p>Hell, Google not only included the Pixel 9 Pro Fold in its first <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16-developer-preview-1-is-here-with-new-features-and-a-snappier-release-timeline">Android 16 Developer Preview</a> release, but it's also available for the original Pixel Fold. Sure, some features are bound to be missing, but that's to be expected given that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/i-hope-google-doesnt-limit-assistant-with-bard">Google fumbled the release</a> anyway.</p><p>The point is that if Google can do it, why can't Samsung? If it wanted to, Samsung could, and for reasons that are below my pay grade to know, chose not to.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/does-it-matter-that-the-galaxy-z-fold-6-didnt-get-the-one-ui-7-beta</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Now that Samsung has released the first One UI 7 beta, I can't but feel left out since the Galaxy Z Fold 6 wasn't included. But, I'm also worried about what that means for the future.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">NQ3vaBSmFqZXBmjESBLbEA</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FJh5pfxdvc8kEW5xXCnzXf.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 20:15:24 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ andrew.myrick@futurenet.com (Andrew Myrick) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FJh5pfxdvc8kEW5xXCnzXf.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 on cobblestone road]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 on cobblestone road]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Tipster claims we won't see the Xiaomi 15 Ultra anytime soon ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Rumors from Weibo claim Xiaomi has "postponed" the launch of its planned 15 Ultra.</li><li>The tipster doesn't suggest a reason why; however, the post notes a recent listing that shows it will feature 90W fast charging and satellite call/text capabilities.</li><li>The Xiaomi 15 was spotted at the FCC recently, signaling its upcoming global launch, but the alleged Ultra delay could effect it.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>There's an Ultra-level device set to grace Xiaomi's latest series; however, a new rumor claims it's a bit further away than previously anticipated.</p><p>According to Weibo leaker <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://weibo.com/6048569942/P3vA3qgZg?pagetype=profilefeed">Digital Chat Station</a> (DCS), Xiaomi has supposedly "postponed" the launch of the 15 Ultra (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidheadlines.com/2024/12/xiaomi-15-ultra-wont-launch-as-soon-as-expected.html">Android Headlines</a>). Despite the curiosity about this (alleged) delay, the tipster did not suggest <em>when </em>consumers could see the device launching.</p><p>In a subsequent post, DCS <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://weibo.com/6048569942/P3pSzsxus">spotted a website certification</a> listing for the Xiaomi 15 Ultra.</p><p>The listing shows the phone will debut with 90W fast charging, which is likely the strength of its wired method. The publication adds that the device may arrive with a battery within the ~5,400mAh to ~5,800mAh range and with the potential for 50W wireless charging. The listing DCS discovered included connectivity support, which leans on satellite capabilities.</p><p>The listing shows the phone will support satellite communications via calls and texts.</p><p>The certification didn't point to any sort of launch, meaning we'll have to play things by ear as 2025 rolls in.</p><p>Xiaomi's 15 and 15 Pro <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/xiaomi-15-and-15-pro-with-snapdragon-8-elite-soc-announced-in-china">debuted in China</a> late in October with Qualcomm's Snapdragon 8 Elite. The devices feature a flat design with rounded corners for an easy handheld experience. The Pro delivers a 6.73-inch LTPO AMOLED 120Hz display and a large 6,100mAh battery. This phone also borrows the same camera from the Xiaomi 14 Ultra: a Sony IMX858 telephoto lens with 5x zoom.</p><p>Speaking of the 14 Ultra, the current 15 Ultra battery rumors claim that a ~400mAh or ~800mAh upgrade is in the cards for its previous 5,000mAh.</p><p>In other news, discussions have been heating up about the Xiaomi 15 series ever since it was <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/xiaomi-15-preps-global-debut-8-elite-fcc-listing">spotted at the FCC</a>. The listing showcased Xiaomi's intent to provide the global phone with HyperOS 2.0 and two RAM/storage configs: 12/256GB, and 12/512GB. It seems likely that the base 15 will debut without the 15 Pro, which would stick to Xiaomi's previous behavior.</p><p>Moreover, the publication wonders if the rumored delay of the 15 Ultra will effect the base model's global appearance. If so, speculation states we could see the phones in February, but there's nothing set just yet. However, a February launch isn't that crazy as Xiaomi <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/xiaomi-14-launch-and-14-ultra">did just that earlier this year</a>.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/xiaomi-15-ultra-alleged-delay-and-certification</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Xiaomi's 15 Ultra allegedly receives some bad news about its launch. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">qEdzwBik3ujaYfssJgGSfP</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qP9rBWmw2LTxfL4GTVUT9B.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 20:13:13 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qP9rBWmw2LTxfL4GTVUT9B.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Xiaomi]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Xiaomi 15 colors]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Xiaomi 15 colors]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ 'Help me create' in Google Home is live for some in Public Preview ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google has started rolling out its "help me create" Gemini feature in the Home app through its Public Preview.</li><li>The experimental feature lets users quickly make an automation for lights, security, and more through the AI model, Gemini.</li><li>Google states this is appearing "gradually" for enrolled Public Preview testers.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google highlighted an upcoming smart home addition in November and that's finally arriving for (a few) enrolled testers.</p><p>According to a new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/googlenest/answer/15684131#zippy=">support page</a>, Google has started rolling out its new automation creation feature for Home in Public Preview. Per the explainer, AI is at the core of this feature as Google states Gemini enters to bring a "help me create" prompt. Essentially, users can control their smart home devices and automation with ease and the potential for more customization.</p><p>Since it's rolling out, enrolled testers can open the Google Home app and find the  Automation button (with a starry icon), tap "Add" and, finally, "help me create." Google states users can get going by using their voice or by writing to the AI in English. However, the company states that you will find Gemini's suggestions for what to automate.</p><p>You can select one of these if you prefer and find the option to edit them to better fit your needs.</p><p>Users can then tap "create" and wait a few moments while the AI does its thing. After, there will be an option to "rate" or save the automation, as well as an "Ask again" button.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:954px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:55.97%;"><img id="nnhyxeVGMUZKwzpqxEkmbc" name="google-home-help-me-create-public-preview" alt="Google Home's "help me create" enters the Public Preview." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nnhyxeVGMUZKwzpqxEkmbc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="954" height="534" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Similar to doing it manually, the post highlights the necessity for three components in "help me create." Those include "Starters," which lets users tell the app/AI "when to begin" alongside "Conditions" for "optional restrictions" when it begins. Then, you have the "Action," which is what <em>should </em>be done.</p><p>Additionally, Google is still working on expanding its device support. There's another page that details which starters, conditions, and actions the prompt supports. Also, "help me create" is stated to only work with Nest cameras "setup or migrated to" the Google Home app.</p><p>This "help me create" feature is rolling out to "eligible users" who've enrolled in Google Home's Public Preview. It seems that only a few are seeing this today (Dec 6), which is also something the company notes. The post states that everyone won't see it simultaneously as it appears "gradually."</p><p>Google teased this <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-home-integrates-gemini-for-smarter-home-automation">new experimental feature</a> during its fall update in early November. The company highlighted a few of its uses, such as the ability for users to automate security, health/wellness, home convenience, and more. That early post said "help me create" would be available "later this year;" however, its arrival in the Public Preview will assist in ironing out any issues before that happens.</p><p>If you're interested in testing "help me create," the post states you can tap the Public Preview icon (it looks like a beaker) and tap the experimental AI features. After agreeing to the terms, the experiment should toggle "on" and the feature should appear shortly after.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/google-home-gemini-help-me-create-public-preview</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google detailed the slow arrival of its "help me create" Gemini-based option in the Home app. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">P4xDdy3eKhvC9gCy4ojtk6</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RhYdgjdYgJhyLt97hqUVtd.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 19:18:35 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Smart Home]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RhYdgjdYgJhyLt97hqUVtd.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Household routines]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Household routines]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google's December security patch for Pixels fixes audio and camera issues ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google detailed the rollout of its December 2024 security update for its Pixel lineup.</li><li>The patch includes even more Bluetooth fixes alongside fixes for display issues, audio problems, and camera woes.</li><li>This security update joins Google's busy week after dropping its major December feature drop for Pixels and Android.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google has started pushing its latest monthly security update to a host of eligible Pixel phones.</p><p>The company revealed the patch notes for its December 2024 security update via a Pixel <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/pixelphone/thread/311687155/google-pixel-update-december-2024?hl=en&sjid=9691303977801195328-NA">community post</a>. Google states the update is rolling out for devices ranging from the Pixel 6 series up to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-series-hands-on">the Pixel 9 series</a>. This patch includes the Pixel Tablet alongside the original Pixel Fold. Owners of any of these devices should soon find version <strong>AP4A.241205.013</strong> available to download.</p><p>Google says users should find a notification about the update's availability, but you can also check for it manually through your settings (system update).</p><p>The changelog begins by fixing some critical audio issues. The post says that the December update fixes "audio stability and performance" under certain situations for Pixel 7, Pixel 8, and Pixel 9 devices. Additionally, Google is solving an issue that would see some Pixel 6 phones restarting when using a USB audio device.</p><p>Several more Bluetooth issues are being fixed for the Pixel 9, which has become <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-pixel-9-verizon-owners-already-receive-november-2024-firmware">quite a trend</a> in recent history.</p><p>Camera improvements are hitting the Pixel 6 alongside some serious "green tint" issues for the old generation.</p><p>The remainder of the changelog is as follows:</p>
<ul><li>General improvements for system stability and performance in certain conditions (Pixel 6/7 series)</li><li>General improvements for network connection stability and performance in certain conditions (Pixel 7, 8, original Fold, and Pixel Tablet)</li><li>Fix to improve wireless (Wi-Fi) stability and performance in certain conditions (Pixel 7, 8, and 9)</li><li>Fix for issue occasionally causing the lockscreen wallpaper to fade out slowly in certain conditions</li><li>Fix for issue with dark mode settings stability in certain conditions</li><li>Fix for issue with delay in call notifications appearing in certain conditions</li><li>Fix for issue with layouts and animations during transitions in certain conditions</li><li>Fix for issue with repeating color selection in Wallpapers & Styles in certain conditions</li><li>Fix for issue with Wallpaper & Style app crashing in certain conditions</li><li>Fix to improve swipe actions in certain condition</li><li>Fix for issue with notification background colors in certain conditions</li></ul>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="RncLB3ktV7LrgvsbN9x5AK" name="google-pixel-9-pro-pixel-9-pro-xl-camera-1.jpg" alt="Camera app on Google Pixel 9 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RncLB3ktV7LrgvsbN9x5AK.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google's December patch arrives shortly after the debut of its latest <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-december-2024-feature-drop-announced">feature drop for Pixels</a>. These updates will likely arrive close together when updating/installing on your phone. More specifically, the latest feature drop brings new goodies to Gemini on Pixel like a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini-spotify-extension-rollout-detailed">Spotify extension</a>, calling/texting capabilities for the AI, and "Saved info with Gemini."</p><p>The Pixel 9 series exclusively received new additions like a revamped Call Screen powered by Gemini Nano for screening calls. The Pixel Screenshots app also got upgraded with better organization and the option of using it in Google Wallet to save cards like your driver's license, boarding pass, and more.</p><p>Android in general received <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-spruces-up-android-with-6-new-features-improving-gemini-accessibility-and-sharing">a major update</a>, as well as the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/googles-december-feature-drop-for-pixel-watch-lets-you-peek-at-nest-cameras-from-your-wrist">Pixel Watch and Nest</a>.</p><p>Google's patch notes for its security update reiterated the decision to grant the Pixel 6, Pixel 7, and Pixel Fold <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-confirms-the-pixel-6-pixel-7-and-pixel-fold-will-get-two-extra-android-os-upgrades">two more years of OS updates</a>. This now makes it so the oldest of the three series is eligible for Android 16, which should arrive much earlier in 2025.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://shop-links.co/link?id=pcmcat1563302848653&publisher_slug=future&exclusive=1&u1=ac-us-1063526181025375017&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Ftop-deals%2Fcell-phone-deals%2Fpcmcat1563302848653.c%3Fid%3Dpcmcat1563302848653&article_name=Google%20gifts%20Pixels%20a%20December%20feature%20drop%20with%20Gemini%20and%20dual-screen%20updates&article_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.androidcentral.com%2Fphones%2Fgoogle-pixel-december-2024-feature-drop-announced" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1943169/565706/9383?subId1=ac-us-1132527717411006155&sharedId=ac-us&u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fcp%2Fcell-phones%2F1105910%3Fpovid%3Dweb_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://shop-links.co/link?publisher_slug=future&exclusive=1&u1=ac-us-9281715705408271408&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.samsung.com%2Fus%2Fshop%2Fall-deals%2Fcell-phone-deals%2F&article_name=Google%20gifts%20Pixels%20a%20December%20feature%20drop%20with%20Gemini%20and%20dual-screen%20updates&article_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.androidcentral.com%2Fphones%2Fgoogle-pixel-december-2024-feature-drop-announced" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://target.georiot.com/Proxy.ashx?tsid=169923&GR_URL=https%3A%2F%2Famazon.com%2Fs%3Fk%3Dcell%2Bphone%26crid%3D19CKV7OMEPEMF%26sprefix%3Dcell%2Bphone%252Caps%252C222%26ref%3Dnb_sb_noss_1%26tag%3Dhawk-future-20%26ascsubtag%3Dac-us-6521902921945227540-20" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-100048248-15733793?sid=ac-us-1332964338590993499&url=https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-100048248-15735111?sid=ac-us-3082407975971228681&url=https://www.att.com/" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="34c47a40-89e8-4817-9091-ea5eff757518">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:131.12%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8traMGgrwAvoqr8vUr6kdH.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL render"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 Pro XL</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>Arriving as the largest of the Pixel 9 slab phones, the 9 Pro XL is the new kid on the block for Google's 2024 flagship series. The phone offers an immersive, fluid 6.8-inch display and a large 5,060mAh battery to keep you scrolling and scrolling.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-december-2024-security-pixel-update</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google detailed its December 2024 security update for Pixels. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">aGj2pi7PcCzo9WApFKLefU</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/j8Xcuz9p4J2Q4W6CLi9tG8.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 18:10:03 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/j8Xcuz9p4J2Q4W6CLi9tG8.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Comparing the backs and sizes of the Obsidian Google Pixel 9 Pro with the Hazel Google Pixel 9 Pro XL]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Comparing the backs and sizes of the Obsidian Google Pixel 9 Pro with the Hazel Google Pixel 9 Pro XL]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ How to change Gemini's voice on Android ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Google's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini</a> assistant is gaining more and more functionality, and it's becoming a critical part of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a>. The AI-powered chatbot can replace your <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-assistant">Google Assistant</a>, have conversational chats with you in the form of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/gemini-live-is-available-for-free-on-android-phones">Gemini Live</a>, and even analyze your documents. However, if you're a fan of using Gemini's voice assistant functionality, you might be wondering how you can change its voice to match your preferences.</p><p>Luckily, you can do just that in the Gemini app, and we're going to show you how in this guide.</p>
<h2 id="everything-you-can-and-can-t-use-a-chosen-gemini-voice-for-2">Everything you can (and can't) use a chosen Gemini voice for</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3556px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="gbE7NDe2Rut6zCprCEjsVE" name="Google-Pixel-9-review-24.jpg" alt="Gemini Live UI on the Pixel 9" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gbE7NDe2Rut6zCprCEjsVE.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3556" height="2000" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>There's only one way to change how Gemini sounds, and that's via the Gemini app. However, this setting changes a lot more than just the voice used in the app. It will also change the voice used for Gemini Live, the Gemini assistant, and all apps that integrate with Gemini. For example, if you tap <strong>Listen</strong> beside a written Gemini response, it'll speak using the voice you select in the Gemini app.</p><p>There are 10 voice options available: Vega, Ursa, Pegasus, Nova, Eclipse, Lyra, Orbit, Dipper, Capella, and Orion. You can pick one of those voices if your first language in Android is a supported language. Supported languages for Gemini voices are the following:</p>
<ul><li>Arabic</li><li>Bengali</li><li>Danish</li><li>Dutch</li><li>English</li><li>French</li><li>German</li><li>Gujarati</li><li>Hindi</li><li>Hungarian</li><li>Indonesian</li><li>Italian</li><li>Japanese</li><li>Kannada</li><li>Latvian</li><li>Lithuanian</li><li>Malayalam</li><li>Marathi</li><li>Norwegian</li><li>Portuguese</li><li>Romanian</li><li>Slovenian</li><li>Spanish</li><li>Swahili</li><li>Swedish</li><li>Tamil</li><li>Telugu</li><li>Turkish</li><li>Ukrainian</li><li>Urdu</li><li>Vietnamese</li></ul>
<h2 id="how-to-change-a-voice-in-the-gemini-app-2">How to change a voice in the Gemini app</h2>
<p>It only takes a few taps to change the Gemini app's voice. You can listen to all the options before making your selection, and can always go back to change it later. Here's how to do it.</p>
<p>1. Open the <strong>Gemini app</strong> on your Android phone.</p><p>2. Tap your <strong>Profile picture</strong> or <strong>initial</strong> in the top right corner of the app.</p><p>3. Press <strong>Settings</strong>, then <strong>Gemini's voice</strong>.</p><p>4. Swipe left or right to <strong>hear a voice</strong>, and stop at the one you like.</p><p>5. Tap the <strong>Back</strong> button to select a voice.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4480px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="AVAuwfCvWRgovCtqMyRQgW" name="Gemini-Voice-Change" alt="The settings to change Gemini's voice in the Gemini app." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AVAuwfCvWRgovCtqMyRQgW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="4480" height="2520" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Future)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>After that, Gemini's voice will now match your selection across all of its apps and features.</p>
<h2 id="why-you-might-want-to-change-gemini-s-voice-2">Why you might want to change Gemini's voice</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="nTX5qhn3isE9xgKu9v44n3" name="google-pixel-9-pro-gemini-live-voices-02.jpg" alt="Using Gemini Live on the Google Pixel 9 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nTX5qhn3isE9xgKu9v44n3.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Now that Gemini is a significant part of Android, you may want to change its voice to match your own, or to simply find one you like the sound of. Voice assistants have had the ability to change voices for years, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-change-voice-google-assistant-your-phone">including the Google Assistant</a>. So, it's natural for you to want to change Gemini to match your preferences, too.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="ae291491-fc17-4be7-a408-9d0ed165ff15">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tnQGJNQVqF2XVQV4KfMbN8.jpg' alt="google pixel 9 square render"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The best phone for Gemini</strong></em></p><p>Google's AI helper is available on a ton of Android phones — and even iPhones — but it's best on the Pixel 9 series. You get Gemini Nano support, Gemini Live, and exclusive AI-powered features like Pixel Screenshots.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-change-geminis-voice-on-android</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ You can pick between an assortment of Gemini voices, which will apply in the app and throughout Android. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">ZxyXypsjKXWqQvyYraGFFm</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dtrMUYschswtaUbkDraqX3.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 16:46:33 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dtrMUYschswtaUbkDraqX3.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Using Gemini Live on the Google Pixel 9 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Using Gemini Live on the Google Pixel 9 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Woah! The Garmin Fenix 7 Pro never lost its Black Friday discount — get it before it's gone ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>There was no shortage of outstanding smartwatch deals this past Black Friday and Cyber Monday, but a few holiday discounts have decided to stick around a bit longer. Pick up the Garmin Fenix 7 Pro (Sapphire Solar Edition) from Amazon right now, for instance, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Garmin-Multisport-Smartwatch-Flashlight-Capability/dp/B0BYFC27W7"><strong>you&apos;ll score a record-smashing 28% off your purchase</strong></a>, the same exact discount that we saw during the big sale events last week. </p><p>With its built-in LED flashlight, 24/7 health and fitness tracking features, and up to 22 days of solar-powered battery life, the Fenix 7 Pro could easily rank among the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-garmin-smartwatch">best Garmin watches</a> if it wasn&apos;t for its steep price tag. Thanks to this leftover Cyber Monday deal, that may not be a problem any longer. </p>
<h2 id="this-premium-garmin-smartwatch-just-got-a-little-less-premium-2">This premium Garmin smartwatch just got a little less premium</h2>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="5574cd41-92c8-4508-834e-49c67d8d0263" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$899.99" data-dimension48="$899.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/Garmin-Multisport-Smartwatch-Flashlight-Capability/dp/B0BYFC27W7" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:967px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:88.52%;"><img id="voY6FBpVwNB4bARsXDbkrn" name="garmin-fenix-7-pro-solar-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/voY6FBpVwNB4bARsXDbkrn.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="967" height="856" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Garmin Fenix 7 Pro (Sapphire Solar) 47mm:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Garmin-Multisport-Smartwatch-Flashlight-Capability/dp/B0BYFC27W7" data-dimension112="5574cd41-92c8-4508-834e-49c67d8d0263" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$899.99" data-dimension48="$899.99"><del>$899.99</del> <strong>$649.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>As part of its <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/early-black-friday-garmin-deals-2024-ditch-your-old-smartwatch-and-save-big-on-forerunner-venu-and-more">leftover Cyber Monday Garmin sale</a>, Amazon is carving an epic 28% off the Garmin Fenix 7 Pro (Sapphire Solar Edition), knocking the price of the watch down to its lowest point ever. This GPS smartwatch harnesses the power of the sun to last up to 22 days in smartwatch mode, plus you get an ultra-durable titanium and reinforced polymer construction, built-in flashlight, and all of the health and fitness tracking features that made Garmin famous. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/Garmin-Multisport-Smartwatch-Flashlight-Capability/dp/B0BYFC27W7" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="5574cd41-92c8-4508-834e-49c67d8d0263" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$899.99" data-dimension48="$899.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>you want great battery life and GPS in a super-durable Garmin watch; you missed the Black Friday/Cyber Monday sales but still want to score some great savings. </p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>you can afford the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-fenix-8-review">Garmin Fenix 8</a>; you prefer a slimmer design in your wearables; you need a smartwatch with an AMOLED display.<strong> </strong></p><p>The Garmin Fenix 7 Pro remains a great choice if the recently released Fenix 8 is a bit too rich for your blood. Currently a whopping $450 cheaper than its newer sibling, the last-gen Fenix 7 Pro boasts almost all the same mapping, training guidance, and sports modes, plus you get the built-in flashlight, solar-powered battery, and a spacious MIP display. </p><p>Sure, if you have a little more cash to spend, consider upgrading to the Fenix 8 or maybe grab the Garmin Epix Pro (Gen 2) while it&apos;s on sale (<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Garmin-Multisport-Smartwatch-Flashlight-Capability/dp/B0BYFC27W7"><strong>also 32% off at Amazon</strong></a>). But if you value durability, advanced training features, and battery life in a rugged package, then this smartwatch deal is for you. </p>


 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/woah-the-garmin-fenix-7-pro-never-lost-its-black-friday-discount-get-it-before-its-gone</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Days after Cyber Monday, Amazon is continuing the holiday deals by carving 28% off the Garmin Fenix 7 Pro (Sapphire Solar edition). ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">9jQTN7mjGRKJSfJQna4iK5</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3JaJNrCD4y93QkLj4zooa4.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 23:04:17 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3JaJNrCD4y93QkLj4zooa4.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Garmin]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Garmin Fenix 7 Pro smartwatch on wrist with hand in coat pocket]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Garmin Fenix 7 Pro smartwatch on wrist with hand in coat pocket]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Apple dethroned Garmin on Strava in 2024; there are two main reasons why ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Strava's Year in Sport 2024 report was published on Wednesday, showing users' fitness trends worldwide.</li><li>The report shows trends for 135 million active Strava users, including a rise in group activities.</li><li>The "Apple Watch Series" and "Apple Watch SE" were the two top tracking devices for runs, with the Garmin Forerunner 245 in third place.</li><li>Two Garmin Edge bike computers topped the list for tracked Ride activities.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Strava is one of the most popular social fitness apps in the world, and its annual Year in Sport trends provide some interesting insight into the trends of hundreds of millions of athletes worldwide. So it was fascinating to see that Apple had dethroned Garmin as the most popular running watch on the platform.</p><p>According to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://press.strava.com/articles/strava-releases-annual-year-in-sport-trend">2024 report</a>, the Apple Watch Series and Apple Watch SE were the number one and two gear for all runners, followed by the Garmin Forerunner 245. Last year, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-watch-from-2015-most-popular-on-strava">8-year-old Garmin Forerunner 235 was the most popular</a> worldwide for runners, while the Forerunner 245 was the most-used watch in the U.S.</p><p>This year's report solely showed global data, but Apple Watches are very popular in the U.S., so they likely would have won regardless. Garmin still dominated with its acclaimed Edge 530 and 830 bike computers, with the Wahoo Elemnt Bolt V1 — the top 2023 bike computer in the U.S. — coming in third.</p><p>Outside of gear, the report showed a major increase in running clubs and group runs of 10+, with women in particular joining Strava clubs 89% more in 2024 than in 2023.</p><p>The Strava Year in Sport 2024 report showed that runners' median activity pace was 10:15 per mile; the 2023 report showed lower median numbers for most generations aside from Boomers, so either people slowed down globally in 2024 or older runners skewed the median.</p><p>For other activities, the median pace or speed was 12.1mph for cyclists, 19:40 min/mile for walkers, and 22:06 min/mile for hikers. Now we know what pace to beat to be "better than average."</p><p>Interestingly, Strava says that 72% of uploaded activities come from the mobile app. While <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-smartwatches-fitness">fitness watches</a> are the overwhelming favorite for marathoners and half marathoners, one in four 5K runners use their phones, perhaps using an external HRM like the Polar H10 or else ignoring heart rate and other wrist-based data entirely.</p>
<h2 id="why-apple-suddenly-beat-garmin-for-runners-worldwide-2">Why Apple suddenly beat Garmin for runners worldwide</h2>
<p>As someone who covers running watches extensively, I believe there are a few reasons why Apple suddenly dominated the Strava gear category for runners.</p><p>The first is about simple categorization and raw sales: Apple consistently sells about 20% of all wearables worldwide (per <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.idc.com/promo/wearablevendor">IDC</a>), and all Apple "Series" watches like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/apple-watch-series-9-long-term-review">Series 9</a> or Series X are categorized as the same "Apple Watch" on Strava, which lets years of different Apple Watch generations tag-team to take the top slot. The same goes for the two generations of Apple SEs.</p><p>(As much as I <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/i-never-expected-to-love-apple-watch-ultra-2-so-much">loved the Apple Watch Ultra 2</a> for its accuracy and ultra-bright, massive squircle display, I don't think it's counted in the same category.)</p><p>Garmin watches all log activities as their own distinct devices, and we've seen five new Garmin Forerunner watches in the last couple of years. Forerunners have excellent longevity — hence why the 2015 Forerunner 235 and 2019 Forerunner 245 kept their Strava crowns for so long — but I suspect many of these loyal Garmin fans gave in and upgraded to the Forerunner 165, 255, 265, 955, or 965 in recent years — or tried <em>other</em> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-garmin-smartwatch">Garmin watch</a> brands like the popular <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-fenix-8-review">Fenix 8</a>.</p><p>So it's likely that Garmin's share of Strava runners hasn't faded below Apple, but rather that the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-forerunner-265-review">Forerunner 265</a>'s training load tools or the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-forerunner-165-review">Forerunner 165</a>'s budget-priced perks tempted 235 and 245 users to swap, and each watch is claiming a distinct portion of the Strava user base.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="rJ8f5hRPohAu9FkXt6RHaT" name="Apple-Watch-Ultra-2-activity.jpeg" alt="A hiking activity on the Apple Watch Ultra 2" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rJ8f5hRPohAu9FkXt6RHaT.jpeg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Still, Apple has to receive at least some credit for this newfound Strava dominance, because it has seriously emphasized improving its running software over the last few generations.</p><p>It started with watchOS 9 in 2022, when Apple let runners see heart rate zones, running power, cadence, or elevation during a workout; race their past route times; and receive accurate track data using an Apple Maps database of public tracks. Garmin already had all this and more, but Apple closed the gap.</p><p>Most recently with watchOS 11, Apple added 7-day and 28-day <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-training-load-focus-needs-one-obvious-fix">training load</a> insights in graph form, showing if you're overtraining or slacking off compared to your past efforts, so you get fitter without straining too hard and hurting yourself. You can't see specific training load numbers or aerobic/anaerobic breakdowns like Garmin offers, but it's a streamlined metric for new-ish runners.</p><p>Even if "serious runners" tend to use Garmin watches with better battery life, Apple is cornering the market on casual couch-to-5K runners trying to get fit and lose weight. Strava itself said in the press release that "5k runners tended to opt for an Apple Watch, while the Garmin Forerunner was more popular for longer distances."</p><p>Basically, Apple is democratizing running insights, making them available for people who aren't sure if they're ready to commit to a specialized fitness watch. So even though I use Garmin watches most frequently, I think Apple swooping in to claim the top Strava crown is an awesome development, because it means more types of people are falling in love with running (or at least fighting through the anguish to get fit).</p><p>The same likely applies to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-3-review">Pixel Watch 3</a> owners now that Fitbit <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/pixel-watch-3-great-running-features-overshadowed-by-fitbit-watches-demise">makes running more of a priority</a> — even if they have much smaller Strava numbers than Apple Watch owners.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="c0f97492-6dca-405c-b351-bbf49bcc26a5">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kes35gCrRe7qtT24rDFeoP.jpg' alt="Render of the Garmin Forerunner 165 showing a daily suggested workout at Tempo pace."></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Garmin Forerunner 165</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Strava-ready</strong></em></p><p>The Garmin Forerunner 165 is one of the best budget-priced fitness watches on the market for anyone trying to get more serious about running, with daily suggested workouts designed to improve your VO2 Max, accurate multi-satellite tracking, and 11-day battery life.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/apple-dethroned-garmin-on-strava-in-2024-heres-why</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The old Garmin Forerunner 235 and 245 topped Strava's charts last year, but Apple has swooped in thanks to its renewed focus on running, among other reasons. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">8v8DXMw4jRvFH5gLJMPoXd</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ikzBFsdFCJgjTtP7VBhkAn.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 22:43:06 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ikzBFsdFCJgjTtP7VBhkAn.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Garmin Fenix 8 and Apple Watch Ultra 2, both showing Run activity start screens.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Garmin Fenix 8 and Apple Watch Ultra 2, both showing Run activity start screens.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Ending soon! Get Samsung's latest tablets for as little as $149.99 during Cyber Week ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>While other retailers have put their Cyber Monday sales out to pasture, Samsung has decided to extend some of its best Android tablet deals to the end of the week. Head to the official site now and you can <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/tablets/galaxy-tab-s10/buy/galaxy-tab-s10-plus-256gb-moonstone-gray-wi-fi-sm-x820nzaaxar/"><strong>score up to $850 off the Galaxy Tab S10 Plus or $1,000 off the Galaxy Tab S10 Ultra</strong></a> when you trade in an eligible device. Skip the trade-in process altogether and you&apos;ll still receive up to $200 off, plus $50 of free Samsung credit, no strings attached. Considering that the Tab S10 series just dropped in early October, those are some pretty exceptional savings!</p>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/"><em><strong>Samsung's Cyber Week ends Sunday! See the full list of deals</strong></em></a></li></ul>
<p>Of course, if you don&apos;t necessarily need the latest <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-tablets">Android tablets</a>, you can still enjoy some major savings by opting for 2023&apos;s still-great Tab S9 series. Keep reading for a few of my favorite tablet deals from Samsung&apos;s Cyber Week, and don&apos;t forget that the sale is set to end Sunday night!</p>
<h2 id="these-top-rated-tablets-are-crashing-into-budget-device-territory-2">These top-rated tablets are crashing into budget device territory</h2>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="e14a5ef1-1718-4f64-a22d-31c5d19c3c98" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,199.99" data-dimension48="$1,199.99" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/tablets/galaxy-tab-s10/buy/galaxy-tab-s10-ultra-256gb-moonstone-gray-wi-fi-sm-x920nzaaxar/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="t8wKQMCesCZuSHwNvkMf4" name="samsung-galaxy-s10-ultra-square-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/t8wKQMCesCZuSHwNvkMf4.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="800" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy Tab S10 Ultra 256GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/tablets/galaxy-tab-s10/buy/galaxy-tab-s10-ultra-256gb-moonstone-gray-wi-fi-sm-x920nzaaxar/" data-dimension112="e14a5ef1-1718-4f64-a22d-31c5d19c3c98" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,199.99" data-dimension48="$1,199.99"><del>$1,199.99</del><strong> $999.99 | From $199.99 with trade-in at Samsung</strong></a></p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/samsung-galaxy-tab-s10-ultra-hands-on">Galaxy Tab S10 Ultra</a> is a ridiculously powerful Android tablet with a massive 14.6-inch AMOLED display, included S Pen stylus, and a ton of useful Galaxy AI features. As part of its epic Cyber Week sale, Samsung is carving a straight $200 off the price of the Ultra, plus you'll be eligible to receive up to $800 off when you trade in. Skip the trade-in process altogether and you'll get a $50 credit. </p>
<p>👀<strong>Alternate deals to consider: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-tab-s10-ultra-14-6-256gb-wi-fi-with-s-pen-moonstone-gray/6593204.p"><strong>Best Buy - $999.99</strong></a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/tablets/galaxy-tab-s10/buy/galaxy-tab-s10-ultra-256gb-moonstone-gray-wi-fi-sm-x920nzaaxar/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="e14a5ef1-1718-4f64-a22d-31c5d19c3c98" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,199.99" data-dimension48="$1,199.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="2cc60d24-7c46-4be0-b627-c92ad1a7e01a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$999.99" data-dimension48="$999.99" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/tablets/galaxy-tab-s10/buy/galaxy-tab-s10-plus-256gb-moonstone-gray-wi-fi-sm-x820nzaaxar/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1277px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:65.54%;"><img id="ZnyMaWLT87rgbCcmuteb6Q" name="samsung-galaxy-tab-s10-plus-product-image.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZnyMaWLT87rgbCcmuteb6Q.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1277" height="837" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy Tab S10 Plus 256GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/tablets/galaxy-tab-s10/buy/galaxy-tab-s10-plus-256gb-moonstone-gray-wi-fi-sm-x820nzaaxar/" data-dimension112="2cc60d24-7c46-4be0-b627-c92ad1a7e01a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$999.99" data-dimension48="$999.99"><del>$999.99</del><strong> $849.99 | From $149.99 with trade-in at Samsung</strong></a></p>
<p>Aside from its smaller 12.4-inch frame, the Galaxy Tab S10 Plus shares a lot of great qualities with its Ultra big sibling, from the included S Pen stylus to the Galaxy AI integration. Pick up this balanced tablet from Samsung during Cyber Week and you'll enjoy a straight $150 discount plus up to $700 when you trade in an old laptop, smartphone, or tablet. </p>
<p><strong>👀Alternate deals to consider: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Android-Durability-Included-Moonstone/dp/B0D84MHZX5"><strong>Amazon - $849.99</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-tab-s10-12-4-256gb-wi-fi-with-s-pen-moonstone-gray/6593196.p"><strong>Best Buy - $849.99</strong></a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/tablets/galaxy-tab-s10/buy/galaxy-tab-s10-plus-256gb-moonstone-gray-wi-fi-sm-x820nzaaxar/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="2cc60d24-7c46-4be0-b627-c92ad1a7e01a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$999.99" data-dimension48="$999.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<h2 id="or-save-even-more-with-a-last-gen-tablet-2">OR save even more with a last-gen tablet</h2>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="4191c8ce-6ca3-436f-970b-1b91164a6094" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799.99" data-dimension48="$799.99" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/tablets/galaxy-tab-s9/buy/galaxy-tab-s9-128gb-graphite-wi-fi-sm-x710nzaaxar/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1024px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="xsup9UhEkSzG3ixPgqsWGL" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Tab-S9-Render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xsup9UhEkSzG3ixPgqsWGL.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1024" height="1024" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy Tab S9 128GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/tablets/galaxy-tab-s9/buy/galaxy-tab-s9-128gb-graphite-wi-fi-sm-x710nzaaxar/" data-dimension112="4191c8ce-6ca3-436f-970b-1b91164a6094" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799.99" data-dimension48="$799.99"><del>$799.99</del><strong> $599.99 | From $99.99 with trade-in at Samsung</strong></a></p>
<p>Despite its last-gen status, the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/samsung-galaxy-tab-s9">Galaxy Tab S9</a> continues to impress with its 11-inch AMOLED display, Snapdragon processor, and IP68 waterproofing. If you'd rather not spend more on a Tab S10 series device, go for the base model S9 during Cyber Week and get $200 off alongside $500 of potential trade-in credit. </p>
<p>👀<strong>Alternate deals to consider: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Android-Snapdragon-Processor-Graphite/dp/B0C4BC6R95"><strong>Amazon - $598.40</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-tab-s9-11-128gb-wi-fi-with-s-pen-graphite/6546661.p"><strong>Best Buy - $599.99</strong></a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/tablets/galaxy-tab-s9/buy/galaxy-tab-s9-128gb-graphite-wi-fi-sm-x710nzaaxar/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="4191c8ce-6ca3-436f-970b-1b91164a6094" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799.99" data-dimension48="$799.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>These offers are impressive, but they only represent a small fraction of all the great Samsung deals currently available after Black Friday/Cyber Monday weekend. To see more, check out our guide to all the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/samsung-black-friday-2024-deals">best Samsung holiday deals</a> for record-smashing discounts on smartphones, tablets, wearables, and more. </p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/ending-soon-get-samsungs-latest-tablets-for-as-little-as-usd149-99-during-cyber-week</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung has extended its Cyber Monday sales through the end of the week, including these outstanding offers on the Tab S10 series.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">jKALHkQ5ZQ3tzycnkB9m2e</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/cAUyEgk2eVmsYftj7McfkY.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 21:33:05 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/cAUyEgk2eVmsYftj7McfkY.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Tab S10 Ultra using Generative Edit]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Tab S10 Ultra using Generative Edit]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung tipped to have smart glasses up its sleeve at Unpacked 2025 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung might finally glimpse the long-rumored smart glasses at the Galaxy S25 series launch.</li><li>It will likely be a sneak peek of the company’s first AR glasses in mid-January.</li><li>The smart glasses will reportedly be based on Samsung’s Extended Reality (XR) platform.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Samsung might be prepping for its Galaxy S25 series launch, which is anticipated to happen in January 2025. While the trio of handsets are expected, a new report reveals that the company might have a smart glasses launch up its sleeve next month.</p><p>According to the Korean news outlet <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.yna.co.kr/view/AKR20241202129000017">Yonhapnews</a>, spotted by tipster Jukanlosreve on X, has indicated that Samsung might be showcasing a sneak peek of its first augmented reality (AR) glasses at the upcoming <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25">Galaxy S25</a> series Unpacked Event. It could be some sort of short video or an image reveal — likely a similar approach from the company where it showcased the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-ring-review">Galaxy Ring</a> for the first time during its 2024 Unpacked Event.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Just in: Samsung is set to unveil a prototype of its augmented reality (AR) glasses, currently in development, during the Galaxy S25 Unpacked event early next year, likely in the form of videos or images.Additionally, prior to revealing the prototype, Samsung plans to introduce…<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1863739719248646330">December 3, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>The upcoming smart glasses will likely rival the Meta’s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/ray-ban-meta-smart-glasses-review">Ray-Ban</a> glasses. They will be built on Samsung’s Extended Reality (XR) platform, which is also tipped to be demoed at the upcoming Unpacked event. The Korean outlet further shares that the smart glasses will likely weigh 50 grams, coupled with the ability to make payments with the help of AI, gesture, and face recognition features.</p><p>While we might see a glimpse of the first smart glasses at the Unpacked event, which may include a prototype, the product is expected to be released sometime in the third quarter of 2025, notes the Korean publication. It is still unclear whether the alleged smart glasses are the ones that were rumored to be co-developed by Google and Qualcomm.</p>
<p>It’s also been a while since we heard about Samsung's smart glasses, which were <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/samsung-glasses-trademark-approval-spotted">trademarked</a> at the Intellectual Property Office in the U.K. last year. The product was then trademarked under the “Virtual reality headsets; Augmented reality headsets; Headphones; Smartphones; Smart glasses” categories.</p><p>Meanwhile, an alleged prototype was spotted before the launch of Apple Vision Pro. It included micro OLED displays powered by the Exynos 2200 chip and other highlighting features like eye-tracking cameras. However, it was soon <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/leaked-samsung-xr-prototype-used-exynos-chip">scrapped</a> after the Vision Pro’s launch.</p><p>Regardless, it is still encouraging to see Samsung still working on its version of smart glasses, which will likely be witnessed first at the Unpacked Event in 2025, which otherwise headlines the much-awaited Galaxy S25 series.</p>
<ul><li><strong>VR headset deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/searchpage.jsp?st=vr+headset"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=vr+headset"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.newegg.com/Virtual-Reality-Headsets/EventSaleStore/ID-2140595"><u><strong>Newegg</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.meta.com/"><u><strong>Meta</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/virtual-reality/5454301"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/samsung-smart-glasses-unpacked-2025-glimpse-tipped</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung is gearing up for the Galaxy S25 series in mid-January next year, and a report suggests we could also see a glimpse of smart glasses. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">4NvqpviE8B7TNbvXUpkMTB</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bkLLaajbrtPenKTVS2xTpB.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 19:57:47 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bkLLaajbrtPenKTVS2xTpB.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Chromebook Plus hands-on]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Chromebook Plus hands-on]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ OnePlus Watch 3 FCC listing teases a bigger battery and launch ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A report notes the OnePlus Watch 3 has appeared in the FCC database for its certification.</li><li>The highlights include a larger 631mAh battery over its predecessor and a slightly thinner frame.</li><li>The OnePlus Watch 3 was previously rumored to arrive "soon" in a global launch alongside the OEM's two smartphones.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>More information is bubbling up about the next OnePlus smartwatch, but this time it's spotted within a government database.</p><p>As highlighted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.91mobiles.com/hub/possible-oneplus-watch-3-fcc-launch/">91Mobiles</a>, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.91mobiles.com/id/hub/spesifikasi-oneplus-watch-3-mengemuka-di-fcc-ukuran-sama-tapi-baterai-lebih-besar/">Indonesian version</a> of the website discovered the OnePlus Watch 3 passing through the FCC database for certification. It seems that the watch possesses model number OPWWE251. The publication dove into the available specs, which state the device will feature a 631mAh battery.</p><p>What's more, the database listing provided by OnePlus says the watch will have the following measurements: 46.6 X 47.6 X 11.75mm.</p><p>A standout in this listing, as noted by the publication, is a potential indication of an imminent launch. The English post spotted OnePlus' EUT information, which states the product it's describing is a "production unit," not a prototype.</p><p>With that, speculation suggests the Chinese OEM is closer to the launch of the Watch 3, which echoes what we've heard previously from tipsters.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="BVf9SbxtVNxgz8HPpSKbfQ" name="oneplus-watch-2-14.jpg" alt="OnePlus Watch 2 custom watch face" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BVf9SbxtVNxgz8HPpSKbfQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>More concrete specs about the Watch 3 weren't spotted; however, the listing details its Bluetooth and several Wi-Fi frequency capabilities. The device is also expected to debut with GNSS and NFC support.</p><p>The OnePlus FCC files indicate its Watch 3 could feature some notable changes over <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oneplus-watch-2-review">its predecessor</a>. For one, the Watch 2 offers a 500mAh battery with a 7.5W VOOC charger. The listing suggests a 131mAh upgrade, meaning users should get a little more life out of the device before resting it. Additionally, its measurements seemingly purport a slightly thinner watch. The rest of its body should remain roughly the same size, but we'll need its launch to know for sure.</p><p>We're unsure about its charging strength, but there was a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/new-oneplus-watch-certification-specs-rendering">previous listing</a> that claimed it might see 10W.</p><p>With the FCC listing suggesting a close launch, it <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oneplus-watch-3-upcoming-global-launch-rumors">echoes rumors from late November</a> that claimed OnePlus could drop the Watch 3 globally with its smartphones "soon." There's a chance we could see these devices appear in January, but it's anyone's guess right now.</p><p>For now, we'll have to wait. There are quite a few areas we hope the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oneplus-watch-3-wishlist">OnePlus Watch 3 can fix</a> that its predecessor fell short on, though.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oneplus-watch-3-fcc-listing-teaser-spotted</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The OnePlus Watch 3 was spotted moving through the FCC. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">mYGj9Udpmu2hLctMxQXfn6</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/G9upm3KjtA3Paovjc4kX3m.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 19:50:29 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/G9upm3KjtA3Paovjc4kX3m.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus Watch 2 watch face ]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus Watch 2 watch face ]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>