<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 21:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Wear OS 5.1 preview is now available — and it's based on Android 15 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The next version of Wear OS, called Wear OS 5.1, is now available for testing as a developer preview.</li><li>The Android 15-based software update can be manually tested within the Android Studio emulator in a virtual Wear OS device.</li><li>Although it's still early, new features include the ability to play audio out of smartwatch speakers and access the new Credential Manager API.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google is giving us our first look at the next Wear OS update, which is based on Android 15. The company <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://developer.android.com/training/wearables/versions/5-1" target="_blank">released</a> the first developer preview of Wear OS 5.1 last week, and it's now available for testing in an Android Studio virtual device. Although it's still early, Google already revealed two key Wear OS 5.1 features: watch speaker audio playback and a credential manager.</p><p>The build number for the initial Wear OS 5.1 preview release is <strong>AP4A.241205.004.F1</strong>, and there are a few known issues. Google recommends developers start testing their Wear OS apps with the latest version to adjust to behavior changes in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a>. Notably, some Android 15 behavior changes won't be arriving on Wear OS 5.1, like Private Spaces and predictive back animations. The known bugs are as follows:</p>
<ul><li>The emulator doesn't always allow the user to add an account during the setup flow following a device reset.</li><li>When tapping on a notification, the app that sent the notification doesn't open until the user scrolls the screen.</li><li>Wear Health Services sometimes fails to start an exercise.</li></ul>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Confirmed: Wear OS 5.1 is the next version of Wear OS, and it's based on Android 15 just as I previously reported. https://t.co/t0pgSRpCW6 pic.twitter.com/lXLkbyxti6<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1861064684826251701">November 25, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>The update currently includes two "notable features," as described by Google. The first is watch speaker playback, which will allow users to listen to audio sources through a smartwatch's inbuilt speaker. This could be a convenient way to listen to music or podcasts, albeit at low volume and subpar quality. To use your watch speaker as an audio output option, both the device's hardware and the specified app must support it in Wear OS 5.1.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="V4LxpJjZ88vsDoXPQrbNrg" name="Google-Pixel-Watch-3-water" alt="A close up of an info-packed watch face on the Google Pixel Watch 3, held above a pond" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/V4LxpJjZ88vsDoXPQrbNrg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The other notable feature is support for the Credential Manager API. This is already available on Android, and it <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/upgrading-to-a-new-phone-android-can-now-keep-your-apps-signed-in-after-restoring-from-a-backup">enables features like auto-sign-in after restoring from a backup</a>. On Wear OS 5.1, the new credential manager will handle passwords, passkeys, and Sign in with Google. It'll also allow this information to be synced across Wear OS 5.1 and Android 15 devices.</p><p>Depending on the release date of Wear OS 5.1, this update could signal the platform catching up with Android. Typically, Wear OS updates have been based on preceding Android versions. For example, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/wear-os-5">Wear OS 5</a> is based on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review">Android 14</a>. The naming of Wear OS 5.1 could indicate that Google is trying to sync up Wear OS and Android. Or, it could simply mean that this year's Wear OS update is a minor one and not worthy of a full numbered version. After all, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16">Android 16 Developer Preview 1</a> is here, so it's not that surprising that we're seeing a new version of Wear OS made available for testing as well.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/the-wear-os-5-1-preview-is-now-available-and-its-based-on-android-15</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google released the Wear OS 5.1 preview for developers, and it's surprisingly Android 15-based. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Gj5kLz4qXcQPmfyxb7DVHn</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PqXZpoB9SLWbgwNXTMhvZh.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 20:59:17 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PqXZpoB9SLWbgwNXTMhvZh.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Wear OS 5 app drawer on the Google Pixel Watch 3]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Wear OS 5 app drawer on the Google Pixel Watch 3]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung's mid-range Galaxy A56 render leak showcases minimal design changes ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung's next higher mid-range phone to sport same design as the predecessor.</li><li>The Galaxy A56 will again sport three rear cameras, flat display, Key Island, and probably a new pink shade.</li><li>The Galaxy device is also tipped to sport 45W fast charging and with a Exynos 1580 chip underneath.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Samsung might be more than a couple of months away from launching the Galaxy A56 for the masses. However, that doesn’t stop leaks of renders showcasing the device in full.</p><p>OnLeaks and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidheadlines.com/samsung-galaxy-a56">Android Headlines</a> have shared the first high-quality renders of the Galaxy A56, the company’s one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-android-phones">mid-range smartphones</a> for 2025. It should be launched sometime in the first quarter of next year.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Good Morning #FutureSquad! Today comes your very first look at the #Samsung #GalaxyA56 (360° video + gorgeous 5K renders + dimensions)!😏On behalf of @Androidheadline 👉🏻 https://t.co/H4dwH89yZA pic.twitter.com/Dz1bJFAjjA<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1860977134342115647">November 25, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>The shared CAD-based renders again reveal a familiar design as its predecessor, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-launches-galaxy-a55-and-a35">Galaxy A55</a>, featuring flat edges and rounded corners. It will have a flat punch-hole display and three rear cameras stacked vertically on the back. A slight difference; however, is that the A55’s rear cameras were placed individually, whereas the placement on the Galaxy A56 appears to be stacked in a single camera module.</p><p>The publication also implies Samsung should be borrowing the “Key Island” design elements introduced in Galaxy A55 alongside the budget Galaxy A15 and Galaxy 25 phones from last year, where the power button and volume rockers are a bit raised on the right pane of the device to spot them easily.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="mcV2jNHxbtFnXLAQoe5aVj" name="samsung-galaxy-a56-renders-01" alt="Galaxy A56 renders" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mcV2jNHxbtFnXLAQoe5aVj.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OnLeaks/ Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="q3JSoHMdznWy3K3zDxRXVj" name="samsung-galaxy-a56-renders" alt="Galaxy A56 renders" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/q3JSoHMdznWy3K3zDxRXVj.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OnLeaks/ Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>While the expected specifications are still unclear, Android Headlines highlights that the device might feature 45W fast charging similar to the flagship Galaxy phones despite the Galaxy A56 being a mid-range phone. According to a recent Chinese certification, the device is also expected to be powered by the Exynos 1580 SoC, which was announced in October.</p><p>If the launch of the predecessor models is any indication, the Galaxy A56 should be released in March 2025 in markets starting with Europe and likely priced under €500.</p>
<p>On the other hand, Samsung’s other Galaxy A series device, dubbed Galaxy A26, was <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-a26-renders-surface-online-revealing-its-design">spotted in the renders</a>—also shared by OnLeaks last week—giving us a good look at the design and some of the expected specifications of the sub-$300 Galaxy phone.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u><strong><br></strong></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-a56-renders-leak</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The first CAD-based renders of the Galaxy A56 device leak right after us witnessing Galaxy A26 renders last week ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">3g7ksJ2JFe6D4BXneGfnEZ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ShKo6QTKmn4wH2H5URhTVj.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 20:27:20 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ShKo6QTKmn4wH2H5URhTVj.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[OnLeaks/ Android Headlines]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Galaxy A56 renders]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Galaxy A56 renders]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Ask Jerry: Why are there old photos in my Google Drive? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Welcome to Ask Jerry, where we talk about any and all the questions you might have about the smart things in your life. I'm Jerry, and I have spent the better part of my life working with tech. I have a background in engineering and R&D and have been covering Android and Google for the past 15 years.</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Ask Jerry</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="rbW6k4ZmBUAZL7mR2bMnV6" name="jerrydude-avatar.gif" caption="" alt="Android Avatar of Jerry" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rbW6k4ZmBUAZL7mR2bMnV6.gif" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Future)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">Ask Jerry is a column where we answer your burning Android/tech questions with the help of long-time Android Central editor Jerry Hildenbrand.</p></div></div>
<p>I'm also really good at researching data about everything — that's a big part of our job here at Android Central — and I love to help people (another big part of our job!). If you have questions about your tech, I'd love to talk about them.</p><p>Email me at <strong>askjerryac@gmail.com</strong>, and I'll try to get things sorted out. You can remain anonymous if you like, and we promise we're not sharing anything we don't cover here.</p><p>I look forward to hearing from you!</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="why-are-old-duplicate-photos-in-my-google-drive-folders-and-what-should-i-do-with-them-2">Why are old duplicate photos in my Google Drive folders and what should I do with them?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="gLFsyoeKH29Ln8HLjbtDJX" name="google-drive-lifestyle.jpg" alt="Google Drive on an Android phone and a laptop" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gLFsyoeKH29Ln8HLjbtDJX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Future)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><em><strong>Jeremy asks:</strong></em></p><p><em><strong>I just noticed that Google seems to have duplicate copies of my whole photo library, which, I'm guessing, is a waste of space.  There's a whole directory in My Drive that seems to be a duplicate of old family photos I scanned years ago, sorted by year and, I guess, not really needed.</strong></em></p><p><em><strong>What's going on here? Does this count against my Google storage limit? Most importantly, can I delete all this?</strong></em></p>
<p>Hi Jeremy! You've stumbled across a secret Google feature that gives you a look at what sets Google apart when it comes to online services: the unintended, multilayered problem.</p><p>On a serious note, this happens (or <em>happened</em>, as we'll see later) to some folks who used <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-set-google-photos">Google Photos</a> in its early days but didn't affect others. The short answer to your questions: you're seeing duplicates because Google Photos stores its files in a hidden folder in your shared Google storage. Yes, it counts against your storage the same way any files you purposefully uploaded to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-drive">Google Drive</a>, and you can delete the folder(s) from Google Drive after you verify you have copies in the Google Photos app. For a discussion of the mess, read on!</p>
<p>Not everyone sees these old duplicate files. At some point, Google changed how Photos stores its data, but it still is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-photos-uploads-will-soon-count-towards-your-google-drive-storage">part of your overall storage space provided by Google</a>. Before this, you could see your Google Photos storage in Drive if you knew where and how to look for it, but it was intended to be hidden.</p><p>During the transition, some people had folders duplicated while the way they were stored changed. I've heard this has to do with specific metadata, how the files were added to Photos, or what device was used to upload them. These theories could be correct, or they could be 100% wrong; regardless, it happened, and when it happened, the folders became visible like any other folder in Drive.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="kyyZs7NSMFx6cQgMZZ3abg" name="google-photos-lifestyle-widescreen-crop.jpg" alt="Google Photos on a Pixel 4a" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kyyZs7NSMFx6cQgMZZ3abg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>These folders are no longer associated with Google Photos and that means they are duplicated elsewhere in a way you can't (easily) find them. It also means they are taking up space.</p><p>You have a limited amount of space associated with your Google account. You <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-one">can pay to have more if you need it</a>, or you can manage your stored and saved files so you don't reach the limit.</p><p>These duplicate folders can be safely deleted once you've double-checked to make sure the photos are also stored in the Google Photos app. <strong>Do not delete them until you have checked. </strong>Never trust anything without verifying it for yourself.</p>
<p>One thing you might want to look at before you delete anything is the quality of the photo being stored, <em>especially</em> if you used to have an original<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare"> Pixel</a> or a Pixel 2.</p><p>It used to be that if you had a Pixel phone, your photos were stored at full quality without any cost to your shared storage allotment. Other photos had their quality reduced; it was still high-quality and is likely good enough for anything other than trying to have physical prints made, but there is a difference.</p><p>There is a chance that these "duplicate" photos would be full quality and the photos in Google Photos are not. This situation happened to me when I got hit with the weird duplication bug/mess/Googleism. A bunch of photos I took with the first Pixel phone were stored in full resolution and quality in my Google Drive but the "copies" in Google Photos were not.</p><p>It's up to you to decide if you want or need these larger-sized files (I didn't), but if you don't know and don't check, you can't decide.</p>
<p>One last thing to note — this happened to a <em>lot</em> of people, and it's probably worth checking if you are one of them and don't know it. Just open your Google Drive and look through all the stuff that's stored there. If you see folders full of pictures, this is probably why.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/ask-jerry-why-are-there-old-photos-in-my-google-drive</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Have a question about the tech in your life? If so, maybe we can get them answered! ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">YCe8rfM6sWNGFqytFFysGo</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HrmCzNcQDgwjg2sArrBf7S.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 20:24:28 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HrmCzNcQDgwjg2sArrBf7S.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android statues]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android statues]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Roku Channel set to gain deeper integration with Google TV for easier access to free content ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The Roku Channel is becoming deeper integrated with Google TV devices, including televisions, set-top boxes, and Chromecasts.</li><li>You can now search for The Roku Channel content in Google TV, find it on the home screen, and in Google TV's collection of live TV channels.</li><li>Roku says that it offers more than 80,000 movies and TV shows completely free as part of The Roku Channel.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google TV already offers a bunch of free content on its platform, including The Roku Channel. However, it will become much easier to discover and use The Roku Channel on Google TV thanks to deeper integration between the two services, Roku <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.roku.com/blog/trc-googletv" target="_blank">announced</a> today. This will bolster Google TV's free content and make it easier to find and watch the tens of thousands of movies and TV shows made available as part of The Roku Channel.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/roku">Roku</a> first added The Roku Channel to Google TV last year, in limited form. There wasn't support for Google TV's search or discoverability functions at the time. That's beginning to change, as Roku says a more integrated experience will be available "in the coming weeks." For starters, Google TV users will be able to search for content from The Roku Channel using the native search function in Android TV.</p><p>Additionally, 500 live TV channels from Roku will join the live tab on Google TV.  The platform already offers nearly 1,000 free or ad-supported live TV channels, and the new ones from The Roku Channel will provide even more options, including channels with news, sports, cooking, DIY, music, and other types of programming.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="oXcrZwfzk2M2rzeMv2kqtQ" name="google-tv-streamer-review-free-live-tv-2.jpg" alt="Google TV Streamer Free Live TV" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oXcrZwfzk2M2rzeMv2kqtQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>A big part of Google TV is the platform's recommendations. There is so much free content on the platform that some users might want help finding what to watch next, and Google recommends content based on your previous watch history. Soon, free Roku movies and TV shows will appear in the <strong>Featured on The Roku Channel</strong>, <strong>Continue watching</strong>, and <strong>Free live TV</strong> on the Google TV home screen.</p><p>Roku says that the free content available via The Roku Channel includes select live MLB games, ABC News broadcasts, and over 80,000 movies and TV shows.</p><p>Whether you have a brand-new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/google-tv-streamer-review">Google TV Streamer</a> or an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/google-tv-streamer-vs-chromecast-with-google-tv-4k">older Chromecast</a>, your Google TV device will get The Roku Channel integration. It'll also be available on any third-party device with Google TV built-in. If you want to get an early look at the content that'll become more closely engrained in your streaming device, you can try out The Roku Channel on Google TV, Fire TV, Samsung devices, and the Roku web and mobile apps.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/the-roku-channel-set-to-gain-deeper-integration-with-google-tv-for-easier-access-to-free-content</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google TV already had content from The Roku Channel, but it'll now be in more places and easier to find. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">LvUXSiTKtSox4xvYoNyCyV</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NcrVgZ5rEAFFffvDNAvrPg.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 20:22:04 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Streaming &amp; TV]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NcrVgZ5rEAFFffvDNAvrPg.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central / Roku]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Roku Channel on a Google TV device.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Roku Channel on a Google TV device.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Rumors say the OnePlus Watch 3 is coming up on a global launch ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Rumors on X state the OnePlus Watch 3 will "launch soon" in global markets outside of China.</li><li>The tipster lists the watch's upcoming launch alongside the global debut of the OnePlus 13 and 13R, though it's unclear if they will all roll out together.</li><li>Early Watch 3 rumors suggest it could arrive with a 500mAh battery, LTE, and eSIM support.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>OnePlus rolled out its 2024 smartwatch early this year; however, a new set of rumors claims it's looking to double dip.</p><p>According to a post on X by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/heyitsyogesh/status/1860932345097867411">Yogesh Brar</a>, OnePlus is gearing up to launch its next flagship smartwatch with some friends (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/oneplus-watch-3-global-launch-13-13r-3502836/">Android Authority</a>). Brar states in their post that the OnePlus Watch 3 will "launch soon in global markets." Unfortunately, they don't state how soon consumers can expect this device, especially considering we're a week out from December.</p><p>The X post states the Watch 3 is a part of the Chinese OEM's "upcoming product schedule," and alludes to some additional devices.</p><p>Brar lists the next watch alongside the OnePlus 13 and OnePlus 13R series phones.</p><p>The publication notes that the OnePlus 13R didn't join the top-of-the-line model during its launch at the end of October. This development is curious, to say the least, as we're unsure how OnePlus will go about releasing these three devices in global markets since one hasn't appeared on home soil (China).</p><p>A perfect scenario would see them all dropped at once globally, but the odds of that could be lower than we want.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">OnePlus 13 OnePlus 13ROnePlus Watch 3These are the upcoming products scheduled to launch soon in Global markets.<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1860932345097867411">November 25, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>Whispers about a OnePlus Watch 3 started earlier this summer when it appeared for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/new-oneplus-watch-certification-specs-rendering">its TENAA certification</a>. Leaked specs suggest the watch will sport LTE and eSIM support alongside a strong 500mAh battery like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oneplus-watch-2-review">its predecessor</a>. Additionally, it seems the watch could feature 10W wired charging.</p><p>Considering how recently the Watch 2 debuted, those earlier rumors felt closer to a variant rather than a jump in the series.</p><p>On the other hand, the "launching soon" rumor sort of makes sense when you consider the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-13-goes-official-in-china">one-month launch difference</a> for the OnePlus 13. The phone debuted in China on October 31, which was a month and some change earlier than the OnePlus 12's December 5 launch last year. A global launch for that device is expected sooner since it's already out in its home China market.</p><p>With that, perhaps we're looking at a December rollout for the OnePlus 13 overseas — but that's just speculation. For context, the OnePlus 12R rolled out in January 2024, a month after the top-tier model. In any case, these devices might slowly trickle out in a similar cadence to OnePlus' past.</p><p>As always, we'll have to wait and see.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oneplus-watch-3-upcoming-global-launch-rumors</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ OnePlus is rumored to be on the cusp of a Watch 3 launch. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">HT7XRkQchxRziwAAVkz3ET</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/R3c6ejWK5GY2yhoa8HCfgN.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 20:16:56 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/R3c6ejWK5GY2yhoa8HCfgN.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The fitness circles watchface for the OnePlus Watch 2]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The fitness circles watchface for the OnePlus Watch 2]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ It's time to ditch your boring wireless carrier — Mint Mobile's Black Friday deals are NO JOKE ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The biggest sale event of 2024 is almost here, and Mint Mobile is marking the occasion by dropping some of the best Black Friday phone deals I&apos;ve ever seen. I know that sounds like something a deal writer <em>would </em>say, but I&apos;m being serious here. Let me explain.</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Black Friday deals</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Black Friday Google Pixel deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Black Friday Motorola deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024">Black Friday Samsung deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Black Friday OnePlus deals</a></p></div></div>
<p>Some of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones </a>of 2024 are getting major discounts through the MVNO carrier, and Mint is pairing the savings with some deeply discounted wireless when you transfer your existing phone number. For instance, you could get the Google Pixel 9 AND a full year of the Unlimited plan for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9/6810275/"><strong>a single payment of $479 (or $20 per month using affirm)</strong></a>. Alternately, you can grab the Samsung Galaxy S24 and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/samsung-galaxy-s24/5418243/"><strong>simply have your phone bill covered for a year</strong></a>.</p><p>Sure, they aren&apos;t straight discounts, but if you&apos;re looking to switch wireless carriers, just imagine: you could make a single payment right now and not have to think about your phone bill again until December 2025. Plus, you&apos;ll get an incredible 2024 device out of the deal. Yeah, it&apos;s that good. </p><p>Keep reading for all of the best deals from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/deals/"><strong>Mint Mobile&apos;s Black Friday sale</strong></a>, but don&apos;t wait too long to make your move — Mint has been known to run out of stock during events like this. If you have any questions about the carrier, take a look at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/mint-mobile-review">our 4/5-star Mint Mobile review</a> while you&apos;re in the neighborhood. </p>
<h2 id="my-favorite-mvno-is-meeting-my-favorite-android-phones-for-the-holidays-x2014-how-sweet-xa0-2">My favorite MVNO is meeting my favorite Android phones for the holidays — how sweet! </h2>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="07383997-34b4-474c-af11-2e652066b8a9" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9/6810275/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="tik5vWBsBmtqriDgoJ23g5" name="google pixel 9 render 400x500.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tik5vWBsBmtqriDgoJ23g5.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Google Pixel 9 128GB: </strong><a href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9/6810275/" data-dimension112="07383997-34b4-474c-af11-2e652066b8a9" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799"><del>$799</del> <strong>$299, plus 50% off one year of Unlimited at Mint Mobile</strong></a></p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-review">Google Pixel 9</a> was one of the best flagship phones released this year, coming complete with a 6.3-inch AMOLED display, a ton of AI software features, and seven years of guaranteed OS updates. </p>
<p>Purchase the phone from Mint Mobile and you'll score a ridiculous $500 discount AND 50% off a year of the unlimited plan (which just so happens to one of the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/carriers/best-unlimited-data-plans">best data plans</a> we've ever used). </p>
<p><strong>👀 Alternate Black Friday deals: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-Unlocked-Smartphone-Advanced/dp/B0D7HWJDQM"><strong>Amazon - $649</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-9-128gb-unlocked-obsidian/6587819.p"><strong>Best Buy - $649</strong></a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9/6810275/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="07383997-34b4-474c-af11-2e652066b8a9" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="d8f53600-7c00-4fbc-b0f9-ee0204a6490d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799" data-dimension48="$799" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/samsung-galaxy-s24/5418243/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1200px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="NqhoUu3WzqW2D7ngA6rmHK" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-render-square-crop-black.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NqhoUu3WzqW2D7ngA6rmHK.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1200" height="1200" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy S24 128GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/samsung-galaxy-s24/5418243/" data-dimension112="d8f53600-7c00-4fbc-b0f9-ee0204a6490d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799" data-dimension48="$799"><del>$799</del> <strong>$620, plus 50% off one year of Unlimited at Mint Mobile</strong></a></p>
<p>Don't let its relatively plain appearance fool you: the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-hands-on">Galaxy S24</a> is all power under the hood, with a bounty of fun Galaxy AI features, a Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 chipset, and a gorgeous 6.2-inch AMOLED display. </p>
<p>Mint Mobile has just added the flagship to its Black Friday lineup, slashing $180 off the phone and dropping 50% off the unlimited plan for one year. </p>
<p><strong>👀 Alternate Black Friday deals: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CMDRCZBJ"><strong>Amazon - $699.99</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-s24-128gb-onyx-black-verizon/6570416.p"><strong>Best Buy - $699.99</strong></a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/samsung-galaxy-s24/5418243/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="d8f53600-7c00-4fbc-b0f9-ee0204a6490d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799" data-dimension48="$799">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="eaa93446-28a9-460b-ad8f-f80d1d86161a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,300" data-dimension48="$1,300" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra/5418319/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="BF24wtWZfPun3awtdNycRT" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-Ultra-titanium-black.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BF24wtWZfPun3awtdNycRT.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra 256GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra/5418319/" data-dimension112="eaa93446-28a9-460b-ad8f-f80d1d86161a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,300" data-dimension48="$1,300"><del>$1,300</del><strong> $1,100, plus 50% off one year of Unlimited at Mint Mobile</strong></a></p>
<p>One of the best Samsung phones ever built, the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review">Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra</a> boasts a gorgeous 6.8-inch AMOLED display with a built-in stylus, plus you get a ton of AI software features, seven years of OS/security updates, and some of the best camera tech around. </p>
<p>Buy the premium device during Mint's Black Friday sale and you'll enjoy $200 off alongside a year of Unlimited for only $15 per month ($180 upfront).</p>
<p>👀 <strong>Alternate Black Friday deals: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Smartphone-Unlocked-Android-Titanium/dp/B0CMDM65JH"><strong>Amazon - $949.99</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-256gb-unlocked-titanium-black/6569855.p"><strong>Best Buy - $949.99</strong></a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra/5418319/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="eaa93446-28a9-460b-ad8f-f80d1d86161a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,300" data-dimension48="$1,300">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="99e86924-7bf1-4ced-bb1d-b0c43253f941" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold 256GB: $1,799" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold 256GB: $1,799" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9-pro-fold/6810584/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="JissherrZpkPfUPoRgiLgn" name="google pixel 9 pro fold square render 1.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JissherrZpkPfUPoRgiLgn.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="800" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold 256GB: </strong><a href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9-pro-fold/6810584/" data-dimension112="99e86924-7bf1-4ced-bb1d-b0c43253f941" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold 256GB: $1,799" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold 256GB: $1,799"><del>$1,799</del> <strong>$1,449, plus 50% off one year of Unlimited at Mint Mobile</strong></a></p>
<p>Versatile and feature-packed, the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-fold-review">Pixel 9 Pro Fold</a> has just about everything you could want in a foldable phone from Google. You get two glorious displays, a durable folding hinge, and all of the fun AI features you could ever need. </p>
<p>The problem is that the 9 Pro Fold is also pretty expensive. Mint Mobile is helping a bit by carving $350 off the phone when you pair the purchase with 12 months of discounted wireless and transfer your phone number. </p>
<p><strong>👀 Alternate Black Friday deals: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-Pro-Fold-Smartphone/dp/B0D7V1J2Y1"><strong>Amazon - $1,499</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-9-pro-fold-5g-256gb-unlocked-obsidian/6587911.p"><strong>Best Buy - $1,499</strong></a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9-pro-fold/6810584/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="99e86924-7bf1-4ced-bb1d-b0c43253f941" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold 256GB: $1,799" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold 256GB: $1,799">View Deal</a></p></div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/its-time-to-ditch-your-boring-wireless-carrier-mint-mobiles-black-friday-deals-are-no-joke</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Mint Mobile has carving hundreds of dollars off some of my favorite phones of the year for Black Friday, but it gets even better.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">jtSGRuPCFxadk3WnYBRfb9</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AKBQTHAzPxRupBQxVXaBic.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 20:08:07 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AKBQTHAzPxRupBQxVXaBic.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Testing Google Pixel 9&#039;s camera]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Testing Google Pixel 9&#039;s camera]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google app for iOS now adds Search links to third-party websites unless they opt-out ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google is now inserting its own links to Google Search result cards into third-party webpages.</li><li>The feature, called Page Annotations, is now live in the Google app for iOS.</li><li>Web publishers can opt-out of Page Annotations, but the request can take up to 30 days to take effect.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google is adding another tool to its web browser that could pull users away from independent sites and toward Google Search results. The company recently <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/websearch/thread/308719098/page-annotation-in-google-app-browser-for-ios?hl=en"> announced </a>the introduction of Page Annotations to the Google app for iOS, which is a multifunctional app hosting Google Search, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini</a>, and functioning as a miniature web browser. As spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.seroundtable.com/google-ios-app-page-annotation-38451.html">Search Engine Roundtable </a>and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/11/25/google-ios-app-link-annotations-search/">9to5Google</a>, Page Annotations insert links to Google Search results in plain text on third-party websites.</p><p>"Words, topics, products, places, celebrity names, and other entities that are mentioned in a page might be highlighted as clickable annotations in the Google App browser for iOS," the company explains in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://developers.google.com/search/docs/crawling-indexing/control-what-you-share#page-insights" target="_blank">support document</a>. "By clicking the annotation, the user will be navigated to the search page with the results for this annotation."</p><p>Google does give web publishers the ability to opt-out of Page Annotations. They can do so via a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1h9I0TbN-H_1e85CqXYb1ng7rQfg2ijfODc1sBxPBd08/viewform?edit_requested=true" target="_blank">Google Form</a>. However, some site owners may be frustrated by how long it can take for their opt-out request to be processed.</p><p>"Site owners can choose to opt out of this annotation feature by submitting the opt-out form," Google explains. "The Page Annotation feature triggered on your site will be disabled within 30 days after submitting the opt-out form. You only need to do this once."</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="jAbTLUkofY6oM9xkicnETD" name="iphone-16-pro-max-20.jpg" alt="Apple iPhone 16 Pro Max dock" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jAbTLUkofY6oM9xkicnETD.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Page Annotations appear differently than regular in-text links, potentially signaling to the user that you're clicking a Google Search link rather than a redirect link from a third-party website. However, it's still possible that Page Annotations pull users away from the site they're browsing.</p><p>More likely, though, is that Page Annotations will simply be a new way for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google">Google app</a> users to quickly find out more information about a person, place, or thing. The Google Search results cards that appear as Page Annotations are designed in a way that makes it easy to return to the site you were previously browsing. It's also worth noting that iOS has a native <strong>Look Up</strong> feature that basically allows users to do the exact same thing, except it works system-wide on any highlighted text.</p><p>When you consider this context, it's unlikely that Page Annotations will materially change how iPhone users browse the web. If publishers are concerned, they do still have the ability to opt-out. While not explicitly listed as a test, it's fair to wonder whether Page Annotations might make their way to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/what-happens-if-google-has-to-sell-chrome">Chrome</a> or Android if they are successful in the Google app for iOS.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-app-for-ios-now-adds-search-links-to-third-party-websites-unless-they-opt-out</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Web publishers can opt out via a provided form, but changes might not take effect for up to 30 days.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">uuJcQMAZpWQAD5xMJxQwkm</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rgWV3CEtK7wN47W7EsZjJQ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 19:30:40 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rgWV3CEtK7wN47W7EsZjJQ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central / Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Page Annotations in the Google app for iOS. ]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Page Annotations in the Google app for iOS. ]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Alleged Nothing Phone 3 database listing suggests a budget-focused chip ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Following an assumed Nothing Phone 3 database listing, it seems the device could arrive with a midrange-level SoC.</li><li>From the listed chip details, it seems Nothing could pack Qualcomm's Snapdragon 7s Gen 3 into the Phone 3 instead of the 8s Gen 3.</li><li>Nothing's CEO Carl Pei stated that the Phone 3 will have AI at its core when it arrives in 2025 following a purposeful delay this year.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Nothing is developing a Phone 3, but a recent discovery suggests its internal SoC isn't so "flagship."</p><p>The folks at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.gsmarena.com/nothing_phone_3_appears_on_geekbench_-news-65473.php">GSMArena</a> found a new listing via the Geekbench database from Nothing. The device in question, with model number "A059," is rumored to be the next Phone 3 flagship. The listing is a little vague, stating this device in development could debut with 8GB of RAM and Android 15.</p><p>However, the more pressing matter is its supposed chip architecture of one processor and eight cores.</p><p>Per the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://browser.geekbench.com/v6/cpu/9045583">database listing</a>, it seems the assumed Phone 3 will have one "main" core at 2.50GHz. The rest of the setup includes four cores at 1.80GHz and three cores at 2.40GHz. These are likely to arrive as "efficiency" and "performance" cores, respectively.</p><p>The publication notes that this particular core, though the listing lacks its name, points toward Qualcomm's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/ai-is-coming-to-more-budget-phones-thanks-to-qualcomms-new-snapdragon-7s-gen-3">Snapdragon 7s Gen 3</a> SoC. Elsewhere, the post claims the rumored Phone 3 could debut with a 6.5-inch OLED display. Early speculation throws a $600 starting price on the table, as well.</p><p>Take such rumors with a grain of salt as the publication adds a "Phone 3 Pro" could join the lineup.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="QDpxXBVTnCcD8c9yNDoYjn" name="Nothing-phone-2-display-home-screen-01.jpg" alt="The home screen of the Nothing Phone (2) with pink icons and wallpaper" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QDpxXBVTnCcD8c9yNDoYjn.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Rumors about the Nothing Phone 3 have <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/nothing-phone-3-qualcomm-chip-price-rumors">been extremely scarce</a> with the "latest" detailing a chance for a Qualcomm variant. It was rumored this past summer that the device could debut with the Snapdragon 8s Gen 3. The chip is a slightly toned-down version of the 2023 SD 8 Gen 3 flagship. It reached 3.0GHz speeds, which was 0.3GHz slower than the higher-tier chip.</p><p>Qualcomm stated the chip was designed for more on-device AI. However, the Snapdragon 7s Gen 3, which is <em>now </em>rumored for the Phone 3, is aimed at "budget-friendly smartphones." It's based on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/snapdragon-7-plus-gen-3-launch">midrange SD 7 Plus Gen 3</a> from March.</p><p>With that, the Snapdragon 7s Gen 3 is a bit slower than the flagship 8 or 8s chips. Still, it focuses heavily on AI as it boasts support for several models like Baichuan-7B and Llama 2.</p><p>AI is a phone aspect that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/nothing-will-prioritize-ai-over-phone-3-but-is-that-the-right-call">Nothing's CEO, Carl Pei, stated</a> he wanted to focus heavily on with the next device. In June, Pei stated that the company had been "prototyping AI interactions." Moreover, it seemed evident that Nothing purposefully delayed the Phone 3's launch to better flesh out its AI software. The company confirmed that it wouldn't arrive in 2024, pushing us into 2025 for an eventual debut.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/nothing-phone-3-database-listing-chip-details-leak</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Rumors claimed Nothing's Phone 3 appeared in a new listing with a vastly different chipset. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">9S2bYVYKHKemBuuu2dAZyR</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CqoaiemQLuCy6AzPJ2chVL.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 19:27:36 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CqoaiemQLuCy6AzPJ2chVL.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Nothing Phone (2)&#039;s colorways with glyph lights on]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Nothing Phone (2)&#039;s colorways with glyph lights on]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung begins rolling out One UI 6 Watch for older Galaxy Watch models ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-32">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Last week, Samsung announced plans to begin the rollout of One UI 6 Watch to older Galaxy Watch models.</li><li>The update began rolling out today for some Galaxy Watch 6 and Watch 6 Classic users in the U.S.</li><li>Following the Galaxy Watch 6 series, One UI 6 Watch will come to Galaxy Watch 5, Galaxy Watch 5 Pro, Galaxy Watch 4, Galaxy Watch 4 Classic and Galaxy Watch FE.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-one-ui-6-watch-wear-os-5-official-rollout">highly-anticipated One UI 6 Watch update</a> is slowly making its way to older Samsung Galaxy Watch models. Users on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GalaxyWatch/comments/1gzl3oe/its_finally_here/" target="_blank">Reddit</a> began reporting seeing updates for One UI 6 Watch become available for their <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-6-review">Galaxy Watch 6 and Galaxy Watch 6 Classic</a> devices today in the U.S. The rollout comes following Samsung's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://news.samsung.com/global/samsung-expands-availability-of-latest-wearable-experiences-to-more-users" target="_blank">announcement</a> of the One UI 6 Watch release schedule last week, which is based on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/wear-os-5">Wear OS 5</a>.</p><p>One UI 6 Watch debuted on the Samsung Galaxy Watch 7 and Ultra earlier this year, packing a few Samsung Health features powered by Galaxy AI. They include <strong>Energy Score</strong>, which is similar to Garmin's Body Battery metric, and <strong>Sleep Analysis</strong>. On top of that, <strong>Race </strong>and <strong>Workout Routine</strong> will help athletes train for their next big event — or simply hit their personal goals. Now, these features and more are set to come to a slew of older Galaxy Watch models.</p>
<blockquote class="reddit-card"  ><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GalaxyWatch/comments/1gzl3oe/its_finally_here">It's finally here...</a> from <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GalaxyWatch">r/GalaxyWatch</a></blockquote><script async src="//embed.redditmedia.com/widgets/platform.js" charset="UTF-8"></script>
<p>The One UI 6 Watch update may arrive in a few different build numbers, including <strong>R965USQU1BXJ5</strong> and <strong>R965UOYM1BXJ5</strong>. It's nearly two gigabytes in size, and some users are reporting that the update takes hours to apply to their Galaxy Watch 6 or Galaxy Watch 6 Classic. The exact details and rollout timeline will depend on your device model, and whether you have the GPS or GPS + LTE versions of the Galaxy Watch.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1440px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="9LHF46EhLFdXuLW2sh2vj4" name="samsung-galaxy-ai-energy-score.JPG" alt="Galaxy AI energy score mock-up for One UI 6 Watch" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9LHF46EhLFdXuLW2sh2vj4.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1440" height="810" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Samsung)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Samsung warns that the included Galaxy AI features are only guaranteed for free until the end of 2025. After that, their future is up in the air. The idea of Samsung offering a subscription for Galaxy AI and/or Samsung Health features has been floated, but nothing is concrete at the moment.</p><p>For now, the One UI 6 Watch update is only available for the Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 and Galaxy Watch 6 Classic. Eventually, One UI 6 Watch will come to Galaxy Watch 5, Galaxy Watch 5 Pro, Galaxy Watch 4, Galaxy Watch 4 Classic and Galaxy Watch FE.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-begins-rolling-out-one-ui-6-watch-for-older-galaxy-watch-models</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A few of our favorite Galaxy Watch 7 features are coming to older models as One UI Watch 6 rolls out. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">N6Dqm7n2Q89zizGXJ35FZT</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/35rjmuxKAAXurGy3xc6fPL.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 19:00:01 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/35rjmuxKAAXurGy3xc6fPL.jpeg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Close-up of the Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 and Watch 6 Classic]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Close-up of the Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 and Watch 6 Classic]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung Galaxy S24 FE vs. Galaxy S23 FE: Bigger, faster, stronger ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[         <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="710409b5-20c0-4ffb-b707-fed48c84135b">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tyzubFKgaHuS3C4VqaL7Vo.jpg' alt="Samsung Galaxy S24 FE square render"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S24 FE</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The best midrange phone today</strong></em><br><br>The Samsung Galaxy S24 FE is priced higher than most Android midrangers, and for good reason. It's bigger and faster than many of its competitors, with a 6.7-inch display and a Samsung Exynos processor. Plus, you get a telephoto lens with 3x optical zoom. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Exynos 2400e chipset helps this phone feel faster than other midrangers</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Outstanding battery life</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Telephoto lens for great 3x zoom shots</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>7 years of OS upgrades</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>A full slate of Galaxy AI features</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Charging speeds are still slow</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>MSRP is roughly $150 more than competing midrangers</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Display bezels are asymmetrical</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Larger form factor is somewhat harder to hold</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="e49363a4-fcb8-4fe6-9713-eddb31d96016">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GkVM7Nd5GdbAoLZMSRdDJ.jpg' alt="Samsung Galaxy S23 FE"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S23 FE</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Still a solid phone</strong></em><br></p><p>The Samsung Galaxy S23 FE is, on paper, a worse phone than the newer model. However, its 6.4-inch screen will be a dream for people who love small, compact handsets. You'll also save a bunch by buying the last-generation version — assuming you can find it in stock. Galaxy S23 FE owners probably don't need to upgrade yet. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Same camera hardware as the newer Galaxy S24 FE</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Lighter and more compact than the Galaxy S24 FE</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Cheaper</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Supports most Galaxy AI features</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Full OS upgrades will end after 2027</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Snapdragon 8 Gen 1 chipset is getting old</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Thicker than the Galaxy S24 FE</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<p>Samsung recently launched the Galaxy S24 FE, its latest midrange phone retailing for $650. Surprisingly, it's a pretty big update. There's an emphasis on Galaxy AI and seven years of software support, plus a fresh Samsung Exynos 2400e chipset that's actually faster than older midrange chips from Google and Qualcomm. The design and cameras are all too familiar, though, heavily resembling the Galaxy S23 FE.</p><p>While the Galaxy S24 FE and the Galaxy S23 FE appear similar from afar, the differences are easily noticed up close. However, should you upgrade if you already own a Galaxy S23 FE, or should you look to buy a discounted Galaxy S23 FE instead of the newer model? After testing both <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">great phones</a> for ourselves, we're here to help you find the answers to all these questions and more.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-s24-fe-vs-galaxy-s23-fe-design-2">Samsung Galaxy S24 FE vs. Galaxy S23 FE: Design</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="inn2brzTWTMaKiHcFYu3UA" name="samsung-galaxy-s24-fe-colors-4.jpg" alt="Samsung Galaxy S24 FE colors" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/inn2brzTWTMaKiHcFYu3UA.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In this case, pictures won't tell you the entire story. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-fe-hands-on">Samsung Galaxy S24 FE</a> appears to have an eerily similar design to the Galaxy S23 FE, and it's true that they do look alike. But a closer look reveals more similarities than differences. For starters, the Galaxy S24 FE now sports a larger 6.7-inch form factor than its 6.4-inch predecessor. The bigger size allowed Samsung to include a larger battery while making the Galaxy S24 FE slimmer than the Galaxy S23 FE.</p><p>This year's model measures 162.0 x 77.3 x 8.0mm, while the older variant measures 158 x 76.5 x 8.2mm. Expectedly, the<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s23-fe-hands-on"> Galaxy S23 FE</a> is a few grams lighter due to its compact size and smaller battery. Both devices are plenty durable, with IP68 certifications and Gorilla Glass 5 coverings. You can choose between five colors on the Galaxy S24 FE and only four on the Galaxy S23 FE, but both midrangers offer a lot of room for choice.</p><p>The newer Galaxy S24 FE takes a few design cues from recent Samsung phones, like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Galaxy Z Fold 6</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-6-review">Galaxy Z Flip 6</a>. That includes the company's most rectangular design yet with flat, matte aluminum side rails and only a slight chamfer along the edges. This can make the phone feel slightly uncomfortable, but the curved corners help limit the potential discomfort.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="ioVFeHRPFQnVzsTJD6eQ4U" name="samsung-galaxy-s23-fe-family-colors-4.jpg" alt="Different colors of the Galaxy S23 FE" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ioVFeHRPFQnVzsTJD6eQ4U.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Meanwhile, the smaller Galaxy S23 FE will feel nicer in the hand than the Galaxy S24 FE. Both phones have raised triple-camera lenses on the back, and an under-display fingerprint reader on the front. There's a hole-punch camera on at the top of the display, too.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-s24-fe-vs-galaxy-s23-fe-hardware-and-specs-2">Samsung Galaxy S24 FE vs. Galaxy S23 FE: Hardware and specs</h2>
<p>Aside from the difference in display size, the 6.7-inch Galaxy S24 FE and the 6.4-inch Galaxy S23 FE have the same screen specifications. Both are AMOLED displays offering a 1080p resolution and a 120Hz refresh rate. They also both have asymmetrical screen bezels with corner radii that don't match the corners of the chassis perfectly; those kinds of things may or may not matter to you, but they're something I've noticed.</p><p>On the inside, the Samsung Galaxy S24 FE is powered by the Exynos 2400e chipset. It's faster than both variants of the Galaxy S23 FE, which had the Qualcomm Snapdragon 8 Gen 1 chipset in the U.S. and the Exynos 2200 processor worldwide. In benchmarks, the Galaxy S24 FE outperformed the Galaxy S23 FE, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12r-review">OnePlus 12R</a>, <em>and</em> the Tensor G3-powered <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-review">Google Pixel 8a</a>.</p><p>In terms of memory and storage, these two midrangers are identical. You get 8GB of RAM and the option of either 128GB or 256GB of storage. Since there's no microSD card support, you'll need to pay for extra storage at the time of purchase if you think you'll need it.</p>

<p>The Galaxy S24 FE packs a larger battery than the Galaxy S23 FE, with the former having a 4,700mAh capacity and the latter having a 4,500mAh capacity. Surprisingly, the bigger size plus the efficiency of the Exynos platform helped the Galaxy S24 FE provide all-day battery life during heavy usage. It's a real reason to pick the newer model over the competition.</p><p>Connectivity is identical between these two phones, and unfortunately so. The devices support 5G, Wi-Fi 6E, and Bluetooth 5.3. However, at a time when we're seeing <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/wi-fi-7-explained">flagships start to support Wi-Fi 7</a>, it would've been nice to see that spec make its way to the Galaxy S24 FE.</p><p>Similarly, the camera system is unchanged. Both phones provide a triple-camera system with a main, ultrawide, and telephoto lens. The main camera is a 50MP, f/1.8 OIS primary shooter, and that's paired with a 12MP, f/2.2 ultrawide and an 8MP, f/2.4 telephoto with 3x optical zoom. That telephoto lens is crucial for both models, because the Galaxy S24 FE and Galaxy S23 FE are some of the only midrangers to feature true optical zoom.</p><p>Really, the biggest differences between these phones are on the inside. The new processor, bigger battery, and larger screen all add up to be the main differentiators for the Galaxy S24 FE.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-s24-fe-vs-galaxy-s23-fe-software-and-performance-2">Samsung Galaxy S24 FE vs. Galaxy S23 FE: Software and performance</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="nFMkDSensEgPivRafCToGQ" name="samsung-galaxy-s24-fe-home-screen.jpg" alt="Samsung Galaxy S24 FE home screen in hand" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nFMkDSensEgPivRafCToGQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The reason it's hard to recommend the Samsung Galaxy S23 FE as a new smartphone in 2024 is its software support. The phone runs Android 14, just like the newer Galaxy S24 FE, although it launched with Android 13. However, the older Galaxy S23 FE will only get full Android upgrades through 2027, which will come sooner than we think. Compared to the full seven-year upgrade promise that comes with the Galaxy S24 FE, there's no discussion needed. The newer phone will outlast the older one by a mile.</p><p>Additionally, it's likely that the Galaxy S24 FE will have a better time running new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-galaxy-ai">Galaxy AI</a> features than the Galaxy S23 FE. It's true that the Galaxy S23 FE did get Galaxy AI via an OTA update this year; it's unclear what features it will get in the future. If AI matters to you, the Exynos-powered Galaxy S24 FE will be better in the long run than the Galaxy S23 FE and its aging Snapdragon chip.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-s24-fe-vs-galaxy-s23-fe-which-should-you-buy-2">Samsung Galaxy S24 FE vs. Galaxy S23 FE: Which should you buy?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="QUvoddCA7TRFjo9FPRqPLG" name="samsung-galaxy-s24-fe-cameras-close.jpg" alt="Close-up on Samsung Galaxy S24 FE cameras" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QUvoddCA7TRFjo9FPRqPLG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>For those looking to buy a new Samsung midranger today, the choice is pretty simple. The Samsung Galaxy S24 FE is bigger and faster than its predecessor, and it has longer battery life and software support. It's closer to the regular <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24">Galaxy S24 series</a> than ever.</p><p>Usually, I'd recommend looking out for a great Galaxy S23 FE deal if you want to save a few bucks. This time around, it's hard to find a Galaxy S23 FE in stock, let alone at a compelling price. It's actually the new Galaxy S24 FE that's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/not-a-typo-samsungs-brand-new-galaxy-s24-fe-is-already-usd175-off-ahead-of-black-friday">already up to $275 off with activation</a> ahead of Black Friday.</p><p>If you already own a Galaxy S23 FE, you probably don't need to upgrade immediately. You still have Samsung's newest midrange camera system and a handful of Galaxy AI features. But if you're in the market for a new midranger, the Galaxy S24 FE is the one to buy.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="7f504c6a-e25c-4c0b-9249-0b11da525803">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tyzubFKgaHuS3C4VqaL7Vo.jpg' alt="Samsung Galaxy S24 FE square render"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S24 FE</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Our top Android midranger</strong></em></p><p>In typical Samsung fashion, the Galaxy S24 FE doesn't feature camera upgrades over the Galaxy S23 FE. But it does add a bigger display, faster processor, and seven years of OS upgrades. That all adds up to make this phone a fantastic midranger, and a quality upgrade over its predecessor.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="455da094-3ff9-4753-880b-5afaf5113370">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GkVM7Nd5GdbAoLZMSRdDJ.jpg' alt="Samsung Galaxy S23 FE"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S23 FE</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Still a great phone</strong></em></p><p>Samsung Galaxy S23 FE owners still have a few years of OS upgrades left, so there's no reason to upgrade to a Galaxy S24 FE right now. However, only buy this phone new if you can find a really great discount. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-fe-vs-galaxy-s23-fe</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Can't decide whether the Samsung Galaxy S24 FE is worth the upgrade? You might be surprised by how it compares to the Galaxy S23 FE. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">JuekDgXZPE3ctyBrxERh7E</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GFCpEkAZZpknHmBWSTMjH9.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 18:50:10 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GFCpEkAZZpknHmBWSTMjH9.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S24 FE colors]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S24 FE colors]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>