<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 21:51:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ OnePlus 13 vs. Google Pixel 9 Pro XL: To buy a Pixel now, or to wait for OnePlus? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[         <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="bad71a1d-2dbc-43b4-984d-939a3ef862e3">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5gei6QXNmvhsLVXjNE39SE.jpg' alt="OnePlus 13 China launch"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">OnePlus 13</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>OnePlus' most premium phone yet</strong></em></p><p>By all indications, Qualcomm's Snapdragon 8 Elite is a monster chipset, and it's powering the brand-new OnePlus 13. Aside from the spec bump, which includes configurations with 24GB RAM and 1TB storage, the OnePlus 13 finally has a mostly-flat display. Plus, it's running OxygenOS 15 (based on Android 15).</p><p>For now, this phone is only available in China, but it will launch globally in January 2025.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Qualcomm's latest Snapdragon 8 Elite chipset</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>OxygenOS 15 (based on Android 15) at launch</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Fast, 100W wired charging speeds </li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Slick black, blue, and white colorways</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Mostly flat display is a much-needed change</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Could cost more than the OnePlus 12</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Not as many AI features as the Pixel 9 Pro XL</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Likely not available for purchase through US carriers</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="0b23a28e-7149-499b-9029-485a1466aa29">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KuP5kCbWwCMJf95Fcb6Twb.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL official render- Obsidian - front and back"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 Pro XL</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Google's biggest and brightest</strong></em></p><p>Google's Tensor G4 chipset might not be the most powerful on the block, but the Pixel 9 Pro XL makes up for that with clever optimization and excellent Google AI features. You also get top-notch build quality, a great display, and a standout camera system. Plus, it's available now, and you don't have to wait in order to buy one.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Plenty of Google AI features, from Gemini to Pixel Screenshots</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Tensor G4 is (mostly) good enough for daily use</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Seven years of OS upgrades guaranteed</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Improved charging speeds</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>A standout camera system</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Fast charging still can't touch OnePlus</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Tensor G4 will lose to Snapdragon 8 Elite every time</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Some may find the boxy Pixel 9 Pro XL uncomfortable to hold</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<p>The tradition of OnePlus' staggered flagship launches continues, and the OnePlus 13 is the worst-kept secret in tech. While the OnePlus 13 <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-confirms-global-launch-window-for-the-oneplus-13-and-its-soon">won't be officially unveiled in North America until January</a>, it's already available in China, and that means we know almost everything about it. So, how does it compare to Google's best Android flagship, the Pixel 9 Pro XL?</p><p>For now, a big unknown is the price of the OnePlus 13 in the US, which will likely be a significant factor in whether it's better or worse than the Pixel 9 Pro XL. Historically, OnePlus phones have been cheaper than most other flagships, but that isn't guaranteed to continue. Both phones have a lot going for them — the Pixel 9 Pro XL has software and AI, meanwhile the OnePlus 13 has raw power and better hardware — and we're here to help you decide which is right for you.</p>
<h2 id="oneplus-13-vs-google-pixel-9-pro-xl-design-2">OnePlus 13 vs. Google Pixel 9 Pro XL: Design</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="TzbPJGZazXSa6yPQ2gCknn" name="google-pixel-9-pro-xl-pixel-8-pro-pixel-7-pro-back-2.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL with Pixel 8 Pro and 7 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TzbPJGZazXSa6yPQ2gCknn.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-13">OnePlus 13</a> and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-review">Google Pixel 9 Pro XL</a> couldn't look more different, or at least, they're as different as two smartphones can be in 2024. While both are fairly rectangular with slight curves around the corners, they're differentiated by their camera housings. OnePlus went with its unmistakable circular camera housing, which holds the triple-camera system and flash. Meanwhile, the Pixel 9 Pro XL has a pill-shaped camera bar at the top of the phone's back. Additionally, the camera circle on the back of the OnePlus 13 isn't symmetrically positioned.</p><p>Both phones have similar screen sizes and dimensions, too. The OnePlus 13 sports a 6.82-inch display and measures 162.9 x 76.5 x 8.5-8.9 mm. On the other hand, the Pixel 9 Pro XL has a 6.8-inch panel with dimensions of 152.8 x 72 x 8.5 mm. In other words, these two devices will feel pretty similar in the hand, although the OnePlus 13 is marginally larger.</p><p>Technically, the OnePlus 13 is more durable than the Pixel 9 Pro XL, as it is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-is-an-ip69-rating-and-why-should-you-care">rated IP69 for dust and water resistance</a>. The Pixel 9 Pro XL is only rated for IP68, but you should know that the difference probably won't matter. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/what-do-waterproof-dustproof-rugged-ip-rating-numbers-mean">IP68 still covers brief submersion in shallow water</a>, and IP69 only takes that a step further, offering protection against high-pressure and high-temperature water jet sprays. You probably won't ever need that level of water resistance on your phone, though it certainly can't hurt.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1780px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:49.72%;"><img id="kXpp9EmL82wDhEaQqiutEo" name="op-13.jpg" alt="OnePlus 13 render" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kXpp9EmL82wDhEaQqiutEo.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1780" height="885" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OnePlus)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The OnePlus 13 can either be equipped with a glass back or an eco-leather silicone polymer back. It'll be available in black, blue, and white colorways. The Pixel 9 Pro XL comes in a few more colors and is only available with a glass back. You can choose from Porcelain, Rose Quartz, Hazel, and Obsidian colorways.</p><p>It's worth noting that, at 210 or 213 grams, the OnePlus 13 will feel noticeably heavier than the 199-gram Pixel 9 Pro XL.</p>
<h2 id="oneplus-13-vs-google-pixel-9-pro-xl-hardware-and-specs-2">OnePlus 13 vs. Google Pixel 9 Pro XL: Hardware and specs</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.30%;"><img id="quDzk7qjpypqXDWpK2ThqW" name="OnePlus-13" alt="OnePlus 13 back camera" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/quDzk7qjpypqXDWpK2ThqW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1080" height="608" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OnePlus / Weibo)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>A theme of this comparison will be that the OnePlus 13 will often win on the spec sheet, but the Pixel 9 Pro XL may still be the winner in daily use. For example, the OnePlus 13 is powered by the latest <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/snapdragon-8-elite">Snapdragon 8 Elite</a> chipset, which uses the same custom Oryon cores that Qualcomm developed for its laptop-class chips. By comparison, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-tensor-g4">Tensor G4</a> chip in the Pixel 9 Pro XL is significantly less powerful, even if it may be better optimized for Google's hardware.</p><p>It's a similar story for the display. The sizes are similar, at 6.82 inches for OnePlus 13 and 6.8 inches for the Pixel 9 Pro XL. They're also both OLED screens capable of reaching 120Hz refresh rates. However, the OnePlus 13 will be brighter thanks to its 4,500-nit peak brightness rating. The Pixel 9 Pro XL tops out at 3,000 nits. If past <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-oneplus-phones">OnePlus phones</a> are any indication of the OnePlus 13's brightness, the difference between these two displays should be noticeable in daily use.</p><p>Both phones use hole-punch, front-facing cameras. The OnePlus 13 has a 32MP, f/2.4 lens, while the Pixel 9 Pro XL has a 42MP, f/2.2 lens. We'll have to test these phones side-by-side for ourselves before we tell you which camera is best.</p>

<p>For the rear cameras, there are a lot of similarities. Both phones use a 50MP main camera with similar apertures. Additionally, the OnePlus 13's 50MP ultra wide camera and the Pixel 9 Pro XL's 48MP wide camera match up well. However, there's a big difference in zoom performance. The Pixel 9 Pro XL provides 5x optical zoom, while the OnePlus 13 only provides 3x optical zoom.</p><p>OnePlus continues its battery and charging dominance with the OnePlus 13. It brings a massive 6,000mAh battery with 100W wired charging. The Pixel 9 Pro XL's 5,060mAh battery and 37W wired charging speeds are fine, but don't compare to the OnePlus 13's offerings.</p><p>In terms of connectivity, the OnePlus 13 and Pixel 9 Pro XL both support <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/wi-fi-7-explained">Wi-Fi 7</a>, 5G, and NFC. The former supports Bluetooth 5.4, while the latter only supports Bluetooth 5.3.</p>
<h2 id="oneplus-13-vs-google-pixel-9-pro-xl-software-and-performance-2">OnePlus 13 vs. Google Pixel 9 Pro XL: Software and performance</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="vwhow3xrTqubFHXGc8enmZ" name="oxygenos-15-6.jpg" alt="OnePlus 12 with OxygenOS 15" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vwhow3xrTqubFHXGc8enmZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The OnePlus 13 will launch with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/i-used-oxygenos-15-for-a-week-these-are-my-favorite-features">OxygenOS 15, which is based on Android 15</a>. It'll get security updates for five years, but OxygenOS upgrades for only four years. That's a low number, considering Google offers seven years of full OS upgrades on the Pixel 9 Pro XL. However, you may not want to make a purchasing decision based on software support alone because we don't know what Android will look like on the Pixel 9 Pro XL in seven years. It's still a gamble.</p><p>One area where the Pixel 9 Pro XL decisively beats the OnePlus 13 is in AI. From features like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-circle-to-search">Circle to Search</a> to apps like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-use-the-pixel-screenshots-app-on-the-google-pixel-9" target="_blank">Pixel Screenshots</a> to features like Add Me — the Pixel has it all. While OnePlus is starting to catch up, if you want AI, you should still buy a Pixel.</p>
<h2 id="oneplus-13-vs-google-pixel-9-pro-xl-which-should-you-buy-2">OnePlus 13 vs. Google Pixel 9 Pro XL: Which should you buy?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="4QEnsjhSowEc2TZM3xYjhY" name="oneplus-13-official" alt="OnePlus 13" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4QEnsjhSowEc2TZM3xYjhY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OnePlus)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>For now, the "sure thing" recommendation is the Pixel 9 Pro XL. It's a rock-solid phone at a decent price with tons of software support. We still haven't tried the OnePlus 13 for ourselves and are missing key details about the handset, namely its US pricing. As such, it's impossible to recommend the OnePlus 13 today.</p><p>However, I'm optimistic that the OnePlus 13 — with a more powerful <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/snapdragon-8-elite">Snapdragon 8 Elite chipset</a> and better hardware in a few key areas — could dethrone the Pixel 9 Pro XL when it launches in January. If you can wait a month to see what the OnePlus 13 will hold, you should.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="85a5df34-aa20-4d37-be5d-cf3b4d50bbd1">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2XehjnwJAvFg5tz6mtaRkk.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL official render - Porcelain - back"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 Pro XL</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The best Android you can buy right now</strong></em></p><p>Don't want to wait? The Google Pixel 9 Pro XL is hands-down the best Android phone you can buy today. It's possible OnePlus or Samsung might usurp the Pixel 9 Pro XL with their own new flagships next month. Even still, this Google phone will be a top option through 2025. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="ccd2ff88-cb5a-418d-bb67-8af1f79d6638">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5gei6QXNmvhsLVXjNE39SE.jpg' alt="OnePlus 13 China launch"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">OnePlus 13</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Might be worth waiting for</strong></em></p><p>Since the OnePlus 13 already launched in China, we know almost everything about the phone — except for North American pricing. That's the wild card. Otherwise, the Snapdragon 8 Elite chipset, display, and camera are all extremely competitive with the Pixel 9 Pro XL.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-13-vs-google-pixel-9-pro-xl</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The OnePlus 13 is set to debut worldwide in January, so should you wait, or buy the Google Pixel 9 Pro XL now? We're here to help you decide. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">KZFvg8nK9LwMLAsoiAQZB5</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9hegvUAcXS9QDHfs3VeH6R.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 21:23:39 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9hegvUAcXS9QDHfs3VeH6R.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Pixel 9 Pro XL back view against colorful background]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Pixel 9 Pro XL back view against colorful background]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ YouTube Music gains a crucial feature for podcast listening and sharing ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Following the shuttering of Google Podcasts, YouTube Music is now Google's podcast delivery app, but it has lacked a few major features typically offered by podcast apps.</li><li>Google is now adding the ability to share audio links from the YouTube Music app that start at a specific timestamp.</li><li>The feature mimics the same functionality that was added to the main YouTube app this year, and is available on both iOS and Android.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google made a major shift in its podcasts delivery strategy this year, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-podcasts-shuts-down">shuttering Google Podcasts</a> in favor of YouTube Music. That decision was met with ire from fans, because YouTube Music lacks a few features that are staples on other podcast apps. However, the company has been making slow-and-steady progress with YouTube Music, and that's continuing — the app is gaining a long-overdue feature that'll be helpful for podcast listeners.</p><p>Just like the main YouTube app, you can now create a shareable link in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/youtube-music">YouTube Music app</a> for a song, podcast, or other recording that starts at a specific timestamp. The new addition, first spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/12/08/youtube-music-timestamp-sharing/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a>, appears to be the result of a server-side change. Android Central confirmed the feature's availability on a variety of Android 14 and Android 15 devices, which didn't require an update.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:324px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:224.38%;"><img id="DErMTEPWYP5mXbV5sP2uwJ" name="YouTube-Music-Timestamps" alt="The timestamp sharing option in YouTube Music." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DErMTEPWYP5mXbV5sP2uwJ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="324" height="727" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Future)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>After tapping the share button on the now playing screen, there is now a toggle at the top right corner of the share card that reads <strong>Start at [timestamp]</strong>. This will create a link for sharing that starts at your current timestamp. It's helpful for when you only want to share a specific part of a long podcast. The app will add <strong>t=XX</strong> to the link, where XX is the current position in the timeline in seconds. Then, you can share it like any other YouTube Music link.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:324px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:224.38%;"><img id="pdnUxJKvw4NazGEwUZDMwJ" name="YouTube-Music-Timestamps-2" alt="The timestamp sharing option in YouTube Music." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pdnUxJKvw4NazGEwUZDMwJ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="324" height="727" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Future)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Although the feature may be more useful for long-form audio content, like podcasts, it'll work for any type of content in YouTube Music, including songs. Now, whether you're using the YouTube or YouTube Music app, you'll be able to create a shareable link that starts at a specific timestamp.</p><p>The new option appears to be widely available on both iOS and Android; however, at least one of Android Central's devices had not yet received the server-side change. It's also available on the YouTube Music web client, which was <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-music-on-the-web-gets-a-redesign-but-its-not-winning-everyone-over">redesigned earlier this year</a>.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-music-gains-a-crucial-feature-for-podcast-listening-and-sharing</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ YouTube Music, now Google's main podcasts app, is gaining a feature it should've had all along.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">SeARCQCKzV2LSExKBbnTDA</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GzQNJ8Q6j77Rdsyt2oQSP8.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 21:15:52 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GzQNJ8Q6j77Rdsyt2oQSP8.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Create a radio section in Youtube Music]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Create a radio section in Youtube Music]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ HP's latest Chromebooks aim to deliver dependable tech to students ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>HP announced a series of Fortis G1i and Fortis G1m Chromebooks and Notebook PCs geared for students.</li><li>The Fortis G1i Chromebook features a 14-inch variant with strong MIL-STD tested durability, ChromeOS updates through 2035, and swift charging.</li><li>The Fortis G1i laptops will hit the market in January 2025 while the Fortis G1m devices become "later" in December for $249 on hp.com.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>HP is expanding its world of available Chromebooks by helping students who're constantly on the go during the school year.</p><p>According to a press release, HP states its latest wave of Chromebooks might help K-12 leaders who've highlighted <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/education/our-insights/when-the-money-runs-out-k-12-schools-brace-for-stimulus-free-budgets">growing concerns</a> for student's access to technology and its dwindling budget in schools. Kicking off HP's December reveal are the Fortis G1i Chrombook and Notebook PCs.</p><p>The top-tier laptop in the Fortis G1i lineup is the 14-inch FHD Chromebook which doubles as a touchscreen for easier use. HP touts the device as a "ruggedized" partner that students can keep with them in the classroom or take on the go.</p><p>To strengthen that, the laptop "adheres" to the MIL-STD in durability and has received an IP51 rating to help its durability. HP intends for these additions to help students (and parents) avoid any costly accidents.</p><p>Software-wise, HP says it has implemented a "low-maintenance" version of ChromeOS on the Fortis G1i 14-inch laptop. The software should be easy to manage for students and the company states it will update automatically. This laptop is guaranteed ChromeOS updates through June 2035.</p><p>This Chromebook features several connectivity options through Wi-Fi 6E wireless LAN and Bluetooth support.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:710px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:84.51%;"><img id="Y3HB4LmZWVn7YfhQEnLW35" name="hp-fortis-g1i-14-inch-chromebook" alt="The HP Fortis G1i Chromebook, 14-inch display version." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Y3HB4LmZWVn7YfhQEnLW35.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="710" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: HP)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Security and privacy is another area HP has honed in on with the Fortis G1i Chromebook. The post states students will have access to its HP Privacy Camera: a feature that includes a shutter to cover the camera lens when not in use. The company states this should give consumers "peace of mind" against "malicious surveillance."</p><p>The laptop is also highlighted as a device that offers "supercharged performance." The Chromebook can charge up to 90% in ~90 minutes. Additionally, consumers will be able to grab the device with up to 16GB of RAM and up to 128GB of storage.</p><p>The company says this device will be available on hp.com in January 2025 with its pricing listed shortly before that. More importantly, the 14-inch display variant will be joined by an 11-inch option. HP detailed the 11-inch Flip Chromebook, which lets students rotate its display 360 degrees in its hinge for comfortable use. Moreover, the computer offers an optional HP stylus for better writing and interactions.</p>
<h2 id="notebook-pc-2">Notebook PC</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:902px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:66.52%;"><img id="Hk8Rp2YFkkscZ8XU7nkGsX" name="hp-fortis-g1i-notebook-pc" alt="Students and a teacher using the HP Fortis G1i Flip Notebook PC." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Hk8Rp2YFkkscZ8XU7nkGsX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="902" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: HP)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The 11-inch Flip Notebook PC is another spin on HP's rotatable laptop. According to its post, the laptop can rotate 360 degrees much like the Chromebook variant for quick note-taking. However, HP states consumers can grab its Pro Slim Rechargeable Pen to help with the laptop's touchscreen. The stylus can be slotted into the computer's "water-resistant garage" on the keyboard for safekeeping.</p><p>Two cameras are what students will find when opening this laptop for the first time. These lenses enter at 5MP, which is useful for recording school projects.</p><p>For apps, HP detailed the addition of several Android apps. The company adds that these apps are tailored toward being educational, which are reportedly "easy to install and manage."</p><p>Other specifications see the Flip Notebook PC offering up to 16GB of RAM and 128GB of onboard storage.</p><p>Like the previously mentioned Chromebooks, the 11-inch Flip Notebook PC will be available for purchase in January 2025 via hp.com. The pricing for it will be posted shortly before that per HP's official announcement.</p>
<h2 id="fortis-g1m-chromebooks-2">Fortis G1m Chromebooks</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:851px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:70.51%;"><img id="SuNAhLxZ9zvFKoYFbHzprM" name="hp-fortis-g1m-11-inch-chromebook" alt="The HP Fortis G1m Chromebook in black." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SuNAhLxZ9zvFKoYFbHzprM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="851" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: HP)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>HP's announcement includes the Fortis G1m series Chromebooks. These devices offer a standard laptop experience, as well as a G1m Flip choice. Starting with the former, HP states the Fortis G1m 11-inch Chromebook is a lightweight computer that offers "key features" like "uninterrupted" performance.</p><p>Managing multiple apps and research papers will become a little easier as the laptop boasts the MediaTek Kompanio 520 processor. Joining that processor is the Chromebook's support for up to 64GB of eMMC storage and up to 8GB of RAM.</p><p>HP designed the G1m Chromebook with a sleek form, making it worth stuffing into your backpack with your books and journals. Similar to the Fortis G1i lineup, the M-version delivers a streamlined ChromeOS experience that takes its power efficiency focus to another level. HP states the software will have a minimal boot up time for students alongside fast web browsing.</p><p>The Fortis G1m Flip Chromebook is said to feature a 360 degree rotation on its hinge, a dual camera system, and an HP USI Garaged Pen.</p><p>These two Fortis G1m devices will be available "later" in December on hp.com for $249.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/hp-chromebooks-notebook-pc-student-focused</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ HP unveiled a host of new Chromebooks for students this school year. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">9Dk7sMwHUWuADK6EWVtGqB</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wkQ7E4py5eTJ5Eqw4mq7U8.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 20:34:59 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Chromebooks &amp; Laptops]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wkQ7E4py5eTJ5Eqw4mq7U8.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[HP]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A student and teacher in a classroom with the HP Fortis G1i Chromebook.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A student and teacher in a classroom with the HP Fortis G1i Chromebook.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Galaxy S24 series' latest security patch is just a One UI 7 waiting room ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung was spotted rolling out its December 2024 security patch to its flagship Galaxy S24 models.</li><li>The patch is extremely light as it seems the company has only included several security fixes alongside "Critical" and "High" level solutions.</li><li>Fortunately, Samsung kicked off its first One UI 7 (Android 15) beta this month, which is filled with loads of new goodies for eager testers.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Samsung was spotted pushing its monthly security patch to several of its current-gen devices.</p><p>As spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.sammobile.com/news/galaxy-s24-plus-ultra-fe-december-2024-security-update/">SamMobile</a>, the Galaxy S24, S24 Plus, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review">S24 Ultra</a> are beginning to receive the December 2024 security patch. What's important about this is that the devices have been spotted downloading the update in South Korea with version number <strong>S92xNKSS5AXKA</strong>. It seems like we can expect the U.S. version and other regions to see the update as the week progresses.</p><p>The changelog is extremely light, with the Korean OEM only highlighting the existence of "security fixes/enhancements" with the December patch.</p><p>The publication highlighted a post by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.galaxyclub.nl/nieuws/deze-samsung-telefoons-krijgen-de-laatste-update-van-2024-als-eerste/">GalaxyClub</a> (Dutch), which states the update features "eight" fixes for aspects like the One UI interface, Settings app, DeX, and more.</p><p>Samsung's December <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://security.samsungmobile.com/securityUpdate.smsb">patch changelog</a> detailed six "Critical" level fixes alongside 28 "High" level fixes. The company is correcting issues for ThemeCenter, as well as an opening that could've allowed an attacker to "improperly" alter your Galaxy phone's settings. A fix for the Cryptographic Signature in SmartSwitch is included, which should remove the possibility of an attacker installing "malicious software" on your device.</p><p>Elsewhere, Samsung states it has rolled in two fixes as part of its Semiconductor patch this month. The fixes were done in tandem with Google to solve critical vulnerabilities that could've negatively impacted your security.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="vx4LkhsVrr6FYWSMWRpFiM" name="samsung-galaxy-s24-fe-selfie-camera-viewfinder.jpg" alt="Selfie Camera viewfinder on Samsung Galaxy S24 FE" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vx4LkhsVrr6FYWSMWRpFiM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The GalaxyClub post also mentions that the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-fe-hands-on">Galaxy S24 FE</a> is receiving an Android 14-based December security update in Europe (vS721BXXS3AXK6). The device is reportedly joined by the recent foldables: the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-6-review">Galaxy Z Flip 6</a> and Fold 6 with versions F741BXXS2AXKC and F956BXXS2AXKC, respectively.</p><p>As previously stated, these updates are currently moving across the world, so keep your eyes peeled for them as we progress.</p><p>The December security patch is light, but that's likely because of what Samsung kicked off last week: <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsungs-first-one-ui-7-beta-is-available-now-public-release-set-for-early-2025">the first One UI 7 beta</a>. While the S24 FE didn't get an invite, the rest of the flagship S24 series is in. The beta is using software based on Android 15 and features several new goodies. Samsung's announcement detailed the "Now Bar," which is lumped into the lock screen to see "important notifications dynamically" without opening your phone.</p><p>"Call Transcript" will automatically transcribe a recorded call in 20 (supported) languages. The Knox Matrix dashboard gives users more security insight into their connected devices alongside much more.</p><p>We've been sitting and waiting for One UI 7's beta through Samsung's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-one-ui-7-beta-pushed-back-again">multitude of delays</a> and it's finally here. While the exact time isn't certain, it appears that we can expect One UI 7's (Android 15) full release during the Galaxy S25 launch or shortly after.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="accc468c-4905-422a-999e-e6cb6f07a127">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jH2nkHNQPuwBpm8KyQ6u4c.jpg' alt="samsung galaxy s24 ultra square render - 1"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>Thinking of an AI Phone? Samsung's answer to that is its Galaxy S24 series — but its S24 Ultra is of a different breed. With a 6.8-inch AMOLED display with a fluid 120Hz refresh rate, scrolling and gaming looks pretty good. Pair that with the company's extensive lineup of Galaxy AI on-device tools and the S24 Ultra can help you through it all.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-s24-series-december-2024-patch-rollout</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung was spotted pushing its December security patch to users in various regions. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">vdHRmPyqyyRmzSfjxLqP68</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LbEqWpgEHpvQNPj9PHWcth.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 19:14:30 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LbEqWpgEHpvQNPj9PHWcth.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Hands-on with the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Hands-on with the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ OPPO Find X8 Pro vs. Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra: A showdown of top Android camera phones ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[         <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="ae0dba47-6676-46da-b617-716d6b441e5b">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4N7FCrhPB4TZcALrM6EHgA.jpg' alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">OPPO Find X8 Pro</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>OPPO's latest challenger, now available globally</strong></em></p><p>The OPPO Find X8 Pro is available globally (though not in North America), and that means more people can choose it over the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra. You'll get a MediaTek processor, a large and fast-charging battery, and a capable camera system inside. It's worth a look in Asia, Europe, and India.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Powerful MediaTek system-on-a-chip</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Industry-leading camera hardware (plus a shutter button)</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>ColorOS 15 (based on Android 15) available right out of the box</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Excellent battery life and speedy fast charging</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Not great for gaming</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>The Find X8 Pro won't be available in North America</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Some software limitations still remain</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="2ca1d372-c22a-4689-aed7-8b1f6efc5ed3">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PBHvpjpX26yLAmUkjL5o3W.jpg' alt="Galaxy S24 Ultra in Titanium Yellow"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Samsung's latest and greatest ... for now</strong></em></p><p>Samsung's premium high-end flagship, the Galaxy S24 Ultra, is often a go-to recommendation for people who want the best Android hardware. It has long software support and exclusive AI features, a powerful Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 chipset, and a large display with S Pen support. However, OPPO's Find X8 Pro might be a better overall choice.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Qualcomm's Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 chip makes for a fast phone</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Plenty of useful Galaxy AI features and a seven-year update guarantee</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Flat, gorgeous display with an inbuilt S Pen</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Versatile camera hardware</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Individually, the rear cameras fall short of competing with the best from OPPO, Vivo, and other industry leaders</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Sharp, square corners may be uncomfortable for some</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Extremely expensive</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<p>Does OPPO have your attention yet? The company took what we loved from the OPPO Find X7 series, improved on it, and released the Find X8 and Find X8 Pro globally. That means if you're in Asia, Europe, or India, the OPPO Find X8 Pro might be a Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra killer. Especially as the Galaxy S24 Ultra nears replacement by the Galaxy S25 series in 2025, is the Find X8 Pro the best Android phone you can buy right now?</p><p>If the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oppo-find-x8-pro-review">OPPO Find X8 Pro</a> is available in your region, the answer is likely yes. The smartphone has a powerful MediaTek processor, a quadruple-camera system with two periscope telephoto lenses, and more. If you're not sure whether to buy the Find X8 Pro or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review">Galaxy S24 Ultra</a>, this breakdown will help you decide.</p>
<h2 id="oppo-find-x8-pro-vs-samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-design-2">OPPO Find X8 Pro vs. Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra: Design</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="GmNeBRFgKk2gJUcXmDs76U" name="oppo-find-x8-pro-1.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GmNeBRFgKk2gJUcXmDs76U.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The OPPO Find X8 Pro and the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra are similarly sized powerhouses. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-oppo-find-x8-series-is-taking-the-fight-to-the-iphone-16-globally">Find X8 Pro comes</a> with a 6.78-inch display, whereas the Galaxy S24 Ultra has a slightly larger 6.8-inch screen. However, the latter will almost certainly feel larger in the hand due to the Galaxy S24 Ultra's boxy design and sharp corners. The Find X8 Pro, meanwhile, measures 162.3 x 76.7 x 8.2 mm and its rounded corners and chamfered edges make for a more comfortable feel. At 162.3 x 79 x 8.6 mm, the Galaxy S24 Ultra is thicker and taller, too.</p><p>Notably, the Galaxy S24 Ultra is quite a bit heavier than the Find X8 Pro — there's an 18-gram disparity between the 215-gram OPPO flagship and the up-to-233-gram Samsung flagship. This is impressive, considering that the 5,910mAh battery inside the Find X8 Pro is significantly larger. The Galaxy S24 Ultra does have one trick up its sleeve: the inbuilt S Pen that can be used for quick drawing or note-taking on that large display.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="WGZFcwvp3vUr2yezPByNfN" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-Ultra-back-titanium-02.jpg" alt="The back of the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra in the Titanium Grey colorway" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WGZFcwvp3vUr2yezPByNfN.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In terms of durability, the Galaxy S24 Ultra has Gorilla Armor covering the display, and it's a reinforced material with an anti-reflective coating. By comparison, the OPPO Find X8 Pro has Gorilla Glass 7i, but it does have the edge with an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-is-an-ip69-rating-and-why-should-you-care"> IP69 water and dust-resistant rating</a>. That's higher than the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/what-do-waterproof-dustproof-rugged-ip-rating-numbers-mean"> IP68 certification </a>of the Galaxy S24 Ultra, and the difference means that the Find X8 Pro is especially protected against high-temperature and high-pressure water jets — however unlikely they may be.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="bYxGZwm4q8HvUXDa4epyRX" name="oppo-find-x8-pro-12.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bYxGZwm4q8HvUXDa4epyRX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Both <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phones</a> have rear quadruple-camera systems, but they're arranged much differently for a unique look. Samsung's lenses are separate from each other, protruding from the back of the Galaxy S24 Ultra in the top-left corner. OPPO stuck with its classic circular-shaped camera housing, and it's centered on the back of the device.</p><p>You can get the Find X8 Pro in Space Black, Pearl White, and Blue colorways, and it's largely made of an aluminum frame. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-titanium-breakdown">Samsung uses titanium for the Galaxy S24 Ultra</a>, and you can buy the phone in Titanium Black, Titanium Gray, Titanium Violet, Titanium Yellow, Titanium Blue, Titanium Green, and Titanium Orange.</p>
<h2 id="oppo-find-x8-pro-vs-samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-hardware-and-specs-2">OPPO Find X8 Pro vs. Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra: Hardware and specs</h2>
<p>MediaTek is often looked down upon as a lower-class chipmaker than Qualcomm, but that isn't the case heading into 2025. In fact, the MediaTek Dimensity 9400 chip inside the OPPO Find X8 Pro actually beats the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 processor inside the Galaxy S24 Ultra in benchmark tests. It's worth noting that the Find X8 Pro loses to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/snapdragon-8-elite">Snapdragon 8 Elite</a>-powered phones, like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/asus-rog-phone-9-pro-review">ASUS ROG Phone 9 Pro</a>, and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25">upcoming Galaxy S25 Ultra</a> will gain Qualcomm's latest chipset. But compared to the older Galaxy S24 Ultra, the Find X8 Pro is faster.</p><p>Both displays are similar — they're LTPO AMOLED panels supporting 120Hz refresh rates and HDR10+. However, as is a common occurrence, OPPO destroys Samsung in terms of peak brightness. The Find X8 Pro supports 4,500 nits peak brightness, while the Galaxy S24 Ultra is limited to 2,600 nits peak brightness. This will matter most in situations where you're using the phones outside in direct sunlight, but Samsung still has the anti-glare edge thanks to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/corning-gorilla-armor-galaxy-s24-ultra">Gorilla Armor</a>.</p><p>We can't forget about the Galaxy S24 Ultra's built-in stylus support, either, thanks to the S Pen. If you're looking for a phone with a pen inside, the Galaxy S24 Ultra is basically your only flagship offering.</p>

<p>OPPO's software support is improved, too, as the brand is now promising five years of full OS upgrades. It's still not quite on par with Samsung's seven-year promise for the Galaxy S24 Ultra, though. Additionally, Samsung has the edge in AI, and software overall. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/oppo-coloros-15-advances-device-ai-google">ColorOS 15 on the Find X8 Pro</a> is based on Android 15, but has some OPPO quirks that may be jarring to longtime One UI users.</p>
<h2 id="oppo-find-x8-pro-vs-samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-cameras-2">OPPO Find X8 Pro vs. Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra: Cameras</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="pFTqLYzHZuCsYZaFSVsUkb" name="oppo-find-x8-pro-24.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pFTqLYzHZuCsYZaFSVsUkb.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>If you want a fantastic Android camera phone, the OPPO Find X8 Pro is a better option than the Galaxy S24 Ultra. It's still not quite as good as the Find X7 Ultra (keep waiting for the Find X8 Ultra if you want the absolute best camera) or Vivo X100 Ultra. Still, it's significantly better than the Galaxy S24 Ultra's camera hardware, which is aging. Crucially, the Find X8 Pro succeeds in areas where the Galaxy S24 Ultra specifically struggles, like quick shutter speeds and limited motion blur when capturing fast-moving subjects.</p><p>For hardware, the Find X8 Pro features a foursome of 50MP camera sensors. There's the 50MP, f/1.6 1/1.4-inch Sony Lytia LYT-808 main sensor, plus a 50MP, f/2.0 ultrawide lens with a 120-degree field of view. On top of that, you get not one, but <em>two</em> periscope telephoto lenses. One handles 3x optical zoom, and the other takes care of 6x optical zoom. Put simply, whether you're after stunning concert photos or basic stills, the Find X8 Pro should handle them all.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="rE4YGhpZYsVBh7ahzPSyhT" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-Ultra-vs-Galaxy-S23-Ultra-camera-lenses-01.jpg" alt="Comparing the camera lens bumps on the Samsung Galaxy S23 Ultra vs S24 Ultra" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rE4YGhpZYsVBh7ahzPSyhT.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Galaxy S24 Ultra's camera specs look great on paper, highlighted by a 200MP, f/1.7 main sensor. However, megapixels aren't everything, and the Find X8 Pro's larger main sensor is actually better. Samsung does offer a capable duo of telephoto lenses, at 3x and 5x optical zoom. The phone's camera system simply doesn't impress compared to the likes of OPPO and Vivo heading into 2025.</p>
<h2 id="oppo-find-x8-pro-vs-samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-which-should-you-buy-2">OPPO Find X8 Pro vs. Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra: Which should you buy?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="Gg9xd2oL2Fp8ry7H86iDpY" name="oppo-find-x8-pro-21.jpg" alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Gg9xd2oL2Fp8ry7H86iDpY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The question of whether you should buy the OPPO Find X8 Pro or the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra is an easy one. It's the Find X8 Pro, hands-down — if the phone is available in your region. The better question to ask is whether the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/new-leak-claims-oppos-find-x8-ultra-will-be-a-camera-beast">Find X8 Ultra</a> or Galaxy S25 Ultra are worth waiting for, and they just might be. For now, the Find X8 Pro represents some of the best hardware Android phones have to offer.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="6b0a37e4-0f89-4a69-9737-b80eb0cade53">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4N7FCrhPB4TZcALrM6EHgA.jpg' alt="OPPO Find X8 Pro"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">OPPO Find X8 Pro</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>A standout Android phone</strong></em></p><p>With a powerful MediaTek processor and impressive camera hardware, the OPPO Find X8 Pro has what it takes to topple the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra. However, you'll have to live with some ColorOS quirks and realize that a rumored "Find X8 Ultra" could be an even better option.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="c0a4e368-a10b-44d7-ab4a-634e2ad646ec">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PBHvpjpX26yLAmUkjL5o3W.jpg' alt="Galaxy S24 Ultra in Titanium Yellow"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Still lagging behind</strong></em></p><p>Samsung didn't do much to upgrade the Galaxy S24 Ultra earlier this year, and now we're looking ahead to the Galaxy S25 series in 2025. Perhaps that lineup can better compete with OPPO's current handsets, but for now, the Find X8 Pro seems to be a better option than the Galaxy S24 Ultra.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oppo-find-x8-pro-vs-samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ OPPO made the Find X8 Pro available globally, and for good reason — it's great enough to challenge the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">nm4LJmhFj2dR37XBj6jHni</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qMypyPS3qjq6ed3kcFTF8b.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 19:02:40 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qMypyPS3qjq6ed3kcFTF8b.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OPPO Find X8 Pro review]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OPPO Find X8 Pro review]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Leaked Pixel 9a images reaffirm a curious design change ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google's upcoming mid-range Pixel 9a surfaces again with real-life images.</li><li>The device appears to be carrying a new design, as seen in earlier leaked renders.</li><li>The Pixel 9a features dual cameras almost completely flushed on the back, unlike the predecessor models.</li></ul>
<p>Google Pixel leaks way ahead of launch have become quite common over the past couple of years. After seeing the possible renders of Pixel 9a already, we now have a good look at the prototype as well — thanks to a new leak.</p><p>The working prototype of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9a">Pixel 9a</a> has been spotted in the wild (via OnLeaks), revealing the familiar design we have seen in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/supposed-pixel-9a-render-camera-bump-change">earlier leaked renders</a> of the upcoming mid-range handset from Google. It includes a taller screen with a punch hole cutout paired with flat sides and a new, flatter camera housing — an unexpected departure from the iconic bar camera module design, which has been the norm since the Pixel 6 series and has even received a redesign with the latest <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-series-hands-on">Pixel 9</a> models.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">#Google #Pixel9a prototype surfaces once again...😏 https://t.co/snDYlyg3kJ pic.twitter.com/dVt24u8Kae<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1864950242795245860">December 6, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>As seen in the prototype, the new camera housing includes dual cameras nearly flush to the back of the phone, coupled with an LED flash that also resides flat to the back of the phone. The prototype handset further includes a matte finish and can be quite a fingerprint magnet, as seen in the images.</p><p>It isn’t the first time we have seen hands-on images of the Pixel 9a. Even before the leaked renders, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9a-alleged-real-life-photos-leak">alleged Pixel 9a handset</a> prototype was spotted on Facebook, and it looks nearly identical to the latest leaked prototype images. All this evidence points to Google circling out the new design element for the upcoming Pixel 9a, which will perhaps see the light of day sometime around Q2 2025 if previous Pixel A series releases are any indication.</p>
<p>The release is still significantly far away, but recent leaks have pointed out what to expect, including the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9a-color-options-leaked">color options</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9a-battery-capacity-pro-xl-leak">supposed battery capacity</a> of the Pixel 9a. The device is likely to comprise four colorways, including the previous Porcelain and Obsidian colors, next to the new Peony and Iris. The Peony is the latest addition to the Pixel 9 series, and it is an all-new pink color.</p><p>On the other hand, the Pixel 9a is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/pixel-9a-dimension-display-size-rumors">rumored</a> to measure 154.7 x 73.2 x 8.9mm, making the device slightly taller and wider than the previous iteration, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-review">Pixel 8a</a>. However, the Pixel 9a's battery capacity should be close to 5000mAh — a significant 11% overall increase over the predecessor.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u><strong><br></strong></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9a-real-life-images-leak-again</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google is quite far away from launching the Pixel 9a. However, that isn't stopping the device to pop up in real life. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">M8vZufH2JWQRFsgowRrHM7</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/E4D8zdSoWLFvdYwmNZJ99o.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 18:11:35 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/E4D8zdSoWLFvdYwmNZJ99o.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Via OnLeaks]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Pixel 9a real-life image leak]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Pixel 9a real-life image leak]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Report allegedly details Samsung's XR device launch plans for 2025 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A new report claims Samsung is looking ahead to the second half of 2025 to get its XR business moving with its AR glasses.</li><li>Sources suggest Samsung will produce ~20,000 AR glasses for a (potential) Q3 2025 launch before looking to Q4 for another ~30,000.</li><li>A recent patent listing showcased a brief outline of Samsung's planned AR glasses and additional details for its XR headset.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Rumors from South Korea have surfaced about Samsung's apparent 2025 plans for its XR venture.</p><p>Murmurings of Samsung's plans stem from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.sedaily.com/NewsView/2DI1YO5LYZ">Sedaily</a> (Korean), claiming the company will enter "mass production" of an XR product in the "second half" of 2025 (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.sammobile.com/news/samsung-manufacture-50000-xr-headsets-2025-launch/">SamMobile</a>). The publication cites "industry sources" in saying that Samsung views its XR business as something that will "follow" its smartphones in terms of revenue. Moreover, rumors claim that this product could be Samsung's AR glasses.</p><p>As such, rumors allege that the OEM is looking into beginning mass production of its XR device by Q3 2025 — potentially signaling a Q3 launch, as well. This start will supposedly involve the generation of roughly 20,000 devices. What's more, this number <em>could </em>rise; however, the publication's sources claim this is dependent on the AR glasses' market influence.</p><p>If all goes well, Samsung is rumored to prepare another ~30,000 AR glasses by Q4 2025 for the holidays. This puts the company at ~50,000 devices by the second half of next year, but certain variables could adversely or positively affect this prediction.</p><p>Elsewhere, sources state that Samsung is preparing to showcase a "sample" of its upcoming XR launch during Unpacked 2025 in January.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1919px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.18%;"><img id="WybUWZoK6GNWQj3w6pe2k7" name="Samsung-unpacked-Feb-2023-XR.jpg" alt="Samsung Qualcomm Google partnership at Galaxy Unpacked Feb 2023" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WybUWZoK6GNWQj3w6pe2k7.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1919" height="1078" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Samsung)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The last bit of that South Korean report is interesting, considering it doubles down on a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/samsung-smart-glasses-unpacked-2025-glimpse-tipped">previous report on Samsung's glasses</a>. Last week, rumors claimed that we might have a special preview of the company's augmented reality (AR) smart glasses during its next Unpacked event. Details aren't set in stone; however, there's a chance this preview could be a "short video or an image reveal."</p><p>The latest report claims that a "sample" of the device may be showcased during the event. Perhaps there's a chance we'll see a live demo on stage or some sort of live, hands-on demo with it. Samsung is expected to host this Galaxy Unpacked event in January 2025, where we will also see the Galaxy S25's debut.</p><p>Rumors of a pair of AR glasses have been few and far between as, aside from these recent reports, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/samsung-glasses-trademark-approval-spotted">only other arrived late in 2023</a>. The glasses reportedly surfaced at the Intellectual Property Office in the U.K. under the Virtual reality headsets and Augmented reality headsets categories. Curiously, rumors back then suggested a similar number of mass-produced glasses (~30,000 to start) in 2024 — though that clearly didn't happen.</p><p>These glasses also appeared in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/samsung-xr-headset-patent-filing-appearance">WIPO patent database listing</a> alongside Samsung's XR headset. The design was a brief outline, which likely detailed several components for functionality. Samsung's patent detailed the device as "AR glasses and/or a head-mounted device."</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/samsung-xr-ar-devce-2025-launch-plans-rumor</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A report might've detailed Samsung's 2025 outlook for a pair of XR/AR glasses. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">nyeXP7oBtTk7TRwvDCoyxc</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/m9nBdBGHXUwKxDeYWdkv6K.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 18:07:47 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/m9nBdBGHXUwKxDeYWdkv6K.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung logo]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung logo]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google might let you share custom Gems for Gemini in the mobile app ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Gemini Advanced subscribers can create and share Gems, which are custom AI chatbots aimed to help with specialized tasks.</li><li>Currently, Gems can only be shared using the Gemini web client.</li><li>Now, an APK teardown of the Google app beta reveals Gem sharing may be coming to mobile soon.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Since its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-io-2024-biggest-announcements">I/O 2024 developer conference</a>, Google has been quickly ramping up Gemini's capabilities, trying to compete with OpenAI's ChatGPT. Part of that effort included <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/gemini-image-3-custom-gems-update-detailed">introducing Gems in August 2024</a>, which are custom AI chatbots designed to be "experts" in a specific area, according to Google. This functionality is only available for Gemini Advanced, Business, and Enterprise subscribers, and it <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/openai-intros-custom-versions-of-chatgpt">rivals OpenAI's GPT Store</a>.</p><p>After creating a custom Gem, you can save and share it with others, but there's a catch. You can only share custom Gems via the Gemini web client, not through the Gemini mobile app or Google mobile app. There's evidence that might be changing, according from an APK teardown from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/gemini-gem-sharing-on-mobile-3506945/" target="_blank">Android Authority</a>. In <strong>beta version 15.49.40.sa.arm64</strong> of the Google app, the team discovered the ability to <strong>Share conversation and gem instructions</strong> in the mobile app.</p><p>The new option appears amongst the list of options in the action menu for Gemini, alongside the existing option to <strong>Share conversation</strong>. While it's still possible to simply share the Gemini conversation, there's now a separate button that will let you share the conversation and Gem instructions with one tap. Before creating a link with your Gem and current conversation, Google reminds users that this link will become public, and anyone with the link can see the name of the Gem and other information.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4480px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="iP65fpHJeRht24DNN5wBan" name="Gem-Sharing-Mobile" alt="The sharing of custom Gems on mobile." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/iP65fpHJeRht24DNN5wBan.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4480" height="2520" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The new option will make it easier for people to share Gems they've created on mobile. The current workflow forces users to switch to the web client in order to share a Gem, which can be cumbersome. A change, if made public, would make the Gemini and Google apps even closer to the desktop experience in terms of feature parity. By all indications, the ability to create and share custom Gems will still remain a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">paid Gemini Advanced feature</a>.</p><p>It's unclear when the ability to share custom Gems on mobile would be available publicly. However, it's always a good sign that Google is making progress with a feature when it's functional as part of an app beta.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-might-let-you-share-custom-gems-for-gemini-in-the-mobile-app</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Gems, which are custom Gemini chatbots trained for a specific purpose, will now be easier to share on mobile. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">fWjMcXtCh3AUwmumFUPXSb</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Msynp8USt4qpuR962SgJfF.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 18:02:09 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Msynp8USt4qpuR962SgJfF.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Gemini app on Lenovo Chromebook Duet 11]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Gemini app on Lenovo Chromebook Duet 11]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Galaxy S25 Ultra could bump up RAM in its higher-end models ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-32">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Leaks hint at RAM and storage upgrades for the Galaxy S25 Ultra, with some models getting more RAM than before.</li><li>The base model will likely have 12GB of RAM and 256GB storage, while premium versions could offer 16GB RAM and up to 1TB of storage.</li><li>With AI apps becoming more demanding, the RAM boost is likely aimed at keeping up with these trends.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>A fresh leak hints at some exciting RAM and storage upgrades for Samsung’s upcoming Galaxy S25 Ultra. It looks like certain models could pack more RAM than their predecessors.</p><p>A recent post by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/Jukanlosreve/status/1865744112072442342" target="_blank">@Jukanlosreve</a> on X suggests the top-tier <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25">Galaxy S25</a> model might bring a RAM boost for its higher-end models. The base version will likely stick to 12GB of RAM and 256GB of storage, but the premium variants could offer 16GB of RAM with storage options up to 512GB or 1TB (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidpolice.com/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-could-rival-pixel-9-pro-where-matters/" target="_blank">Android Police</a>).</p><p>If this is accurate, the 512GB and 1TB versions of the Galaxy S25 Ultra are set to beat the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review">Galaxy S24 Ultra</a> in RAM, offering 16GB instead of 12GB. Samsung’s move lets users go for more storage without sacrificing RAM, giving them more options to choose from.</p><p>Samsung has always offered different storage options in its Ultra series, but the RAM has mostly stayed the same. The last Ultra model with 16GB of RAM was the Galaxy S21 Ultra, and the ones that followed stuck with 12GB. But it looks like the Galaxy S25 series is ready to change things up.</p><p>This RAM boost will definitely appeal to users who need top-notch performance for multitasking, gaming, and heavy apps. With the higher RAM option, Samsung is looking to strengthen its spot in the competitive smartphone market.</p><p>Moreover, Samsung is apparently looking to stay on top of industry trends with this RAM upgrade, especially with the rise of AI-powered apps. As AI models get more complex and demanding, having more RAM is key for smooth performance.</p><p>That said, the 12GB RAM setup for the 256GB model raises some questions. It’s unclear if this model will have any AI performance limits or if the extra RAM is meant for other performance boosts. Either way, the added RAM will likely improve overall performance, including AI tasks. Hopefully, this upgrade won’t come with a big price increase.</p>
<hr>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="aa703187-580d-4c78-8706-72f644ba13c2">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jH2nkHNQPuwBpm8KyQ6u4c.jpg' alt="samsung galaxy s24 ultra square render - 1"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>The Galaxy S24 Ultra is a tech powerhouse, with an impressive AMOLED display, top-tier hardware, seamless S Pen integration, and a sleek quad-lens rear camera system.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-galaxy-s25-ultra-could-bump-up-ram-in-its-higher-end-models</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Certain Galaxy S25 Ultra models might get a nice performance upgrade. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">ZBoawMAY5fWYXgkvhe7j8M</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/X65GexZdyC98NmHwvCEFNJ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 06:56:06 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/X65GexZdyC98NmHwvCEFNJ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[OnLeaks / Android Headlines]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Galaxy S25 Ultra renders leak]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Galaxy S25 Ultra renders leak]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Docs is tapping into Gemini to whip up formatted documents ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-37">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google Docs is testing a new "Help me create" feature powered by Gemini, allowing you to create formatted docs from scratch.</li><li>You can easily integrate Google Drive files by typing "@" followed by the file name, pulling your content right into the doc.</li><li>While it pulls from Workspace files, it doesn’t keep the original layout or style and can’t generate images of people yet.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google Docs is stepping up its AI capabilities with "Help me create," a Gemini-powered feature that crafts formatted docs from the ground up.</p><p>According to Google Docs' <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/docs/answer/15541387" target="_blank">support page</a>, the experimental "Help me create" feature, powered by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini</a>, lets you generate formatted docs straight from your Google Workspace files. Just type "@" and the file name, and your Drive files are instantly in the mix (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/12/06/google-docs-help-me-create/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a>).</p><p>This new feature pairs perfectly with the "Help me write" tool, letting you tweak text or whip up something totally new. You can create anything from proposals and project trackers to dinner menus, vacation plans, or even brainstorms and blog posts.</p><p>Give Gemini AI a bit of context—like your audience, purpose, or goals—and it can fine-tune templates to fit your needs.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1280px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:62.50%;"><img id="JoeyFGxT7uj4CCk8SKoTRg" name="Google-Docs-help-me-create" alt="Help me create feature in Google Docs" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JoeyFGxT7uj4CCk8SKoTRg.gif" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1280" height="800" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While the "Help me create" feature can pull from various <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/everything-you-need-know-about-google-workspace-spaces-and-smart-canvas">Workspace</a> files, it won’t keep the original layout or style. It also can’t generate inline or cover images of people yet. For best results, try using natural, conversational language when making prompts.</p><p>When it’s ready, you’ll see the "Help me create" prompt pop up at the top, right next to your usual options like meeting notes, cover images, polls, and the like.</p><p>Alternatively, you can find "Help me create" by going to the "File" menu, hitting "New," and selecting it from there. Then, just pick the type of doc you want to make.</p><p>The latest addition is part of the company’s focus on boosting productivity and creativity. This fits right in with the latest AI advancements, including the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-docs-now-uses-imagen-3-for-custom-image-generation-if-youre-a-paid-user">ability to generate images in Google Docs with Gemini</a>.</p><p>The "Help me create" feature is currently web-only and available only to those in the Gemini for Google Workspace Alpha and Workspace Labs programs. It's also limited to new, blank docs and being rolled out slowly.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-docs-is-tapping-into-gemini-to-whip-up-formatted-documents</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ With Gemini, you can now create formatted docs in Google Docs from scratch. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">AdaKKJ7dyW6h7SVJ7YABpa</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HmgT6NLvyE4WELvEBJTPtb.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 05:37:51 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HmgT6NLvyE4WELvEBJTPtb.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Docs logo on a laptop screen]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Docs logo on a laptop screen]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>