<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 09:41:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ This tiny dongle fixes the biggest problem with Kindles, and it's just $15 for Cyber Monday ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>I exclusively use the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/five-years-later-the-kindle-oasis-is-still-the-best-e-reader-ive-used-and-thats-a-problem">Kindle Oasis</a> to read books, but after five years of continuous use, the battery life on the e-reader is pitiful, and it only lasts a few days between charges. I had to travel recently, so instead of the Oasis, I took the Voyage. While the Voyage also has a similar-quality screen, the page turn buttons on the sides are woefully inadequate, and I hated using it. <br><br>That is the case with all new Kindles as well, with Amazon ditching physical page turn buttons altogether. Thankfully, DATAFY's accessory solves this problem; the accessory attaches to the side of the e-reader, and you can use the bundled remote control to physically turn pages on your Kindle. It's a novel solution, and it transforms how you use an e-reader. Best of all, it's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/DATAFY-Paperwhite-eReaders-Recording-Triggers/dp/B0CN6SSC17">just $15 right now</a>, so you're not spending too much cash either.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="615a08da-1e6d-4abe-ac40-d5b55914b867" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="This tiny attachment brings a page turning button back to the Kindle, and if you use e-readers a lot, it is a must-have accessory." data-dimension48="This tiny attachment brings a page turning button back to the Kindle, and if you use e-readers a lot, it is a must-have accessory." data-dimension25="$15" href="https://www.amazon.com/DATAFY-Paperwhite-eReaders-Recording-Triggers/dp/B0CN6SSC17" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:818px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:148.17%;"><img id="iFEmv6qc7mBBqhMYQ3YSTQ" name="page-turn" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/iFEmv6qc7mBBqhMYQ3YSTQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="818" height="1212" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>This tiny attachment brings a page turning button back to the Kindle, and if you use e-readers a lot, it is a must-have accessory. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/DATAFY-Paperwhite-eReaders-Recording-Triggers/dp/B0CN6SSC17" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="615a08da-1e6d-4abe-ac40-d5b55914b867" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="This tiny attachment brings a page turning button back to the Kindle, and if you use e-readers a lot, it is a must-have accessory." data-dimension48="This tiny attachment brings a page turning button back to the Kindle, and if you use e-readers a lot, it is a must-have accessory." data-dimension25="$15">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if:</strong> You need a page turner button to use with your e-reader. <br><strong><br>❌Skip this deal if:</strong> You need a button that goes to previous page as well as the next one.</p>
<p>The best part about the Oasis is the physical page-turn buttons; you just get much better tactility, and I got so used to the feature that I can't go back to a regular Kindle. It's annoying that Amazon doesn't sell the Oasis any longer, nor is there a new model that includes page turn buttons. The only alternative is to use an accessory like the DATAFY attachment, and to its credit, it does a great job. <br><br>The dongle attaches to the Kindle, and the page turning is by way of a remote that you hold in your hand. The remote uses an RF signal to connect to the dongle, and it doesn't need Bluetooth. Battery life is great, and it charges over USB-C. The only issue is that because it connects to one side, you can use it to go to the next page in a book; if you need to go back, you'll need to use the touch controls on the other side.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/this-tiny-dongle-fixes-the-biggest-problem-with-kindles-and-its-just-usd15-for-cyber-monday</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ DATAFY's dongle brings page turning buttons back to Kindles.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">6cSheWfunS8Q7cowhaGPGh</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qf4HvVXazz36xZ8oG9yJUQ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 09:30:48 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qf4HvVXazz36xZ8oG9yJUQ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[DATAFY ]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[DATAFY Page Turn Remote Control render]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[DATAFY Page Turn Remote Control render]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ WHAT?! How is the Amazfit Balance already on sale for this cheap? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/black-friday-2024">Cyber Monday 2024</a> is almost upon us and boy are the deals getting good. The recently launched <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/amazfit-balance-review">Amazfit Balance</a> has now gone on sale, even though we didn&apos;t see any Black Friday discounts on it. The Balance has many pros to its name, but the best feature about this smartwatch is undoubtedly its battery life which goes up to 20 days.</p><p>This Cyber Monday deal brings down the price of the Amazfit Balance by a whopping 30%. If you want to take up on this offer, it&apos;s available on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://amazon.com/dp/B0C7GGYS7M"><strong>Amazon for $139.99</strong></a>. For a wearable that usually costs about $200, that&apos;s an insanely good discount!</p><p>I just reviewed the Amazfit Balance and gave it a very good rating. What sets this watch apart is the AI features baked in, like Zepp Flow, Zepp Coach, and Zepp Aura. It uses AI to learn from your metrics and design strategies for you to hit your fitness goals smartly, based on the data collected.</p><p>The smartwatch also has plenty of watch faces, a solid companion app, and over 150 sports modes. Then there&apos;s also a ton of health tracking metrics such as heart rate monitoring, SpO2 monitoring, sleep tracking, menstrual tracking, and more! It&apos;s one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-amazfit-smartwatch">best Amazfit smartwatches</a> for sure, and easy on the eyes too.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="c380ce62-90da-455a-924f-59732d24badc" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Amazfit Balance: $199.99" data-dimension48="Amazfit Balance: $199.99" href="https://amazon.com/dp/B0C7GGYS7M" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="pezmQeG4BtLgLcGiqi6mQ3" name="amazfit-balance-render-w-space" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pezmQeG4BtLgLcGiqi6mQ3.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1080" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Amazfit Balance: </strong><a href="https://amazon.com/dp/B0C7GGYS7M" data-dimension112="c380ce62-90da-455a-924f-59732d24badc" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Amazfit Balance: $199.99" data-dimension48="Amazfit Balance: $199.99" data-dimension25=""><del>$199.99</del><strong> $139.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>The Amazfit Balance destroys every other smartwatch when it comes to battery life. A single full charge can last you two to three weeks easily, so you will never have battery anxiety again. Other than that, the Balance is extremely lightweight, boasts 5ATM waterproofing, and comes with over 150 sports modes. With 30% off this Cyber Monday, the watch is cheaper than it has ever been.</p>
<p><strong>Price comparison: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/amazfit-balance-smartwatch-38mm-aluminum-alloy-black/6554708.p"><strong>$149.99 at Best Buy</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Amazfit-Balance-Smartwatch-38mm-Aluminum-Alloy-W2287GL2N-Black/5209727653"><strong>$149.99 at Walmart</strong></a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://amazon.com/dp/B0C7GGYS7M" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="c380ce62-90da-455a-924f-59732d24badc" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Amazfit Balance: $199.99" data-dimension48="Amazfit Balance: $199.99" data-dimension25="">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>you hate charging your wearable, require NFC for payments, want Alexa onboard, and like to track your health and fitness metrics.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>you want access to a lot more third-party apps and need an accurate pedometer as a serious sportsperson.</p><p>If you&apos;re interested in a full-length evaluation of the Amazfit Balance, you can read my in-depth review. What I can summarize for you is that this is an excellent budget smartwatch that works really well for everyday use. This smartwatch has Alexa onboard, a built-in speaker and mic combo, as well as GPS and NFC for payments.</p><p>I also love the fact that you can store music locally on your Amazfit Balance and pair your Bluetooth headphones or earbuds with it directly. And if you forgot your earbuds, it just plays the music out loud through the watch&apos;s speaker.</p><p>Although the Amazfit Balance doesn&apos;t support hundreds and thousands of apps like Wear OS, the current selection of apps is decent enough. You can respond to messages on the notification bar with a full QWERTY keyboard too, which was not an option on older Amazfit smartwatches. It&apos;s not as capable as a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wear-os-watch">Wear OS watch</a>, but still an excellent smart wearable for the price.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/what-how-is-the-amazfit-balance-already-on-sale-for-this-cheap</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ It's so new that it's hard to believe that the Amazfit Balance is already on sale with this Cyber Monday deal, taking 30% off the retail price. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">MzLW94H6FA722rTTCXWjPN</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NfopaUXyDgyVNcuw8jotcV.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 08:44:06 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NfopaUXyDgyVNcuw8jotcV.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Amazfit Balance smartwatch]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Amazfit Balance smartwatch]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Ditch your boring cable — this retractable 100W USB-C cable is much better, and it's on sale for Cyber Monday ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>I have way too many cables in the house, and the biggest issue is the inevitable tangle when I have more than two cables on my desk. Thankfully, Baseus came to the rescue with this retractable USB-C cable, and I haven't used anything else in the past year. Having a retractable cable makes a huge difference in regular use; I don't need to worry about cluttering up my desk, and it's a more elegant solution. <br><br>The best part is that Baseus's retractable cable charges at 100W, making it a great choice to use with phones, notebooks, and just about any accessory. The cable has four preset lengths and goes up to two meters when fully extended, and it tucks away neatly when not in use. It usually costs $18, but you can <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Baseus-Retractable-Charging-4-Stage-Charger/dp/B0CZDJTRPZ">get it for $13 during Cyber Monday</a>, and that's a decent deal.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="48c0295e-54e0-45ab-a400-37b5fc705786" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="This retractable cable is significantly easier to use, has great build quality, and charges your devices at 100W. I have four of these in the house now, and it's now my go-to choice when I need to connect two devices, charge phones, or just about anything else that involves a USB-C cable." data-dimension48="This retractable cable is significantly easier to use, has great build quality, and charges your devices at 100W. I have four of these in the house now, and it's now my go-to choice when I need to connect two devices, charge phones, or just about anything else that involves a USB-C cable." data-dimension25="$13" href="https://www.amazon.com/Baseus-Retractable-Charging-4-Stage-Charger/dp/B0CZDJTRPZ" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1200px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="EQGFvyzQ3nibZUbLpBHNg8" name="baseus-100w-cable.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/EQGFvyzQ3nibZUbLpBHNg8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1200" height="1500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>This retractable cable is significantly easier to use, has great build quality, and charges your devices at 100W. I have four of these in the house now, and it's now my go-to choice when I need to connect two devices, charge phones, or just about anything else that involves a USB-C cable. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/Baseus-Retractable-Charging-4-Stage-Charger/dp/B0CZDJTRPZ" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="48c0295e-54e0-45ab-a400-37b5fc705786" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="This retractable cable is significantly easier to use, has great build quality, and charges your devices at 100W. I have four of these in the house now, and it's now my go-to choice when I need to connect two devices, charge phones, or just about anything else that involves a USB-C cable." data-dimension48="This retractable cable is significantly easier to use, has great build quality, and charges your devices at 100W. I have four of these in the house now, and it's now my go-to choice when I need to connect two devices, charge phones, or just about anything else that involves a USB-C cable." data-dimension25="$13">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if:</strong> You need a retractable cable that can deliver 100W of power over the USB PD standard.<br><strong><br>❌Skip this deal if:</strong> You don't care about the retractable design.</p>
<p>I used this cable for over a year now, and it is still going strong. What I like the most about it is the preset lengths; I usually have my phone on a stand and run a cable via the charging station, and one of the preset lengths on the cable is the ideal distance. The actual cable itself is flat, and it didn't have any problems delivering 100W of power to my devices. <br><br>It's good when transferring data between devices as well; I switch between phones every ten days on average, and I only used this cable to do so in the last year. The retractable mechanism is smooth, the case is made out of a matte texture, and overall, this is one of the best cables I have in the house. If you need a clutter-free cable with a retractable design, you can <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Baseus-Retractable-Charging-4-Stage-Charger/dp/B0CZDJTRPZ">now get it for just $13</a> — it holds up just as well in the car.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/ditch-your-boring-cable-this-retractable-100w-usb-c-cable-is-much-better-and-its-on-sale-for-cyber-monday</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Baseus makes a retractable USB-C cable, and it's so good I don't use anything else.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">455uFcozocK2KoRV6k3Z7E</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/B3Au7JKZG2fqp5gHx3LnfG.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 08:37:16 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/B3Au7JKZG2fqp5gHx3LnfG.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Baseus USB-C to USB-C 100W Retractable Cable]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Baseus USB-C to USB-C 100W Retractable Cable]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Pixel users are getting a pesky notification bug from a Quick Phrases glitch ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Pixel users are dealing with a bug in Google Assistant’s Quick Phrases, causing annoying toast notifications to stay on screen.</li><li>The issue involves the 'Say Stop' prompt not disappearing after alarms or timers are turned off, with reports on both stable and beta Android 15 versions.</li><li>The bug seems to be tied to the Google app, which powers both Gemini and Assistant, and there’s no fix yet.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Pixel owners are facing a persistent <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-assistant">Google Assistant</a> Quick Phrases bug, leaving annoying toast notifications on their screens.</p><p>Quick Phrases are meant to simplify voice commands like stopping alarms or handling calls. However, multiple <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/android_beta/comments/1h0x4z2/qpr2_beta_anyone_getting_the_quick_phrases_answer/" target="_blank">Reddit users</a> are reporting about a lingering issue with Google Assistant’s 'Say Stop' prompt. Apparently, the notification refuses to disappear even after alarms or timers are turned off (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/11/29/pixel-quick-phrases-bug/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a>).</p><p>In one instance, the bug has been spotted on a Pixel 8 running <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a>. One user reported the 'Say Stop' prompt sticking around, even on the lock screen.</p><p>The issue isn’t tied to a specific device or software version, with users on both stable and beta Android 15 reporting the problem.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/pixel-say-answer-bug-fix-3504194/" target="_blank">Android Authority</a> has spotted a similar glitch on a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-review">Pixel 9 Pro XL</a> with the latest Android 15 update. When receiving a call, a toast notification popped up, asking users to "Say ‘Answer’".</p><p>While this notification was supposed to disappear once the call ends, it stuck around and locked up that area of the screen. Even worse, it covered the caller ID, making it hard to see who’s calling before you answer.</p><p>As 9to5Google pointed out, this ongoing issue seems to stem from the Google app, which powers both Gemini and Assistant. Until Google rolls out a fix, users might have to rely on temporary workarounds to deal with the annoying toast notification glitch.</p><p>Some users have found that restarting their device clears up the persistent bubble issue, while others have had luck disabling certain toggles in the Quick Phrases menu.</p><p>As a quick fix, Android Authority suggests force-closing and reopening the Google app (found in Settings > Apps > Google) to get rid of the persistent notification.</p><p>Alternatively, turning off the Quick Phrases feature can offer a more lasting solution, since force-stopping the Google app is just a temporary fix that might pop up again with future calls.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/pixel-users-are-getting-a-pesky-notification-bug-from-a-quick-phrases-glitch</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A tiny bug in Google Assistant's Quick Phrases is creating a big headache for Pixel owners. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">V4trdAv2Shvq2BZLoLhb7J</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sbYuZheHwLgaRf2vNq8GrE.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 07:59:53 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sbYuZheHwLgaRf2vNq8GrE.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Pixel 9 top-down view of home screen]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Pixel 9 top-down view of home screen]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ You don't need another charger, but this Cyber Monday deal will make you buy one anyway ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>I've lost count of the number of chargers I have in the house. I got everything from tiny 20W GaN chargers to gargantuan charging stations that go up to 300W, alongside the monstrosities that OnePlus and Vivo bundle with their phones. While it's obviously great to have choices, I only really use two chargers on a daily basis: the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/ugreen-nexode-200w-review">Nexode 200W charging station</a> is handy at charging up to six devices at once, and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/ugreen-nexode-pro-gan-chargers-launch">Nexode Pro 160W</a> is what I use in the bedroom to charge phones and smartwatches. <br><br>If you just want something that you can use on your desk, the Nexode 200W is a decent choice, and it's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/UGREEN-Nexode-200W-Desktop-Charger/dp/B09MGRNYHH">down to $97</a> now. But if you've also amassed a collection of chargers over the years and just want one that handles everything, you should pick up the Nexode Pro 160W. It usually costs $119, but the charger is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/UGREEN-Charger-Compact-MacBook-Pixelbook/dp/B0CCVPB4PC">down to $95 for Cyber Monday</a>, and while that's still quite a lot of cash to put toward an accessory, it is the best all-in-one GaN charger I've used, and it's worth the purchase.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="c7279adc-3c0a-4d21-8d0b-77e30c17d7cb" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="The Nexode Pro 160W has three USB-C ports and a USB-A port, and it does a great job charging four devices at once. The reason I'm recommending this charger is because of the main USB-C port, which goes up to 140W — allowing you to easily charge your MacBook or Windows notebook." data-dimension48="The Nexode Pro 160W has three USB-C ports and a USB-A port, and it does a great job charging four devices at once. The reason I'm recommending this charger is because of the main USB-C port, which goes up to 140W — allowing you to easily charge your MacBook or Windows notebook." data-dimension25="$95" href="https://www.amazon.com/UGREEN-Charger-Compact-MacBook-Pixelbook/dp/B0CCVPB4PC" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1125px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:133.33%;"><img id="TSUi6mEq8o7Q4vf49S9hDB" name="nexode-pro-160w.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TSUi6mEq8o7Q4vf49S9hDB.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1125" height="1500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>The Nexode Pro 160W has three USB-C ports and a USB-A port, and it does a great job charging four devices at once. The reason I'm recommending this charger is because of the main USB-C port, which goes up to 140W — allowing you to easily charge your MacBook or Windows notebook. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/UGREEN-Charger-Compact-MacBook-Pixelbook/dp/B0CCVPB4PC" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="c7279adc-3c0a-4d21-8d0b-77e30c17d7cb" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="The Nexode Pro 160W has three USB-C ports and a USB-A port, and it does a great job charging four devices at once. The reason I'm recommending this charger is because of the main USB-C port, which goes up to 140W — allowing you to easily charge your MacBook or Windows notebook." data-dimension48="The Nexode Pro 160W has three USB-C ports and a USB-A port, and it does a great job charging four devices at once. The reason I'm recommending this charger is because of the main USB-C port, which goes up to 140W — allowing you to easily charge your MacBook or Windows notebook." data-dimension25="$95">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>You need an all-in-one charger that doesn't take up much room and still manages to charge all of your tech. I used the Nexode Pro 160W for a year now, and it has been faultless. <br><br><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>You don't need 140W charging. If you want a 100W GaN charger instead, I recommend this Anker charger instead, which is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Anker-Charger-GaNPrime-Compact-Foldable/dp/B09W2PNLX7">now available for $59</a>.</p>
<p>The Nexode Pro 160W is smaller than any of the other 140W GaN chargers I tested, and the foldable pins make it a great choice if you need to take it on the road. I used this charger every day throughout 2024, and didn't run into any issues whatsoever. I charged over a hundred different devices in that time — including 70 or so Android phones, a dozen tablets, my Steam Deck, and a smorgasbord of accessories. <br><br>It uses the USB PD 3.1 protocol to deliver 140W of power to the primary USB-C port, with the secondary USB-C port going up to 100W, and the third hitting 30W. When the two main USB-C ports are in use, you get 100W out of one and 60W out the other, and the 160W power budget should be ideal to charge a notebook and phone or any accessory like a Steam Deck, which only needs 35W. <br><br>With all ports in simultaneous use, you get a total power budget of 135W, with 65W each going to the primary USB-C ports, and 15W split evenly between the third USB-C and USB-A ports. Basically, you can charge a phone, notebook, smartwatch, and any other accessory just with a single charger. While there are dozens of products that do the same, the Nexode Pro 160W has been the most reliable in my testing, and with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/UGREEN-Charger-Compact-MacBook-Pixelbook/dp/B0CCVPB4PC">discount to $95</a>, it is a smidgen more affordable, and that's always a good thing.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/you-dont-need-another-charger-but-this-cyber-monday-deal-will-make-you-buy-one-anyway</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ UGREEN's Nexode Pro 160W is the best all-in-one GaN charger I used, and it will easily charge all of your tech.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">ZgenRrJhhLBeEmEcWzDtdU</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pu4eic4thFVLkTqjijCtv6.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 04:28:38 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pu4eic4thFVLkTqjijCtv6.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[UGREEN Nexode Pro 100W and 160W GaN chargers]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[UGREEN Nexode Pro 100W and 160W GaN chargers]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ I never leave the house without this unique power bank, and you should snag one before Black Friday/Cyber Monday weekend ends ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>It's my belief that everyone should own at least one portable power bank. There are plenty of great options out there, like this large <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/i-cant-live-without-this-25-000mah-power-bank-and-now-its-cheaper-than-its-ever-been-for-black-friday">25,000mAh UGREEN power bank with 145W charging</a>. However, you always have to take size into consideration, and the more capacity a power bank has, the larger it'll be. That's why I love this Anker Nano Power Bank (30W), which is on sale for Black Friday/Cyber Monday with a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C9CJKCH3/">25% discount</a>.</p><p>The Anker Nano Power Bank (30W) normally sells for $39.99, which already isn't bad for what you get. But for Black Friday/Cyber Monday, this 25% off deal brings it down to $29.99, a small but welcome discount for a surprisingly versatile power bank.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="565e6fe8-721b-458d-9f2a-09201189a980" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Snag this 25% deal on the Anker Nano Power Bank, which you can have for just under $30. You get plenty of battery power and multiple USB ports, making this a worthwhile deal whether you're an Android or iPhone user." data-dimension48="Snag this 25% deal on the Anker Nano Power Bank, which you can have for just under $30. You get plenty of battery power and multiple USB ports, making this a worthwhile deal whether you're an Android or iPhone user." data-dimension25="$29.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C9CJKCH3/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1200px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="iFHvRMhqPS2L9oF5W35Wy" name="Anker-Nano-Power-bank.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/iFHvRMhqPS2L9oF5W35Wy.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1200" height="1200" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>Snag this 25% deal on the Anker Nano Power Bank, which you can have for just under $30. You get plenty of battery power and multiple USB ports, making this a worthwhile deal whether you're an Android or iPhone user.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C9CJKCH3/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="565e6fe8-721b-458d-9f2a-09201189a980" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Snag this 25% deal on the Anker Nano Power Bank, which you can have for just under $30. You get plenty of battery power and multiple USB ports, making this a worthwhile deal whether you're an Android or iPhone user." data-dimension48="Snag this 25% deal on the Anker Nano Power Bank, which you can have for just under $30. You get plenty of battery power and multiple USB ports, making this a worthwhile deal whether you're an Android or iPhone user." data-dimension25="$29.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Black Friday/Cyber Monday</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Cyber Monday Google Pixel deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Cyber Monday Motorola deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024-early-deals-and-how-to-prepare-for-the-big-sales">Cyber Monday Samsung deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Cyber Monday OnePlus deals</a></p></div></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>You want a power bank with plenty of power and easy portability thanks to its small size and looping USB-C cord.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>You want something that charges faster than 30W and has a larger capacity than 10,000mAh.</p><p>There's a lot to like about the Anker Nano Power Bank. The 10,000mAh capacity means I can charge my <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/this-motorola-razr-plus-2024-deal-is-wild">Razr Plus 2024</a> at least twice, making it more than enough for me on any given day, particularly when at conventions and such. Then there's the fact that it has a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/everything-you-need-know-about-usb-c" target="_blank">USB-C</a> and USB-A port since the former is the new standard, and the latter is still pretty common (just ask OnePlus).</p><p>The best part is that the attached USB-C cable loops into the device, making the power bank easy to carry around, whether that's just in your hand or looped onto your bag. As <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-battery-packs">portable chargers and power banks</a> go, it's incredibly convenient, as is the mini display on the side of the device that tells you how much time is left to charge your phone and how much capacity remains in the charger.</p><p>The 30W charging speed is also fast enough for some of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a>, including the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/ditch-your-boring-phone-for-the-galaxy-z-flip-6-now-more-than-usd300-off">Galaxy Z Flip 6</a> (25W) and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-amazon-black-friday-sale-has-finally-fixed-the-google-pixel-9s-price-problem">Pixel 9</a> (27W). My <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2024-review">Razr Plus 2024</a> charges at 45W and would still top up pretty quickly with the Anker Nano Power Bank, which is why I would recommend it to anyone looking for a compact power bank.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/i-never-leave-the-house-without-this-unique-power-bank-and-you-should-snag-one-before-black-friday-cyber-monday-weekend-ends</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Anker's best portable power bank is on sale for Black Friday/Cyber Monday. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">eRCVVrQtzFfwrQRXWoZhwc</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/N9YD9PyjJRRcffZeQLhMCK.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 03:06:27 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ derrek.lee@futurenet.com (Derrek Lee) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/N9YD9PyjJRRcffZeQLhMCK.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Anker Nano Power Bank 10,000mAh]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Anker Nano Power Bank 10,000mAh]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ I almost made a big mistake and clicked 'Buy' on the wrong product — then I looked at the reviews and got this instead ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>That was a close one! I'll start by saying that I was fully set on buying the Ultimate Ears (UE) Boom 4 during Black Friday/Cyber Monday. I have an older version of the speaker from many years ago, and it was always my favorite thing to bring around small gatherings. However, after reading the reviews, I changed my mind and decided to go for this <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CXKSCY1G/">Sony ULT Field 1 deal</a> instead.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/sony-ult-field-1-review">Sony ULT Field 1</a> was released earlier this year and retails for just $130. That's already not bad, but I prefer to stick to speakers under $100 if I can help it. Fortunately, this Black Friday/Cyber Monday deal brings the price down to $98, which is right at the top of my self-imposed price range (I'm cheap, so what?).</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="f5eafc08-a0d3-4d77-9569-c7f3bf50b0f4" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="The ULT Field 1 is the cheapest speaker in Sony's new lineup, but Black Friday/Cyber Monday makes it even cheaper. This 25% discount drops the price below $100, which makes this a perfect buy for you or a friend." data-dimension48="The ULT Field 1 is the cheapest speaker in Sony's new lineup, but Black Friday/Cyber Monday makes it even cheaper. This 25% discount drops the price below $100, which makes this a perfect buy for you or a friend." data-dimension25="$98.00" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CXKSCY1G/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="97wu6zVwjT6ZTzdAcfw4pL" name="sony-ult-field-1-square.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/97wu6zVwjT6ZTzdAcfw4pL.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1080" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>The ULT Field 1 is the cheapest speaker in Sony's new lineup, but Black Friday/Cyber Monday makes it even cheaper. This 25% discount drops the price below $100, which makes this a perfect buy for you or a friend.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CXKSCY1G/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="f5eafc08-a0d3-4d77-9569-c7f3bf50b0f4" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="The ULT Field 1 is the cheapest speaker in Sony's new lineup, but Black Friday/Cyber Monday makes it even cheaper. This 25% discount drops the price below $100, which makes this a perfect buy for you or a friend." data-dimension48="The ULT Field 1 is the cheapest speaker in Sony's new lineup, but Black Friday/Cyber Monday makes it even cheaper. This 25% discount drops the price below $100, which makes this a perfect buy for you or a friend." data-dimension25="$98.00">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Black Friday/Cyber Monday</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Cyber Monday Google Pixel deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Cyber Monday Motorola deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024-early-deals-and-how-to-prepare-for-the-big-sales">Cyber Monday Samsung deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Cyber Monday OnePlus deals</a></p></div></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>You want a portable speaker with great bass, long battery life, and a good design with support for high-quality audio codecs.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>You want the best sound experience and want the option to utilize a 3.5mm audio jack or USB-C connection for audio playback.</p><p>I'm by no means an audiophile, so I see no point in paying top dollar to have the absolute best sound. I was hoping the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CVFKZ1LC">UE Boom 4</a> would satisfy my need for a new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-bluetooth-speakers">Bluetooth speaker</a> to have at get-togethers, as I remember really liking my older UE Boom. That said, Amazon warned me that the product is frequently returned, and upon reading reviews, many people noted that the speaker was pretty lacking when it comes to bass, which is something I <em>do</em> need (a guy's gotta twerk).</p><p>That's when I remembered our <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/sony-ult-field-1-review">Sony ULT Field 1 review</a>, which was done by Android Central contributor Tshaka Armstrong. I read through his review, as well as the reviews on Amazon, and decided this is exactly what I need. Granted, he is an audiophile, so his score is lower than the one on Amazon, but poor sound quality is not among his reasons. He notes a lack of USB-C audio and a 3.5mm audio jack as his main negatives.</p><p>As far as audio quality goes, Armstrong says the Sony ULT Field 1 sounds fine but a little flat if the UTL mode is turned off. However, he notes that "turning it on immediately imbues presence and depth to the sound, making the music fuller and more robust close-up and at greater distances like 50 feet." He even says the ULTE Field 1 is his new go-to take-along speaker.</p><p>Others in the Amazon reviews also note how it has good sound quality, with one review highlighting how the speaker is "<strong>LOUDDDDD as hell</strong>." That's all more than enough to convince me that this is the portable speaker that I need to buy.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/sony-ult-field-1-black-friday-cyber-monday-2024-deal</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Make sure you read reviews when looking for products to buy online, especially during Black Friday/Cyber Monday. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">o5tTqr2wAdSUHwhdZGQvd8</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/W7ow2habKZTrGqJCwtFYQQ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 01:04:43 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ derrek.lee@futurenet.com (Derrek Lee) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/W7ow2habKZTrGqJCwtFYQQ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Tshaka Armstrong]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Sony ULT Field 1]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Sony ULT Field 1]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Skip the Galaxy Watch Ultra: These two Android smartwatches cost half as much and last longer ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>I reviewed and loved the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-ultra-review">Galaxy Watch Ultra</a>; it may be the best premium Android smartwatch of the year. But it's expensive as hell, even with this <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/watches/galaxy-watch-ultra/buy/galaxy-watch-ultra-47mm-titanium-gray-sm-l705udaaxaa/"><strong>$215-off Black Friday deal</strong></a>. Unless you have a good watch to trade in — which can cut the price another $300 — $434 is more than most of you will be willing to pay.</p><p>Looking strictly at Wear OS watches that beat the Galaxy Watch Ultra's 72-hour battery life, you have two main options with major Black Friday discounts: The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-100-Hour-Tracking-Sapphire-Dual-Engine/dp/B0CV5ZG5TC"><strong>OnePlus Watch 2 for $199 ($100 off)</strong></a> or the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Ticwatch-Pro-Enduro-Smartwatch-Compatible/dp/B0D179VBXY"><strong>TicWatch Pro 5 Enduro for $209 ($140 off)</strong></a> with the Amazon coupon.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oneplus-watch-2-review">OnePlus Watch 2</a> can last anywhere from 90 to 100 hours per charge thanks to some incredible hybrid efficiency, using its special OnePlus-brand coprocessor to power things while barely using battery life. With its RTOS-only mode, its battery jumps to <em>a week</em> while still showing calls and notifications, whereas other low-power modes only show the time.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="b9b3801c-ca8f-464f-b5cb-a7a1e3d95577" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Pixel Watch 3" data-dimension48="Pixel Watch 3" data-dimension25="$199.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-100-Hour-Tracking-Sapphire-Dual-Engine/dp/B0CV5ZG5TC" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="hfR3taXQxKFmeYGrH3pmEc" name="oneplus watch 2 square render 2.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hfR3taXQxKFmeYGrH3pmEc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="800" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>The OnePlus Watch 2 has the same processor, RAM, storage, 1.43-inch AMOLED display size, and water resistance as the excellent <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-3-review" data-dimension112="b9b3801c-ca8f-464f-b5cb-a7a1e3d95577" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Pixel Watch 3" data-dimension48="Pixel Watch 3" data-dimension25="$199.99">Pixel Watch 3</a>; unlike that watch, it lasts four days per charge and has a military-grade stainless steel case with full IP68 dust and water protection.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-100-Hour-Tracking-Sapphire-Dual-Engine/dp/B0CV5ZG5TC" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="b9b3801c-ca8f-464f-b5cb-a7a1e3d95577" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Pixel Watch 3" data-dimension48="Pixel Watch 3" data-dimension25="$199.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>Then you have the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/mobvoi-ticwatch-pro-5-enduro-review">TicWatch Pro 5 Enduro</a>, which <em>starts</em> at 90 hours per charge but can last at least a <em>month</em> using its secondary, low-res screen, a trick unique to Mobvoi watches. Like the OnePlus Watch 2, its Black Friday deal puts it at less than half of what the Ultra costs.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="a086c956-2984-4bf3-97fa-93ef86ce28a1" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="The TicWatch Pro 5 Enduro is a rugged watch with 1.43-inch AMOLED display, Snapdragon W5+ Gen 1 processor with 2GB of RAM, a lightweight design, and Wear OS 4 software. Unlike the OnePlus Watch 2, it has a working crown for easier controls. Make sure to click the coupon before buying it to get the full discount!" data-dimension48="The TicWatch Pro 5 Enduro is a rugged watch with 1.43-inch AMOLED display, Snapdragon W5+ Gen 1 processor with 2GB of RAM, a lightweight design, and Wear OS 4 software. Unlike the OnePlus Watch 2, it has a working crown for easier controls. Make sure to click the coupon before buying it to get the full discount!" data-dimension25="$209.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/Ticwatch-Pro-Enduro-Smartwatch-Compatible/dp/B0D179VBXY" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="BcJ6h7TPbheCkAkq7M8jMM" name="ticwatch-pro-5-enduro-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BcJ6h7TPbheCkAkq7M8jMM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="500" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>The TicWatch Pro 5 Enduro is a rugged watch with 1.43-inch AMOLED display, Snapdragon W5+ Gen 1 processor with 2GB of RAM, a lightweight design, and Wear OS 4 software. Unlike the OnePlus Watch 2, it has a working crown for easier controls. Make sure to click the coupon before buying it to get the full discount!<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/Ticwatch-Pro-Enduro-Smartwatch-Compatible/dp/B0D179VBXY" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="a086c956-2984-4bf3-97fa-93ef86ce28a1" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="The TicWatch Pro 5 Enduro is a rugged watch with 1.43-inch AMOLED display, Snapdragon W5+ Gen 1 processor with 2GB of RAM, a lightweight design, and Wear OS 4 software. Unlike the OnePlus Watch 2, it has a working crown for easier controls. Make sure to click the coupon before buying it to get the full discount!" data-dimension48="The TicWatch Pro 5 Enduro is a rugged watch with 1.43-inch AMOLED display, Snapdragon W5+ Gen 1 processor with 2GB of RAM, a lightweight design, and Wear OS 4 software. Unlike the OnePlus Watch 2, it has a working crown for easier controls. Make sure to click the coupon before buying it to get the full discount!" data-dimension25="$209.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>If you want a detailed breakdown on how these two watches compare to Samsung's flagship watch, I wrote a guide on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-ultra-vs-ticwatch-pro-5-enduro">Galaxy Watch Ultra vs. TicWatch Pro 5 Enduro</a>, while another colleague wrote how the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-ultra-vs-oneplus-watch-2">Watch Ultra and OnePlus Watch 2 compare</a>.</p><p>By and large, the Galaxy Watch Ultra <em>is</em> better. It beats the Enduro for faster software updates, Google Assistant support, built-in LTE, and brighter display. But the Enduro is more comfortable to wear and (again) costs so much less while offering most of the same Play Store apps.</p><p>As for the OnePlus Watch 2, it matches the Ultra with dual-band GPS, performance, and durability, while falling a bit short for health accuracy and lacking an LTE option. Neither watch has a working crown, so the TicWatch is your choice if you need one.</p><p>Again, the Galaxy Watch Ultra <em>is</em> better than both of these watches; it's the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch#section-best-premium-pick">best premium Android watch</a> thanks to its stylish, rugged titanium frame, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-ultra-fitness-test">accurate fitness data</a> backed by Samsung Health, and reliable battery life. The only question is whether you should pay another $250 for it, or if you can happily settle for a OnePlus or TicWatch. If I'm Black Friday deal-hunting, I'm choosing the cheaper option.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/skip-the-galaxy-watch-ultra-these-two-android-smartwatches-cost-half-as-much-and-last-longer</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Galaxy Watch Ultra may be $200 off, but you can save ANOTHER $250 by choosing these Wear OS watches with 3+ days of battery life. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">wEpg3ksMDqytM7tYSowQEV</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/R3c6ejWK5GY2yhoa8HCfgN.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:42:46 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/R3c6ejWK5GY2yhoa8HCfgN.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The fitness circles watchface for the OnePlus Watch 2]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The fitness circles watchface for the OnePlus Watch 2]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Forget buying a high-priced NAS system. Build your own on Black Friday/Cyber Monday and save hundreds ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Black Friday</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Black Friday Google Pixel deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Black Friday Motorola deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024-early-deals-and-how-to-prepare-for-the-big-sales">Black Friday Samsung deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Black Friday OnePlus deals</a></p></div></div>
<p>It's high time I sorted out my home server mess. I use a couple of ancient desktop PCs in a closet filled with hard drives, and everything is patched together, so I have somewhere to store all of my stuff.</p><p>I also realize I don't need a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/this-black-friday-you-should-get-yourself-a-starter-nas">NAS designed for enterprise speed and multiple users</a> connecting to it at once, but I do need to save as much money as humanly possible. It's just my wife and me here, storing pictures or music along with the occasional document that can't get lost. A Raspberry Pi and a few hard drives are <strong>exactly</strong> what I need, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/black-friday-2024">Black Friday</a> is the time to get it all.</p>
<h2 id="here-s-what-i-need-to-build-a-nas-2">Here's what I need to build a NAS</h2>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="384a9648-e422-43ed-b2ab-aef89581c082" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="The Raspberry Pi 5 is the brains of the operation. Unless you already have one set up, buying a starter kit with a case, power supply, and accessories is a good way to save a few dollars." data-dimension48="The Raspberry Pi 5 is the brains of the operation. Unless you already have one set up, buying a starter kit with a case, power supply, and accessories is a good way to save a few dollars." data-dimension25="$116" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CW1RL12G" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:99.87%;"><img id="KHmEvgtbNxBWePtopKiomj" name="PI-5-kit" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KHmEvgtbNxBWePtopKiomj.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1500" height="1498" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>The Raspberry Pi 5 is the brains of the operation. Unless you already have one set up, buying a starter kit with a case, power supply, and accessories is a good way to save a few dollars.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CW1RL12G" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="384a9648-e422-43ed-b2ab-aef89581c082" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="The Raspberry Pi 5 is the brains of the operation. Unless you already have one set up, buying a starter kit with a case, power supply, and accessories is a good way to save a few dollars." data-dimension48="The Raspberry Pi 5 is the brains of the operation. Unless you already have one set up, buying a starter kit with a case, power supply, and accessories is a good way to save a few dollars." data-dimension25="$116">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>You'll need a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/raspberry-pi">Raspberry Pi</a> to run everything. A model 4 can work, but the newer model 5 is a lot better. We don't need excessive speed, but nobody wants to make things slower on purpose. Unless you already have one up and running, buy a kit. It will come with the board itself, a power supply, a case with heat sinks and a fan, and extras like an SD card and cables. You're going to save some money this way.</p><p>This one has it all, and it's on sale for a great price.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="4c260307-ef09-4209-8919-984e802e3947" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="A USB Type A hub with external power is always a good idea when you're connecting a Raspberry Pi to other things. This one has individual power switches and an extra port up top for charging your phone." data-dimension48="A USB Type A hub with external power is always a good idea when you're connecting a Raspberry Pi to other things. This one has individual power switches and an extra port up top for charging your phone." data-dimension25="$15" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B083XTKV8V" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:976px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:95.49%;"><img id="wwcKkwshyDxx4tBhaigP9f" name="powered-USB-hub" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wwcKkwshyDxx4tBhaigP9f.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="976" height="932" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>A USB Type A hub with external power is always a good idea when you're connecting a Raspberry Pi to other things. This one has individual power switches and an extra port up top for charging your phone.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B083XTKV8V" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="4c260307-ef09-4209-8919-984e802e3947" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="A USB Type A hub with external power is always a good idea when you're connecting a Raspberry Pi to other things. This one has individual power switches and an extra port up top for charging your phone." data-dimension48="A USB Type A hub with external power is always a good idea when you're connecting a Raspberry Pi to other things. This one has individual power switches and an extra port up top for charging your phone." data-dimension25="$15">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>Grab yourself a powered USB Type-A hub, too. A Raspberry Pi is tiny and doesn't have a robust power control circuit, so running everything from the Pi's internal USB power isn't a great idea. Using a powered hub means you're not going to see issues copying files back and forth because there isn't enough juice to go around.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="6680ac96-f92d-4a7d-b02d-2e0d7e865753" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Unless you're building a custom case, a drive dock is an easy way to connect multiple drives with one cable. This one has room for four 2.5 or 3.5-inch drives, and you can save $20 on Black Friday." data-dimension48="Unless you're building a custom case, a drive dock is an easy way to connect multiple drives with one cable. This one has room for four 2.5 or 3.5-inch drives, and you can save $20 on Black Friday." data-dimension25="$58" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D4V9SX1C" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1096px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:103.74%;"><img id="uuBBSjXWKTyydZ47yBcNk4" name="HDD-dock" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uuBBSjXWKTyydZ47yBcNk4.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1096" height="1137" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>Unless you're building a custom case, a drive dock is an easy way to connect multiple drives with one cable. This one has room for four 2.5 or 3.5-inch drives, and you can save $20 on Black Friday.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D4V9SX1C" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="6680ac96-f92d-4a7d-b02d-2e0d7e865753" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Unless you're building a custom case, a drive dock is an easy way to connect multiple drives with one cable. This one has room for four 2.5 or 3.5-inch drives, and you can save $20 on Black Friday." data-dimension48="Unless you're building a custom case, a drive dock is an easy way to connect multiple drives with one cable. This one has room for four 2.5 or 3.5-inch drives, and you can save $20 on Black Friday." data-dimension25="$58">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>Next is somewhere to put the storage. I'm <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/this-creality-3d-printer-is-usd130-off-and-works-from-my-phone-so-im-buying-it">3D printing</a> an enclosure for everything and using individual SATA to USB cables, but a drive dock is a lot easier. You can connect multiple storage drives using one USB cable, which can add up to a ton of storage.</p><p>Buying something like this one from MAIWO means you can mix and match 2.5 and 3.5-inch drives, and there's even a built-in drive cloning feature for when you decide to go bigger.</p><p>When all is said and done you'll have this dock and your Raspberry Pi case beside it so you won't need much room for it all.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="e3ba1506-a045-4942-8235-6d921763d0a9" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="You need storage if you want to store anything! This drive from Western Digital is designed for NAS use, which means it's rated for a lot of read and write cycles. A 6TB heavy-duty hard drive for just $99 is a heck of a deal, too." data-dimension48="You need storage if you want to store anything! This drive from Western Digital is designed for NAS use, which means it's rated for a lot of read and write cycles. A 6TB heavy-duty hard drive for just $99 is a heck of a deal, too." data-dimension25="$99" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BDXQ61Z9" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:679px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:145.51%;"><img id="vPAmuG2XGqYhrPadSkogi7" name="WD-plus-HDD" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vPAmuG2XGqYhrPadSkogi7.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="679" height="988" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>You need storage if you want to store anything! This drive from Western Digital is designed for NAS use, which means it's rated for a lot of read and write cycles. A 6TB heavy-duty hard drive for just $99 is a heck of a deal, too.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BDXQ61Z9" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="e3ba1506-a045-4942-8235-6d921763d0a9" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="You need storage if you want to store anything! This drive from Western Digital is designed for NAS use, which means it's rated for a lot of read and write cycles. A 6TB heavy-duty hard drive for just $99 is a heck of a deal, too." data-dimension48="You need storage if you want to store anything! This drive from Western Digital is designed for NAS use, which means it's rated for a lot of read and write cycles. A 6TB heavy-duty hard drive for just $99 is a heck of a deal, too." data-dimension25="$99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>With room for four hard drives, you're going to need at least one. Most people choose spinning disk drives rather than solid-state drives for storage because they have higher capacities and cost less. Since you're not trying to run applications from the drive, speed isn't as important, and the cost-benefit makes it well worth the trade-off.</p><p>I already bought some <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Toshiba-Performance-Gaming-Internal-Drive/dp/B07N8WTFBY">12TB drives </a>over the summer because I knew I was going to do this, but to get started these 6TB drives are great. The Black Friday sale price can't be beat, either.</p><p>Whether you spend $150 bucks on a Raspberry Pi and HDD dock or $500 on a NAS from a company like Synology you're going to have to buy the hard drives.</p>
<hr>
<p>Putting it together is easy. Follow <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.raspberrypi.com/documentation/computers/getting-started.html">an online guide</a> to get your Raspberry Pi up and running once you've put the kit together. Connect the USB hub to the Pi and a wall socket, connect the HDD bay to the Hub and a wall socket, plug in your drives, and turn it all on.</p><p>You don't need any special NAS software because everything you need to share a drive across your home network (or the internet!) is built into the Raspberry Pi's operating system.</p><p>Use an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://magpi.raspberrypi.com/articles/samba-file-server">online tutorial to set up Samba</a> for sharing, and make sure you mind your permissions. Once that's done, your files and folders stored on your homemade NAS will show up through the standard Windows, Mac, and iOS "files" application, and there are plenty of Android file apps that can connect to network-shared storage.</p><p>Of course, you can go a step further and set up something like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/plex">Plex</a> or a network-aware music player on the Raspberry Pi and do more than just store stuff. You can even install OMV, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.openmediavault.org/">a NAS operating system</a> on the Pi, and get all the features you'll find on expensive models, too.</p><p>Enjoy doing it yourself and saving a boatload of money. I do ☺️.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/build-your-own-nas-on-black-friday-cyber-monday-and-save-hundreds</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A Raspberry Pi can power your home NAS and save you a ton of cash. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">RaTXdoAyG4ZVacJTtP6Yh5</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ozhw2qkcVbGRtMbTypuYTC.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 23:22:40 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Smart Home]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ozhw2qkcVbGRtMbTypuYTC.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jerry Hildenbrand / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Terminal app open on Chromebook]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Terminal app open on Chromebook]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Finding the best Chromebook or Android tablet deals isn't as easy as it looks ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>It's the time of the year when everywhere you turn, there are so many Black Friday and Cyber Monday deals that you just "can't miss." Even if it's for something that you never even considered but were enticed by the idea of saving money, we've all been there and fallen victim to it before, and while we tell ourselves it won't happen again, it always does.</p><p>Two categories of devices that we ALWAYS see this with are Chromebooks and tablets. You might see a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/samsung-is-practically-giving-away-its-latest-chromebook-for-cyber-monday">Chromebook for under $100</a> or a tablet for $25 and immediately add them to your cart or hit the "Buy Now" button. Amazon is notorious for this, as you used to be able to get the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/this-perfect-portable-companion-tablet-is-only-50-bucks-during-prime-day-but-youre-running-out-of-time">Fire 7</a> for dirt cheap. But the truth is that practically nobody should actually buy the Fire 7.</p><p>If someone tries to give one to you, tell them thanks but no thanks. Or politely accept it and then take it to somewhere nearby that responsibly recycles electronics.</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Cyber Monday</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Cyber Monday Google Pixel deals<br></a>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Cyber Monday Motorola deals<br></a>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/samsung-black-friday-2024-deals">Cyber Monday Samsung deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Cyber Monday OnePlus deals</a></p></div></div>
<p>Obviously, a sub-$50 tablet is very enticing, especially if you're out shopping and they're conveniently placed right by the register. It might even work pretty well for a week or two, but it won't be long before you start noticing that it takes a year just to open an app. And you can forget about quickly switching back and forth between multiple apps.</p><p>Although it's definitely more difficult to find a good tablet for under $100, there are deals to be found. My favorite cheap tablet deal is for the Lenovo Tab M9, which i<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/lenovo-tab-m9-9-tablet-32gb-arctic-grey/6536782.p?skuId=6536782">s on sale for almost 50% over at Best Buy</a>, coming in at $80. It's not anything spectacular, but you get a near-stock Android experience, a much better display, and even a microSD card slot.</p><p>Arguably, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/black-friday-chromebook-deals-2024-score-major-savings-on-acer-lenovo-samsung-and-more">Chromebook deals</a> can be even worse, as there are still countless listings for sub-$100 laptops that are barely worth the components within them. Many online retailers peddle these devices like they're the ice cream truck driving around the neighborhood. You get excited, spend a couple of bucks, and eat the ice cream, only to realize that it's freezer-burned and probably 10 years past its expiration date.</p><p>Look, I love ice cream as much as the next person, but just because I can get an ice cream bar for 90% off doesn't mean I'm going to fork over my money. This is the same kind of mindset that you should have when shopping, whether it be for Black Friday, Cyber Monday, or because it's the fifth Sunday in April.</p>

<h2 id="trust-your-instincts-2">Trust your instincts</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="CPAPCQNtMe8AkCYyheoQwi" name="lenovo-ideapad-3-chromebook-11-logo.jpg" alt="Lenovo IdeaPad 3 Chromebook 11 Chromebook logo" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CPAPCQNtMe8AkCYyheoQwi.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The first rule of thumb is to avoid any impulse purchases. I have a tendency to buy things when I'm feeling down, and that's usually when my dumbest purchases are made. Then, Amazon drops them off and I feel like an even bigger idiot because now I have to waste the gas to return whatever it is I bought.</p><p>In years past, I had a <em>really</em> bad tendency of buying something just because it was on sale. Even if it was something that I was already considering. But I didn't take the time to do some "window shopping," and just hit the big "BUY ME NOW" button.</p><p>Don't be like me. Do some research and check out more than just one retailer before making a final decision.</p><p>Android Central's Jerry Hildenbrand <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-shop-wisely-prime-day">broke down</a> how you shouldn't spend money just because there's a deal but because it's something you actually want to spend money on, and I wholeheartedly agree.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.15%;"><img id="WKb2WsXrFhtdXTvYtBMcbG" name="samsung-chromebook-4-plus-lid-logo" alt="Samsung Chromebook 4 Plus Lid" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WKb2WsXrFhtdXTvYtBMcbG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1150" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Future)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While shopping, you might have seen a deal or two on Amazon for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://amazon.com/dp/B07XQQRCG5">Samsung Chromebook 4 Plus</a>, priced at $219 after a $100 discount. It uses the Intel Celeron N4000, has a 15.6-inch screen, 4GB of RAM, 64GB of storage, and all that jazz. Sounds good, right?</p><p>Well, how does this one sound? It has a 15.6-inch display, 8GB of RAM, and 128GB of storage. It is powered by the Intel Core i3-1215U and includes 12 months of Google AI. Oh, and you can save $120 by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/acer-chromebook-plus-515-laptop-with-google-ai-15-6-fhd-display-intel-i3-1215u-8gb-lpddr5x-128gb-ufs-wi-fi-6e-steel-gray/6551627.p?skuId=6551627">getting it for just $279</a>.</p><p>I just described the Acer Chromebook Plus 515, which is just over a year old. That's a mighty stark difference compared to the Samsung Chromebook 4, which landed on the scene all the way back in 2019.</p><p>Yes, I know and understand that not everyone can spare the extra $60 for the Acer. But that's just one example. There are a plethora of other deals that are actually worth anything and are not just a way for a retailer to get you to spend your money.</p>
<h2 id="still-need-guidance-we-ve-got-you-covered-2">Still need guidance? We've got you covered</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="TcunmhdCkXXt3neJb5zYSa" name="anbernic-rg406v-game-boy-dmg" alt="Anbernic RG406V next to Game Boy DMG playing Pokemon Yellow" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TcunmhdCkXXt3neJb5zYSa.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I don't mean for this to come off as condescending, but the truth is that there are plenty of people that get taken advantage of. It's happened to members of my own family, and in some instances, I've been able to get them to return whatever it was and help them find something that's worth the money. But there are other times when it's just too late, resulting in money being just flushed down the drain.</p>
<p>That being said, you shouldn't just avoid Black Friday and Cyber Monday deals and sales altogether. It's just important to do a bit of research first, making sure you really are getting the best bang for your buck. And if you need a bit of guidance or don't know which device to get, we've got your back.</p><p>Our team works tirelessly to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/samsung-black-friday-2024-deals">find the best deals</a>, and that doesn't just mean finding the cheapest thing and writing about it. We research and source deals that make sense, even if the "deal" only saves you a few bucks compared to if it weren't on sale. And if you're still stuck, just hit us up on social media, and we're sure <em>someone</em> will be able to help.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/how-to-find-the-best-black-friday-and-cyber-monday-chromebook-and-android-tablet-deals</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ If you're not careful while shopping for deals, you might just end up with a big ole' paperweight, instead of a Chromebook or tablet that's actually worth what you spent.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">sHyKXR3GaixeohPpw3qGLk</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/viwmiLb8GbCkQ2DKg3pTeL.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 23:17:59 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Chromebooks &amp; Laptops]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ andrew.myrick@futurenet.com (Andrew Myrick) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/viwmiLb8GbCkQ2DKg3pTeL.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Lenovo IdeaPad Slim 3 Chromebook review]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Lenovo IdeaPad Slim 3 Chromebook review]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>