<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 20:50:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ My son's favorite smart watch is at its lowest price ever on Prime Day ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Looking to get your kids off screens and a little more active this school year? The Fitbit Ace LTE is the perfect way to do that with original games and activities that encourage your kids to move all throughout the day, and it&apos;s a fantastic <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Fitbit-Google-Ace-LTE-Activity-Based/dp/B0CV5T2YG6/"><strong>$50 off</strong></a> for Amazon&apos;s October Prime Day sale, officially known as Amazon Big Deal Days!</p><p><strong>See all the October Prime Day deals: </strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://target.georiot.com/Proxy.ashx?tsid=169923&GR_URL=https%3A%2F%2Famazon.com%2F%3Ftag%3Dhawk-future-20%26ascsubtag%3Dac-us-1210862076431904870-20" target="_blank"><strong>USA</strong></a><strong> |</strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://target.georiot.com/Proxy.ashx?tsid=169923&GR_URL=https%3A%2F%2Famazon.co.uk%2F%3Ftag%3Dhawk-future-21%26ascsubtag%3Dac-us-1341344957438454073-21" target="_blank"><strong>UK</strong></a><strong> |</strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://target.georiot.com/Proxy.ashx?tsid=169923&GR_URL=https%3A%2F%2Famazon.ca%2F%3Ftag%3Dhawk-future-ca-20%26ascsubtag%3Dac-us-3488521891369348908-20" target="_blank"><strong>Canada</strong></a><strong> |</strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://target.georiot.com/Proxy.ashx?tsid=169923&GR_URL=https%3A%2F%2Famazon.in%2F%3Ftag%3Dtech0e7-21%26ascsubtag%3Dac-us-7261173557223770566-21" target="_blank"><strong>India</strong></a></p><p>When I reviewed the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fitbit-ace-lte-review">Fitbit Ace LTE</a> a few months ago, my son fell in love with the amazing games that come preloaded on the watch. These games give kids a few minutes of play time and require a specific amount of movement throughout the day to earn coins, turns, and other in-game activities. Plus, each game is active, so they&apos;ll be slinging their wrist to cast a line in the Smokey Lake fishing game, aiming with their watch to take bad guys out in the Galaxy Rangers strategy, or swinging their wrist like a golf club in Kaiju Golf.</p><p>New games are added seasonally and there are over half a dozen to play right now. Fitbit even built an entire "virtual pet" type experience called Eejies which feel a bit like a cross between Tamagotchi and Animal Crossing. Daily activity will grant rewards in the form of outfits and furniture for their Eejie&apos;s rooms, and new watchbands from Fitbit unlock exclusive outfits that match the bands. It&apos;s an incredible experience that&apos;s unlike any other smartwatch on the market, and it&apos;s made just for kids!</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="a6d0bc13-38b5-43db-aaf7-d81151ead7d9" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$229.95" data-dimension48="$229.95" href="https://www.amazon.com/Fitbit-Google-Ace-LTE-Activity-Based/dp/B0CV5T2YG6/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:718px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:55.85%;"><img id="JWtsr7q6dpJNKQC5aH7HeJ" name="fitbit-ace-lte-greenlight-gohenry-support.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JWtsr7q6dpJNKQC5aH7HeJ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="718" height="401" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Fitbit Ace LTE:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Fitbit-Google-Ace-LTE-Activity-Based/dp/B0CV5T2YG6/" data-dimension112="a6d0bc13-38b5-43db-aaf7-d81151ead7d9" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$229.95" data-dimension48="$229.95"><del>$229.95</del> <strong>$179.95 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>Get the best kids fitness watch money can buy for $50 less during October Prime Day! Encourage kids to keep moving with fun games and daily activities, virtual pets, and more.</p>
<p><strong>Price check:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/fitbit-ace-lte-kids-smartwatch-with-in-app-calling-messaging-gps-spicy/6585806.p?skuId=6585806&extStoreId=953&utm_source=feed&ref=212&loc=21514448786&gad_source=1&gclid=EAIaIQobChMI05G2ltP_iAMVlivUAR1UMgdXEAQYASABEgJLM_D_BwE&gclsrc=aw.ds">Best Buy - $199</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/Fitbit-Google-Ace-LTE-Activity-Based/dp/B0CV5T2YG6/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="a6d0bc13-38b5-43db-aaf7-d81151ead7d9" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$229.95" data-dimension48="$229.95">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>It&apos;s hard to sing enough praises about this amazing watch, but lets cover the full cost of everything first. You&apos;ll be getting $50 the Fitbit Ace LTE by buying it from Amazon today but you&apos;ll need to keep an Ace Pass subscription active to get it connected to an LTE network. A Fitbit Ace Pass is $9.99 per month and comes with LTE connectivity so your kids can message and call you all from their watch without needing a smartphone.</p><p>Any connected watch will require a data plan of some kind and and most companies charge around $10 for that cost anyway, so this isn&apos;t something unique to the Fitbit Ace LTE. What IS unique, however, is Fitbit&apos;s commitment to regular updates, new games, and fun new features that&apos;s included in that same plan. It&apos;s a huge advantage over other kids smartwatches.</p><p>And while your kids are having fun and staying active, you can rest easy knowing the Fitbit Ace LTE has the best smart watch hardware of any kids smartwatch, too. It uses the same powerful health tracking sensors and processor as the Google Pixel Watch 3 and is even the thinnest and lightest smartwatch available. In fact, putting a Fitbit Ace LTE next to most other kids smartwatches makes them look a decade older than what Fitbit was able to put together.</p><p>Of course, since this is a kids smartwatch you know there are great parental controls, school mode features that let parents restrict usage during school times, geofencing alerts, and more. Fitbit&apos;s app is so much better and sleeker than the competition, too, so if you&apos;re upgrading from another kids smartwatch you&apos;ll be blown away by the difference.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fitbit-ace-lte-october-prime-day-deal-2024</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ October Prime Day deals are always great, especially when you can get $50 off a great kids smartwatch like the Fitbit Ace LTE! ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">7BnDXdDD2ZFKiUXo4LLFiP</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8mqw4BjCbnGBBYPNxhYHHA.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 20:47:28 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8mqw4BjCbnGBBYPNxhYHHA.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Customizing the Eejie on a Fitbit Ace LTE]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Customizing the Eejie on a Fitbit Ace LTE]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ I review tablets for a living and this Pixel Tablet Prime Day deal is too good to pass up ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Ever since it was originally teased, a lot has been made about whether Google&apos;s Pixel Tablet is actually a tablet or a smart home hub. No matter how you look at it, this does offer a different experience compared to other tablets, and thanks to Prime Day in October, you can <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CZMFZMR8"><strong>save yourself $100</strong></a>. </p><p>Normally priced at $399, Prime Day in October brings the Pixel Tablet down to just $299. This is for just the tablet and doesn&apos;t include the Speaker Dock. Those who want the entire ensemble are in luck, but you&apos;ll have to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-tablet-with-charging-speaker-dock-11-android-tablet-128gb-wi-fi-hazel/6543740.p?skuId=6543740"><strong>swing over to Best Buy</strong></a> in order to enjoy the $100 discount.</p>
<ul><li><strong>See all the October Prime Day deals: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/" target="_blank"><strong>USA</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/" target="_blank"><strong>UK</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.ca/" target="_blank"><strong>Canada</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.in/" target="_blank"><strong>India</strong></a></li></ul>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="b1dd9641-0885-470e-9728-7606c46e578a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$399" data-dimension48="$399" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CZMFZMR8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1253px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="YFGstf4NTU6gy8fU4rhZrP" name="pixel-tablet-square-reco.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YFGstf4NTU6gy8fU4rhZrP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1253" height="1253" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Google Pixel Tablet:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CZMFZMR8" target="_blank" data-dimension112="b1dd9641-0885-470e-9728-7606c46e578a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$399" data-dimension48="$399"><del>$399</del> <strong>$299 at Amazon (Tablet Only)</strong></a></p>
<p>It might not be the flashiest or most powerful tablet out there, but the Pixel Tablet still manages to pull its weight. You'll enjoy USI 2.0 support if you want to use it as a digital notebook, and you can pair it with any number of Bluetooth keyboards.</p>
<p><strong>Pixel Tablet w/ Speaker Dock:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-tablet-with-charging-speaker-dock-11-android-tablet-128gb-wi-fi-hazel/6543740.p?skuId=6543740"><del>$499</del> <strong>$399 at Best Buy</strong></a></p>
<p>By itself, the Pixel Tablet offers a great value, even without this Prime Day deal. But if you want even more value, then spring for the Pixel Tablet with Speaker Dock combination. Not only will you be able to enjoy a fantastic tablet, but when connected to the Speaker Dock, it turns into a supercharged Nest Hub Max.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CZMFZMR8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="b1dd9641-0885-470e-9728-7606c46e578a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$399" data-dimension48="$399">View Deal</a></p></div>
<hr>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/october-prime-day-google-pixel-deals-2024-dollar400-off-the-pixel-9-pixel-watch-discounts-and-more"><strong>See all the best Google Pixel deals of October Prime Day 2024</strong></a></li></ul>
<p>✅<strong>Recommended if:</strong> you&apos;re looking for a tablet that offers a different experience compared to many of the others; you want a tablet that doubles as a smart home hub and digital picture frame.</p><p>❌<strong>Skip this deal if:</strong> you need a more powerful tablet or if you want something to use as a laptop replacement when you&apos;re away from home.</p>
<p>After being previewed at I/O 2022, we had to wait a whole year before the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/google-pixel-tablet-review">Pixel Tablet</a> was released into the wild. It&apos;s powered by Google&apos;s Tensor G2, which is the same chip that debuted with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-7-review">Pixel 7</a> and 7 Pro. The G2 is paired with 8GB of RAM and either 128GB or 256GB of storage. Unfortunately, that&apos;s all you get, as there&apos;s no microSD card slot on board.</p><p>At first glance, you might be deterred by the lack of an OLED display, but the LCD panel looks quite a bit better than I expected. Another good reason why Google opted against an OLED screen is that you don&apos;t have to worry about screen burn-in if you decide to just keep the Pixel Tablet docked all of the time (like I have.)</p><p>Surprisingly, this is also one reason why I&apos;m not terribly disappointed with there only being two storage options without the ability to use a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-micro-sd-card-android">microSD card</a>. I still wish it weren&apos;t the case, but since I don&apos;t actually keep anything other than apps on there, it&apos;s not something I have to think about.</p><p>At the end of the day, if you need something with more power or an OLED display, there are plenty of options to choose from. Many of them are on sale thanks to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/prime-day-is-back-next-month-faq-early-deals-and-everything-you-need-to-know-about-the-big-sale">Prime Day</a> in October.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/i-review-tablets-for-a-living-and-this-pixel-tablet-prime-day-deal-is-too-good-to-pass-up</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ One of the key considerations when deciding on a tablet is how versatile it can be. While it's definitely not perfect, the Pixel Tablet remains one of the more unique options on the market. If you've been hesitant about getting one, now's the perfect time thanks to Prime Day.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">WBVYagbcq8akhPJfJe6GXU</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3HPQpanRc6kHcuRNCZodKP.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 20:44:04 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ andrew.myrick@futurenet.com (Andrew Myrick) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3HPQpanRc6kHcuRNCZodKP.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Home Assistant Dashboard on Pixel Tablet]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Home Assistant Dashboard on Pixel Tablet]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ This Galaxy Z Flip 6 Prime Day deal makes it MUCH easier for me to recommend ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>When it comes to foldable phones, flip phones are often the top sellers because they&apos;re more compact, they trigger a sense of nostalgia, and—most importantly— they&apos;re cheaper. Samsung&apos;s Galaxy Z Flip 6 hits the first two points, but the phone is $100 more expensive than its predecessors, which made it a little hard for me to recommend over its competitors. However, with this pretty great <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D195JKYD">October Prime Day deal</a>, I can <em>finally</em> recommend the Galaxy Z Flip 6.</p><p>At $1099, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-6-review">Galaxy Z Flip 6</a> is priced at a premium over flagship <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-flip-phones">flip phones</a>. This 23% discount brings it down to just $849, giving you $250 off without the need for a trade-in. This deal is available for all major color options at 256GB, although you can also get the 512GB variant for 26% off, which still costs less than $999.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="b8da026e-5a23-49f1-84be-a60ce3f2f217" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1099" data-dimension48="$1099" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D195JKYD" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1501px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="JrEgbbZSCjj6z4VY5Zx5XP" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Z-Flip-6-official-render-blue.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JrEgbbZSCjj6z4VY5Zx5XP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1501" height="1501" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 6:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D195JKYD" data-dimension112="b8da026e-5a23-49f1-84be-a60ce3f2f217" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1099" data-dimension48="$1099"><del>$1099</del> <strong>$849 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>Samsung's best flip phone is making its Prime Day debut with a massive discount that brings this powerful device down to its lowest price yet. This 23% discount is one you don't want to miss out on because we don't know when this Galaxy AI-powered phone will be this cheap again.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D195JKYD" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="b8da026e-5a23-49f1-84be-a60ce3f2f217" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1099" data-dimension48="$1099">View Deal</a></p></div>
<ul><li> <strong>See all the October Prime Day deals:</strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/"> <u><strong>USA</strong></u></a><strong> |</strong><a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/"> <u><strong>UK</strong></u></a><strong> |</strong><a href="https://www.amazon.ca/"> <u><strong>Canada</strong></u></a><strong> |</strong><a href="https://www.amazon.in/"> <u><strong>India</strong></u></a> </li></ul>
<p>The Galaxy Z Flip 6 is one of the most powerful flip phones on the market, thanks to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-3">Snapdragon 8 Gen 3</a> chipset, enabling fast performance and access to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-galaxy-ai">Galaxy AI</a> features that let you generate, transcribe, and summarize content using <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/why-on-device-ai-processing-is-important">on-device AI</a> processing. Equipped with 12GB of RAM, the phone handles multitasking and gaming well, and the 4,000mAh battery keeps the lights on all day long.</p><p>The phone received a decent spec bump compared to its predecessor, not just with the processor and battery but also with the cameras. It now features a 50MP primary sensor for enhanced detail and zoom capabilities, and with Auto Camcorder, you can just fold the Galaxy Z Flip 6 at a 90-degree angle to start shooting video.</p><p>The massive cover screen is still a little rough around the edges in terns of functionality, but it lets you easily do the basics like respond to messages, check the weather, and more. And for power users like me, you can also <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-set-up-and-use-apps-on-the-samsung-galaxy-z-flip-6-cover-screen">use apps on the Galaxy Z Flip 6 cover screen</a>, which can come in handy.</p>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>You want the latest flip phone with a sleek design, access to latest AI features from Google and Samsung, and a large cover screen that&apos;s perfect for selfies you can take with its excellent 50MP camera.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if:</strong> Honestly, there&apos;s very little reason to skip this deal, unless you absolutely need a telephoto camera and/or you would prefer to buy the excellent Razr Plus 2024 instead.</p>
<p>The Galaxy Z Flip 6 isn&apos;t the only flip phone on sale, nor is it the cheapest. If you&apos;re in the market for a flip phone and want to save even more money, you can also consider this <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2024-october-prime-day-deal">Motorola Razr Plus 2024 Prime Day deal</a>, which brings the phone down to its lowest price since launching in June.</p><p>And while you&apos;re at it, check out more of our favorite <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/october-prime-day-early-samsung-galaxy-deals-phones-tablets-and-more">October Prime Day deals on Samsung phones</a>.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/this-galaxy-z-flip-6-prime-day-deal-makes-it-much-easier-for-me-to-recommend</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 6 is at its lowest price for Amazon's October Prime Day sales event. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">XU6oC39hSstGCtA5U3GDse</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LJz33H2ujQaKK5kQ3vJgQX.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 20:38:46 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ derrek.lee@futurenet.com (Derrek Lee) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LJz33H2ujQaKK5kQ3vJgQX.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 6 display folded at an angle]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 6 display folded at an angle]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Pixel 8a was already the value champ, and now you can save 120 bucks during Prime Day ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Normally, I&apos;d think twice before I told you to buy a year-old phone new. There&apos;s nothing wrong with using last year&apos;s model and it&apos;s a great way to save a few dollars, but if you want one buying used is usually a better bet. That changes when it&apos;s so cheap.</p><p>Google has already released the Pixel 9 with its various Pro and XL models, and everyone knows that a Pixel 9a is coming soon. Until we see it and its price tag, the Pixel 8a is still the phone to beat — <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CYQFJSRF"><strong>especially at $379</strong></a><strong>.</strong></p>
<ul><li> <strong>See all the Prime Day deals: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/"><strong>USA</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/"><strong>UK</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.ca/"><strong>Canada</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.in/"><strong>India</strong></a><strong> </strong></li></ul>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="019fc85a-390d-4620-b1e6-5391933ebea8" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$499" data-dimension48="$499" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CYQFJSRF" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="vmLdNVEV4CGYnz9stgpRA" name="google pixel 8a render 400x500.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vmLdNVEV4CGYnz9stgpRA.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Google Pixel 8a:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CYQFJSRF" data-dimension112="019fc85a-390d-4620-b1e6-5391933ebea8" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$499" data-dimension48="$499"><del>$499</del> <strong>$379 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>The Pixel 8a is the best cheap phone available today and it's even better when you're saving $120. You can buy something newer, but you're going to pay a lot more or end up with a lot less phone. </p>
<p>It has a great camera, superb build quality, and internal specs strong enough to do anything you could ask of it. You even get plenty of Google's AI tricks, too. It's my pick for the best phone of 2024.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CYQFJSRF" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="019fc85a-390d-4620-b1e6-5391933ebea8" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$499" data-dimension48="$499">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>✅<strong>Recommended if:</strong> You don&apos;t demand to have the latest specs as long as everything runs well; you like to save money.</p><p>❌<strong>Skip this deal if:</strong> You&apos;re not a fan of Google&apos;s phones or software; you plan to play a lot of games.</p>
<p>Everyone in tech has an opinion and a lot of people would disagree with me saying the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a">Pixel 8a</a> is the best phone of 2024. You should always listen to more than one person before you spend your money.</p><p>It is the phone I spent my own money on, though. It&apos;s not hard for me to get just about any phone I want to use and I have looked at several of them. When it came to my money, I decided that the Pixel 8a was the best way to spend it. I&apos;m not alone and Google&apos;s a series phones are always the company&apos;s best sellers because they offer <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-android-phones">insane value</a>.</p>
<p>If you want to play games for hours you can get <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/redmagic-9-pro-review">something better</a> and there are phones with "better" cameras out there. None offer the same value as the unassuming little Pixel 8a, though. <strong>ProTip:</strong> Buy the Aloe (green) one. you&apos;ll thank me once you see it in person.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-pixel-8a-was-already-the-value-champ-and-now-you-can-save-120-bucks-during-prime-day</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ At $399 this is the pound-for-pound champ of the Android world. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">k3RZkeGS4jCdDwJFSw8CZJ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6tcayRk63cRY9xtVSBnnQQ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 20:28:44 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6tcayRk63cRY9xtVSBnnQQ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The blue Google Pixel 8a on a tea tray with blue hydrangeas above it]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The blue Google Pixel 8a on a tea tray with blue hydrangeas above it]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ This Creality 3D printer is $130 off and works from my phone  so I'm buying it ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>I told myself I <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-shop-wisely-prime-day">wasn&apos;t going to buy anything expensive</a> on Prime Day but I was wrong. The 3D Printer I&apos;ve been wanting went <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Creality-K1C-High-Speed-Clog-Free-Filaments/dp/B0D9BGHHKF">on sale at Amazon for $469</a> and I just bought one. I don&apos;t need another 3D printer but it&apos;s something I enjoy doing and I wanted to try something different.</p><p>The "something different" I want to check out is using a printer that works <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">through my phone</a>, and that&apos;s something the Creality K1C is supposed to do very well. I might enjoy messing with things but I also enjoy it when stuff works right the first time.</p>
<ul><li><strong>See all the Prime Day deals:</strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/"><strong> USA</strong></a><strong> |</strong><a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/"><strong> UK</strong></a><strong> |</strong><a href="https://www.amazon.ca/"><strong> Canada</strong></a><strong> |</strong><a href="https://www.amazon.in/"><strong> India</strong></a><strong> </strong></li></ul>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="d64a19d6-366a-4ccc-810b-9c3c781c2c86" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$599" data-dimension48="$599" href="https://www.amazon.com/Creality-K1C-High-Speed-Clog-Free-Filaments/dp/B0D9BGHHKF" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:425px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:124.24%;"><img id="xGMrN98CnChDTZgJoTs9r6" name="creality-printer-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xGMrN98CnChDTZgJoTs9r6.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="425" height="528" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Creality K1C 3D Printer:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Creality-K1C-High-Speed-Clog-Free-Filaments/dp/B0D9BGHHKF" data-dimension112="d64a19d6-366a-4ccc-810b-9c3c781c2c86" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$599" data-dimension48="$599"><del>$599</del> <strong>$469 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>This super-fast 600 mm/s 3D printer is fully enclosed, has a unique nozzle system designed for tough materials like carbon fiber, has a built-in AI camera, and is designed to work through Wi-Fi with an app for your phone or a standard webpage.</p>
<p>Add in easy to use auto calibration and leveling system and this printer is the plug and play version from the biggest name in 3D printing. I'm buying it while it's on sale.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/Creality-K1C-High-Speed-Clog-Free-Filaments/dp/B0D9BGHHKF" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="d64a19d6-366a-4ccc-810b-9c3c781c2c86" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$599" data-dimension48="$599">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>✅<strong>Recommended if:</strong> You&apos;re new to 3D printing or just want a simple-to-use printer that&apos;s also powerful and can turn out quality prints.</p><p>❌<strong>Skip this deal if:</strong> You like to tinker and fuss with things or want to use a dedicated print server system like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://octoprint.org/">OctoPrint</a>.</p>
<p>I&apos;ve been fooling with 3D printers for a long time; my first one came in pieces and needed a trip to the hardware store to assemble. It&apos;s a hobby I enjoy and making something useful or fun from a spool of plastic wire is fascinating.</p><p>I&apos;m also not averse to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/the-five-raspberry-pi-accessories-im-buying-on-prime-day">messing with stuff</a>. The "best" printer I have requires constant attention and manual calibration once in a while, and I need to use a USB thumb drive to copy files for printing. However, I still enjoy it, and it&apos;s a workhorse.</p>
<p>I wanted something a bit different, though. For starters, I want to start using carbon fiber filament and not have to change out a worn nozzle with every spool. For a few years, printers that connect through Wi-Fi and can be controlled through the web or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/android-apps-3d-printing-hit-or-miss-tons-fun">from an app</a> were available and I even bought one. I hated it and it was constantly breaking down; Craigslist help me make it someone else&apos;s problem and I don&apos;t miss it at all.</p><p>I&apos;ve seen about a million reviews of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Creality-K1C-High-Speed-Clog-Free-Filaments/dp/B0D9BGHHKF">Creality K1C</a> and it seems to be exactly what I&apos;m looking for. It even includes a built-in camera that uses "AI" to detect issues during the printing process to keep you from wasting expensive CF filament. Best of all, it doesn&apos;t have a bunch of known issues like my last one did.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7wQk7K_l-DU" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>I relentlessly obsess over buying anything and it&apos;s not something I enjoy doing; I&apos;m definitely not a typical shopper. I knew this was the printer I wanted and being able to save $130 was enough to get me to click that button.</p><p>I can finally print <del>tiny 3D models of WWII planes</del> useful things, from bed, with a great app on a fancy new printer!</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/this-creality-3d-printer-is-usd130-off-and-works-from-my-phone-so-im-buying-it</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ I love to tinker with things but can appreciate stuff when it just works, too. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Q27Khi2Vu6tL9Edh7B8rnX</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Fd4fycXNVCVAUsYqWBBrdH.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 19:07:02 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Fd4fycXNVCVAUsYqWBBrdH.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Creality]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Creality K1C 3D Printer]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Creality K1C 3D Printer]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Prime Day impulse buy alert! The coolest earbuds ever are just $31 right now ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Have you ever been somewhere in public and one of your earbuds fell out? It&apos;s a painful experience because they usually bounce or roll somewhere inaccessible or disgusting. Thanks to this crazy <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/CMF-Buds-Cancelling-Waterproof-Headphones/dp/B0CXDGZ1WL/?th=1"><strong>$31 Prime Day deal</strong></a>, this irritating occurrence won&apos;t be so painful if it happens in the future.</p>
<p><strong>See all the October Prime Day deals: </strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/"><u><strong>USA</strong></u></a><strong> |</strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/"><u><strong>UK</strong></u></a><strong> |</strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.ca/"><u><strong>Canada</strong></u></a><strong> |</strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.in/"><u><strong>India</strong></u></a></p>
<p>CMF Buds are seriously impressive buds with ANC and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/nothing-cmf-buds-amazing-budget">blew our editor Harish away</a> with their value. Even at the normal $39 price, CMF Buds look and sound great, and this Amazon Big Deals Day deal makes that statement even more true.</p><p>Obviously, spending just $31 on wireless earbuds isn&apos;t going to give you the best sound quality in the world but these are more than acceptable. They&apos;re legit good and they even include active noise cancellation (ANC) — something usually reserved for earbuds three times the price or more.</p><p>Grab a quick pair as a backup or switch over to them permanently so you don&apos;t have to worry about losing one. Plus, the unique case features a dial that doubles as a fidget spinner, letting you move it back and forth with a satisfying click that&apos;ll keep your hands busy when you need to sit still.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="5bb1a362-6982-4508-b176-cee6fc1f7ca5" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="CMF Buds: $39" data-dimension48="CMF Buds: $39" href="https://www.amazon.com/CMF-Buds-Cancelling-Waterproof-Headphones/dp/B0CXDGZ1WL/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:865px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:164.74%;"><img id="o2zBVRPhtUgKRi9htNJPuN" name="CMF-Buds-render-orange.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/o2zBVRPhtUgKRi9htNJPuN.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="865" height="1425" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>CMF Buds: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/CMF-Buds-Cancelling-Waterproof-Headphones/dp/B0CXDGZ1WL/" data-dimension112="5bb1a362-6982-4508-b176-cee6fc1f7ca5" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="CMF Buds: $39" data-dimension48="CMF Buds: $39"><del>$39</del> <strong>$31 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>CMF Buds are nothing but a great pair of truly wireless earbuds for a lot less than the competition. This <strong>21% off</strong> Prime Day deal somehow makes them even more affordable, and they don't even miss out on ANC!<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/CMF-Buds-Cancelling-Waterproof-Headphones/dp/B0CXDGZ1WL/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="5bb1a362-6982-4508-b176-cee6fc1f7ca5" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="CMF Buds: $39" data-dimension48="CMF Buds: $39">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>✅<strong>Recommended if:</strong> You just need an inexpensive pair of truly wireless earbuds with active noise cancellation. They&apos;re so cheap it probably won&apos;t even make you cry if you lose one.</p><p>❌<strong>Skip this deal if:</strong> You need louder noise cancellation or the best quality audio. These sound just fine and have a great fit, but more expensive earbuds will get you better quality.</p>
<p>But hear me out: I&apos;d recommend spending just $16 more to get the upgrade CMF Buds Pro 2. At $47, they&apos;re <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/CMF-Buds-Pro-Cancelling-Technology/dp/B0D83J6JJ9/?th=1"><strong>32% off</strong></a><strong> </strong>for October Prime Day and will deliver an even better experience than the regular CMF Buds. Just like CMF Buds, the CMF Buds Pro 2 come in a range of snazzy, eye-catching colors, or you can opt for the more subdued white or black colorways if that&apos;s more your jam.</p><p>As you might expect, choosing the CMF Buds Pro 2 will net you better overall sound quality including louder noise cancellation that&apos;s important when you&apos;re on an airplane or somewhere else particularly noisy. It&apos;s also got better quality microphones, so your calls and meetings will sound less tinny than with the regular CMF Buds.</p><p>On top of that, CMF Buds Pro 2 feature the most unique earbud case on the market. It looks identical to the CMF Buds case but that little wheel actually serves a purpose on these buds. The dial can be used to quickly adjust the volume of your music — something that feels truly amazing when it&apos;s sitting in your pocket — or it can be clicked in up to three times to act as a customizable button for playing/pausing music, pulling up Google Gemini, and more.</p><p>To me, this case is the best part of the earbuds. Sure, the sound quality is good — especially for this rock-bottom price — but the case is just so darn fun to use! I&apos;ve been using these all day to listen to music while writing Prime Day deals and I can&apos;t recommend them enough!</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="6c8f93bb-d7b7-4d1e-b4b3-3b3babc6bbf2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="CMF Buds Pro 2: $69" data-dimension48="CMF Buds Pro 2: $69" href="https://www.amazon.com/CMF-Buds-Pro-Cancelling-Technology/dp/B0D83J6JJ9/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="8HXWLJQgTouoNLhFiZuNK5" name="CMF-Buds-Pro-2.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8HXWLJQgTouoNLhFiZuNK5.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>CMF Buds Pro 2: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/CMF-Buds-Pro-Cancelling-Technology/dp/B0D83J6JJ9/" data-dimension112="6c8f93bb-d7b7-4d1e-b4b3-3b3babc6bbf2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="CMF Buds Pro 2: $69" data-dimension48="CMF Buds Pro 2: $69"><del>$69</del> <strong>$47 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>Keep your phone charged for days with the Anker Prime 27,650mAh power bank, on sale for <strong>20% off </strong>during October Prime Day! It's even got enough juice to power a laptop and just about any gadget that accepts a USB charge<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/CMF-Buds-Pro-Cancelling-Technology/dp/B0D83J6JJ9/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="6c8f93bb-d7b7-4d1e-b4b3-3b3babc6bbf2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="CMF Buds Pro 2: $69" data-dimension48="CMF Buds Pro 2: $69">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>✅<strong>Recommended if:</strong> You&apos;re looking for something uniquely excellent with a case that does much more than just charge these excellent ANC earbuds.</p><p>❌<strong>Skip this deal if:</strong> You need the highest quality sound available from earbuds. These aren&apos;t bad by any means, but they also can&apos;t compete with buds that are $100-$200 more expensive.</p>
<p>No matter which you pick, you&apos;ll be getting a great pair of earbuds for next to nothing during October Prime Day!</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/earbuds/cmf-buds-october-prime-day-deal-2024</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ CMF Buds and CMF Buds Pro 2 are on sale for October Prime day, making these the best deals ever on earbuds. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">pkhUgDwW6FB5Wzq9hHayNa</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jdffJQiivXQ4kUVNcGsHdM.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 19:06:33 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Earbuds]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jdffJQiivXQ4kUVNcGsHdM.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A pair of black CMF Buds Pro 2 with their unique case]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A pair of black CMF Buds Pro 2 with their unique case]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Last year's Motorola Razr lands a remarkable 50% discount during October Prime Day ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Tons of Prime Day phone deals have been going live since <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/prime-day-is-back-next-month-faq-early-deals-and-everything-you-need-to-know-about-the-big-sale">Big Deal Days</a> kicked off early this morning, but this next entry is particularly compelling. For the duration of the 48-hour sale, Amazon is slashing <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CGWHHC69"><strong>50% off the Motorola Razr (2023)</strong></a>, resulting in a price tag of only $349.99. While it isn&apos;t the latest offering for this flip phone, we liked this one a lot when it came out, and that&apos;s why it&apos;s now our favorite option for a value flip phone.</p>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/october-prime-day-motorola-deals-have-come-early-score-40-off-foldable-phones-epic-flagship-discounts-and-more"><em><strong>Check out our guide to the best Motorola deals of October Prime Day 2024</strong></em></a></li></ul>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="023bbbb4-f1ca-4d80-bbac-bb1a3e0845bc" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$699.99" data-dimension48="$699.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CGVXZSQJ" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:551px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:106.17%;"><img id="Hkpc23iV2we3rPE7odqnDk" name="motorola-razr-2023-render-sage-green.JPG" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Hkpc23iV2we3rPE7odqnDk.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="551" height="585" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Motorola Razr (2023):</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CGVXZSQJ" target="_blank" data-dimension112="023bbbb4-f1ca-4d80-bbac-bb1a3e0845bc" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$699.99" data-dimension48="$699.99"><del>$699.99</del> <strong>$349.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>October Prime Day has launched with some pretty killer deals, including this half off deal for the capable 2023 edition of the Motorola Razr. If you want a flip phone that's super affordable and still boasts a few pretty strong performance details, this might be a good stop. From its beautiful inner screen with a 144Hz refresh rate to the excellent battery life, we loved this phone when it came out, and we'd probably love it just as much today at this price point.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CGVXZSQJ" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="023bbbb4-f1ca-4d80-bbac-bb1a3e0845bc" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$699.99" data-dimension48="$699.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<ul><li><strong>See all the October Prime Day deals: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/"><u><strong>USA</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/"><u><strong>UK</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.ca/"><u><strong>Canada</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.in/"><u><strong>India</strong></u></a> </li></ul>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if:</strong> you&apos;re looking for an excellent deal on an already cheap flip phone, and you don&apos;t mind getting one from last year; you want something with strong battery life; a high refresh rate display is something you value in a phone.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>you&apos;d rather get the latest generation of the Razr, which Motorola released last month; you aren&apos;t looking for a flip or foldable phone; you wouldn&apos;t like having such a minimal cover screen.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-2024-review">2024 Motorola Razr dropped last month</a> and it&apos;s another great flip phone from Motorola, but there&apos;s no shame in saving your money and going with the 2023 version. It&apos;s worth noting the much-more-minimal cover screen, though some users may actually prefer that to the 2024 anyway.</p><p>Despite being from last year, performance on the 2023 Razr is actually pretty solid, and the 6.9-inch internal display offers an impressive 144Hz refresh rate. Besides that, battery life is incredible on this little phone, and the main camera takes pretty decent pictures for the price. At half off, this option is frankly looking even better for the budget-friendly buyer.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/last-years-motorola-razr-lands-a-remarkable-50-percent-discount-during-october-prime-day</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Amazon's October Prime Day has launched a crazy 50% off deal on last year's Motorola Razr — and it was already our favorite value Moto phone before this. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">R8Tp3VhfPLqApL9C9vFoXT</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fXTHrsCDX5KzynkbG2UGgT.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 18:59:34 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ zacharydvisconti@gmail.com (Zachary Visconti) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fXTHrsCDX5KzynkbG2UGgT.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Razr 2023 on a table]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Razr 2023 on a table]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Pixel 9 Pro Fold changed my mind about foldables, but I still prefer flip phones ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Since foldable phones first burst onto the scene, there have been two major form factors to choose from: larger book-style foldables and smaller clamshell flip phones. Both styles serve different purposes with their form factors, with larger foldables acting as miniature tablets when unfolded, while flip phones are more focused on miniaturization.</p><p>Yet, despite being something of a two-in-one device, book-style foldable phones never caught my eye, and my focus has been on flip phones like the Motorola Razr series. I always felt that larger foldables seemed too big and cumbersome, and the "small tablet" form factor just did not appeal to me, especially since I already wasn&apos;t big on using some of the multitasking features on smaller phones. I knew there was a particular use case for the larger folding screen, but I never really <em>got</em> it.</p><p>That is until the Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold landed on my doorstep, and I got to experience Android on a bigger screen for the first time. And while I still prefer flip phones, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-fold-review">Pixel 9 Pro Fold</a> gave me a new appreciation for book-style foldables.</p><p>So, if you&apos;ve been unsure about foldable phones and which type to choose, hopefully, my experiences with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2024-review">Motorola Razr Plus 2024</a> and Pixel 9 Pro Fold can provide some insight into what it&apos;s like to use either option. And with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/prime-day-is-back-next-month-faq-early-deals-and-everything-you-need-to-know-about-the-big-sale">October Prime Day sale</a> happening, grabbing a foldable phone is now easier than ever, especially with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2024-october-prime-day-deal">Razr Plus 2024 hitting its lowest price</a> since launching in June.</p>
<p><strong>See all the Prime Day deals:</strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" target="_blank" href="https://www.amazon.com/"><strong> USA</strong></a><strong> |</strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" target="_blank" href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/"><strong> UK</strong></a><strong> |</strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" target="_blank" href="https://www.amazon.ca/"><strong> Canada</strong></a><strong> |</strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" target="_blank" href="https://www.amazon.in/"><strong> India</strong></a></p>

<h2 id="sometimes-bigger-is-better-2">Sometimes, bigger is better</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="YmTFWEufryiiRhADLHhgTY" name="Google-Pixel-9-Pro-Fold-Motorola-Razr-Plus-2024-open.jpg" alt="Pixel 9 Pro Fold next to the Razr Plus 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YmTFWEufryiiRhADLHhgTY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I&apos;ve been using the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-fold">Pixel 9 Pro Fold</a> for a couple of weeks now, and I&apos;m surprised at how much I enjoy it. Something about having all that screen real estate makes it incredibly fun to use, and I almost never close it to use the external display.</p><p>Apps are given plenty of more room to shine, which is especially evident with things like e-books and streaming apps like YouTube. Not only is it nice to have an 8-inch display to view content readily available, but the foldable form factor makes it so easy to set the phone down while still viewing a still-large video on half the display. This has been particularly helpful on airplanes in lieu of using a laptop or tablet during long flights.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="pznZc4sAEJRb9jEBZyXZRK" name="Google-Pixel-9-Pro-Fold-07.jpg" alt="Pixel 9 Pro Fold" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pznZc4sAEJRb9jEBZyXZRK.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Speaking of long flights, battery life is another area that foldables have over <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-flip-phones">flip phones</a>. Given the larger form factor, the Pixel 9 Pro Fold has more room to incorporate large batteries, which it definitely needs to power two displays. I&apos;ve been delightfully surprised with the battery life of the Pixel, lasting pretty much all day before needing a top-up, although <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/how-fast-is-the-google-pixel-9-pro-fold-charging-speed">the charging situation</a> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/does-the-pixel-9-pro-fold-support-wireless-charging">could be better</a>.</p><p>This differs from my early experience with flip phones, with phones like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2023-how-it-started-how-its-going">Razr Plus 2023</a> struggling to make it through even half a day.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="8kTUfssJKYiZ6JZLTWBch9" name="Google-Pixel-9-Pro-Fold-06.jpg" alt="Pixel 9 Pro Fold home screen" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8kTUfssJKYiZ6JZLTWBch9.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2384" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I also realize that I&apos;ve changed quite a bit of my usual behaviors when using the 9 Pro Fold. For example, I normally don&apos;t like to have widgets or apps on my main home screen, opting to keep it clean with just the bottom row of apps and a clock widget at the top. However, the large inner screen on the 9 Pro Fold <em>invites</em> you to fill it with widgets and apps, and it was one of the first things I did when I set it up.</p><p>Additionally, I often don&apos;t use split-screen multitasking on regular phones or even flip phones because it feels awkward working with two scrunched-up apps on a smaller display. The 9 Pro Fold changed that for me, and multitasking feels easy-to-use and incredibly natural thanks to having two fully-sized apps to work with, as well as the easily accessible app pairs to instantly open up two apps simultaneously.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4232px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.26%;"><img id="foMdWDkAdjygAHYBSNvT7H" name="Google-Pixel-9-Pro-Fold-04.jpg" alt="Pixel 9 Pro Fold open apps view" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/foMdWDkAdjygAHYBSNvT7H.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4232" height="2381" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>And I love having a taskbar at the bottom that I can easily recall whenever I want to open a frequently used app. Suffice it to say the Pixel 9 Pro makes me feel incredibly productive, more so than I&apos;ve felt with any other phone.</p>
<h2 id="there-apos-s-still-work-to-be-done-2">There&apos;s still work to be done</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="4CnEX2VGNqXpumbPV2w5GV" name="Google-Pixel-9-Pro-Fold-Motorola-Razr-Plus-2024-cover-screens.jpg" alt="Pixel 9 Pro Fold next to the Razr Plus 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4CnEX2VGNqXpumbPV2w5GV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>One area that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">foldable phones</a> also do better in is photography, as these devices often come with more than a few cameras. On many foldable phones like the Pixel 9 Pro Fold, you&apos;ll find three rear cameras with varying focal lengths, plus a front-facing camera on the external display and another on the inner display. This makes it possible to capture better images with arguably better (and more) sensors.</p><p>That said, not all foldables are made the same, and often you&apos;ll find that the sensors being used are downgraded compared to their more traditional candybar counterparts. This is the case with the Pixel 9 Pro Fold, which does not get the same sensors as the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-review">Pixel 9 Pro</a>. And while I would prefer that an $1800 phone should have the best cameras, I doubt you&apos;ll be disappointed by the images. Are they the best? I don&apos;t think so. But they are still quite good and show off Google&apos;s excellent computational photography, which can boost even mediocre sensors.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="UNUp45MCEw9mHcXCqrynaH" name="PXL_20240921_024633737.jpg" alt="Lights handing above a street" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/UNUp45MCEw9mHcXCqrynaH.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="4000" height="3000" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Unfortunately, my experience with the Pixel 9 Pro Fold has also shown me that there&apos;s still some work to do with large-screened foldables. This is particularly noticeable with the app experience, which has been... mixed.</p><p>There are a number of apps that fully take advantage of the larger folding display by adjusting their UI with new placement of various elements or even dual-pane views. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-messages-first-things-to-do">Google Messages</a> is one such app that I love using in this view, as I can easily keep my inbox in view while responding to a text. This is also the same for the Settings menu and plenty of Google apps, and I love using the Kindle app on the foldable.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="QKFizebsYUmJFi5ZmZUPb8" name="Google-Pixel-9-Pro-Fold-kindle-app.jpg" alt="The Pixel 9 Pro Fold next to books" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QKFizebsYUmJFi5ZmZUPb8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Unfortunately, not all apps have been optimized for such a large display. Instagram has a different UI on the larger screen, but the app just looks strange when blown up, and the content is way too large. Many other apps that aren&apos;t optimized look even weirder, and don&apos;t even get me started on games, which are painful to play on the large display. You have the option to adjust the aspect ratio of the apps, but the solution isn&apos;t perfect, and switching between displays can lead to some wonkiness.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="djA6kQZuk7nZCyxFBFi9S9" name="Google-Pixel-9-Pro-Fold-10.jpg" alt="Gmail on the Pixel 9 Pro Fold" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/djA6kQZuk7nZCyxFBFi9S9.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2384" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4130px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.22%;"><img id="QfrnrVDpXfDevP3bSvAz4A" name="Google-Pixel-9-Pro-Fold-09.jpg" alt="Gmail on the Pixel 9 Pro Fold" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QfrnrVDpXfDevP3bSvAz4A.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4130" height="2322" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The weirdest example I&apos;ve had is with the Gmail app, which has a foldable/tablet UI but requires that you rotate the phone to get it to show up. This isn&apos;t the case with the original <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-fold-review">Pixel Fold</a>, and it&apos;s likely a result of the new aspect ratio of the Pixel 9 Pro Fold. Having such a large display, I would love to take advantage of it as often as possible. Still, as Android Central senior editor Nick Sutrich points out, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/everyone-was-wrong-about-the-og-pixel-fold">perhaps the Pixel Fold had it right all along with its design</a>.</p>
<h2 id="flip-phones-are-perfectly-imperfect-2">Flip phones are perfectly imperfect</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="KrYVmGmoLkmnXejc4GWS8h" name="Motorola-Razr-Plus-2024-review-04.jpg" alt="The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 open at an angle with a video playing and the Android Bot placed on it" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KrYVmGmoLkmnXejc4GWS8h.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>There&apos;s no doubt the Pixel 9 Pro Fold is a great phone, and there&apos;s plenty to like about it and the form factor. However, my allegiance continues to lie with flip phones, and there are a few reasons why.</p><p>Of course, there&apos;s nostalgia. It&apos;s cool to have a big folding phone, but having a flip phone just takes me back. Not to mention the novelty of the form factor, which captures the attention of most people who see me using it. In my experience, iPhone users are particularly intrigued by my Razr and are always very impressed with the phone, although ultimately bummed that it&apos;s not an iPhone.</p><p>But beyond simple nostalgia, I really love the form factor and the cover screen experience, especially when companies get it right. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-6-hands-on">Samsung always fumbles this</a> a bit, but Motorola has <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-set-up-use-motorola-razr-cover-screen-apps">nearly perfected the cover screen experience</a>, allowing users to open and use nearly any app without opening the phone. It can take some getting used to, but this is mostly how I use my <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2024">Razr Plus 2024</a>.</p><p>With larger foldables, you have a regular-sized display and an even larger display. This is great for some, but I like the smaller cover screen experience partly because I find it to be a more inconspicuous way to use apps.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="WiWAHUFxCTTZ5fGX89DZMa" name="Motorola-Razr-Plus-2024-review-03.jpg" alt="The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 cover screen panels view" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WiWAHUFxCTTZ5fGX89DZMa.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Of course, not every flip phone has an expansive cover screen, but companies try to make the best out of what they have, using them as ways to simply view notifications, check the time or weather, and utilize a few other simple functions. In a way, these <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/nubia-flip-5g-review">simpler flip phones</a> are great for anyone who maybe wants to physically shut their phone away without having too much to distract them aside from glanceable notifications, almost like a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch">smartwatch</a>.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="xbvS7EPcY8cr5BroM4PLe8" name="Nubia-Flip-5G-review-4.jpg" alt="Notifications showing on the Nubia Flip 5G cover screen" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xbvS7EPcY8cr5BroM4PLe8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Lastly, there&apos;s the price. Large-screen foldables often cost $1800 or more, while flip phones usually cost around $999 and will <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-2024-review">even go for much less</a>. It&apos;s much easier to offer a mid-priced flip phone than it is a book-style foldable, and I just can&apos;t see myself paying a month&apos;s rent for a phone. Do you know how many PS5 Pros I can get for the price of a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Galaxy Z Fold 6</a>?</p><p>But I digress. After all, foldables still have the upper hand when it comes to certain things. They usually have more cameras, with most flip phones limited to two rear sensors and a selfie cam.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4221px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="YRQTJ9P6J9rk777bFSQAcR" name="Google-Pixel-9-Pro-Fold-Motorola-Razr-Plus-2024-hinge.jpg" alt="Pixel 9 Pro Fold next to the Razr Plus 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YRQTJ9P6J9rk777bFSQAcR.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4221" height="2374" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It&apos;s also easier to make a thinner book-style foldable, again, given the larger real estate. This means you have more surface area to fit the battery and other components, so foldables like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-v3-hands-on">Honor Magic V3</a> will be as thin as a regular phone when folded, whereas a flip phone will often be twice as thick in its folded state. I don&apos;t have a problem with it, but it makes it difficult when cases are involved.</p>
<h2 id="to-fold-or-to-flip-2">To fold or to flip</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3984px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="XwmSSrLrKvQfobwQaJ9hSN" name="Google-Pixel-9-Pro-Fold-Motorola-Razr-Plus-2024-cameras.jpg" alt="Pixel 9 Pro Fold next to the Razr Plus 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XwmSSrLrKvQfobwQaJ9hSN.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3984" height="2241" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Many people are still not fully comfortable with the idea of owning a foldable phone, which is understandable. However, they&apos;ve come a long way and have improved their design, functionality, and durability with each passing year. As a result, we&apos;re seeing more foldables from more companies, and we&apos;re even getting some affordable options that won&apos;t cost an arm and a leg.</p><p>I love Motorola&apos;s flip phones, but the Pixel 9 Pro definitely surprised me with its impressive build quality and the overall experience of owning a phone with such a large display. Plus, having access to all the fun Google AI features is a huge win in Pixel&apos;s favor, although I wish I could take advantage of an S Pen-like stylus like what you can do with Samsung phones.</p><p>Foldables aren&apos;t for everyone, but once you consider the idea, it comes down to whether you want a book-style foldable with a large, tablet-like screen for productivity and content viewing or a compact flip phone with a small cover screen and the nostalgic sensation of shutting your phone closed when you want to hang up on someone dramatically.</p><p>There are pros and cons to both, but the biggest is price. Fortunately, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/prime-day-is-back-next-month-faq-early-deals-and-everything-you-need-to-know-about-the-big-sale">Amazon&apos;s October Prime Day sale</a> is upon us, and there are plenty of intriguing sales on phones. The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 has already received some <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/october-prime-day-motorola-deals-have-come-early-score-40-off-foldable-phones-epic-flagship-discounts-and-more">impressive discounts</a> this year despite going on sale in July, and even if the Pixel 9 Pro Fold isn&apos;t on sale, there are other discounts on book-style foldable phones, such as this <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C34DL6Z7">nearly $700 discount on the original Pixel Fold</a>.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="d401810d-6720-40c5-b2c7-5394a5e6b722">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZkX3CQEBivTSyqQpFs3ntU.jpg' alt="The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 in Spring Green"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Motorola Razr Plus 2024</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Flip the script</strong></em></p>
<p>The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 is one of our favorite phones this year, sporting a powerful Snapdragon chip, upgraded cameras, and all-day battery life. The large 4-inch cover screen makes it fun to use apps or take selfies without even opening the phone.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="a1eb0d18-ee72-46b1-b965-ecb3168f67ad">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/eN3jfcnhHLaPsGfQNGHWdf.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold Official Render - Porcelain - Tabletop"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The folding standard</strong></em></p>
<p>The Pixel 9 Pro Fold features the best of the Pixel series but with a large folding display. It's perfect for multitasking and watching content, and the Tensor chip supports plenty of fun AI features to help take your photos to the next level.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/pixel-9-pro-fold-changed-my-mind-about-foldables-but-i-still-prefer-flip-phones</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Foldable phones come in two main flavors, and choosing between them means figuring out what you want out of your phone. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">J9fm5p5bi9RNMGNdQT3b7i</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qmMDRrLXfwiavZT8Tx2A3F.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 18:39:09 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ derrek.lee@futurenet.com (Derrek Lee) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qmMDRrLXfwiavZT8Tx2A3F.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Pixel 9 Pro Fold next to the Razr Plus 2024]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Pixel 9 Pro Fold next to the Razr Plus 2024]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ My favorite Sony OLED TV just received a staggering 32% discount during Amazon Prime Day ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Prime Day is always a good time to hunt down OLED TV deals, but even I&apos;m surprised by the discounts on display during this week&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/prime-day-is-back-next-month-faq-early-deals-and-everything-you-need-to-know-about-the-big-sale">Prime Big Deal Days event</a>. </p><p>While most of the attention so far has been drawn towards Amazon&apos;s epic <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=lg+oled"><strong>LG OLED discounts</strong></a><strong> </strong>(rightfully so), you should know that the top-rated 65-inch Sony Bravia 8 OLED TV has just received its own <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CVQ6YLH7"><strong>record-smashing 32% price drop</strong></a> — and you don&apos;t even need to be a Prime member to receive the savings. </p>
<ul><li><strong>See all the October Prime Day deals: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/"><u><strong>USA</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/"><u><strong>UK</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.ca/"><u><strong>Canada</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.in/"><u><strong>India</strong></u></a> </li></ul>
<h2 id="a-prime-day-deal-for-the-history-books-2">A Prime Day deal for the history books</h2>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="21f4c8ce-bc7a-4355-9d92-131adedf16e6" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$2,499.99" data-dimension48="$2,499.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CVQ6YLH7/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:60.47%;"><img id="8GfcT2siLEGWYSmKwZPoeG" name="sony-bravia-8-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8GfcT2siLEGWYSmKwZPoeG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1500" height="907" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Sony 65" Bravia 8 OLED TV:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-Exclusive-Features-PlayStation-K-65XR80/dp/B0CVQ6YLH7/" data-dimension112="21f4c8ce-bc7a-4355-9d92-131adedf16e6" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$2,499.99" data-dimension48="$2,499.99"><del>$2,499.99</del> <strong>$1,698 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>Make no mistake: OLED TVs are a major purchase, but when you're ready to spend some cash to upgrade your home theater, why not go big? The Sony Bravia 8 is one of the OLEDs that I recommend the most, namely because of the TV's powerful XR processor with contrast boosting that optimizes picture and sound in real time, alongside the suite of exclusive PS5 features that every serious gamer should experience at least once. </p>
<p>As part of Amazon's 48-hour Prime Day sale, the 65-inch Bravia 8 is enjoying an incredible 32% discount. That's the biggest price drop that the TV has EVER received, and it's unlikely to drop much further until 2025, at least. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CVQ6YLH7/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="21f4c8ce-bc7a-4355-9d92-131adedf16e6" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$2,499.99" data-dimension48="$2,499.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>If the 65-inch smart TV isn&apos;t right for your home, fear not: the 55-inch and 77-inch models are receiving <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-Exclusive-Features-PlayStation-K-65XR80/dp/B0CVPSBMGY">22%</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-Exclusive-Features-PlayStation-K-65XR80/dp/B0CVQGRW9F">10% discounts</a>, respectively, so take your pick. </p><p>Like all of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-tvs">best Android TVs</a> out there, the Sony Bravia 8 (2024) was specifically designed with gamers and movie lovers in mind. The AI-powered XR processor optimizes all of the images in real time so the brightness, color, and contrast are as immersive as possible, while Sony&apos;s Acoustic Surface Audio Plus technology delivers cinema-quality sound, even when you aren&apos;t using one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-soundbars">best soundbars</a>. </p>
<h2 id="want-a-cheaper-alternative-2">Want a cheaper alternative?</h2>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="c2a2a242-3354-4bcd-bda7-f97d91c8ff7c" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$449.99" data-dimension48="$449.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D4NYW7QS" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:61.47%;"><img id="7VHDhD9qWQXJR3quvT8SyN" name="tcl-class-s5-4k-smart-tv-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7VHDhD9qWQXJR3quvT8SyN.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1500" height="922" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>TCL 65" Class S5 UHD 4K Fire TV:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D4NYW7QS" data-dimension112="c2a2a242-3354-4bcd-bda7-f97d91c8ff7c" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$449.99" data-dimension48="$449.99"><del>$449.99</del> <strong>$369.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>Of course, you don't need to drop over a thousand bucks if you simply want good picture. Although it won't win any awards for innovation, the 65-inch Class S5 Fire TV by TCL delivers crystal clear 4K resolution with Dolby Vision and a surprisingly-decent game optimization mode. The only catch is that you need to be an Amazon Prime member to take advantage of this deal. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D4NYW7QS" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="c2a2a242-3354-4bcd-bda7-f97d91c8ff7c" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$449.99" data-dimension48="$449.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<ul><li><strong>More</strong> <strong>TV deals: </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/browse/electronics/tvs/3944_1060825_447913"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/televisions-home-theater/tvs/all-tvs/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/promo/tv-deals"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/40E7E961-A3DD-4E8C-8B88-4274A840DF67?ingress=0&visitId=183fc793-0cec-425f-816d-4e9b1d420367"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.newegg.com/TV-Video/Category/ID-59"><u><strong>Newegg</strong></u></a> </li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/my-favorite-sony-oled-tv-just-received-a-staggering-32-percent-discount-during-amazon-prime-day</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ As part of its sitewide Prime Day sale event, Amazon is carving a record-breaking 32% off this top-rated 65-inch OLED by Sony.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">j3Do4phzaSAHB8nQcJZpv8</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/cBkbjy8kq4yDFnxxHrcWnk.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 18:30:23 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Streaming &amp; TV]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/cBkbjy8kq4yDFnxxHrcWnk.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Sony]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Sony Bravia 8 OLED TV in living room]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Sony Bravia 8 OLED TV in living room]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ This incredible "beast of a smartwatch" just got a 35% discount during the October Prime Day sale ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The TicWatch Pro 5 got rave reviews from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/ticwatch-pro-5-review">our reviewer</a>, who gave it 4.5 stars for its incredible performance, multi-day battery life, and overall Wear OS 3 experience. While it’s usually $349.99, this smartwatch is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BYS4KJV6"><strong>now selling for $227.49, $122.50 off</strong></a> during Amazon Big Deal Days. That’s a 35% discount!</p><p>What should you know about this smartwatch? It’s only compatible with Android devices and runs Wear OS 3. Our reviewer describes it as a Pixel Watch with a larger 1.43-inch display. What he really loves about this device is Essential Mode that involves a standard screen that’s always visible combined with a low-power panel you can use when you want to save battery life. That helps contribute to the up to 80-hour battery life, or just over three days. </p>
<ul><li><strong>See all the October Prime Day deals: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/"><u><strong>USA</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/"><u><strong>UK</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.ca/"><u><strong>Canada</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.in/"><u><strong>India</strong></u></a> </li></ul>
<p>Key features include a 5ATM water-resistant rating so you can safely swim with it, 100+ sports modes, built-in GPS, speaker and mic, sleep tracking, blood oxygen saturation, stress monitoring, 24-hour heart rate monitoring, and smart training features. Bottom line: this watch pretty much has it all.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="25e7dc96-c59e-4e99-bb99-91f6711ef6d4" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Ticwatch Pro 5: $349.99" data-dimension48="Ticwatch Pro 5: $349.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BYS4KJV6" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="BcJ6h7TPbheCkAkq7M8jMM" name="ticwatch-pro-5-enduro-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BcJ6h7TPbheCkAkq7M8jMM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="500" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Ticwatch Pro 5: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BYS4KJV6" data-dimension112="25e7dc96-c59e-4e99-bb99-91f6711ef6d4" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Ticwatch Pro 5: $349.99" data-dimension48="Ticwatch Pro 5: $349.99"><del>$349.99</del><strong> $227.49 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>What truly sets the Pixel Watch-like Ticwatch Pro 5 apart from others is the extremely useful Essential Mode that helps extend battery life by displaying a low-power panel when you manually select it, or even on a schedule. Packed with premium features, this watch is being offered for the lowest price we’ve ever seen it sell for.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BYS4KJV6" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="25e7dc96-c59e-4e99-bb99-91f6711ef6d4" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Ticwatch Pro 5: $349.99" data-dimension48="Ticwatch Pro 5: $349.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>Recommended for:</strong> Someone who wants an experience like a Google Pixel Watch without the added frills and the bigger price tag. </p><p><strong>Skip this deal if: </strong>You want Google Assistant and worry about long-term use with future Wear OS updates it might not support. </p><p>What else does our reviewer love about this premium smartwatch? He appreciates that the Snapdragon W5+ processor ensures snappy performance: he didn’t once experience slow loading or stutter when scrolling through menus. He misses not having Google Assistant access, but realistically, how often would you use it anyway? He also has concerns about future Wear OS updates. But for now, this smartwatch is indeed updatable to the latest Wear OS 4. </p><p>Overall, he gives this watch the seal of approval even over the Samsung Galaxy Watch 5, mostly thanks to the genius that is Essential Mode. It’s a feat to be able to deliver a smartwatch at this price that rivals a Samsung Galaxy model. </p><p>Knowing you can immediately update this smartwatch to WearOS 4 out of the box and get the best performance possible makes it easy to forget that it was launched a year and-a-half ago. The Mobvoi Ticwatch Pro 5 still has plenty of life left in it, and with the stand-out Essential Mode feature, you can extend battery life for those times you need it most. A smartwatch like this at its regular price is a bargain, and with the cost down to $227.49 for Amazon Big Deal Days, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BYS4KJV6">reduced by $122.50 from the regular price of $349.99</a>, it’s worth considering for the fitness fan on your list.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/this-incredible-beast-of-a-smartwatch-just-got-a-35-percent-discount-during-the-october-prime-day-sale</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The TicWatch Pro 5 is a solid smartwatch to rival the Google Pixel Watch with some stand-out features, and it's on sale right now for Amazon Big Deal Days. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Kh8rAzKRF7Mm98b2kaVgRE</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/F6C2nwA7DGLpsCDHvWgpTS.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 18:06:37 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ christinep2424@gmail.com (Christine Persaud) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/F6C2nwA7DGLpsCDHvWgpTS.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[TicWatch Pro 5 Enduro review hero 16x9]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[TicWatch Pro 5 Enduro review hero 16x9]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>