<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 16:49:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ OnePlus Ace 3 Pro aces with prominent specs and a new Glacier battery ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>OnePlus Ace 3 Pro was unveiled in China and comes with three interesting finishes.</li><li>It also sports a massive 6100mAh battery with support for 100W fast charging.</li><li>The Ace 3 Pro also sports a 6.78-inch curved AMOLED panel with a 120Hz refresh rate.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>The OnePlus Ace 3 Pro is the company&apos;s next flagship phone, and it looks like the device packs some serious specs and a new battery technology. It was announced in China this week alongside the new OnePlus Pad Pro and OnePlus Watch 2.</p><p>The highlighted flagship specs of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.oneplus.com/cn/ace-3-pro">OnePlus Ace 3 Pro</a> involve the handset powered by the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 and supports up to a whopping 24GB of LPDDR5X RAM aided by up to 1TB of storage. Besides, the company provides multiple storage combinations for users to choose from. </p><p>The Ace 3 Pro also features the OnePlus’s new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-introduces-new-glacier-battery-featuring-6100mah">Glacier battery technology</a>, which is more efficient than conventional ones and sports large capacity while maintaining a minimum build. It means a massive 6100mAh battery capacity, backed by 100W Super Flash Charge, is equipped in the flagship.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="69ssppNtHhuVB6th4dvbNn" name="OnePlus-Ace-3-Pro-03.jpg" alt="OnePlus Ace 3 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/69ssppNtHhuVB6th4dvbNn.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OnePlus)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="2CRNnsacVjmArRB48jzc8n" name="OnePlus-Ace-3-Pro-02.jpg" alt="OnePlus Ace 3 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2CRNnsacVjmArRB48jzc8n.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OnePlus)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>On the design front, the OnePlus Ace 3 Pro stands out with its premium design, color options, and a slightly curved screen up front. It comes in three finishes on the back comprising glass finishes, next to leather and ceramic finishes. The device’s thickness amongst these finishes slightly differs, too. While they look different from the back in these finishes, they all use metal middle frames and look the same from the front.</p><p>According to OnePlus, the display measures 6.78 inches with a 120Hz refresh rate and is an AMOLED flexible curved screen. It features a screen-to-body ratio of 94.2% and achieves a peak brightness of 4500 nits. The display is protected by Corning Gorilla Glass Victus 2. The overall design of the Ace 3 Pro appears similar to that of the flagship OnePlus, with minor design changes at the back with the camera module, which now seems slightly pronounced.</p><p>The gigantic camera module, in fact, reminds us of the visor from other OnePlus/Oppo devices like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-open-review">OnePlus Open</a> and Find N3, for example. The camera visor on the Ace 3 Pro includes a 50MP primary lens aided by an 8MP ultra-wide angle lens and a tiny 2MP camera with macro shooting capabilities. The device relies on a 16MP selfie camera on the front. Rear cameras are capable of 4K video recording, whereas the front camera settles with 1080p.</p>
<p>Other notable features of the Ace 3 Pro include support for Spatial Audio and the inclusion of dual stereo speakers. It further comes with IP65 dust and water resistance. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review">Android 14</a>-based ColorOS 14.1 is seen on the handset for the Chinese region, whereas the other markets could be seeing OxygenOS 14 when released. The handset supports 5G, Wi-Fi 6, Bluetooth 5.4, GPS, and NFC connectivity options.</p><p>The Ace 3 Pro will go on sale in China from July 3. The glass and leather finish models are priced at CNY 3199 for 12GB+256GB and CNY 3499 for 16GB+256GB. The larger 16GB+512GB variant is priced at CNY 3799, followed by the 24GB+1TB variant for CNY 4399. The Porcelain variant, on the other hand, comes in 16GB+512GB and 24GB+1TB, which are priced at CNY 3999 and CNY 4599, respectively.</p><p>If previous Ace Pro series releases are any indication, the latest Ace 3 pro is likely to take on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones </a>later this year on a global level, dubbed as the OnePlus 12T.<br></p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-ace-3-pro-announced-in-china</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ OnePlus has introduced its next Ace series device, which might debut as the OnePlus 12T — if the company chooses to release the “T” model later this year. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">QsYzXQ6VNUqQzRwHJwFy3C</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2ZmwaNSKKBukbLphQ6UuHn.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 16:09:09 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2ZmwaNSKKBukbLphQ6UuHn.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[OnePlus]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus Ace 3 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus Ace 3 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Honor Magic V3 teaser suggests it could shake things up for foldables ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Following the success of the slim Magic V2, Honor aims to push the boundaries of innovation with the Magic V3.</li><li>Honor promises the V3 will challenge "the new height of folding and thinness," with a visual comparison highlighting its sleek design.</li><li>The V3 will include AI-powered eye protection and anti-fraud technology.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Honor has teased a new foldable phone, the Magic V3, and it looks like the phone maker is aiming for pocket-perfect thinness.</p><p>When the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-v2-review">Honor Magic V2</a> hit the market last year, it shook things up as the slimmest foldable phone ever made. But Honor isn&apos;t stopping there. The company seems to be determined to keep pushing the boundaries of innovation and setting new standards.</p><p>Honor has everyone buzzing about its upcoming Magic V3 with a teaser on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://m.weibo.cn/detail/5049505227477101" target="_blank">Weibo</a> (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/06/27/honor-magic-v3-foldable-teaser/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a>). The post asks (machine-translated), "Can folding screens be thinner and lighter?"</p><p>The Chinese firm also gave a nod to the Magic V2, which wowed the public as the thinnest foldable at 9.9mm. Achieving the sleek profile of last year&apos;s model was no small feat, especially with all the high-end features packed into it. The hinge mechanism provided a smooth and durable folding experience. Plus, the use of lightweight materials made the phone both easy to hold and impressively sturdy.</p><p>Honor wraps up its Weibo post with a bold claim: the Magic V3 will challenge "the new height of folding and thinness." The company backs this up with a visual comparison, showing the profiles of the Magic V2 and the upcoming V3 side by side.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:22.73%;"><img id="9BEvCsBmqBtsYWRAkpYE39" name="Honor-magic-V3-teaser.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3 teaser on Weibo showing its relative slim design" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9BEvCsBmqBtsYWRAkpYE39.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4400" height="1000" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Honor / Weibo)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:22.73%;"><img id="kH9NN6wd9o2sKuVCjWHfQ8" name="Honor-magic-V2-thickness.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V2 thickness" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kH9NN6wd9o2sKuVCjWHfQ8.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4400" height="1000" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Honor / Weibo)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Honor&apos;s teaser for the Magic V3 gives us a glimpse of a phone that looks impossibly thin compared to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">leading foldable phones</a> out there. While the image hints at the V3&apos;s sleek design, Honor is keeping the exact thickness under wraps, leaving fans eagerly guessing until the big reveal.</p><p>Rumors have been swirling that the Magic V3 will be a beast under the hood, featuring a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-3">Snapdragon 8 Gen 3</a> chipset. It&apos;s said to have a 5,000mAh battery with 66W fast charging. Photography enthusiasts will love the rumored 50MP main camera.</p><p>In another post, Honor highlights the Magic V3&apos;s smart features, including AI-powered eye protection and anti-fraud technology. The wait won&apos;t be long, as Honor hints at an imminent launch, with rumors suggesting a Chinese release next month.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-v3-teaser-suggests-it-could-shake-things-up-for-foldables</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Honor has dropped a teaser for the Magic V3, hinting that it will be even slimmer than its predecessor. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">vfm5UoYf9KKsDdZFwpbxgg</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9V7gzZidQA3CXRY8mRYChh.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 15:54:13 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9V7gzZidQA3CXRY8mRYChh.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Honor Magic V2 review]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Honor Magic V2 review]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Here’s what the odd timing of the Google Pixel event could mean ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google usually announces products in October, but the company sent out surprise invites for a Made by Google event in August this week.</li><li>Additionally, Google bucked a growing trend when it decided not to announce or showcase new hardware at Google I/O 2024 last month. </li><li>Google could be trying to streamline its product announcements, thwart leaks, and beat competitors to the punch with the early event.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Tech product launches are nothing if not consistent. Samsung does biannual Galaxy Unpacked events in the summer and winter, Apple makes iPhone announcements in September, and Google does Pixel events in October. At least, that was the launch cycle until Google surprised us all by announcing a Made by Google event in the middle of August. Invites were <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/made-by-google-event-2024-date-announced">sent out earlier this week</a>, and it’s clearly the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9">Pixel 9 series</a> launch event.</p><p>Media invites explained that the Made by Google event was happening Tuesday, August 13 at Google’s Mountain View headquarters. There’s a keynote scheduled for 10 AM PT, and attendees will get hands-on time with the products afterward. But the stunner has something to do with the date: Google didn’t host a Made by Google event until October 4 of last year.  </p><p>Many could be announced at the Made by Google event, including as many as four smartphones. There might be three regular Pixel 9 series devices revealed, as well as a Pixel Fold successor. Additionally, Google could release multiple Pixel Watch variants for the first time ever. If that wasn’t enough, there’s always the possibility that Google surprises us with something else. </p><p>The Pixel Tablet might be due for an update, and Google hasn’t touched Nest hardware in a while. On top of that, there are devices that rumors and leaks have suggested are ready to go, like a new version of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/chromecast-with-google-tv-4k-successor-may-come-soon-new-remote">Chromecast with Google TV 4K</a>. The Pixel 9 and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-3">Pixel Watch 3</a> models feel like virtual locks for a debut at the Made by Google event, but there could be more.</p><p>Android 15 might also be revealed further at the event since the Pixel 9 series will be the first smartphone to ship running the updated operating system. But why is the event coming nearly two months earlier than usual? We don’t know for sure, but there are a few reasons Google might have jumped the gun on the Pixel 9 series launch.</p>
<h2 id="google-didn-x2019-t-announce-hardware-at-google-i-o-2">Google didn’t announce hardware at Google I/O</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4096px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="3pBjJC5bKxADjVBKFg7LSk" name="Google-IO-2024-Sundar-Pichai.jpg" alt="Sundar Pichai at Google I/O 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3pBjJC5bKxADjVBKFg7LSk.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4096" height="2304" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nick Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>This year, Google I/O 2024 was all about software. It’s a developer conference, but this is the first time in a while that no hardware products were previewed or announced at I/O. If you recall, the Pixel Tablet was showcased at I/O 2022 and subsequently released after I/O 2023. Google also announced the first Pixel Fold at I/O 2023. </p><p>It would make sense for Google to keep a consistent release cycle by refreshing the Pixel Fold and Pixel Tablet at subsequent I/O conferences. That didn’t happen this year. Instead, it’s possible that Google wants to confine the main Pixel hardware releases to a single event. This might give us a reason why Google is rumored to call the Pixel Fold successor the Pixel 9 Pro Fold, as opposed to the Pixel Fold 2. </p><p>In a way, this strategy is sound. Google’s hardware releases are spread out, with the A-series Pixel, Pixel Tablet, and Pixel Fold all usually releasing sometime in May. Then, the flagship Pixels and Pixel Watch release in October. This approach means that there are new Pixel devices released roughly every 6 months. </p><p>August is right in the middle of May and October, so if Google wants to consolidate its product releases, August would be the month to do it. As such, I wouldn‘t be surprised if we saw a variety of hardware releases at the Made by Google event. If this is indeed Google’s plan, buyers would be able to get a look at the complete Pixel ecosystem every summer. </p>
<h2 id="google-might-be-getting-ahead-of-apple-intelligence-2">Google might be getting ahead of Apple Intelligence</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="YfD6Q5pxGMKDQxCieNMHP6" name="everything-ios-18-stole-from-android.png" alt="iOS 18 Lock Screen on iPhone 15 Pro Max and Android 15 logo on Pixel 8 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YfD6Q5pxGMKDQxCieNMHP6.png" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>By moving the Made by Google event to August, Google is getting ahead of Apple’s annual September event. There’s no way to know whether this was intentional or just a coincidence, but there are clear advantages to the move. Google was the first to make an “AI smartphone” with the Pixel 8 and Pixel 8 Pro last year, and with Apple Intelligence on the horizon, it will need to work hard to stay at the top of the mobile AI race.</p><p>Google has a numerous artificial intelligence features bundled with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a>, including <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-io-2024-gemini-nano-detect-suspected-scams">AI-based spam call detection</a> and automatic theft detection. There are plenty more that tie in with Gemini, Circle to Search, and other features. Android 15 will publicly release first on the Pixel 9 series, so Google could get ahead of Apple Intelligence by moving up the Made by Google event date. </p><p>Google might also debut new AI features that are exclusive to the Pixel 9 series. It has a chance to set the bar before Apple Intelligence and the iPhone 16 series are publicly released, and that’s a huge benefit to having an event in August. </p><p>Finally, the company could by trying to cut down on leaks by releasing the Pixel 9 series earlier. Recent Pixel releases have been ravaged by leaks, with nearly all details about the devices becoming available before they’re announced. Shortening the release cycle gives leakers less time to gather information. However, this is probably the least likely of the possible reasons for the August event. Companies are always trying to limit leaks, but they don’t usually alter their plans because of them.</p><p>Of all the potential reasons for Google moving its event up to August, I think the release schedule makes the most sense. There have been inklings that Google has wanted to consolidate its product releases, and there being no launches at I/O was a telltale sign that the company is shaking things up. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/heres-what-the-odd-timing-of-the-google-pixel-event-could-mean</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google’s hardware event comes two months early, and we have a few guesses as to why.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Z6gPT4xUpWdZzYLCfRnfoM</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/q3Tw3ZYvQEcbBC7akRG9UE.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 13:36:10 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/q3Tw3ZYvQEcbBC7akRG9UE.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9 mockup with name]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9 mockup with name]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ These new Solos smart glasses take the fight to Meta AI with ChatGPT-4o integration ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Solos unveiled its new AirGo Vision smart glasses at the Hong Kong Smart Glasses Summit. These are the first wearables to be integrated with ChatGPT-4o.</li><li>These glasses are programmed to provide real-time answers to visual and vocal prompts based on what the user is looking at and recognizing people or objects.</li><li>AirGo Vision will go on sale in July and can be purchased on Solos' website for $249.99.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>On Friday (June 28), Solos announced the launch of its AirGo Vision, the first-ever smart glasses integrated with ChatGPT-4o, which gives these glasses a multimodal AI touch. </p><p>Earlier this year, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/chatgpt-on-solos-airgo-3-smart-glasses">Solos AirGo 3</a> smart glasses received ChatGPT&apos;s capabilities to translate speech to and from your language of choice via the glasses&apos; built-in microphone and speakers.</p><p>With the new version, the glasses come with an in-built camera and LED frames, although the company states these glasses "aim to provide consumers with both choice and privacy." One unique feature introduced with this new version is allowing users to swap out frames, choosing when and how they want to use their front camera. When the user opts out of using the front camera, the glasses will continue to maintain all smart functionality aside from the camera. </p><p>These AirGo Vision smart glasses are said to provide real-time information based on what the user is looking at, be it recognizing people or objects. For instance, you can ask the glasses, "What am I looking at?" or even help the user navigate through a new city by simply asking for directions to a landmark or monument without pulling out the phone. The glasses will then respond to the prompts via the built-in speakers.</p><p>Much like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/ray-ban-meta-smart-glasses-multimodal-ai-video-calling-update">Meta&apos;s Ray Ban smart glasses</a>, these AirGo Vision glasses can also capture photos/visuals on the go.</p><p>The company states that users can even track visual progress and next steps while performing activities like cooking, home improvement, and shopping. Users can simply ask the glasses for a better price option for the commodity in question. </p><p>"Our in-house software team has built the AirGo Vision to harness the power of the best AI models available today," said Kenneth Fan, co-founder of Solos. </p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="JiRV3D5dmeGjsQipihhzCm" name="Solos-AirGo.jpg" alt="Solos AirGo Vision" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JiRV3D5dmeGjsQipihhzCm.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4000" height="4000" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Solos)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4780px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:65.21%;"><img id="RSChScTHNJtgmzuv2j7VLh" name="Solos-AirGo-Vision-frames .jpg" alt="Solos AirGo Vision" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RSChScTHNJtgmzuv2j7VLh.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4780" height="3117" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Solos)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="6BsFz9EQ7tAkCnYXjeinFi" name="Solos-AirGo-Vision-2.jpg" alt="Solos AirGo Vision" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6BsFz9EQ7tAkCnYXjeinFi.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4000" height="4000" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Solos)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Regarding the wearable&apos;s usage and power conservation, Solos claims that these smart glasses are built to be used throughout the day and are the most power-efficient on the market.  </p><p>The company states that it wants to really hone in on the hands-fee capabilities of the AirGo Vision. The glasses are expected to have LED notifications on the frame that can be modified into sound or vibration based on the environment the user is in. </p><p>For instance, if the person wearing the glasses is in a quiet location like a library or meeting room, a discreet flash will alert the wearer without disturbing others with sound or vibration. Whereas in noisy environments, where a notification might not be heard, the LED light will visually alert users of incoming calls or important emails. This also acts as a great accessibility feature for those who have problems with hearing. </p><p>"We understand there are different ways people want or need to receive information and are committed to enhancing and customizing the AirGo experience so wearable AI is accessible to all," said Kenny Cheung, Solos GM and president. </p><p>AirGo Vision is set to go on sale "later this year." Solos will release LED-only frames in three different styles starting in July, which can be purchased on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://solosglasses.com/">Solos&apos; website</a> for $249.99.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/solos-airgo-vision-launch</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Solos announced its new AirGo Vision smart glasses, which are said to be integrated with all of ChatGPT-4o's multimodal capabilities and more. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">SsLaQEXewcw5FXP2Lq4TNH</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XHTRjLRvuxgdrGndtnwfok.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 13:00:29 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nandika.iyerravi@futurenet.com (Nandika Ravi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XHTRjLRvuxgdrGndtnwfok.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Solos]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Solos AirGo Vision]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Solos AirGo Vision]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Apple should be ashamed it waited so long to put RCS on iPhones ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>While many iPhone users are rejoicing about the potential of the revamped Siri experience and the ability to place icons anywhere, others are more excited about RCS. Despite not being available with the first iOS 18 Developer Beta, RCS Messaging has been enabled with the second beta, released this week.</p><p>The promise of RCS is pretty simple, as it aims to provide a much smoother and feature-rich messaging experience. The easiest comparison is to think of it as using something like Telegram or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/whatsapp">WhatsApp</a> but from the built-in Messages app. This includes things such as read receipts, typing indicators, message reactions, and high-quality media. </p><p>For years, Google has tried to get Apple on the RCS train to no avail, and it wasn&apos;t until late 2023 that Apple caved. In its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/apple-announces-rcs-support-coming-to-iphone">surprise announcement</a>, Apple confirmed it would be bringing RCS compatibility to the iPhone, while "also working with the GSMA to improve the RCS standard."</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1290px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:82.79%;"><img id="ag4SP9fp6YzTbdXU7axU4A" name="enable-rcs-messaging-iphone.PNG" alt="Toggle to enable RCS Messaging in iPhone Settings app" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ag4SP9fp6YzTbdXU7axU4A.png" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1290" height="1068" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>After installing the latest <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/everything-ios-18-stole-from-android">iOS 18 Developer Beta</a>, I jumped into the Settings app to confirm that the RCS toggle was available. Not only was it available, but it was already enabled. Then, I opened the Messages app and started to send a text to my colleague, Nick Sutrich. </p><p>To my surprise, the Messages app informed me that it was sending a Text Message and that it was using RCS. A few minutes later, we found that a lot of things worked just as we&apos;d expected. Typing indicators appeared, videos sent either way were crystal clear, and Tapback reactions popped up as soon as they were made.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1290px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:22.56%;"><img id="VivfyPMrivoLCaZom3v2x9" name="ios-18-rcs-messaging-test-2.jpeg" alt="Initial RCS test message sent from Andrew's iPhone" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VivfyPMrivoLCaZom3v2x9.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1290" height="291" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It&apos;s also evident that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/early-look-rcs-support-apple-iphone">Apple has some work to do</a>. Nick tried reacting with a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-photomoji-google-messages">Photomoji</a> to the video I sent. However, instead of showing up just like a Tapback reaction, it came through to my iPhone as an MMS with a message that said, "Reacted with a photomoji."</p><p>About a minute later, the conversation switched back to RCS from SMS/MMS. This is where another hiccup appears, as one would hope that the transition back and forth would be instantaneous. Although, I guess it&apos;s better than needing to go back into the Settings app and toggle RCS off and on.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3315px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:72.76%;"><img id="cj9f6Yrm35Ft2sVNgw4Bs9" name="ios-18-dev-beta-rcs-testing.jpg" alt="RCS testing between Nick and Andrew" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/cj9f6Yrm35Ft2sVNgw4Bs9.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="3315" height="2412" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>An earlier report from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5mac.com/2024/06/24/ios-18-rcs-iphone-beta/">9to5Mac</a> stated, "RCS support on the iPhone relies on Apple working with carrier partners to get them to update their bundles." At the time of that writing, it was reported that RCS Messaging was only available on AT&T and T-Mobile. </p><p>This no longer seems to be the case, as my personal <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/apple-iphone-15-pro-max-long-term-review">iPhone 15 Pro Max</a> is on Verizon and was used in the above screenshots. That being said, don&apos;t expect this to work across all carriers, primarily the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-mvno-carrier">MVNO carriers</a> such as Mint Mobile or Visible, just yet. We&apos;ve also seen reports of users with older iPhone models not being able to use RCS <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/iOSBeta/comments/1dnjsji/comment/la58uqy/">without a workaround</a> despite being enrolled in the iOS 18 Developer Beta. </p><p>We&apos;re still early in the development cycle for iOS 18, as the latest software isn&apos;t expected to arrive until this Fall. That gives Apple ample time to work out the kinks before the final release. But this showed us what messaging between iOS and Android should have been all along. </p>
<h2 id="it-didn-apos-t-have-to-be-this-way-2">It didn&apos;t have to be this way</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="YcMNVPGPdvh6VTJEcfRgGW" name="imessage-green-bubble.jpeg" alt="An iMessage chat showing blue and green bubbles" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YcMNVPGPdvh6VTJEcfRgGW.jpeg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Daniel Bader / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I&apos;ve long complained about not being able to use iMessage on Android, as it&apos;s one of the primary ways I keep in touch with family. As a result, I&apos;ve turned to workarounds such as AirMessage, Bluebubbles, Sunbird, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/beeper-mini-removed-from-the-play-store">Beeper</a>. But, after <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/sunbird-pulls-app-from-playstore">security issues exposed Sunbird</a> and Beeper failed to win the fight against Apple, I&apos;ve all but given up on the idea.</p><p>The reality of the situation is that it should have never been this way. Apple might be one of the most valuable companies in the world, but it also holds the distinction of being among the consumer-hostile companies.</p><p>It&apos;s not like RCS is a standard spawned out of thin air, nor is it something brand new. In fact, RCS has been around since 2008 and was made available on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phones</a> through <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-messages-first-things-to-do">Google Messages</a> back in 2020. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="4evyiRw853RVxpTLwWtYqL" name="beeper-app-galaxy-z-fold-5-iphone-14-pro-max-angled-close.jpg" alt="Angled close-up of Beeper app icon on Galaxy Z Fold 5" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4evyiRw853RVxpTLwWtYqL.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Meanwhile, it wasn&apos;t until the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/beeper-gives-android-imessage-app-one-more-go">Beeper debacle</a>, paired with <em>another </em>threat from the EU, that Apple decided to change its tune. What makes the entire situation maddening is that it&apos;s never needed to be this way. </p><p>After using <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-enable-rcs-chat-features-google-messages">RCS</a> to send messages back and forth to Nick for just a few minutes, I ended up incredibly irritated. The "walled garden" approach is a fantastic idea for offering an unrivaled cross-device experience. Your phone, tablet, and computer all work <em>together</em> without needing to jump through hoops. </p><p>The problem is that Apple doesn&apos;t (or didn&apos;t) want its customers to think or even consider what&apos;s on the other side of the wall. It&apos;s why we see ancient phones being used to depict various Android-related features on Apple&apos;s support pages. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1280px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="QCEyddpVeGNmiKC3G4dZhg" name="facetime-links.jpg" alt="Facetime Links" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QCEyddpVeGNmiKC3G4dZhg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1280" height="720" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apple)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Seriously, Apple was using a picture of a chonky, generic-looking Android phone to showcase "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/android-users-can-finally-get-facetime-new-invite-links">FaceTime invite links</a>" in 2021. This was a time when phones like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/samsung-galaxy-s21-ultra-review">Galaxy S21 Ultra</a>, OnePlus 9 Pro, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-3-review">Galaxy Z Fold 3</a> were making waves. All in an effort to let Apple customers think that the other side of its finely pruned garden was a wild jungle.</p><p>It&apos;s also why Apple kept up the charade for so long regarding RCS and iMessage. The elitism on display is essentially a Cold War-style attack on the non-Apple consumer. </p><p>Did you want to send your grandparents a video of your newborn from your <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review">Galaxy S24 Ultra</a>? Get ready for questions about why it looks like the video was taken on a camcorder from the 90s. Were you left out of a group chat with iPhone-wielding friends? Good luck trying to get everyone to use a different messaging platform, especially if you&apos;re the only one with an Android phone. </p><p>Don&apos;t get me wrong, I&apos;m extremely happy to see RCS finally come to the iPhone. But after actually using it, it just reaffirmed the stubbornness of a company with the resources and size of Apple. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/apple-should-be-ashamed-rcs-ios</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Apple finally flipped the switch for RCS Messaging on the iPhone with iOS 18, and it actually works much better than we expected. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">xVnarZqNb3wV3PaxBSWuEa</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GB5TtmLRcpbMih8aXYemjj.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 11:00:52 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ andrew.myrick@futurenet.com (Andrew Myrick) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GB5TtmLRcpbMih8aXYemjj.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Messages on an Android phone and iMessage on an iPhone]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Messages on an Android phone and iMessage on an iPhone]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Translate is using AI to translate a whopping 110 new languages ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google Translate's latest expansion covers languages spoken by over 614 million people, about 8% of the global population.</li><li>The new languages range from widely spoken ones to indigenous dialects and even those without current native speakers.</li><li>Google's PaLM 2 language model has been crucial in adding languages related to Hindi and French creoles.</li><li>About a quarter of the new additions are African languages like Fon, Kikongo, Luo, Ga, Swati, Venda, and Wolof.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Artificial intelligence is helping Google Translate expand with 110 new languages, which is its biggest update yet.</p><p>Google announced in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.google/products/translate/google-translate-new-languages-2024/" target="_blank">blog post</a> that this huge expansion includes languages spoken by over 614 million people worldwide, or about 8% of the global population. The variety is amazing, from the widely spoken world languages spoken by more than 100 million people to the cherished dialects of indigenous communities.</p><p>Even languages with no current native speakers are included, showing Google&apos;s dedication to preserving endangered languages.</p><p>Adding to this impressive update, Google has focused on African languages, making up about a quarter of the new additions. Languages like Fon, Kikongo, Luo, Ga, Swati, Venda, and Wolof are now part of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-translate-ai-accessibility-improvements">Google Translate</a>, marking its most significant push into African languages so far.</p><p>Google&apos;s PaLM 2 large language model has been crucial in expanding Translate. It learns related languages, enabling the addition of Hindi-related tongues like Awadhi and Marwadi, as well as French creoles like Seychellois and Mauritian.</p><p>Meanwhile, adding widely spoken languages like Cantonese comes with its own set of challenges due to the shared written characters with Mandarin. Despite these hurdles, Google’s dedication to linguistic diversity shines through. A prime example is the inclusion of Manx, a Celtic language from the Isle of Man that nearly went extinct in 1974. Thanks to revitalization efforts, fluency has risen to thousands.</p><p>This expansion also includes Punjabi written in the Shahmukhi script, a Perso-Arabic variant used in Pakistan, where it&apos;s the most widely spoken language.</p><p>Google recognizes that translating languages isn&apos;t easy due to regional variations, dialects, and spelling differences. Some languages, like Romani, with its many dialects, don&apos;t have a single standard version, making translation tricky.</p><p>Before this expansion, Google Translate&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-translate-adds-two-dozen-languages-used-by-over-300-million-people">biggest update was in May 2022 with the introduction of Zero-Shot Machine Translation</a>. This technology allows the model to learn new languages without needing pre-existing translated examples. This was a major advancement in machine translation, helping Google bridge language gaps even further.</p><p>This expansion is a major step toward Google&apos;s 1,000 Languages Initiative, which aims to use AI models to support the world&apos;s top 1,000 languages.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-translate-adds-110-new-languages</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google Translate is rolling out its biggest language update ever. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">sRkmHi2cYRwNoRoJfo7ru</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mtVpEHDgVrdyBbxQF6XseR.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 02:10:30 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mtVpEHDgVrdyBbxQF6XseR.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Translate app on a Google Pixel 6]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Translate app on a Google Pixel 6]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ OnePlus Pad Pro is perhaps the company's most powerful tablet to date ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>OnePlus has a new third Android tablet in its portfolio, launched in China this week.</li><li>Dubbed OnePlus Pad Pro, it comes with a 12.1-inch 144Hz display and a unique 7:5 aspect ratio.</li><li>The tablet has a massive battery underneath with support for 67W fast charging.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>After introducing the first OnePlus Pad, followed by a cheaper “Go” variant, the company is back with a Pro edition, dubbed OnePlus Pad Pro, and it has been unveiled in China.</p><p>It has been tailored as a performance-driven Android tablet with Qualcomm’s flagship Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 underneath. While the design seems like the first OnePlus Pad, the new Pro model weighs 584 grams and measures 6.49mm in thickness.</p>
<p>It comes in two simple colorways: Khaki Green and Space Gray. The Pro variant has a bigger 12.1-inch LCD display with a 144Hz refresh rate, 3000 x 2120 resolution, a unique 7:5 aspect ratio, and 900 nits of peak brightness.</p><p>Keeping the lights on the OnePlus Pad Pro is a massive 9510mAh battery capacity supporting the company’s proprietary 67W super flash charging. </p><p>The OnePlus Pad Pro includes a stylus and a Smart Touch Keyboard that offers a PC-level trackpad. On the side note, OnePlus has <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.opposhop.cn/cn/web/products/28809.html">also shared</a> the tablet’s AnTuTu benchmark rating with the Snapdragon chip, which hit a 2316067 score.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="sFGKHnJdYCH3VehWmxMDxK" name="OnePlus-Pad-Pro-01.jpg" alt="OnePlus Pad Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sFGKHnJdYCH3VehWmxMDxK.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OnePlus)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Pad Pro’s camera specs are still unclear, but it comes with both front and rear cameras with modules similar to those seen in older <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/oneplus-pad-review">OnePlus Pad</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/oneplus-pad-go-launched-in-india">Pad Go</a> tablets. The other highlights of the Android tablet include support for 5G, NFC, and ColorOS for Pad running out of the box. For audio, the tablet relies on six-speaker surround sound.</p><p>The OnePlus Pad Pro is offered in multiple storage models, including 8GB+128GB, 8GB+256GB, 12GB+256GB, and 16GB+512GB, which are priced for pre-sale at CNY 2799, CNY 2999, CNY 3299, and CNY 3699, respectively. The device will be widely available starting July 3 as the official sale begins.</p><p>While the launch of the new tablet aimed at the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-tablets">best Android tablets</a> is currently confined to China, its global debut is expected to happen soon, presumably with the same OnePlus Pad Pro moniker.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Tablet deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/ipad-tablets-ereaders/tablets/pcmcat209000050008.c?id=pcmcat209000050008"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/search?q=tablet"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/tablets-laptops-computers-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=tablet&crid=2HCFROTF588S1&sprefix=tablet%2Caps%2C159&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.dell.com/en-us/search/tablet"><u><strong>Dell</strong></u></a><strong> |</strong></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/oneplus-pad-pro-launched-in-china</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ OnePlus just unveiled a flagship tablet that ships with up to 16GB of RAM and a massive 9510mAh battery capacity. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">PRjvkrYrNn3HGT24M75LRV</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SG5s3RpLi9ey85kReYWjEi.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 20:44:25 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SG5s3RpLi9ey85kReYWjEi.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[OnePlus]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus Pad Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus Pad Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The OnePlus Watch 2 variant debuts in China with eSIM support and more ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-32">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>OnePlus debuts its new Watch 2 variant in China, which brings eSIM (LTE) support to consumers, which its earlier launch lacked.</li><li>With a 1.43-inch AMOLED display, the Watch 2 variant boasts Qualcomm's Snapdragon W5 SoC, "high-precision" sensors for fitness, and map updates.</li><li>The device is available for pre-order in China at a price that roughly equates to $247.</li><li>There are rumors that OnePlus could rebrand the device to the "Watch 2R" for an overseas launch, but this has not been confirmed.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>OnePlus debuted a new wearable in China, dubbed the "Watch 2," and its specifications look similar to the current 2024 model.</p><p>The company announced the OnePlus Watch 2 launch <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://weibo.com/3871046669/OkYyNziZV?pagetype=profilefeed">on Weibo</a> following its presentation today (June 27). From its official pre-order listing, OnePlus states the Watch 2 features a 1.43-inch AMOLED display. Powering the device is Qualcomm&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/qualcomm-snapdragon-w5-platform-announcement">Snapdragon W5</a> SoC, which is the same as the current overseas <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oneplus-watch-2-review">OnePlus Watch 2</a>.</p><p>A (machine-translated) <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://weibo.com/3871046669/OkXGDlAQb">subsequent post</a> highlights what sets this device apart: independent eSIM (LTE) support. OnePlus states that its Watch 2 will let users answer and send messages and calls without grabbing their Android phone. Moreover, the company states it has improved the watch&apos;s map navigation, creating a more intuitive and "secure" environment.</p><p>For workouts, the Watch 2 packs "high-precision" sensors on its back to assist the user in obtaining "accurate" fitness data.</p><p>The device contains a few features aimed at convenience, such as falling asleep with the watch on, which will "automatically pause music." The Watch 2 can search for your paired smartphone if you&apos;ve misplaced it, vibrate for reminders, and take photos remotely with the push of a button.</p><p>Another difference is the new Watch 2 in China offers a circular dial around its watch face instead of the full glass design from earlier this year. OnePlus also includes two raised physical buttons on the side, sliding away from the raised vertical edge.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1790px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:33.52%;"><img id="DqGN2AHjDLCiPjAVy35t98" name="oneplus-watch-2-2024-china-esim-support.jpg" alt="The OnePlus Watch 2's launch in China brings eSIM support." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DqGN2AHjDLCiPjAVy35t98.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1790" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OnePlus / Weibo)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1821px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:32.95%;"><img id="26YEEVswNFdxHJxd2vUoZD" name="oneplus-watch-2-2024-china-specs.jpg" alt="The OnePlus Watch 2 in China brings improved map navigation, accurate sensors, Android, and iOS support." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/26YEEVswNFdxHJxd2vUoZD.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1821" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OnePlus / Weibo)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Other specifications see the device offering a RAM/storage configuration of 2/32GB. Keeping the Watch 2 running is a 500mAh battery. OnePlus adds that the smartwatch supports Android (Wear OS), alongside iOS devices.</p><p>The OnePlus Watch 2 is available for pre-order in China for ¥1,749, which is roughly $247. The company adds that the device will hit the shelves on July 3 on home soil.</p><p>Whether folks overseas will see this device is still unclear. However, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/06/27/oneplus-watch-2-china-updated-design-lte/">9to5Google</a> notes that there have been rumors that China&apos;s OnePlus Watch 2 could be rebranded as the "Watch 2R" overseas. The "R" moniker is typically how OnePlus rebrands its devices when making them available outside of China.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oneplus-watch-2-china-variant-launch</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ OnePlus launched its new Watch 2 variant in China, which brings LTE support and other upgrades. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">ks9oq3j2BzeZpihk7yCGLj</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VJVaAM6XzPmZ6Csr7PHSVk.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 20:15:54 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VJVaAM6XzPmZ6Csr7PHSVk.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[OnePlus / Weibo]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus Watch 2 China launch brings LTE (eSIM) support.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus Watch 2 China launch brings LTE (eSIM) support.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Amazon's Xbox collab brings its cloud gaming library to the Fire TV Stick in July ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-37">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Amazon announced its collaboration with Xbox, which will bring the Game Pass Ultimate library of titles to its Fire TV Stick in July.</li><li>The company states that users can enjoy "graphically intensive" titles through the Fire TV Stick, though a strong internet connection is required for performance reasons.</li><li>Xbox previously started its TV app on Samsung through a partnership several years ago and recently brought its titles to Meta's Quest 2 and Quest 3.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Today (June 27), Amazon announced its new partnership with Xbox as it looks to bring cloud gaming capabilities to its streaming product.</p><p>According to a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/devices/xbox-gaming-on-amazon-fire-tv">press release</a>, Amazon stated that Xbox players could enjoy the Game Pass Ultimate library on their TV in July with a "compatible" Fire TV Stick. Users must download the Xbox app through the Amazon app store to get started, alongside their Microsoft account credentials.</p><p>If users are already an Xbox Game Pass Ultimate member, the entire library will be accessible. If not, Amazon will prompt them to sign up to begin enjoying its cloud gaming privileges.</p><p>The company states that its cloud gaming capabilities through the Fire TV Stick enable gamers to enjoy graphic-intensive titles like Senua&apos;s Saga: Hellblade II, Fallout 4, and Fallout 76.</p><p>Amazon adds that a "solid internet connection" is required to maximize its full gaming possibilities.</p><p>Additionally, games can be played with a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-gaming-controllers-amazon-fire-tv">Bluetooth-capable controller</a>. The post states such devices include the Xbox Wireless Controller, Xbox Adaptive Controller, and PlayStation&apos;s DualSense and DualShock 4 controllers.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:759px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:55.99%;"><img id="4M3ddBzbd5bMzaLmbY6x54" name="amazon-fire-tv-stick-xbox-app-game-pass-ultimate.jpg" alt="The Xbox Game Pass Ultimate available on select Amazon Fire TV sticks." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4M3ddBzbd5bMzaLmbY6x54.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="759" height="425" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Amazon)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Those interested can grab a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/amazon-fire-tv-stick-4k-max-2023-review">Fire TV Stick 4K Max (2023)</a> or the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/amazon-fire-tv-stick-4k-2023-vs-chromecast-with-google-tv">Fire TV Stick 4K (2023)</a>, as both will gain Xbox cloud gaming support in July. Pricing starts at $49.99, and each stick offers 4K resolution, a remote controller for comfort, and more. Moreover, Amazon states that consumers without Xbox Game Pass Ultimate can opt for the free trial version, letting them play titles like Fortnite.</p><p>News of the Xbox app arriving on select Amazon Fire TV sticks shows an expansion of the company <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/xbox-game-pass-meta-quest-launch">beyond Meta&apos;s Quest headsets</a>. Late last year, Xbox and Meta announced that users could stream its Game Pass on the Quest 2 and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-3-review">Quest 3</a> VR headsets just in time for the 2023 holiday season. Like Amazon, Meta warned that users would need a strong internet connection, ideally one with 200Mbps or higher.</p><p>Elsewhere, Xbox also had a partnership <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/why-microsofts-xbox-partnership-samsung-could-be-big-deal">with Samsung</a>, where its app was only available on its TVs.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="ba7b45a7-c27f-4d0d-a0f4-5eab78d7949f">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.33%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sUZ8QArieRbALiDjhP9zUb.jpg' alt="Amazon Fire TV Stick 4K Max 2023"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Amazon Fire TV Stick 4K Max (2023)</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Setting the standard, again</strong></em></p>
<p>Amazon's Fire TV Stick 4K Max brings even more storage than its base version. The small, convenient device also provides improved Wi-Fi support, a quicker processor, and more improvements that will make a difference when gaming or binging.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/amazon-xbox-cloud-gaming-fire-tv-stick-collab</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Amazon announced its Xbox partnership, which will see its cloud gaming library on the Fire TV Stick. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">baEDyoihpAGT3LFbbJH2nm</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8fX4fYvjWqWXW3bdJ4JV9B.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 19:59:23 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8fX4fYvjWqWXW3bdJ4JV9B.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Amazon]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Amazon announces its partnership with Xbox, bringing its gaming library to the Fire TV stick.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Amazon announces its partnership with Xbox, bringing its gaming library to the Fire TV stick.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Ahead of the Unpacked event, official cases of Galaxy Z Fold 6 and Z Flip 6 leak ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-42">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>As we gear up for the Unpacked event next month, a new leak reveals protective cases of the Galaxy Z Fold 6 and Z Flip 6.</li><li>The cases have been displayed in colorways that complement the foldables’ options.</li><li>The leak also confirms the Galaxy Z Fold 6’s updated design featuring pointed corners.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Samsung is prepping for its foldables launch, which is now only a couple of weeks away, and we are finally moving away from renderings to official image leaks. Thanks to one such leak, the Galaxy Z Fold 6 and Z Flip 6 can now be spotted in their official cases.</p><p>Tipster <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/MoisesElPro2/status/1806035151459368961">Arsène Lupin on X</a> managed to grab the images of the upcoming Galaxy foldables devices in their official cases, which are generally sold alongside the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6">Galaxy Z Fold 6</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-6">Galaxy Z Flip 6</a> after their release after the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-unpacked-summer-2024-confirmed">July 10 launch</a>. While the devices are seen incorporated in the protective cases, it gives a closer look at the upcoming <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">foldables</a>.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:900px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:66.67%;"><img id="crwA5vqujpjGipkJBCY98M" name="Galaxy-Z-Folg-6-case-leak-04.jpg" alt="Galaxy Z Fold 6 cases leak" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/crwA5vqujpjGipkJBCY98M.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="900" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: @MysteryLupin via X)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:900px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:66.67%;"><img id="m9UVcbx87NuAQdPXLutUqL" name="Galaxy-Z-Folg-6-case-leak-02.jpg" alt="Galaxy Z Fold 6 cases leak" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/m9UVcbx87NuAQdPXLutUqL.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="900" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: @MysteryLupin via X)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:900px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:66.67%;"><img id="v74A4QpemCfEBtR6ZvXgjL" name="Galaxy-Z-Folg-6-case-leak-01.jpg" alt="Galaxy Z Fold 6 cases leak" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/v74A4QpemCfEBtR6ZvXgjL.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="900" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: @MysteryLupin via X)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 4 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:900px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:66.67%;"><img id="aTose8KzH44cyN2iBA9AwL" name="Galaxy-Z-Folg-6-case-leak-03.jpg" alt="Galaxy Z Fold 6 cases leak" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/aTose8KzH44cyN2iBA9AwL.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="900" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: @MysteryLupin via X)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>The cases match the device’s color options; for instance, the Galaxy Z Fold 6 comes in gray, silver, and navy blue colorways, and the protective cases complement the handset. Some of the cases also include support for the S-Pen. On the other hand, the Galaxy Z Flip 6 seems to be coming in sea green and accompanied by the same colored key holder case alongside other gray and navy blue colorways.</p><p>The rest of the devices resemble the predecessor <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-5-review">Galaxy Z Fold 5</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-5-review">Z Flip 5</a> models. The Galaxy Z Flip 6 comes again with the same folder-icon-shaped cover screen with dual primary cameras placed right next to it. Interestingly, the rings surrounding the camera lenses also match the device’s color accent, giving a comprehensive look.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:900px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:66.67%;"><img id="sD6GyGmjTk7X6mt7XPQX2M" name="Galaxy-Z-Flip-6-case-leak-02.jpg" alt="Galaxy Z Flip 6 cases leak" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sD6GyGmjTk7X6mt7XPQX2M.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="900" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: @MysteryLupin via X)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:900px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:66.67%;"><img id="9UJx9LMDUXHmPTS3RXj8YL" name="Galaxy-Z-Flip-6-case-leak-03.jpg" alt="Galaxy Z Flip 6 cases leak" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9UJx9LMDUXHmPTS3RXj8YL.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="900" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: @MysteryLupin via X)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:900px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:66.67%;"><img id="Sma9PSxzHWkA2Wxm5YaFSL" name="Galaxy-Z-Flip-6-case-leak-01.jpg" alt="Galaxy Z Flip 6 cases leak" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Sma9PSxzHWkA2Wxm5YaFSL.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="900" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: @MysteryLupin via X)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>The device is said to carry a new design this year, including sharp edges instead of rounded corners, as seen in the previous iteration. The exact design change can also be spotted in the aforementioned images. The cover screen is also expected to be wider than the predecessor; however, that isn&apos;t rightly visible in the cases’ images.</p><p>While we await the launch alongside the case renders, alleged official images of the other product portfolio, such as the Galaxy Watch 7, the new Watch 7 Ultra, and the new Galaxy Buds 3, have also <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/galaxy-watch-7-buds-3-series-render-leak">popped up on the internet</a>.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-z-fold-6-and-z-flip-6-protective-cases-leak</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Upcoming Galaxy foldables are shown in exciting case renders involving new colorways and accompanying cases. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">BA8harF4LP7N7d7AbysYAm</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/efkb767D4mRmRzpNBJYceL.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 19:55:15 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/efkb767D4mRmRzpNBJYceL.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[@MysteryLupin via X]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Galaxy Z Flip 6 cases leak]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Galaxy Z Flip 6 cases leak]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>