<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 02:10:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Docs now uses Imagen 3 for custom image generation, but there’s a catch ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google is adding Imagen 3 support to Google Docs for paid Gemini in Workspace users.</li><li>The feature will allow users to generate custom inline images that can be used anywhere in their Google Doc — without leaving the site.</li><li>Google Docs previously supported generating full-bleed cover images, but not inline images.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google is leveraging its latest image generation model, Imagen 3, to bring custom images to your <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-docs-new-feature-is-your-go-to-tool-for-wrangling-those-giant-documents">Google Docs</a>, it announced in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://workspaceupdates.googleblog.com/2024/11/use-gemini-in-google-docs-to-create-images.html" target="_blank">blog post</a> today. The company calls these images "photorealistic," and they could be a replacement for stock images in some situations. However, in order to create your own images with Imagen 3 in Google Docs, you'll need to be a paid Workspace user or a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-one">Google One AI Premium</a> subscriber.</p><p>Before the rollout of Imagen 3 in Docs, Google was already experimenting with image generation in Workspace. It first added support for generating full-bleed cover images in Google Docs and image generation in Google Slides. Now, there's support in Google Docs for unabridged inline image generation. A quick prompt is all it takes to create a cover or in-text image, as you can see in the example from Google below.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1200px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:62.25%;"><img id="LLEdv4aSVGMqqL9frJ29JZ" name="gemini-createacoverimage" alt="The new image generation capabilities in Google Workspace." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LLEdv4aSVGMqqL9frJ29JZ.gif" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1200" height="747" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>To start using <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/googles-imagen-3-is-now-open-to-everyone-in-the-us">Imagen 3</a> in Google Docs, navigate to the <strong>Insert </strong>menu and click <strong>Image</strong> or <strong>Cover image</strong>. Then, select <strong>Help me create an image</strong>. From there, you can use a text prompt to help Imagen 3 create the image you're looking for, and manually choose a style to further refine your prompt. After your image is created, you can pick from three aspect ratios to find the one that best suits your document.</p><p>For now, cover images are only supported when viewing Google Docs in what the company calls "pageless mode." This makes the custom AI-generated image cover the entire document. To activate it, navigate to <strong>File > Page setup > Pageless or Format > Switch to Pageless format</strong>.</p><p>Unfortunately, text-to-image generation in Google Docs isn't available for free users. Users of Gemini Business, Gemini Enterprise, Gemini Education, or Gemini Education Premium will be able to use it. Additionally, individual Workspace users subscribed to Google One AI Premium have access. It's rolling out now, but can take some time to show up for all users, especially if your school or work uses a scheduled release timeline.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-docs-now-uses-imagen-3-for-custom-image-generation-if-youre-a-paid-user</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ You can now ask Gemini to generate custom images that'll liven up your Google Doc. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">KNUM7MQ8hjoAvexYHsrLb3</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7toEJcBHissLb7zzLyXyUg.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 21:43:07 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7toEJcBHissLb7zzLyXyUg.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Help me write in Google Docs on Samsung Galaxy Chromebook Plus]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Help me write in Google Docs on Samsung Galaxy Chromebook Plus]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Who needs Black Friday? Best Buy just chopped $130 OFF our favorite last-gen smartwatch ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>With Black Friday just a couple of weeks away, some great Android watch deals are starting to hit the market. This includes Best Buy's decision to chop <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-watch6-aluminum-smartwatch-40mm-bt-graphite/6546704.p?skuId=6546704" target="_blank"><strong>$130 off the Samsung Galaxy Watch 6</strong>,</a> which happens to be our favorite last-gen smartwatch.</p><p>The Watch 6 was well-liked upon release in 2023, especially for its capacitive bezel, vibrant 1.5-inch AMOLED display, and excellent integration with other devices in the Galaxy ecosystem. It also comes with the many health tracking and GPS features we've come to expect in a modern smartwatch, so even the last-gen option may be sufficient for basic users.</p><p>Still, Samsung did improve the accuracy of GPS and health monitoring sensors in the Galaxy Watch 7 released this year, so that might also be worth considering if you don't mind paying extra.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="bec1356e-17b4-44ff-9589-921bbab0c1fd" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy Watch 6:" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy Watch 6:" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-watch6-aluminum-smartwatch-40mm-bt-graphite/6546704.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="ZFk8tX7bD9dZBwf8oaBae8" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Watch-6-square-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZFk8tX7bD9dZBwf8oaBae8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="800" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy Watch 6:</strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-watch6-aluminum-smartwatch-40mm-bt-graphite/6546704.p?skuId=6546704" target="_blank" data-dimension112="bec1356e-17b4-44ff-9589-921bbab0c1fd" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy Watch 6:" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy Watch 6:" data-dimension25=""> <del>$299.99</del> <strong>$169.99 at Best Buy</strong></a></p><p>The Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 is a great smartwatch effort, despite being from 2023, and at $130 off the normal purchase price, it's a pretty great deal. While the Watch 6 was our top pick for the best Android watch when it came out, we still think it's the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch#section-best-last-gen-option" target="_blank">best last-gen Android watch</a> there is.</p><p><strong>Price comparison:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Aluminum-Smartwatch-Advanced-Coaching-Bluetooth/dp/B0CCW7H9P9" target="_blank">$169.99 - Amazon</a> | <a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/watches/galaxy-watch6/buy/galaxy-watch6-40mm-gold-lte-sm-r935uzeaxaa/" target="_blank">$219.99 - Samsung</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-watch6-aluminum-smartwatch-40mm-bt-graphite/6546704.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="bec1356e-17b4-44ff-9589-921bbab0c1fd" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy Watch 6:" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy Watch 6:" data-dimension25="">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Black Friday deals</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Black Friday Google Pixel deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Black Friday Motorola deals<br></a>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024-early-deals-and-how-to-prepare-for-the-big-sales">Black Friday Samsung deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Black Friday OnePlus deals</a></p></div></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>you want a watch with a really good-looking display; you're looking for a watch with passive AFib detection; you don't mind going with using a last-gen smartwatch.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if:</strong> you need great battery life; you want a watch with hyper-accurate GPS tracking; you have a little extra money to spend and would rather upgrade to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-7">Galaxy Watch 7</a>.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-6-review" target="_blank">Samsung Galaxy Watch 6</a> was released in 2023, but it's still a pretty good option today—especially if you're just getting into the smartwatch world.</p><p>Despite being last year's model, it comes with a beautiful 1.5-inch AMOLED display that users love, ultra-fast charging, tons of useful health features, and GPS tracking. Plus, it offers ease-of-use with other Galaxy devices, and buyers will get three years of Wear OS updates to keep it fresh on a software level.</p><p>The Watch 6's health features include sleep and heart rate monitoring, personalized heart rate zones, passive AFib detection, blood pressure monitoring, and more.</p><p>While the Watch 7 was released this year, the Watch 6 will still get you some of Samsung's latest Galaxy AI features, so you don't have to break the bank on that one if you don't have to.</p><p>It's worth considering that the Watch 6 does not have dual-band GPS, making the GPS tracking feature a bit inaccurate compared to some competitors. However, Samsung did update this in the Watch 7, giving it the coveted dual-band GPS hardware for peak accuracy, and it also upgraded multiple other sensors in the 2024 release.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/who-needs-black-friday-best-buy-just-chopped-usd130-off-our-favorite-last-gen-smartwatch</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A last-gen smartwatch at a serious discount. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">PJeN7RHLGhp4HdvvZ2c6ZX</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Fv8w4ovRSAzeVxiGJYugXX.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 21:03:18 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ zacharydvisconti@gmail.com (Zachary Visconti) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Fv8w4ovRSAzeVxiGJYugXX.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Samsung]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Official lifestyle images of the Samsung Galaxy Watch 6]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Official lifestyle images of the Samsung Galaxy Watch 6]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung tipped to have a late January timeline for the Galaxy S25 series in the US ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung will likely launch the Galaxy S25, S25 Plus, and the Galaxy S25 Ultra in the U.S. on January 22 or 23, 2025.</li><li>The expected dates are shared by multiple sources, including the Korean media next to tipster Max Jambor.</li><li>If it turns out to be accurate, the next flagship series will be slightly delayed — contrary to the early launch rumors.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Samsung’s next batch of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">flagship phones</a> is anticipated to launch early next year. However, new information from multiple sources confirms that the Korean tech giant might aim for a later January launch date.</p><p>Firstly, a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.fnnews.com/ampNews/202411141109523375">Korean media outlet</a> (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.sammobile.com/news/galaxy-s25-may-descend-on-this-january-day-without-4th-variant/">SamMobile</a>) has noted that the Unpacked event will be held on January 23, 2025—not similar to what we saw in the Galaxy S24 series launch, which was on January 17.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">22.1<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1857001999218188624">November 14, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>The upcoming Unpacked event is believed to be held in San Francisco, U.S. However, another reliable tipster, Max Jambor on X, noted that it might be on January 22, 2025 — a day earlier than the aforementioned predicted date.</p><p>Regardless of both the hinted dates, the launch date of the Galaxy S25 series isn’t drastically different from the predecessor models. Previous rumors of an early launch of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-samsung-phones">Samsung flagships</a> didn’t turn out to be accurate. However, there could still be a possibility of shuffling these launch dates as we approach them in the coming weeks and months.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1066px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.29%;"><img id="n6PXaFPNmcpnShZH3pGRHJ" name="Galaxy-S25-Ultra-renders-leak-03.jpg" alt="Galaxy S25 Ultra renders leak" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/n6PXaFPNmcpnShZH3pGRHJ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1066" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OnLeaks/ Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>As the publication notes, Samsung launched the Galaxy S23 series in San Francisco in 2023, and the successors were introduced in San Jose. It is likely that the company will bring the next flagship phones to San Francisco again, alongside its home ground.</p><p>As we near the anticipated launch, we expect the Galaxy S25, S25 Plus, and the Galaxy S25 Ultra to be unveiled at the Unpacked event. Earlier reports have also hinted that a new Galaxy S25 Slim might also be in the works. This device <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/a-slim-galaxy-s25-might-be-samsungs-answer-to-apples-rumored-thin-iphone-17">is expected</a> to debut in the second quarter of 2025 and not alongside the Galaxy S25 series.</p>
<p>As the name implies, the Galaxy S25 Slim is believed to be a thinner variant of the flagship lineup to take on Apple’s rumored iPhone 17 “Air,” which is also slated to launch next year. The rumor mill also hints that the expected Galaxy S25 Slim could be some kind of a pilot program from Samsung, which will have a test run next year. If it all goes well, users can expect the successor for the masses, likely with the Galaxy S26 series the following year.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-series-to-launch-on-january-22-or-23-2025</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung launched the Galaxy S24 series on January 17 in the U.S. However, the successors are likely to arrive a week later next year. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">SfUWFrZMrUi8vhZz7YLPz4</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kGzS4kjwfjF3e7Hsuhz2ra.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 20:19:10 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kGzS4kjwfjF3e7Hsuhz2ra.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Headlines]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[An angled view of the Galaxy S25 Plus&#039; front and back panels.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[An angled view of the Galaxy S25 Plus&#039; front and back panels.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Messages dual SIM support for RCS rolls onto US phones, per reports ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Users have taken to Reddit to report an apparent stable, server-side rollout of dual SIM support for RCS chats in Google Messages.</li><li>Reports claim support has arrived for varying carriers like T-Mobile, AT&T, Visible, and more, though not everyone has seen it yet.</li><li>Google was first spotted moving such support into beta earlier this year, letting users quickly swap connections between SIM cards.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>A wave of reports claim that Google's dual SIM support for RCS chats in the Messages app is starting to roll out.</p><p>Users have <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GoogleMessages/comments/1gedpvv/dual_rcs_support_enabled/?utm_source=share&utm_medium=web3x&utm_name=web3xcss&utm_term=1&utm_content=share_button">taken to Reddit</a> to report that Google Messages has started pushing its dual SIM for RCS support to stable users/versions (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidpolice.com/dual-sim-rcs-starts-appearing-for-some-in-us/">Android Police</a>). One user in the U.S. states that they've started noticing support appear within the app's RCS settings. Another user confirmed as much, stating no notification was given about its arrival in the app.</p><p>A <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GoogleMessages/comments/1gqs4si/just_got_dual_sim_rcs/?utm_source=share&utm_medium=web3x&utm_name=web3xcss&utm_term=1&utm_content=share_button">separate thread</a> in the app's subreddit states a user received dual SIM support on a Pixel 9 Pro XL. The user states they are in the U.S. and have U.S. Mobile and Visible. However, some users are having a more troubling experience with the app's dual SIM RCS support. One user in the Google Messages beta <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GoogleMessages/comments/1gedpvv/comment/lujud3i/?utm_source=share&utm_medium=web3x&utm_name=web3xcss&utm_term=1&utm_content=share_button">hasn't yet received the feature</a>, stating they have two SIMs from Verizon.</p><p>Another report confirmed additional issues, which could point to an ongoing rollout on Google's side. Users claim that clearing data and Play Services has done nothing to produce the feature. So, it's probably best if users wait for Google to flip the switch.</p>
<blockquote class="reddit-card"  ><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GoogleMessages/comments/1gedpvv/dual_rcs_support_enabled">Dual RCS support enabled!</a> from <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GoogleMessages">r/GoogleMessages</a></blockquote><script async src="//embed.redditmedia.com/widgets/platform.js" charset="UTF-8"></script>
<p>Elsewhere, the publication states that users have noticed the dual SIM support for RCS chats appear in v20241018_01_RC00 of the beta. The post adds that reports from other users say they've received proper support with SIMs from T-Mobile, AT&T, and Google Fi in conjunction with those previously mentioned.</p><p>Google was first tipped to bring <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-messages-support-for-dual-sim-rcs">dual SIM support for RCS-enabled chats</a> early this year. Similar to how users see it today, the app will display two checkboxes within its RCS settings. Each box will showcase the name of the SIM card's cellular network and its current status. Naturally, for RCS, the app will need to run through its verification steps. Once you're good and green, users can easily toggle their SIM card connection.</p><p>Google seemingly teased this in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/messages/answer/7189714">support document</a>, stating, "RCS chats are available for your default or preferred call SIM at this time and may be available for other SIMs later." However, with the rollout appearing fragmented, it's still taking time.</p><p>A more recent Google Messages beta showed the company might shift its UI elements — specifically <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-messages-read-receipts-placement-redesign-spotted">its read receipts</a>. Users might soon find them implemented alongside a user's text, instead of directly beneath.</p>
<ul><li> <strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://shop-links.co/link?id=pcmcat1563302848653&publisher_slug=future&exclusive=1&u1=ac-us-1347741738096060203&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Ftop-deals%2Fcell-phone-deals%2Fpcmcat1563302848653.c%3Fid%3Dpcmcat1563302848653&article_name=Google%20Messages%20is%20preparing%20to%20handle%20dual%20SIM%20for%20RCS%20%7C%20Android%20Central&article_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.androidcentral.com%2Fapps-software%2Fgoogle-messages-support-for-dual-sim-rcs" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1943169/565706/9383?subId1=ac-us-1238094203838800728&sharedId=ac-us&u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fcp%2Fcell-phones%2F1105910%3Fpovid%3Dweb_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://shop-links.co/link?publisher_slug=future&exclusive=1&u1=ac-us-1344133660160465490&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.samsung.com%2Fus%2Fshop%2Fall-deals%2Fcell-phone-deals%2F&article_name=Google%20Messages%20is%20preparing%20to%20handle%20dual%20SIM%20for%20RCS%20%7C%20Android%20Central&article_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.androidcentral.com%2Fapps-software%2Fgoogle-messages-support-for-dual-sim-rcs" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://target.georiot.com/Proxy.ashx?tsid=169923&GR_URL=https%3A%2F%2Famazon.com%2Fs%3Fk%3Dcell%2Bphone%26crid%3D19CKV7OMEPEMF%26sprefix%3Dcell%2Bphone%252Caps%252C222%26ref%3Dnb_sb_noss_1%26tag%3Dhawk-future-20%26ascsubtag%3Dac-us-5017098020828040012-20" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-100048248-15733793?sid=ac-us-8385198117185052055&url=https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-100048248-15735111?sid=ac-us-3730037906854105740&url=https://www.att.com/" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-messages-dual-sim-rcs-support-us-rollout</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google is reportedly rolling out its RCS dual-SIM support for the Messages app. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">ameK6EcWFgi5c5csc8JWa9</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ziZDiSfrJmLq6TJoFTB57F.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 20:08:44 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ziZDiSfrJmLq6TJoFTB57F.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Messages blue logo]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Messages blue logo]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Visible's Black Friday deal is going to make me finally ditch T-Mobile — get two years of Unlimited for just $20 per month! ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The Black Friday deals are officially in full swing across the world wide web, and Visible has just joined the party with an intriguing offer of its own. Join the Verizon-owned wireless carrier before December 2nd and type in the <strong>code SAVE24</strong> during checkout and you&apos;ll be guaranteed to receive two years of coverage for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.visible.com/deals/"><strong>as little as $20 per month for the base plan or $35 per month for Visible Plus</strong></a>. Only new members are eligible for the deal, but that&apos;s basically where the fine print ends.  </p>
<h2 id="our-favorite-unlimited-plan-gets-cheaper-2">Our favorite unlimited plan gets cheaper</h2>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="3a8f9dcd-a403-47ab-b405-7a4ec6659f2a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Visible by Verizon: Get 24 months of Unlimited from $20 per month with code SAVE24" data-dimension48="Visible by Verizon: Get 24 months of Unlimited from $20 per month with code SAVE24" href="https://www.visible.com/plans" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="TkDgN6zJ9rLev3cPfq5HhN" name="visible-logo-reco.png" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TkDgN6zJ9rLev3cPfq5HhN.png" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1000" height="1000" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Visible by Verizon: </strong><a href="https://www.visible.com/plans" data-dimension112="3a8f9dcd-a403-47ab-b405-7a4ec6659f2a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Visible by Verizon: Get 24 months of Unlimited from $20 per month with code SAVE24" data-dimension48="Visible by Verizon: Get 24 months of Unlimited from $20 per month with code SAVE24"><strong>Get 24 months of Unlimited from $20 per month with code SAVE24</strong></a></p>
<p>Sign up for Visible and use the code SAVE24 during checkout and you'll get discounted wireless for two years, no strings attached. The deal knocks $5 off the base plan every month while Visible Plus users will get $10 shaved off their phone bill every month for 24 months. That may not seem like a lot, but considering that it's a no-hassle discount on one of our favorite <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/carriers/best-unlimited-data-plans">unlimited plans</a>, it's certainly deserving of your attention.  </p>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>your area has good Verizon coverage; you want affordable wireless that doesn't skimp on premium features. </p>
<p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>you need multi-line discounts; you're happy with your current phone bill</p>
<p><strong>👀Alternative deal: </strong><a href="https://mintmobile.com/deals/">three months of Unlimited for $15/month at Mint Mobile</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.visible.com/plans" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="3a8f9dcd-a403-47ab-b405-7a4ec6659f2a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Visible by Verizon: Get 24 months of Unlimited from $20 per month with code SAVE24" data-dimension48="Visible by Verizon: Get 24 months of Unlimited from $20 per month with code SAVE24">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/visible-review">Visible Wireless</a>, while not technically an MVNO, remains a great alternative for folks who want a simpler solution for their wireless needs. There are only two plan options, both of which come with unlimited talk, text, and data on Verizon&apos;s vast 5G network, plus you get some premium perks, such as a free mobile hotspot and unlimited talk and text in Mexico and Canada. </p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Black Friday</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Black Friday Google Pixel deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Black Friday Motorola deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024-early-deals-and-how-to-prepare-for-the-big-sales">Black Friday Samsung deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Black Friday OnePlus deals</a></p></div></div>
<p>Going with the Visible Plus plan will get you everything above alongside unlimited Ultra Wideband 5G data, 50GB of premium data from Verizon, and free smartwatch data with select wearables (a $10/month value). That plan also hooks you up with increased hotspot speeds and some additional international perks, including free calls to over 30 countries, free texts to over 200 countries worldwide, and one day of Verizon&apos;s Global Pass every month.</p><p>That&apos;s a lot of perks for only $35 per month. If you&apos;re still on the fence about Visible, it&apos;s also worth noting that the carrier offers a<strong> </strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.visible.com/free-trial"><strong>15-day free trial</strong></a><strong> </strong>that lets you explore the service at no additional cost, just don&apos;t forget that the Black Friday deal expires on December 2nd.</p><p><em>Preferred partner (</em><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/content-funding-on-android-central"><em>What does this mean?</em></a><em>)</em></p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/carriers/visibles-black-friday-deal-is-going-to-make-me-finally-ditch-t-mobile-get-two-years-of-unlimited-for-just-usd20-per-month</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Visible by Verizon just launched a holiday deal that discounts both of its unlimited plans for two years.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">tXT7qGUGwknibms2vuHvTS</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/iW3ezBdsDXPBMzSRVTddME.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 19:48:01 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Carriers]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/iW3ezBdsDXPBMzSRVTddME.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Visible]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Visible smile logo on phone]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Visible smile logo on phone]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Real-time Scam Detection is rolling out now in Google Phone app beta ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Scam Detection, the AI-based Google Phone app feature first previewed at Google I/O, is finally rolling out to beta testers.</li><li>After announcing the rollout earlier this week, Phone by Google beta app users noticed a new Scam Detection toggle in the app's settings menu today.</li><li>Scam Detection automatically runs in the background, scanning unknown calls that have the potential to be scams with AI.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>One of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-io-2024-gemini-nano-detect-suspected-scams">best features previewed at Google I/O</a> is finally rolling out to beta testers today, as spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/ArtemR/status/1857445901364810069" target="_blank">Artem Russakovskii on X (formerly Twitter)</a>. Google previously <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/pixel-phones-now-use-ai-to-detect-scam-calls-in-real-time" target="_blank">announced</a> that it planned to start rolling out Scam Detection to users enrolled in the Google Phone app beta, and now the feature is officially reaching beta testers. To try the feature for yourself, you must be in the U.S., enrolled in the Phone by Google beta, and using a Pixel 6 or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">newer smartphone</a>.</p><p>Scam Detection is available as a toggle in the Google Phone app settings, and is identified with a "beta" badge. After flipping on the toggle, Scam Detection will run in the background using on-device AI, notifying you if there is a potential scam happening in your phone call — all in real time.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Scam Detection went silently live for me in the Google Phone app on the Pixel 9 Pro XL.

I had to check the settings to manually turn it on. pic.twitter.com/JJsC2a9upQ<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1857445901364810069">November 15, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>For privacy reasons, Scam Detection is disabled by default, even for those enrolled in the Google Phone app beta. If you want to try it out, you'll need to manually flip the toggle on yourself by going to <strong>Phone app settings </strong>and <strong>Assistive</strong>, then selecting <strong>Scam Detection</strong>. Additionally, Scam Detection can be turned off at any time, or in the middle of a specific call. When Scam Detection is active for a particular call, a beeping tone will play periodically to signal that the call is being anaylzed.</p><p>Owners of the new Google Pixel 9 series will get Gemini Nano as the on-device AI model screening calls for potential scams. However, the rest of the supported devices are vaguely said to use "other Google machine learning models."</p><p>The new Scam Detection page in the Phone by Google beta app settings explains more about how the feature works. It won't ever screen calls with people saved in your contacts. Call content is never saved or recorded, according to Google. The screening will only take place when calling unknown numbers in calls "that have the potential to be scams."</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:840px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:60.00%;"><img id="CxXrDt8FUYjzGqWxoSwySB" name="Google-scam-detection-feature" alt="Google scam detection flashing warning on the screen" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CxXrDt8FUYjzGqWxoSwySB.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="840" height="504" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>If a potential scam is detected, a pop-up will appear explaining that the call is "likely scam" and there was "suspicious activity detected for this call." From there, users can press <strong>Not a scam</strong> if they trust the caller, or <strong>End call</strong> to immediately cut the call off.</p><p>Google is looking for beta testers to share feedback about their experience with Scam Detection, and the company plans to share more about the feature in the coming months following this beta rollout.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/real-time-scam-detection-is-rolling-out-now-in-google-phone-app-beta</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ One of Google I/O's best features is officially hitting beta testers now. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">tFWqKocxnVJSivNM6d3ZGA</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/o5inagdzARJeYyuCLtsu37.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 19:26:20 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/o5inagdzARJeYyuCLtsu37.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[google phone app listing on the play store]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[google phone app listing on the play store]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google tipped to roll out a 'shield' to protect your email from online risks ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google was spotted developing a new feature through Play Services called "Shielded Email."</li><li>The feature will supposedly let users create a "fake," "generated" email for apps that may require one to avoid potential online risks.</li><li>Google stepped up its fight against spam/phishing attempts by rolling out verified marks in Gmail and bolstering it with a new spam detector.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google is reportedly developing an email protection feature that echoes what Apple's done for iOS.</p><p>Well-known X tipster AssembleDebug (<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/google-shielded-email-3499803/">Android Authority</a>) dove into the latest Play Services build (v24.45.33) and found support for a new feature. Strings in the code suggest Google is working on a "generated email address" tool under the "Shield Email" moniker.</p><p>Other strings give us an idea of how this might work as one claims users can generate an email "created for this app." The company's early description reads, "this can protect you from online tracking and data breaches."</p><p>Another set of strings highlights "email forwarding." This generated guise will seemingly let users forward emails it receives to their true address. There is space in the code for users to enter their <em>actual </em>email when the time comes. Moreover, Google is working on an option that lets users opt out if things turn to spam.</p><p>Additional descriptors show that Google intends this feature to keep users' emails private. The publication states these generated emails will be "single-use" or "limited-use aliases." The recent Play Services build notably lacks where Google could implement this feature.</p><p>The post states that further digging through the APK suggests Google plans to work Shielded Email directly into apps that may ask for your email.</p><p>Despite its rollout uncertainty, the feature has reportedly appeared on the Autofill settings page. However, the tipster notes that tapping it doesn't offer much as it's still under development, but this could indicate a debut that's sooner, not later.</p><p>Google has consistently stepped up its game to combat spam as Gmail picked up a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-improves-gmail-spam-detection">new spam detector</a>. The company implemented a new text vectorizer called "RETVec." Research showed that it enhanced the app's spam detection by roughly 38% and reduced false positives by ~20%. In short, RETVec would scan an incoming email with sharp eyes on the symbols used to weed out would-be spam.</p><p>Similarly, Gmail received <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/gmail-gets-blue-verification-checkmarks-to-prevent-phishing">blue verification checkmarks</a>, a part of the BIMI authentication system. The purpose of the marks is to give users quick, forward-facing confirmation of an email's legitimacy. If a sender is who they say they are, they will display a blue checkmark beside their logo/name. Of course, this applies to official businesses to help users dodge dangerous phishing attempts.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-shielded-email-online-risk-protection-spotted</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google was spotted developing a new feature to protect users' emails from online risks. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">f4CQXdsMtpYvGLxyB3jzSA</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/f8tGeSUqNBTSbz7iEeM7zM.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 19:19:32 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/f8tGeSUqNBTSbz7iEeM7zM.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nick Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Gmail in light mode on Pixel 6 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Gmail in light mode on Pixel 6 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google is reportedly prototyping the Pixel Tablet 2 with a valuable accessory ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Rumors claim Google has started prototyping its "Pixel Tablet 2," which reportedly features a design close to the original.</li><li>Google has supposedly started prototyping its official "keyboard cover" accessory.</li><li>The company was rumored to have a keyboard and accessory in the works; however, nothing ever happened due to alleged "quality issues."</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>With the Pixel 9 series in our hands, all eyes turn to Google's next tablet (potentially) in 2025.</p><p>The latest rumors stem from Mishaal Rahman (<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/pixel-tablet-2-keyboard-3500081/">Android Authority</a>) and an unknown "Google source" who spoke about the Pixel Tablet 2's supposed design. The insider claims the tablet's "early prototypes" feature a design quite close to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/google-pixel-tablet-review">the original device</a> from 2023. However, certain physical aspects like its camera have been shifted to the left alongside its power button.</p><p>Rumors suggest its display bezels could shrink, but this is seemingly restricted to the "top and bottom." The camera is reportedly receiving an upgrade, though it's unclear if this applies to the front <em>and </em>back.</p><p>Another rumor claims the Pixel Tablet 2 is being developed with a "keyboard cover" accessory. The keyboard allegedly attaches to the pogo pins on the tablet's back panel. Moreover, since rumors point toward it doubling as a "cover," speculation states it can "prop up" the tablet during use.</p><p>This accessory is supposedly in a prototyping stage so, hopefully, it arrives.</p><p>The post ends with speculation on the 2nd-gen Pixel Tablet, stating it could feature the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-tensor-g4">Tensor G4</a> or the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-has-reportedly-finished-designing-the-pixel-10s-custom-tensor-g5-soc">Tensor G5</a> SoC. Similarly, speculation claims it's a toss-up between Android 15 and 16 for its launch.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:5472px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="RXanYi5x26R6DLFRudWFHK" name="google-pixel-tablet-review-usi-stylus-pens.jpg" alt="USI Stylus pens on Pixel Tablet in Google Canvas" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RXanYi5x26R6DLFRudWFHK.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="5472" height="3078" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>We've been through this song and dance with the Pixel Tablet's <em>supposed </em>accessories <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/pixel-tablet-more-accessories-rumor">since last year</a>. Early rumors claimed Google had two more planned: a keyboard and a stylus. Neither of them saw the light of day. Those rumors surged when its re-release of the Pixel Tablet <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/pixel-tablet-relaunch-accessories-rumored">was just a theory</a>, but nothing happened (again).</p><p>At the time, it was initially rumored that the accessories hadn't arrived because they "weren't ready." It seems Google had striking quality concerns with its in-house accessories. Rumors didn't expand on a potential stylus, so we're still in the dark.</p><p>In February, Google's Android 14 beta featured <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/rumored-pixel-tablet-2-codenames">two codenames</a>: "Clementine" and "Kiyomi." Both names were rumored to reference the Pixel Tablet 2 as the company has a history of using citrus-based fruits for its tablet. Speculation said Google could have a "Pixel Tablet Pro" in the works and potentially an OLED display upgrade over the O.G's LCD.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Tablet deals: </strong><a href="https://shop-links.co/link?id=pcmcat209000050008&publisher_slug=future&exclusive=1&u1=ac-us-6679384887145822017&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fipad-tablets-ereaders%2Ftablets%2Fpcmcat209000050008.c%3Fid%3Dpcmcat209000050008&article_name=Google%27s%20latest%20beta%20may%20have%20spilled%20its%20Pixel%20Tablet%202%20codenames%20%7C%20Android%20Central&article_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.androidcentral.com%2Ftablets%2Frumored-pixel-tablet-2-codenames" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1943169/565706/9383?subId1=ac-us-9225475089942591934&sharedId=ac-us&u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fsearch%3Fq%3Dtablet" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://shop-links.co/link?publisher_slug=future&exclusive=1&u1=ac-us-9367231853129825184&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.samsung.com%2Fus%2Fshop%2Fall-deals%2Ftablets-laptops-computers-deals%2F&article_name=Google%27s%20latest%20beta%20may%20have%20spilled%20its%20Pixel%20Tablet%202%20codenames%20%7C%20Android%20Central&article_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.androidcentral.com%2Ftablets%2Frumored-pixel-tablet-2-codenames" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://target.georiot.com/Proxy.ashx?tsid=169923&GR_URL=https%3A%2F%2Famazon.com%2Fs%3Fk%3Dtablet%26crid%3D2HCFROTF588S1%26sprefix%3Dtablet%252Caps%252C159%26ref%3Dnb_sb_noss_1%26tag%3Dhawk-future-20%26ascsubtag%3Dac-us-2576789603442781212-20" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-100048248-12578053?sid=ac-us-1216649483872271025&url=https://www.dell.com/en-us/search/tablet" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Dell</strong></u></a></li></ul>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="1a16179d-9b63-47d1-9c51-402ec38d0ee2">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:89.23%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uuB3gSyzvN9ARDKJHV5Hpi.jpg' alt="Pixel tablet product render"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel Tablet</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Jack of most trades, master of one</strong></em></p><p>The Pixel Tablet is a device with a simple exterior, but peel apart the layers of its software, and it might surprise you. The tablet brings what consumers love about the Pixel series and its goodies to a larger screen that can be an assistance no matter where you are.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/google-pixel-tablet-2-accessory-prototype-rumors</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Rumors claimed Google has started prototyping the Pixel Tablet 2 with a crucial accessory. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">PAxryr5uRoKYVDeC6gxZoM</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6E7eWHw34R3q89FU6GEPfH.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 18:18:21 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6E7eWHw34R3q89FU6GEPfH.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android 13 clock on Pixel Tablet]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android 13 clock on Pixel Tablet]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ I hope Samsung doesn't make the same mistakes as Apple ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Beyond the Alphabet</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="74uXEL5FbSyzjPgHM9K6b7" name="lloyd-beyond-the-alphabet2.png" caption="" alt="Android Central's LLoyd with a projection with a Google logo" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/74uXEL5FbSyzjPgHM9K6b7.png" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text"><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/beyond-the-alphabet">Beyond the Alphabet</a> is a weekly column that focuses on the tech world both inside and out of the confines of Mountain View.</p></div></div>
<p>If there's one thing we know for sure, 2024 has been pretty odd when it comes to software updates. Google released its new flagship lineup of phones before Android 15 was out, Apple announced a bunch of features that won't arrive until at least March of next year, and we're midway through November with no sign of stable Android 15 for Samsung phones. However, with what little we know about One UI 7, I can't help but wonder if Samsung is following Apple's example in more ways than one, and for better or for worse.</p><p>For years, I abstained from even considering using a Samsung phone. I didn't care how cool or "reliable" Samsung phones were because the software was just so incredibly awful that it ruined everything else for me. However, that all changed once Samsung finally moved away from TouchWiz in favor of One UI.</p><p>Not only was <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/touchwiz">TouchWiz</a> packed to the gills with features, but there were more issues than you could count. I'm actually grateful for how bad it was because otherwise, I might not have enjoyed the different offerings from LG, Motorola, HTC, and Google. Heck, if it weren't for Samsung, I might not even be sitting here writing these words.</p>

<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1200px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="GzB57RWu3DeXXxZ5ETmAUc" name="s3-new-3.jpg" alt="Samsung Galaxy S3 in-hand unlocked on the Home Screen" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GzB57RWu3DeXXxZ5ETmAUc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1200" height="675" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Nevertheless, here we are and Samsung is gearing up to release its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/one-ui-7-first-beta-to-hit-galaxy-devices-after-november-17-in-us">first beta for One UI 7</a>. Although it has been a little over six years since One UI was originally unveiled, it shares one commonality with TouchWiz as Samsung still takes an "everything but the kitchen sink" approach to features.</p><p>I'm not expecting Samsung to really add any "game-changing" features to the mix, but it does seem as though a UI overhaul is in store. With the exception of a few differences here and there, One UI has largely remained the same since <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/samsung-one-ui-40-android-12">One UI 4</a> in 2021. This was based on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/android-12">Android 12</a>, which introduced the Material You design language.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>Although Material You arrived with One UI 4, it didn't really get fully implemented until One UI 5.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>Samsung's implementation with One UI 4 was half-baked, to say the least, but the company rectified those issues with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-one-ui-5-review">One UI 5</a>. That puts us at about two years of using the same general software experience, meaning that we're definitely due for something new.</p><p>Most of the time, I don't really care about how the software looks on any phone, not just Samsung. However, given that it's taken Samsung this long to actually release the beta of One UI 7, I've grown a bit worried that we might be in store for a bit of a storm.</p><p>It really wasn't all that long ago that Samsung was considered among the worst companies when it comes to software updates. That's changed in recent years, with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-samsung-phones">best Samsung phones</a> receiving updates faster than any other phone besides Google's Pixel.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1073px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:55.92%;"><img id="53xsrHgfAhYnTg8D9Lvd7d" name="one-ui-7-quick-settings-panel-sdc-2024-demo.jpg" alt="Samsung had a demo of One UI 7 on an S24 Ultra, which showed off its revamped Quick Settings." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/53xsrHgfAhYnTg8D9Lvd7d.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1073" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: SammyGuru)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I can't help but feel like there's a little bit of writing on the wall with the One UI 7 update, considering the beta has already been delayed several times. And if it weren't for a few leaky faucets, we wouldn't have any idea what to expect.</p><p>That being said, we're likely to see Samsung <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-one-ui-7-changes-teased-sdc-2024">overhaul everything</a> and anything, ranging from icons and widgets to "smoother animations" and even a new Quick Settings panel. I've seen some suggestions that Samsung is trying to make One UI a bit more like iOS, especially when it comes to animations.</p><p>While I agree that animations could be better, I could really care less about whether the software <em>looks</em> like the Android equivalent of an iPhone. Why? Because I'm just going to download <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/one-ui-7-good-lock-module-customization-update-spotted">Good Lock</a>, a few icon packs, and make my phone look the way I want it to anyway.</p><p>No, the bigger problem here is that Samsung is also rumored to be taking another page out of Apple's book, but it's not a good one. Instead of announcing features when they're ready, Samsung might announce its latest batch of features, only to delay some of them until One UI 7.1.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2070px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="TspK8cw2ucPMRV64qWaxHQ" name="apple-intelligence-prompt-imore.jpg" alt="Apple Intelligence prompt on iPhone" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TspK8cw2ucPMRV64qWaxHQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2070" height="1164" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Future)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>When Apple introduced the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/apple-iphone-16-pro-max-review">iPhone 16</a> series, the company also leaned heavily into the "Apple Intelligence" aspect. Of course, this was just a part of the company's initial marketing push, but there was one problem — many of those features <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/has-apple-lost-its-touch-as-android-innovation-grows">weren't available yet</a>.</p><p>In fact, there are some that we're still waiting for, as Image Playground and ChatGPT integration with Siri is currently only available if you're using the iOS 18.2 beta. Meanwhile, the <em>really cool</em> features, such as Personalized Responses and On-Screen Awareness, aren't expected to arrive until March 2025.</p><p>So without even knowing everything that Samsung has up its sleeve for new features, I'm keeping my fingers crossed that it doesn't travel down this same path. If we are indeed getting an overhauled UI, that's plenty for Samsung to hang its hat on and promote. Then, the company can properly announce its AI features after they are fully baked and ready for primetime.</p><p>Some of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/huge-one-ui-7-samsung-parent-ai-features-leak">rumored AI features</a> include things such as "AI Notification," which summarizes your notifications. It has also been said that Samsung will introduce new options for its existing AI features, such as <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-use-sketch-to-image-on-a-samsung-galaxy-phone">Sketch to Image</a>.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:694px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:86.46%;"><img id="g5R7Ra2k3tyXsbBdLpxQf6" name="one-ui-7-rumored-lock-screen-enhanced-notifications-example" alt="One UI 7 is rumored to debut an "enhanced lock screen" and other "smart management" tools for alerts." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/g5R7Ra2k3tyXsbBdLpxQf6.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="694" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Given the constant need for companies to figure out ways to get AI into headlines, I suspect that Samsung won't take the reserved approach. Instead, it will likely make the same mistakes as Apple, which could be pretty comical if One UI ends up looking like iOS.</p><p>I don't have a crystal ball and can't see what the future holds, so it's possible that I'm completely off base. Maybe Samsung delayed the release of One UI 7 so that it could release <em>everything</em> at once. Or maybe the plan all along was to release the final version alongside the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25">Galaxy S25</a>, but the lack of transparency and communication has let our imaginations go wild.</p><p>At the same time, I'm a bit worried that Samsung is about to revert back to its old ways when it comes to software updates. Samsung may try to do too much, which would result in delayed updates and half-baked promises.</p><p>Let's just hope it doesn't come to that and that this is just a blip on the radar.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://shop-links.co/link?id=pcmcat1563302848653&publisher_slug=future&exclusive=1&u1=ac-us-1310386257270800476&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Ftop-deals%2Fcell-phone-deals%2Fpcmcat1563302848653.c%3Fid%3Dpcmcat1563302848653&article_name=One%20UI%207%20first%20beta%20tipped%20to%20soon%20hit%20Galaxy%20devices%20in%20South%20Korea%20and%20the%20US&article_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.androidcentral.com%2Fapps-software%2Fone-ui-7-first-beta-to-hit-galaxy-devices-after-november-17-in-us" target="_blank"><strong>Best Buy</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1943169/565706/9383?subId1=ac-us-1616575986852848016&sharedId=ac-us&u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fcp%2Fcell-phones%2F1105910%3Fpovid%3Dweb_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all" target="_blank"><strong>Walmart</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://shop-links.co/link?publisher_slug=future&exclusive=1&u1=ac-us-1046258332279967407&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.samsung.com%2Fus%2Fshop%2Fall-deals%2Fcell-phone-deals%2F&article_name=One%20UI%207%20first%20beta%20tipped%20to%20soon%20hit%20Galaxy%20devices%20in%20South%20Korea%20and%20the%20US&article_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.androidcentral.com%2Fapps-software%2Fone-ui-7-first-beta-to-hit-galaxy-devices-after-november-17-in-us" target="_blank"><strong>Samsung</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://target.georiot.com/Proxy.ashx?tsid=169923&GR_URL=https%3A%2F%2Famazon.com%2Fs%3Fk%3Dcell%2Bphone%26crid%3D19CKV7OMEPEMF%26sprefix%3Dcell%2Bphone%252Caps%252C222%26ref%3Dnb_sb_noss_1%26tag%3Dhawk-future-20%26ascsubtag%3Dac-us-3885757905967324900-20" target="_blank"><strong>Amazon</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-100048248-15733793?sid=ac-us-7048853059555476519&url=https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/" target="_blank"><strong>Verizon</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-100048248-15735111?sid=ac-us-1085212239477296294&url=https://www.att.com/" target="_blank"><strong>AT&T</strong></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/delayed-one-ui-7-update-has-me-worried</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung's release of One UI 7 is shaping up to be almost as ambitious as the move from TouchWiz to One UI. However, the delayed release doesn't leave us feeling great.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">7QvjpjQ8URc2XkX3ERpPne</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nFMkDSensEgPivRafCToGQ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ andrew.myrick@futurenet.com (Andrew Myrick) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nFMkDSensEgPivRafCToGQ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S24 FE home screen in hand]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S24 FE home screen in hand]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The first Google TV Streamer update lets you manually choose an audio output format ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-32">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google quietly started rolling out the first Google TV Streamer update with "other bug fixes and performance improvements."</li><li>However, users quickly noticed a new manual audio output format option in the TV Streamer's settings following the update.</li><li>Aside from the default <strong>Automatic</strong> format, users can now select <strong>Dolby Digital Plus</strong>, <strong>Dolby Digital</strong>, or <strong>PCM Stereo</strong>.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/google-tv-streamer-review">Google TV Streamer</a>, a long-awaited successor to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/chromecast">Chromecast</a> with Google TV 4K, finally launched in September. Now, it's receiving its first OTA update, as first spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/11/15/google-tv-streamer-audio-format-update/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a>. The update's release notes are extremely light on details; in fact, Google's official <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/chromecast/answer/7124014#zippy=%2Ccurrent-production-firmware-version" target="_blank">changelog</a> still lists the current TV Streamer version as <strong>UTT3.240625.001.K5</strong>, which was the original zero-day release.</p><p>Regardless, users are starting to see the new version <strong>UTT3.240625.001.K9</strong> appear for their Google TV Streamer. The update is roughly 35MB in size, and requires two steps to apply it, plus a restart. As for the update's contents, Google only shares that the new version includes "other bug fixes and performance improvements."</p><p>There is at least one significant change to the Google TV Streamer's software following the tiny update, though. As 9to5Google notes, the update brings a new settings menu that will let users pick a manual audio output format. This page can be found by navigating through Settings, selecting <strong>Audio options</strong>, and scrolling down to <strong>Output format</strong>.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4480px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="oSCNoksGQT3qCR4JMPRpUV" name="TV-Streamer-Audio-Options" alt="New audio output settings on Android TV 14." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oSCNoksGQT3qCR4JMPRpUV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4480" height="2520" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: <a href="https://9to5google.com/2024/11/15/google-tv-streamer-audio-format-update/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a>)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>By default, the TV Streamer's audio output format will be set to <strong>Automatic</strong>. "Your system will choose the best audio quality format available," the screen explains. "You may need to power cycle your Google TV Streamer for a settings change to take effect."</p><p>Aside from the Automatic mode, the update adds manual selection of the <strong>Dolby Digital Plus</strong>, <strong>Dolby Digital</strong>, or <strong>PCM Stereo</strong> formats. It's worth noting that some users have reported seeing this menu on day one of owning their Google TV Streamer, so perhaps this update simply brings the experience to all users.</p><p>While this feature addition is welcomed by audiophiles and home theater fans, there still may be work to do for Google. Unlike the Chromecast with Google TV, the new Google TV Streamer does not support audio passthrough. Additionally, some TV Streamer owners are looking for a way to use <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/nest-audio-review">Nest speakers</a> as a default audio output for their new set-top box.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/the-first-google-tv-streamer-update-lets-you-manually-choose-an-audio-output-format</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ You'll want to update your Google TV Steamer to pick a custom audio output format. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">hH6w6HJcvembrj2qQzmHwh</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MDPwVpKzcsN8sxueXDcnhN.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 17:11:52 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Streaming &amp; TV]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MDPwVpKzcsN8sxueXDcnhN.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google TV Streamer with Android figure and remote]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google TV Streamer with Android figure and remote]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>