<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 20:41:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Nothing Phone 2a Special Edition is here and looks like a multicolored R2-D2  ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Phone 2a gets yet another color variant dubbed Special Edition.</li><li>The device's design blends Nothing's red, yellow, and blue signature colors.</li><li>The device ships with 12GB RAM and 256GB storage variant, priced at £349/ ₹27,999 / €379.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Phone 2a debuted recently as Nothing&apos;s first cheaper Android phone. Since the company has managed to keep the phone in the limelight with prompt updates and new colorways, there&apos;s now a new special edition of the same budget handset.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/nothing-phone-2a-first-impressions">Phone 2a</a> is already a great-looking phone as it retains Nothing&apos;s signature translucent design. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-android-phones">cheaper Android handset</a> now has a Special Edition, which looks like a new colorway at first glance, yet it still incorporates Nothing&apos;s signature colors.</p>
<div class="looped-video"><video class="lazyload-in-view lazyloading" data-src="https://s3-nothing-prod.s3.eu-central-1.amazonaws.com/2024-05-29/1716973891-382746-nothing-2a-16x9.mp4" autoplay loop muted playsinline src="https://s3-nothing-prod.s3.eu-central-1.amazonaws.com/2024-05-29/1716973891-382746-nothing-2a-16x9.mp4"></video></div>
<p>Until now, the company has blended in colors like red, yellow, and blue for its audio products separately, such as Ear, Ear, and Phone 2a, respectively. Taking things forward, the Special Edition Phone 2a blends in all three colors at the back as part of a new design, making the first Nothing product to feature more than a single or couple of different colors.</p><p>Adam, Design Director at Nothing, has further shared about the product in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://nothing.community/d/10897-introducing-phone-2a-special-edition">community post</a>, indicating, "We are very happy to unveil Phone (2a) Special Edition. The first product to explore our palette of the primary colors: red, blue and yellow. Its overall aesthetic references some of our design heroes from the past, whilst creating a new expression for a smartphone. Elevating a functional device into a striking piece of art."</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Be one of the first to walk away with Phone (2a) Special Edition at our London drop this Saturday 1 June. From 11:00, we will have limited quantities available to buy from Nothing Store Soho.4 Peter St, London W1F 0AD pic.twitter.com/cuWwOoss3V<a href="https://twitter.com/nothing/status/1795761271792386113">May 29, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>Aside from the notable incorporation of three colors, the rest of the Phone 2a looks like a mix of White and Black and features the same glyph interface and identical specifications. </p><p>However, the Phone 2a Special Edition will be available in 12GB RAM and 256GB onboard storage variants and is priced at £349/ ₹27,999 / €379 for the respective markets, the same as the traditional colorway variants featuring the same storage option.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="c4rHsgjzLJEcPEzgDKN3UJ" name="nothing-phone-2a-special-editon-2.jpg" alt="Nothing Phone 2a Special Edition" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/c4rHsgjzLJEcPEzgDKN3UJ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nothing)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Nothing says users can grab one of these starting today (May 29) through the company site or associated e-commerce platforms. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/nothing-phone-2a-review">Phone 2a</a> turned out to be an excellent choice and a super valued phone for the cheaper Android phones segment that it is competing in. </p><p>There is no better time for interested consumers since the phone is now being offered in four colorways, and the latest Special Edition is believed to be available in limited quantities.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/nothing-phone-2a-special-edition-goes-official</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ After teasing for a couple of days with colors this week, Nothing finally reveals that it is Phone 2a in a new avatar. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">WxPBBhbjLaN3PPnac2wLTd</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/a4uZsfHrBBQbLiAZvuEJPJ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 20:36:41 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/a4uZsfHrBBQbLiAZvuEJPJ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nothing]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Nothing Phone 2a Special Edition]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Nothing Phone 2a Special Edition]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Galaxy Z Flip 6 and 'Watch 7 Ultra' appear as Samsung's FCC tour continues ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung's upcoming Galaxy Z Flip 6 and the supposed "Galaxy Watch 7 Ultra" have appeared at the FCC.</li><li>The database shows the Flip 6 will feature 5G support with Bluetooth, Wi-Fi, NFC, and wireless charging capabilities like the Flip 5.</li><li>The supposed Watch 7 Ultra listing shows LTE support for U.S. brands with Bluetooth, Wi-Fi, and wireless charging support.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>This year&apos;s Samsung summer comes into focus as the company&apos;s upcoming foldable and smartwatch appear at the FCC.</p><p>The folks at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.droid-life.com/2024/05/29/samsungs-galaxy-watch-7-ultra-galaxy-flip-6-hit-fcc/">DroidLife</a> spotted the Galaxy Z Flip 6&apos;s FCC listing, confirming some of the extra specifications regarding connectivity. The database gave the device an "A3LSMF741U" ID number, which contains Flip 6&apos;s apparent SM-F741U model number from previous rumors.</p><p>The clamshell&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://apps.fcc.gov/oetcf/eas/reports/ViewExhibitReport.cfm?mode=Exhibits&RequestTimeout=500&calledFromFrame=Y&application_id=1t4G8YUYURx8lUzCI%2B6gUA%3D%3D&fcc_id=A3LSMF741U">listing confirms</a> that the device will support 5G cellular networks. Additionally, the Flip 6 will have Bluetooth, Wi-Fi, and NFC capabilities alongside wireless charging, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-5-review">similar to last year</a>.</p><p>Joining the expected foldable phone is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://apps.fcc.gov/oetcf/eas/reports/ViewExhibitReport.cfm?mode=Exhibits&RequestTimeout=500&calledFromFrame=Y&application_id=wUkjFAQycN8glZZ5SB3Ucw%3D%3D&fcc_id=A3LSML705">what could be</a> Samsung&apos;s new top-tier smartwatch, the "Galaxy Watch 7 Ultra." The publication states that the Watch 7 Ultra has been rumored with model number SM-L705. The FCC&apos;s listing ID features the same number, furthering speculation about the device&apos;s existence.</p><p>Samsung&apos;s information shows that the device will support an LTE connection. The publication notes that such support will involve the "major" U.S. brands. Other specifications learned from the listing include Bluetooth, Wi-Fi, wireless charging, and NFC capabilities.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="yPJxVVLin9sT5JtTkMPshL" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Watch-6-Classic-apps.jpeg" alt="A close-up of the Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 Classic" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yPJxVVLin9sT5JtTkMPshL.jpeg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div></figure>
<p>The hype is building for a "Galaxy Watch 7 Ultra" with the latest batch of leaks showing up recently with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-7-ultra-renders-leak">supposed renderings</a>. The device may sport quite the design shift as Samsung could go for a mix between a squarish chassis and a circular display design. The tipster suggested that the Watch 7 UItra could see a 1.5-inch display in diameter. Its overall dimensions make it appear as though it&apos;ll be slightly larger than the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-6-review">Watch 6 Classic</a>.</p><p>The renderings show a new third button joining the typical two on the watch&apos;s right side. Rumors claim this to be an "action button" of some sort.</p><p>The Flip 6 alongside the Fold 6 <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-z-flip-6-fold-6-qualcomm-exclusivity-choice-report">was rumored</a> to drop Samsung&apos;s Exynos chip in favor of Qualcomm&apos;s Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 exclusively. The company had reportedly discussed the idea of "cost control" and "efficiency," which were the driving forces behind the chip decision. So, instead of featuring Qualcomm&apos;s chip in the U.S. and Exynos in other regions, it seems everyone will get the same experience chip-wise.</p><p>The Galaxy Ring made <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/galaxy-ring-fcc-listing-cradle-specs-confirmed">an FCC appearance</a> yesterday (May 28), and with the listing came major spoilers about what it&apos;s offering. The database confirmed the existence of nine ring sizes for the device, alongside a quick look at a charging "cradle." A more concrete look at the cradle wasn&apos;t available, however, it seems Samsung will mark each one with a consumer&apos;s chosen Galaxy Ring size.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-z-flip-6-watch-7-ultra-specs-fcc-listing</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung's FCC run continues with its next clamshell foldable and "Ultra" watch variant. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">ES6SUJk3Hbvij4BdKgNm7Z</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Efbq8s7t7vMpS5SMPuNjFN.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 19:46:01 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Efbq8s7t7vMpS5SMPuNjFN.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The larger cover display of the Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 5]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The larger cover display of the Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 5]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Telegram gains AI smarts via Microsoft Copilot for a 'conversational' experience ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Microsoft announced that Copilot has arrived in Telegram through a beta.</li><li>The AI lets users enjoy a "conversational" experience through text-based queries only with the ability to ask follow-up questions.</li><li>Copilot in Telegram can be accessed through a one-on-one chat, where users can talk about sports, games, movies, food, and more.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Microsoft is giving Telegram an AI boost and touting it as your "everyday companion."</p><p>Microsoft <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/edge/copilot-for-social?form=MY02F9">announced</a> that its AI chatbot, Copilot, has arrived on Telegram today (May 29). Similar to the AI experience users would get through Windows, Copilot in Telegram is powered by OpenAI&apos;s GPT and Bing Search. The company states that the AI uses "natural language to provide responses on a range of topics."</p><p>Such topics include gaming and sports. For the former, users can ask Copilot in Telegram about the latest game releases and walkthroughs. For sports, the AI can quickly grab scores, schedules, "and more" for those curious about the NFL, NBA, and the NHL, among others.</p><p>Other topics <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/microsoft-copilot-google-assistant-chromeos">Copilot</a> can work with are traveling, fitness, food, music, romance, movies, and brain teasers to pass the time.</p><p>Microsoft states that Copilot&apos;s initial beta period in Telegram limits the AI to text-based prompts.</p><p>Users can get started by hopping into the Telegram app on desktop or mobile. Searching for "CopilotOfficialBot" in the app will produce the AI&apos;s chat thread. Simply pose your question or give the AI some instructions and let it do the rest. Microsoft adds that users can also deliver a follow-up question to the AI after it&apos;s delivered a response to your query.</p><p>Copilot&apos;s arrival on Telegram is free, meaning users on Android, iOS, Windows, and macOS can get started today (May 29). When using Copilot, those concerned about their privacy and security can check out Microsoft&apos;s "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/privacystatement">comprehensive</a>" approach.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="nQbyL3TPWyw2rMSEs3aToE" name="telegram-logo-lifestyle-4-wide.jpg" alt="Telegram logo lifestyle." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nQbyL3TPWyw2rMSEs3aToE.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Chris Wedel / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Microsoft dropped its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/microsoft-copilot-play-store-launch">Copilot app for Android</a> onto the Play Store early in January. Utilizing OpenAI&apos;s GPT-4 model, all users can ask the bot questions or ask it to write content for them. Moreover, the app features DALL-E 3, a model designed to handle a user&apos;s text-to-image generation requests. Microsoft classified this as the "imaginative" side of Copilot.</p><p>There&apos;s also an "Image Creator," which gives users the tools to make social media items, logo designs, illustrations for books, and more. With Copilot starting out as a beta in Telegram, and only accepting text-based prompts, perhaps there&apos;s a future where we see DALL-E 3&apos;s influence in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-messaging-apps">popular messaging app</a>.</p><p>Elsewhere, an update for Copilot in February enabled the AI to be used as a user&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/microsoft-copilot-default-assistant-beta-rollout">default assistant</a> on Android. Users can swipe diagonally from the corner of their device or long-press their power button to produce it. However, it&apos;s not entirely seamless as instead of experiencing a floating UI, keeping you where you are, users are thrown into the main Copilot app.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/telegram-microsoft-copilot-ai-beta-rollout</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Microsoft announced the arrival of its AI Copilot in Telegram for a "conversational" experience. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">eJYZsiiREcjrT6ZQcBNwNC</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bbaAgjdsQaQCW7HL5rCiQS.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 18:52:03 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bbaAgjdsQaQCW7HL5rCiQS.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Microsoft Copilot logo on a phone screen]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Microsoft Copilot logo on a phone screen]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ YouTube is glitching for Adblock users, but it’s not what you think ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Users with ad blockers on YouTube are experiencing problems like videos skipping to the end or muting.</li><li>YouTube denies these issues are related to its anti-ad blocker efforts, attributing them to recent performance improvements.</li><li>The problems mainly affect AdBlock Plus users; uBlock Origin users report no issues.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>If you&apos;re encountering issues on YouTube, your ad blocker might be the culprit. Some users with ad blockers are noticing their videos unexpectedly skipping to the end.</p><p>On the r/youtube subreddit, ad blocker users have reported odd problems like videos being muted or jumping straight to the end. For example, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/youtube/comments/1d1pgng/new_youtube_adblock_weird_behaviour_video/" target="_blank">u/SDHD4K</a> shared a clip showing their video ending abruptly with Adblock Plus enabled, as reported by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/05/28/youtube-skipping-to-end-adblockers/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a>.</p>
<blockquote class="reddit-card"  ><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/youtube/comments/1d1pgng/new_youtube_adblock_weird_behaviour_video">New Youtube adblock weird behaviour - video automatically skips to the end</a> from <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/youtube">r/youtube</a></blockquote><script async src="//embed.redditmedia.com/widgets/platform.js" charset="UTF-8"></script>
<p>The original poster tried replaying the video from different points, but it still ended suddenly. Others mentioned audio problems, like one user who only got sound by constantly adjusting the volume.</p><p>At first, it seemed like these issues were part of YouTube&apos;s increased efforts to fight ad blockers, but the company has denied this. In a statement to 9to5Google, YouTube said the problems stem from recent improvements to the platform&apos;s performance and reliability, not from its anti-ad blocker campaign.</p><p>The glitch mostly affects AdBlock Plus users, but many ad blockers have released updates to fix it. Meanwhile, users reported no problems with uBlock Origin.</p><p>YouTube has been stepping up its fight against ad blockers. Last month, it <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-blocks-third-party-ad-blockers">tightened restrictions on third-party apps</a>, warning that those blocking ads might lose API access. In November, YouTube confirmed that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-loads-slower-on-firefox">slowdowns in major web browsers were linked to its anti-ad-blocker efforts</a>. Back in June 2023, it <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-three-strikes-policy-for-ad-blockers">began alerting users they&apos;d be cut off after three videos</a> if an ad blocker was detected.</p><p>People use ad blockers to avoid pop-ups and intrusive ads for a better online experience. The recent increase in YouTube ads and the rising cost of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/youtube-premium">YouTube Premium</a> likely pushed more people to install ad blockers.</p><p>Despite YouTube&apos;s aggressive stance against ad blockers, which apparently caused a spike in uninstalls, ad-block developers quickly released updates to counter the changes.</p><p>Unsurprisingly, people are quick to blame YouTube&apos;s ad-blocker crackdown for any related glitches. Intentional or not, these latest issues make using ad blockers so irritating that you&apos;ll likely turn them off, leaving you to either put up with the ads or spring for Premium.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-is-glitching-for-adblock-users-but-its-not-what-you-think</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Trying to watch YouTube with an ad blocker? Looks like you're getting fast-forwarded to the end credits. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">YtXyxkWdVhq8FhaCAzbeq6</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/53Hee9M7ttmhbNwJuiddgP.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 18:46:08 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/53Hee9M7ttmhbNwJuiddgP.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Chris Wedel/Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[YouTube on Pixel 7 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[YouTube on Pixel 7 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Message users receive distorted GIFs sent from Apple iPhones ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Android users reportedly received distorted GIFs and memes from their friends who use iPhones.</li><li>Several Pixel and Galaxy phone users took to Reddit to report the issue.</li><li>Reddit users also suggested some workarounds, which helped resolve the issue for some.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Last week, we <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-messages-users-are-getting-hit-with-rcs-spam-texts">saw</a> Google Messages users receive spam messages, including random letters and numbers, along with a Google support page link. This week, we&apos;re back with another blue and green bubble error, as reports suggest that Android users are receiving distorted GIFs sent from iPhones as SMS/MMS.</p><p>Several <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phone</a> users took to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GoogleMessages/comments/1d1th6c/whats_up_with_this_with_the_screenshot_this_time/?sort=new">Reddit</a> (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/05/27/google-messages-android-iphone-distorted-gifs/">9to5Google</a>) to share their Google Messages, receiving distorted GIFs from their iPhone friends. Notably, these were received via SMS/MMS by users on Google Pixel and Samsung Galaxy phones. It wouldn&apos;t be the case if iPhones were adapted to RCS instead of relying on older communication protocols for Android handsets. The Apple iPhones are yet to gain RCS support, which is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" target="_blank" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/apple-announces-rcs-support-coming-to-iphone">anticipated</a> to happen later this year.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:787px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:66.71%;"><img id="xcCReMw8yN7gMcCu66WnaZ" name="google-messages-distorted-gif.jpeg" alt="Google Messages distorted GIF" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xcCReMw8yN7gMcCu66WnaZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="787" height="525" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Reddit user u/ForwardMotion6565)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Per the Reddit posts, users saw distortion issues with GIFs and memes. However, other media messages, like photos, appear as usual. Initially, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GoogleMessages/comments/1d1th6c/comment/l60dtvz/?utm_source=share&utm_medium=web3x&utm_name=web3xcss&utm_term=1&utm_content=share_button">multiple users</a> attributed this issue to file sizes sent from iPhones to Google Messages—the smaller file sizes of the GIFs rendered well, while the bigger ones struggled to render.</p><p>Meanwhile, another Reddit user noted that Google had recommended factory resetting their Pixel phone when contacted regarding the issue. In the accompanying comments, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GoogleMessages/comments/1cwcol3/comment/l4yptya/?utm_source=share&utm_medium=web3x&utm_name=web3xcss&utm_term=1&utm_content=share_button">another user hinted</a> that turning off “Send Messages Faster” had somehow fixed the distortion. And other users <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GoogleMessages/comments/1cwcol3/comment/l5d9ugg/?utm_source=share&utm_medium=web3x&utm_name=web3xcss&utm_term=1&utm_content=share_button">who tried</a> the workaround were lucky enough to get the issue fixed as well. It appears to be a temporary solution for users facing the problem.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:462px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:129.87%;"><img id="5kiNbyu3aTbyUinVmPvpQZ" name="google-messages-distorted-gif-2.jpeg" alt="Google Messages distorted GIF" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5kiNbyu3aTbyUinVmPvpQZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="462" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Reddit user u/Wooden-Structure158)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It is still unclear when the issue with iMessage and Google Messages started popping up, as many users on Reddit have indicated that it had been happening for more than a couple of weeks. </p><p>As mentioned, Google hasn’t officially acknowledged the issue despite <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GoogleMessages/comments/1cwcol3/distorted_gifs_from_imessage/?utm_source=share&utm_medium=web3x&utm_name=web3xcss&utm_term=1&utm_content=share_button">suggesting</a> a factory reset for a user. Such issues might still pop up across iMessage and Google Messages unless Apple quickly adopts RCS support as promised.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-messages-users-face-distorted-gifs-issue-due-to-iphones</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google Messages has been facing some issues lately, and a new one is now paired up with iPhone users sending distorted GIFs, likely due to a bug. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">wdoPcvsea2K9Y3dY4VGRHZ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ziZDiSfrJmLq6TJoFTB57F.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 18:39:51 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ziZDiSfrJmLq6TJoFTB57F.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Messages blue logo]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Messages blue logo]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Heads up! This Samsung deal is carving $1,000 OFF one of the best OLED TVs on the market ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Most of the Memorial Day sales have come to an end, but apparently nobody told Samsung, as they&apos;re <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/televisions-home-theater/tvs/oled-tvs/65-class-s90c-oled-4k-smart-tv-2023-qn65s90cafxza/"><strong>currently dropping $1,000 off</strong></a> one of the best OLED TVs on the market. At this very moment, the 65-inch Class OLED S90C smart TV is sitting with a massive 38% discount on Samsung&apos;s website, sending the price of the premium TV crashing to $1,599.99. </p><p>Now I&apos;ll be completely honest, Android TVs aren&apos;t my favorite thing to write about — I&apos;d prefer a smartphone discount or affordable wireless carrier any day — but if you&apos;ve been dreaming of owning an OLED TV, this Samsung deal might present the perfect opportunity. </p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="db723d5f-c8a0-434c-b8c8-f489a3e99da6" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$2,599.99" data-dimension48="$2,599.99" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/televisions-home-theater/tvs/oled-tvs/65-class-s90c-oled-4k-smart-tv-2023-qn65s90cafxza/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:781px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.03%;"><img id="5BitnRqerMZMYznejkEMDZ" name="samsung-s90c-oled-tv-render.JPG" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5BitnRqerMZMYznejkEMDZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="781" height="586" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung 65" Class OLED S90C 4K Smart TV:</strong> <a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/televisions-home-theater/tvs/oled-tvs/65-class-s90c-oled-4k-smart-tv-2023-qn65s90cafxza/" data-dimension112="db723d5f-c8a0-434c-b8c8-f489a3e99da6" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$2,599.99" data-dimension48="$2,599.99"><del>$2,599.99</del> <strong>$1,599.99 at Samsung</strong></a></p>
<p>For a limited time, Samsung is carving $1,000 off the 65-inch S90C OLED smart TV, an absolute powerhouse of entertainment that boasts real-time 4K upscaling, exceptionally bright picture, and refresh rate support up to 144Hz. </p>
<p>This particular price drop is for the 65-inch version, but it's worth noting that the 55-inch, 77-inch, and 83-inch models are getting similarly-great discounts at Samsung.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/televisions-home-theater/tvs/oled-tvs/65-class-s90c-oled-4k-smart-tv-2023-qn65s90cafxza/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="db723d5f-c8a0-434c-b8c8-f489a3e99da6" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$2,599.99" data-dimension48="$2,599.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<ul><li><strong>TV deals: </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/browse/electronics/tvs/3944_1060825_447913"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/televisions-home-theater/tvs/all-tvs/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/promo/tv-deals"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/40E7E961-A3DD-4E8C-8B88-4274A840DF67?ingress=0&visitId=183fc793-0cec-425f-816d-4e9b1d420367"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.newegg.com/TV-Video/Category/ID-59"><u><strong>Newegg</strong></u></a> </li></ul>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>you&apos;re looking for an entry-level OLED TV that&apos;s under $2,000; 65 inches is your Goldilocks zone. </p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>you don&apos;t care about OLED technology; you can afford to upgrade to the S95D from Samsung. </p><p>OLED smart TVs are notoriously expensive, but you&apos;re getting a lot of bang for your buck with the S90C. In addition to delivering exceptionally bright OLED picture quality, the set boasts an AI-powered Neural Quantum Processor that upscales all of your content to 4K in real-time. You also get some nice gaming support, Object Tracking Sound, and outstanding contrast. </p><p>If you don&apos;t care about OLED, you can easily save a bunch of money and get a similarly great experience by going with one of the best non-OLED <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-tvs">Android TVs</a>. But if you&apos;ve been waiting for the right time to upgrade, this might be it.  </p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/heads-up-this-samsung-deal-is-carving-dollar1000-off-one-of-the-best-oled-tvs-on-the-market</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Head to Samsung today and you'll score a whopping 39% discount on the Class OLED S90C smart TV, one of the most highly-rated OLED TVs available today.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">mPXCm3GWe8W72Jz4TC7udP</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jVmKqeNMWzj9mbshEun3cF.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 18:14:31 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Streaming &amp; TV]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jVmKqeNMWzj9mbshEun3cF.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Samsung]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung S90C OLED TV]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung S90C OLED TV]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Best Fitbit Ace LTE bands 2024 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Google has finally succeeded the Fitbit Ace 3 children&apos;s smartwatch with a new cellular wearable. It&apos;s called the Fitbit Ace LTE instead of the Ace 4, which is what we were expecting, but the rest of it is anything but a disappointment.</p><p>If you&apos;ve decided to get the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fitbit-ace-lte-launch">Fitbit Ace LTE</a> for your child, you&apos;ll probably want to invest in spare bands. Kids are messy and accidents happen. Besides that, it&apos;s also fun for them to have options and personalize their wearables as they like. Any of the best Fitbit Ace LTE bands will suit your child&apos;s tender skin and also please them design-wise. As a bonus, each Fitbit Ace LTE band unlocks new items for the watch&apos;s character, Eejie.</p>
<h2 id="all-of-fitbit-apos-s-ace-lte-bands-look-superb-2">All of Fitbit&apos;s Ace LTE bands look superb</h2>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="705cc159-68f6-42c3-98c4-100bbc0664df">
            <a href="https://store.google.com/us/product/spooky_pugs_woven_band_fitbit_ace_lte" data-model-name="Fitbit Ace LTE Spooky Pugs Comfort Band"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/h6Q8mgvrbEx77qkniuuQvQ.jpg' alt='Fitbit Ace LTE Spooky Pugs Comfort Band'><span class='featured__label hero__label'>Staff pick</span></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Spooky Pugs Comfort Band</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>So much personality</strong></em></p>
<p>The bright green Spooky Pugs Comfort Band is a soft woven band made of recycled yarn. It is water-resistant and full of personality thanks to the spiderweb silicone overlay.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="a42f8fd8-181e-45fa-9029-c9ebb1417538">
            <a href="https://store.google.com/us/product/moovin_woven_band_fitbit_ace_lte" data-model-name="Fitbit Ace LTE Moovin Comfort Band"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dKsU3WFUBFH2QfKmyrrDwh.jpg' alt='Fitbit Ace LTE Moovin Comfort Band'></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Moovin' Comfort Band</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Funky and comfy</strong></em></p>
<p>This is another woven yarn band that's waterproof too. Green and pink threads overlap to create a groovy, funkalicious pattern that kids will adore.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="61718f96-bd81-458f-923c-305d071fe344">
            <a href="https://store.google.com/us/product/camp_nightmare_active_band_fitbit_ace_lte" data-model-name="Fitbit Ace LTE Camp Nightmare Active Band"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vWrGrDWrF5mii4G8N3Afmh.jpg' alt='Fitbit Ace LTE Camp Nightmare Active Band'></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Camp Nightmare Active Band</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Outdoorsy vibes</strong></em></p>
<p>The silicone Camp Nightmare Active Band is ideal for kids who like to play outdoors. It has an adventurous appeal to it and of course, it's water-resistant.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="195f45f3-d8c4-41a6-8fa4-c73b91bb939c">
            <a href="https://store.google.com/us/product/strange_arcade_woven_band_fitbit_ace_lte" data-model-name="Fitbit Ace LTE Strange Arcade Comfort Band"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vfcLEjpKDwA9DsbZZJ7HcW.jpg' alt='Fitbit Ace LTE Strange Arcade Comfort Band'></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Strange Arcade Comfort Band</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Stranger things</strong></em></p>
<p>This woven Fitbit strap has a muted retro feel, reminiscent of the atmosphere of TV shows like <em>Stranger Things</em>. The dark and light ash hues are suitable for picky children.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="2d225b4f-21e8-43e9-9b0a-7d33a5bd085b">
            <a href="https://store.google.com/us/product/courtside_active_band_fitbit_ace_lte" data-model-name="Fitbit Ace LTE Courtside Active Band"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jfisrNw7EUxn2D3Dnf3e4E.jpg' alt='Fitbit Ace LTE Courtside Active Band'></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Courtside Active Band</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Soft blue is a mood</strong></em></p>
<p>Fitbit's Active Band lineup, like the Courtside Active Band, all have a soft coating on top. It makes the wear experience extremely delightful.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="647b3b84-709a-4ea5-b5a1-9e83b0db8b31">
            <a href="https://store.google.com/us/product/glitterbomb_skate_active_band_fitbit_ace_lte" data-model-name="Fitbit Ace LTE Glitterbomb Skate Active Band"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JpgEDdLsGVqqPVbqQxjgLd.jpg' alt='Fitbit Ace LTE Glitterbomb Skate Active Band'></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Glitterbomb Skate Active Band</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Pretty in pink</strong></em></p>
<p>The soft-coated Glitterbomb Skate Active Band is tender against your kid's soft skin. If your child doesn't want anything but pink, this one's the easy answer.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<ul><li><a href="#main"><strong>Back to the top ^</strong></a></li></ul>
<h2 id="choosing-the-right-fitbit-ace-lte-band-depends-on-your-child-apos-s-needs-2">Choosing the right Fitbit Ace LTE band depends on your child&apos;s needs</h2>
<p>The Fitbit Ace LTE is easily the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-fitbit">best Fitbit</a> for kids. This wearable makes fitness fun by gamifying the process of health tracking and staying active. One of the other most attractive features of this wearable is cellular connectivity, making it a good replacement for a phone.</p><p>Just ordered the Fitbit Ace LTE for your little ones? It&apos;s time to accessorize! Involve your offspring in the process and enjoy watching them personalize the style of their smartwatch. There are loads of fantastic Fitbit Ace LTE bands to choose from. Google opted for proprietary bands so you can&apos;t get third-party picks just yet, but the first-party ones are super cool and not too pricey.</p><p>Every Fitbit Ace LTE band unlocks a new Noodle, an outfit for Eejie, and a wide range of fun items for Eejie. Apart from digital collectibles, the material and design of the bands should be decisive factors in picking a band or two for your kid&apos;s Fitbit Ace LTE.</p><p>The Spooky Pugs Comfort Band is animal and Halloween-themed, which is a really fun mix for character items and the home screen Noodle. Speaking of the band itself, it is an adjustable stretch recycled yarn that is waterproof and comfortable to wear for extended periods. This is our top pick, but really any of these fantastic bands will make your child happy.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-fitbit-ace-lte-bands</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ There are a bunch of fun Fitbit Ace LTE bands available right now. If you want your child to have several options to wear, here's what you can choose from. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">xCHeoJ6Vw6nqwGU2Zk98aB</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SeA6joAVvtnE984jnVB6R4.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 16:51:29 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SeA6joAVvtnE984jnVB6R4.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Fitbit]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Fitbit Ace LTE]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Fitbit Ace LTE]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Fitbit Ace LTE vs. Fitbit Ace 3 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[         <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="37946363-12c4-4fd0-8864-18a88023f9a3">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qH9y9XK6RHT9Y5XqoiyqKc.jpg' alt='Fitbit Ace LTE'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Fitbit Ace LTE</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>A phone alternative </strong></em></p>
<p>If your child is too young for their own cell phone but you still want them to be able to contact you to check in or in case of emergency, the Fitbit Ace LTE is a good option. It isn’t the first kids’ GPS and cellular watch, but it’s the first from Fitbit. And it offers some compelling features. But the subscription requirement, access to on-wrist games, and lack of sleep tracking might make you think twice.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Comes with cellular connectivity</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Includes GPS location tracking</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Charges quickly</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Gamifies fitness to get kids moving</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Requires a recurring monthly fee</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Not needed if they have a phone</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No sleep tracking</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Significantly shorter battery life</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="46827af6-8d46-4ad0-b553-03634c0a394f">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4MW5pxakiLHXZv4JbTtbJN.jpg' alt='Fitbit Ace 3'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Fitbit Ace 3</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>A kids’ starter tracker </strong></em></p>
<p>The Fitbit Ace 3 is a simple device designed for younger kids that can track their activity and sleep while letting them personalize on-screen characters, get reminders to move, and more. It’s limited in functionality but for some parents (and kids), that’s all you want. At its current price, it’s a great tracker to test the waters before diving into something more feature rich.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>No subscription required</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Detailed sleep tracking</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Simpler band design</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Great battery life</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Limited functionality</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Older model in need of a refresh</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No connectivity without a phone</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<p>There comes a time when kids get older and need some autonomy. When this is the case, you might be mulling over getting them a cell phone. However, many parents prefer not to get their kids cell phones at an early age. The new Fitbit Ace LTE is an interesting in-between device, a kids&apos;s smartwatch with, as the name implies, LTE cellular connectivity.</p><p>While both the Fitbit Ace LTE vs. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/fitbit-ace-3-review">Fitbit Ace 3</a>, the brand&apos;s last kids&apos; activity tracker, might bear the same name and be for kids of around the same age, they are very different devices.</p><p>The Fitbit Ace LTE&apos;s subscription-based connectivity could be a viable compromise you want for kids who need more autonomy or parents who want some peace of mind. But do you need it? Let’s examine how these two wrist-worn devices work to help you make the right decision for your little one.</p>
<h2 id="fitbit-ace-lte-vs-fitbit-ace-3-how-they-look-2">Fitbit Ace LTE vs. Fitbit Ace 3: How they look</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="NLsazfA8qzZ9nP4PHNehtb" name="fitbit ace lte bands.jpg" alt="Fitbit Ace LTE" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NLsazfA8qzZ9nP4PHNehtb.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>First, let’s consider the looks. The Fitbit Ace LTE comes in Spicy Pebble with a Moovin’ Band or Mild Pebble with a Strange Arcade band (other bands are available separately and interchangeable with the originals). Made of plastic, stainless steel, and glass, the device has a square smartwatch-style face that incorporates recycled materials. It is designed to be scratch, bump, and water-resistant. The band is made from recycled polyester yarn while the clasp and lugs are plastic and silicone.</p><p>Compatible with most phones running Android 11 or newer as well as iOS 15 or newer, the Fitbit Ace LTE has a scratch-resistant Corning Gorilla Glass 3 Color OLED screen. It’s water-resistant to 50 meters via the 5ATM rating so kids can wear it underwater, in the bath, while playing outside in the rain, you name it. The watch even comes with a protective bumper case for especially clumsy kids. </p><p>Offering up to 16 hours of battery life, this is mostly affected by cellular connectivity and GPS tracking, which I’ll discuss in more detail in the next section. So, keep in mind that you need to recharge this tracker daily. It does, however, quick charge to 60 percent, or about 11 hours worth of battery life, in just 30 minutes, or to full in just over an hour.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.33%;"><img id="PBWxtYkbKFekRmeNEqfW3m" name="Fitbit-ace-3-minions-watch-face-lifestyle-16x9.jpg" alt="Fitbit Ace 3 with Minions watch face" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PBWxtYkbKFekRmeNEqfW3m.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="600" height="338" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Also designed for kids aged six to seven and older, the Fitbit Ace 3 comes in Black and Sport Red or Cosmic Blue and Astro Green with two buttons on the side. Employing a thin and rectangular activity tracker design, it comes with a silicone band with an adjustable plastic clasp. There are Fitbit branded and third-party band options you can swap in, including Fitbit’s licensed Minions character bands.</p><p>I reviewed the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/fitbit-ace-3-review">Fitbit Ace 3</a> when it was released and love how easy it is to pop the tracker out of the band and swap it with another. Even if you keep the same band, though, you’ll want to remove it and clean around the underside of the band to prevent skin irritation.</p><p>Equipped with a PMOLED touch-sensitive display, it also meets a 5ATM rating for use in and around water. It’s compatible with Android 10 or higher and Apple iOS 15 or higher devices.</p><p>Battery life is a big differentiator here since this watch can run for up to eight days per charge, though it takes about two hours to fully charge to 100 percent. This is because the Fitbit Ace 3 doesn’t connect to anything beyond a phone or other device via Bluetooth.</p>
<h2 id="fitbit-ace-lte-vs-fitbit-ace-3-the-specs-2">Fitbit Ace LTE vs. Fitbit Ace 3: The specs</h2>
<p>Before diving into the core features of these two fitness trackers for kids, let’s see how the specs compare.</p>

<p>As you can see, while the names of these two activity trackers for kids are similar, there is a lot more than meets the eye to the Fitbit Ace LTE.</p>
<h2 id="fitbit-ace-lte-vs-fitbit-ace-3-what-kids-can-do-with-them-2">Fitbit Ace LTE vs. Fitbit Ace 3: What kids can do with them</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="Y3vRauNmyR9PjzVTSwt67b" name="fitbit ace lte calls messages.jpg" alt="Fitbit Ace LTE" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Y3vRauNmyR9PjzVTSwt67b.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Fitbit Ace LTE is not your standard wrist-worn step tracker for kids. It takes the experience much further. It includes built-in 4G LTE cellular connectivity via an included SIM card. This also means there’s a monthly subscription fee. At the time of this writing, it’s $9.99/mo. or $120/yr. and includes the ability for kids to call, message, and share location.</p><p>A purchase of the plan (the watch doesn&apos;t make much sense without one) also includes an Ace Band, with a new band at every annual renewal period. Six fun bands are available at launch, and there will likely be more down the line. The plan is on for half price through August 31, 2024.</p><p>Once set up and activated, your kids can use the Fitbit Ace LTE along with its built-in microphone and speaker to call and message up to 20 contacts. This can include trusted individuals like parents and caregivers, grandparents, close friends, and other family members.</p><p>The smartwatch also features GPS location tracking with advanced location technology powered by Google. Keep an eye on where your child is in real-time and ensure they aren’t leaving the school premises, for example, or keep track of older kids as they walk home alone from school or a friend’s house. Google says only parents or caregivers can see the location data, which is automatically deleted after a short time.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="Kfj3cPrk24FGSV7tzu6dQb" name="fitbit ace 3 games apps.jpg" alt="Fitbit Ace LTE" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Kfj3cPrk24FGSV7tzu6dQb.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Additionally, kids can play interactive 3D games in the Fitbit Arcade that use haptics, sounds, and the accelerometer. Think games that see them racing through space or going fishing; new games will be added every few months. While gaming from the wrist might sound like a distraction, gameplay is intentionally spaced out, rewarding kids only when they participate in active play in the real world. Essentially, the more the child moves in real life, the more game segments they can unlock in a virtual one. The School Time option, meanwhile, limits gameplay during school hours.</p><p>Further encouraging physical activity is a Noodle activity ring that appears on the watch’s home screen, recording their movement throughout each day. There’s a fun animation each time they reach a Move Goal, which can be achieved by walking, jumping, or even spinning in circles! The goal is to encourage kids to get at least an hour of physically active time per day, in line with the recommendations from the World Health Organization.</p><p>Tying everything together is Eejie, a virtual character who lives in the virtual Bit Valley world on the watch. Fitbit’s reimagining of the Tamagotchi, kids keep Eejie happy by meeting their daily move goals. The more they move, the more items they earn for Eejie, like a ping pong table for its room or a skateboard for it to ride. Kids can connect with their friends’ Eejies to visit them in other parts of Bit Valley as well.</p><p>With Tap to Pay coming soon, older kids can leverage the built-in NFC sensor and use the watch to pay for items from compatible terminals, like at the convenience store or fast-food restaurant during lunch at school. All they need is a payment card loaded to the account. It’s a great way to teach older kids about the importance of saving and give them some independence to occasionally spend, too. Parents can set controls and receive real-time notifications whenever a child spends money.</p><p>The Fitbit Ace LTE also has basic functions like an alarm clock, daily goals settings, and rewards. Kids get expected activity tracking along with an optical heart rate sensor. One glaring omission, however, is sleep tracking. This is presumably because daily charging and the always-on connectivity mean kids have to recharge overnight. But it’s an important feature that many parents might not be willing to forego.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="WiVZKfqSBzdwGkMUkYKBCj" name="Fitbit-ace-3-on-wrist-lifestyle-16x9.jpg" alt="Fitbit Ace 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WiVZKfqSBzdwGkMUkYKBCj.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>How does the Fitbit Ace 3 compare? It’s very different. Introduced years ago in March 2021, the Fitbit Ace 3 offers the same reliable sleep tracking you get with other Fitbit devices, advising if your kids are getting enough sleep and good quality sleep, and when they go to bed and rise. Kids (and parents) can use the Fitbit app to schedule bedtime reminders and set silent alarms that wake kids up gently with a light buzzing on their wrists.</p><p>Parents can see if kids go to sleep when they say they do, how restless they are at night and their overall sleep patterns. Beyond just satisfying curiosity, this could suggest patterns, like that your child tends to be temperamental on nights when they don’t get good quality sleep or wake up groggy when they go to bed after a certain hour. Since you can see a full history in the app, it’s a useful feature and a shame it isn’t in the Fitbit Ace LTE as well.</p><p>The Fitbit Ace 3 activity tracker monitors kids’ daily movements as well with on-wrist reminders to move or for them to get up and stretch if they have been sitting too long. Along with basic steps, it also tracks Active Minutes. This presumably uses the built-in heart rate sensor to measure, though the app does not display heart rate data for kids. Kids can receive messages on the watch (they can’t reply to them) but only when it’s paired with a nearby connected and compatible smartphone.</p><p>There’s nothing as interactive as eejie with the Fitbit Ace LTE, but there are virtual badges, animated clock faces with characters like a rocket, bunny, or even Minions, and personalized avatars kids can enjoy. It’s on a much more rudimentary level on the much smaller screen. I do love the celebratory messages, however, when kids achieve goals along with virtual badges they can collect and view them in the app.</p><p>Other simple features in the Fitbit Ace 3 include a timer and stopwatch for racing with friends or timing chores. Kids can also see their stats on their wrists as they move throughout the day.</p>
<h2 id="fitbit-ace-lte-vs-fitbit-ace-3-which-should-you-buy-2">Fitbit Ace LTE vs. Fitbit Ace 3: Which should you buy?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="HeXUDsKN4SsLZBjVWxN4Gb" name="fitbit ace lte child jumping.jpg" alt="Fitbit Ace LTE" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HeXUDsKN4SsLZBjVWxN4Gb.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It’s a complicated decision between the Fitbit Ace LTE vs. the Fitbit Ace 3. While the Fitbit Ace LTE offers a compelling proposition, it has a bit of an identity crisis. Some of the features, like NFC and GPS location tracking, are better suited to older kids with more autonomy, like teens and tweens. Other features, meanwhile, like games, are better suited to younger kids. So, who would want this watch?</p><p>The Fitbit Ace LTE is ideal for kids in the age 8-13 range who might not yet be old enough for a cell phone but are ready for a bit of independence. Some kids between these ages, for example, are allowed to walk home from school alone, go to the local park, leave school on lunch, or play with friends outside. The Fitbit Ace LTE would provide peace of mind.</p><p>But then, why not just get them a cell phone with a plan? There is a cost-benefit: even with a monthly plan, the Fitbit Ace LTE is still nowhere near what even the cheapest phone and plan would cost. Plus, the child doesn’t have to bring along a phone, easily staying in touch from the watch right on their wrist.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="SWxRNnsYTYtSr9MTL4e96k" name="fitbit ace 3 wet.jpg" alt="Fitbit Ace 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SWxRNnsYTYtSr9MTL4e96k.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Fitbit)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>For younger kids aged 6-10, the Fitbit Ace 3 is still a good option. It’s ultra-affordable and simple. While it doesn’t have games, per se, there are simple gamification features that young kids will love. They are engaging, not distracting. The battery life of more than a week and the detailed sleep tracking are the two biggest pluses of this tracker.</p><p>Bottom line: for older kids who aren’t yet ready for a cell phone, consider the Fitbit Ace LTE. It gives kids autonomy and parents peace of mind. But when you start getting into the teen years, chances are they’ll want something more substantial in a smartwatch, not to mention a phone!</p><p>For younger kids, stick with the Fitbit Ace 3. While having LTE connectivity for emergencies is great, the monthly cost adds up. Alternatively, consider placing a Bluetooth device tracker in their backpack or pocket, like the Samsung Galaxy SmartTag2 or any of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-bluetooth-trackers">the best Bluetooth trackers</a>. You might find that these satisfy your need for GPS location tracking at the very least. If you’re interested in what else is out there beyond these two, see our picks for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-kids-fitness-tracker">the best kids’ fitness trackers</a>.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="b4f2b874-1e5b-4b73-81d9-66d0d7de843b">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Z7YCpaGAA46yWCrxvSAqCc.jpg' alt='Fitbit Ace LTE'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Fitbit Ace LTE</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>A connected kid</strong></em></p>
<p>If you want your kid to be connected for emergency purposes and show some responsibility but don’t yet want to invest in a smartphone and plan, the Fitbit Ace LTE is a good transitional device. While it requires a monthly plan, the device nor the plan costs anything close to a smartphone and plan. Plus, it helps encourage kids to get moving more and have fun while doing it.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="8d863800-e035-4c89-b753-54218cbac0f3">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4MW5pxakiLHXZv4JbTtbJN.jpg' alt='Fitbit Ace 3'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Fitbit Ace 3</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Simple yet fun</strong></em></p>
<p>The Fitbit Ace 3 is several years old now and due for a refresh. But as a simple activity tracker for younger kids, it has useful features like move reminders, active minutes, and detailed sleep tracking, all of which parents can monitor from the parent view of the app. It’s a basic but also fun and useful wristwatch that kids will feel important wearing.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fitbit-ace-lte-vs-fitbit-ace-3</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Fitbit hasn't made a kids' smartwatch since the Ace 3, and the Fitbit Ace LTE is a worthy successor. But it's also a very different wrist-worn device. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">nT7jAQWab5uDaTgys8FCH8</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Wp2VYv2kcHPiM2MaRU5mib.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 15:04:56 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ christinep2424@gmail.com (Christine Persaud) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Wp2VYv2kcHPiM2MaRU5mib.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Fitbit Ace LTE]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Fitbit Ace LTE]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Android users don't have to worry about data being stored by Google Play apps ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The Google Play Store account deletion policy finally went live for app users.</li><li>Users can choose their accounts and data collected by app developers to be kept or removed entirely.</li><li>Google initially proposed the policy for app developers last April, with a deadline of May 31, 2024.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google Play Store is finally allowing users to easily delete their account data from Android Apps.  The feature that was introduced to developers by Google last April seems to be rolling out to everyone starting this week.</p><p>The new rule, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-play-account-data-deletion-policy">first proposed</a> by Google targeting apps that usually allow account creation for users, will now also allow them to delete accounts permanently. According to contributor Assemble Debug through <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/google-play-store-app-account-deletion-3446261/">Android Authority</a>, Google Play Store is showcasing the new "Account deletion available" badge for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phone</a> users under the Data Safety section for relevant apps.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:270px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:222.22%;"><img id="sW2hqwGDqUhso8n4dyfYBe" name="google-play-store-app-account-deletion.jpg" alt="Google Play Store App Account Deletion feature" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sW2hqwGDqUhso8n4dyfYBe.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="270" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:270px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:222.22%;"><img id="SMd7ZTxGWVsKVr2xDRG32e" name="google-play-store-app-account-deletion-01.jpg" alt="Google Play Store App Account Deletion feature" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SMd7ZTxGWVsKVr2xDRG32e.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="270" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:270px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:222.22%;"><img id="rZjrgnF4hAs6tBShGwBJ7e" name="google-play-store-app-account-deletion-03.jpg" alt="Google Play Store App Account Deletion feature" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rZjrgnF4hAs6tBShGwBJ7e.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="270" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Clicking the badge would take users to the Data deletion pane, which includes options like Delete app account and Manage app data. The former allows users to "submit a request" to app developers to delete their account data and other associated information that users have given while creating the account. The Delete app account section further provides the relevant developer’s site link. Upon clicking, it will showcase instructions for users on how to delete their accounts.</p><p>With the Manage app data, account holders can request the developer delete only specific data collected by the app, not the entire account. This data can include activity history, transaction history, and images and video.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:355px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:183.10%;"><img id="GRyXnnrFmViSkcrR5Ns8pL" name="Google-Play-account-data-deletion.gif" alt="Requesting account deletion from an app on the Google Play Store" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GRyXnnrFmViSkcrR5Ns8pL.gif" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="355" height="650" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The new findings appear on track as promised during the proposal with an early 2024 timeframe. Google mandated that app developers provide straightforward methods for account deletions online or via the app&apos;s web version. </p><p>This new ability is "especially important so that a user can request account and data deletion without having to reinstall an app," noted Bethel Otuteye, Senior Director of Product Management, Android App Safety, in the blog post.</p><p>When Google initiated this policy, it also gave developers a deadline of May 31, to include the easy app account deletion option for their apps. As the extension is only a couple of days away, Google Play Store bringing the new changes sounds achievable.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-play-store-account-deletion-policy-goes-live</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Last year, Google introduced a new policy for developers to allow app users to create and delete their accounts and associated data easily. The move finally appears official. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">ktCKbzbyhTe7ERCky2BrWQ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AhaX4oiMTLreQSzTcsAWn7.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 14:08:28 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AhaX4oiMTLreQSzTcsAWn7.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Play Store home page on Android and Chrome OS]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Play Store home page on Android and Chrome OS]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The new Fitbit Ace LTE is a Pixel Watch 2 for kids ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-32">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google has announced the Fitbit Ace LTE, a kids-only smartwatch aiming to promote a more healthy and active lifestyle.</li><li>Along with various "eejies," "games," and other ways to get kids moving, the Ace LTE also offers calling, messaging, and location sharing.</li><li>In order to take advantage of the cellular connectivity, parents need to sign up for Ace Pass, which costs $9.99 per month or $119.99 per year. </li><li>This new smartwatch is priced at $229.95 and will be available starting June 5 from Google and Amazon.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>It&apos;s not very often that we hear about a new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/best-kids-smartwatch">kids smartwatch</a>, let alone one that comes directly from Google and Fitbit. That&apos;s all changing, as the Fitbit Ace LTE looks to offer a completely different way to keep your kids healthy and motivated to move around.</p><p>Besides the bands and included Bumper Cover, the Ace LTE doesn&apos;t look too dissimilar from the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fitbit-versa-4-review">Fitbit Versa 4</a> or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fitbit-sense-2-review">Sense 2</a>. However, despite the similarities, the Ace LTE actually features the same internals as the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-2-review">Pixel Watch 2</a>, even down to the charger.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.15%;"><img id="RfkhsnJjwJJK75vd6gqH64" name="fitbit-ace-lte-hero-6.jpg" alt="Fitbit Ace LTE promo hero" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RfkhsnJjwJJK75vd6gqH64.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1078" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Fitbit / Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>This new wearable is water resistant up to 50 meters, while the screen uses Corning Gorilla Glass 3. In terms of connectivity, the Ace LTE is equipped with 4G LTE, 2.4GHz Wi-Fi, Bluetooth 5.0, and there&apos;s even NFC. The NFC is particularly interesting, as "tap to Pay" will become available "in a couple of months," presumably via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet">Google Wallet</a>.</p><p>Along with being water-resistant and quite powerful, battery life should be able to keep up with your little ones. It&apos;s rated for up to 16 hours on a single charge, and thanks to fast charging, you can get another 11 hours of juice with just a 30-minute charge. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.15%;"><img id="e5J46exUPwAp8ioumS5i83" name="fitbit-ace-lte-back-glass-2.jpg" alt="Fitbit Ace LTE back glass" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/e5J46exUPwAp8ioumS5i83.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1078" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Fitbit / Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>As for what the Fitbit Ace LTE keeps track of when it comes to workouts, this smartwatch sports a plethora of sensors. These include an accelerometer, optical heart rate, altimeter, magnetometer, gyroscope, and ambient light sensor. </p><p>As for software, Fitbit built this new interface on top of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/wear-os-4">Wear OS</a> in order to offer a "bespoke experience." This opened the doors for things like "Eejies," the "Noodle," and "interval-based gaming." According to Fitbit, Eejies are "customizable creatures that feed off daily activity." </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="N4QiDd3VxtKKcQGeFBnca4" name="fitbit-ace-lte-overview.jpg" alt="Fitbit Ace LTE overview promo" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/N4QiDd3VxtKKcQGeFBnca4.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Fitbit / Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Not only are they there to be right beside your kids, providing encouragement, but playing games and earning "arcade tickets" will unlock different customizations. Speaking of games, Google and Fitbit worked with different game studios to create interactive 3D games that can be played right from the watch. </p><p>At launch, the Ace LTE comes with six games, but more are planned to launch every quarter. The goal is to get your kids "at least 60 minutes of physical activity per day," along with incentivizing them by building streaks. This is similar to what the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/i-never-expected-to-love-apple-watch-ultra-2-so-much">Apple Watch</a> offers by closing rings, but children aren&apos;t penalized just for missing a day. </p><p>Instead, children are still rewarded for partial completion, which is a concept we hope is adopted for "adult" <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch">smartwatches</a>. That way, there&apos;s no guilt to be felt in the event that your little one wasn&apos;t feeling great and spent the day resting and recharging. </p><p>Thanks to the new Fitbit Ace app, parents can control and monitor everything that their children are doing with the watch. This includes adding up to 20 trusted contacts for your kids to call or text, along with viewing their location, and more. Do you want to make sure that your child is paying attention in class and not playing games? Set up School Time to keep things locked down while any activities are still monitored and accounted for.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="2WQkPsqWbNxsNsvvijk8kj" name="fitbit-ace-app-overview.jpeg" alt="Overview of the Fitbit Ace app" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2WQkPsqWbNxsNsvvijk8kj.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Fitbit / Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Another benefit is that much like the best Fitbit wearables, the Ace LTE is platform-agnostic. You&apos;re able to install the Fitbit Ace app and set everything up, regardless of whether you&apos;re using <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android</a> or an iPhone. All of this is made possible without needing to give your child a phone of their own.</p><p>By now, you might be wondering about how privacy comes into play with all of this. According to Google, the only people who can see your child&apos;s location and activity are parents. Additionally, location data is automatically deleted after 24 hours, while activity data remains in the app for a "maximum of 35 days" before it too is automatically deleted.</p><p>You also won&apos;t find any third-party apps, as your child is only able to access the content that is available out of the box and through subsequent software updates. The same goes for ads, as there aren&apos;t <em>any</em> ads being served on this kid&apos;s smartwatch. Google also confirmed that none of the data collected will be used for Google Ads. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.15%;"><img id="Kfwqsfc4eLPVxkXxKvebEo" name="fitbit-ace-lte-side.jpg" alt="Side view of the Fitbit Ace LTE" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Kfwqsfc4eLPVxkXxKvebEo.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1078" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Fitbit / Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Last but not least, is <em>how</em> this smartwatch is capable of offering things such as LTE, voice calls, GPS, and messaging without a dedicated phone. Well, all of that is made possible by signing up for Ace Pass. </p><p>For $9.99 per month or $119.99 per year, Ace Pass includes the LTE data plan, access to the Arcade, and more. Google worked with different carriers to provide the best coverage possible, and the SIM card is already installed in the smartwatch. All you&apos;ll need to do is download the Fitbit Ace app, link the smartwatch, and get everything set up from there.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.15%;"><img id="tHY7rcLSb7pLu4f7Vg9gFn" name="fitbit-ace-lte-hero.jpg" alt="Fitbit Ace LTE hero promo" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tHY7rcLSb7pLu4f7Vg9gFn.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1078" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Fitbit / Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Unfortunately, all of this means that Ace Pass is required to "access most features." This is rather disappointing, as it essentially turns the smartwatch into a paperweight without a subscription unless, of course, you buy into it.</p><p>You can preorder the Fitbit Ace LTE starting today for $229.95 from Google, ahead of its June 5 release date. As an added bonus, if you sign up for the yearly subscription of Fitbit Ace Pass between now and August 31, you&apos;ll save 50%, along with receiving a free collectible Ace Band. </p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="cada3b57-a021-47ad-8ea0-c2f0150218fe">
            <a href="g.co/fitbitace" data-model-name="Fitbit Ace LTE"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ewKUwayxTSr3U59nTLYZrk.jpg' alt='Render of Fitbit Ace LTE with Spooky Pugs band'></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Fitbit Ace LTE</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Keeping healthy and having fun</strong></em></p>
<p>The Fitbit Ace LTE is arguably the most powerful kids smartwatch on the market. It features all of the same internals as the Pixel Watch 2, and makes it easy for parents to keep a watchful eye on their little ones.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fitbit-ace-lte-launch</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ While we await the arrival of a potential Fitbit Sense 3 or Versa 5, the Fitbit Ace LTE is here, providing an extremely powerful and robust kids smartwatch. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">QRAHqxm4d3Du5VPodXEQy3</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/c9DWkS4m6pPWdzMSetj4kD.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 14:00:31 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ andrew.myrick@futurenet.com (Andrew Myrick) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/c9DWkS4m6pPWdzMSetj4kD.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Fitbit / Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Fitbit Ace LTE Moovin and Glitterbomb Skate Bands lifestyle image]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Fitbit Ace LTE Moovin and Glitterbomb Skate Bands lifestyle image]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>