<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 21:42:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ T-Mobile appears to suffer network outage, leaving many without service ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>T-Mobile appears to be affected by a network outage.</li><li>The outage appears to be centered in Utah and affecting T-Mobile-based MVNOs such as Google Fi Wireless and Mint Mobile.</li><li>T-Mobile has not yet commented on the outage on its social accounts.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>If you're a T-Mobile customer and have found that you can't connect to the network, then you are not alone. The carrier appears to have been dealing with a network outage in certain parts of the U.S., with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://downdetector.com/status/t-mobile/">Downdetector</a> seeing a spike in outage reports on Tuesday, Nov. 12.</p><p>The reports seem to have started around 2 p.m. EST, and it seems the outage is mostly concentrated throughout the state of Utah, although it may be affecting other areas as well. Local news in Salt Lake City has <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.abc4.com/news/local-news/is-t-mobile-down-for-you-utahns-report-outage-throughout-the-state/">reported</a> that users across the state appear to be affected by the outage.</p><p>Meanwhile, users have <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/TMobileHelp/with_replies?lang=en">flooded T-Mobile's X account</a> to complain about the lack of service, with most appearing to reside in Utah. That said, there are reports that things are improving for some who are able to connect once more to the network.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:758px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:42.08%;"><img id="8ftsUs9nDrbtWdNF2MH3c" name="T-Mobile-outage-november-12-2024" alt="T-Mobile outage reports on November 12, 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8ftsUs9nDrbtWdNF2MH3c.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="758" height="319" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Downdetector)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The outage appears to have affected other carriers that rely on T-Mobile's network. That includes Metro by T-Mobile, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/mint-mobile-review">Mint Mobile</a>, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-fi">Google Fi-Wireless</a>.</p><p>So far, T-Mobile has not publicly commented on the outage on its social media accounts but apparently <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://kutv.com/news/local/major-event-impacting-cell-towers-in-st-george-knocks-out-internet-service">told one news outlet</a> that a "major event" was causing the outage (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.tomsguide.com/news/live/t-mobile-is-down-the-latest-on-the-major-outage">Tom's Guide</a>). Android Central has reached out for a comment to confirm the status of the outage and affected areas, and we will update this article when we hear back.</p><p><em>Check back for updates...</em></p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/carriers/t-mobile-outage-november-12-2024</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The outage appears to be affecting T-Mobile brands and MVNOs like Google Fi Wireless and Metro. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">jEmRZQJYW8azZ22voCqyoc</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Mr8skv235NeD5miZHHjWGg.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 20:43:27 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Carriers]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ derrek.lee@futurenet.com (Derrek Lee) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Mr8skv235NeD5miZHHjWGg.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[T-Mobile store logo]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[T-Mobile store logo]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Android 15 QPR2 Beta 1 starts for enrolled Pixels ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google highlighted the start of Android 15 QPR2 Beta 1 to Pixel testers on Reddit.</li><li>The update contains the November security patch and a list of known issues users may encounter.</li><li>The QPR2 update is expected to arrive as the March 2025 feature drop while we brace for a much earlier Android 16 launch.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>The next major Android 15 update enters its first beta as Google drops the details to enrolled testers.</p><p>Google posted its announcement via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/android_beta/comments/1gpt8p6/android_15_qpr2_beta_1_now_available/">the Android Beta subreddit</a>, informing users that they can begin downloading Android 15 QPR2 Beta 1. Enrolled testers will find QPR2 Beta 1 as version <strong>BP11.241025.006</strong> when downloading. The update is available for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-series-hands-on">latest Pixel 9 series</a>, the original Pixel Fold, the Pixel Tablet, and the Pixel 8 down to the Pixel 6.</p><p>This patch includes the latest <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/googles-pixel-november-update-squashes-the-first-round-of-android-15-bugs">November 2024 security patch</a> for Pixels. Additionally, Google delivered an advisory for this looking to exit the Beta Program following Android 15 QPR1.</p>
<ul><li>If you prefer to leave the Beta program and receive the public stable release of Android 15 QPR1 in December, you can do so without wiping your device by opting out and <strong>not installing</strong> <strong>today’s QPR2 Beta 1 update</strong>*. If you opt-out of the program* <strong>after</strong> installing Beta 1 or any future updates, all user data on the device will get wiped per usual program guidelines. <strong>Opting out will trigger a ‘Downgrade’ OTA. Ignore this update and wait for the Android 15 QPR1 public release instead.</strong></li></ul>
<blockquote class="reddit-card"  ><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/android_beta/comments/1gpt8p6/android_15_qpr2_beta_1_now_available">Android 15 QPR2 Beta 1 now available!</a> from <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/android_beta">r/android_beta</a></blockquote><script async src="//embed.redditmedia.com/widgets/platform.js" charset="UTF-8"></script>
<p>If you do not wish to leave, Google states that those in the previous QPR beta will automatically grab QPR2 Beta 1 and those that follow. The update should appear within 24 hours, but you should continue to check throughout the week.</p><p>The company's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://developer.android.com/about/versions/15/release-notes">official changelog</a> detailed a few "general advisories" testers should be aware of. Among them, Google states your Pixel could experience battery, stability, and performance problems. If so, it's recommended that you submit bug reports and feedback via the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.google.com/android/beta/feedback">appropriate channels</a>. The log also states that some of your apps "may not function properly" in the beta.</p><p>While Google didn't explicitly state what's new, Mishaal Rahman (<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/android-15-qpr2-linux-terminal-3498872/">Android Authority</a>) discovered that QPR2 adds a "Linux Terminal" app. The new tool is reportedly tucked within "Developer Options" in the Settings menu. After getting it to surface, Google's on-device description states the Terminal app lets developers "run Linux terminal on Android." Rahman states developers can "configure, run, and interface" apps using an instance of Debian.</p><p>Moreover, Google's patch notes reiterate the "16KB boot mode" in the Developer Options page. This option already existed in QPR1, but it only concerned the Pixel 8 and 8 Pro. With QPR2, this has extended to the Pixel 8a.</p><p>Google prepared us for Android 15 QPR2 Beta 1 earlier this month, stating it was on the way. The company's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-teases-upcoming-android-15-qpr-2-beta-1">announcement</a> states the patch will "build on top of" the Android 15 QPR1 update, which is expected to the December feature drop. The QPR2 beta is expected to debut as the March 2025 feature drop.</p><p>Speaking of 2025, Google highlighted a much <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-play-store-gemini-android-studio-sdk-updates">earlier arrival of Android 16</a> in October. The post confirmed that the next major OS will arrive in Q2 2025, giving us April to June as a potential launch timeframe.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-qpr2-beta-1-pixel-test-start</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google started rolling out Android 15 QPR2 Beta 1 to Pixel testers. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">aiKbnhNmANzySearb8Bv9g</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LHz4r4kjv3nPsuHeqarvFP.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 20:31:14 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LHz4r4kjv3nPsuHeqarvFP.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Pixel 9 Pro XL back view against colorful background]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Pixel 9 Pro XL back view against colorful background]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Surprise! Grab the Galaxy Z Fold 6 for as low as $499.99 during Samsung's Black Friday sale ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Alright folks, call off the search: Samsung finally dropped a Black Friday Galaxy Z Fold 6 deal that I can afford. Pick up the innovative foldable in one of its exclusive color variants and trade in an old or broken phone and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/smartphones/galaxy-z-fold6/buy/galaxy-z-fold6-256gb-unlocked-sm-f956uzwaxaa/"><strong>you&apos;ll get up to $1,400 off your purchase</strong></a>, knocking the price of the Z Fold 6 down to as low as $499.99. </p>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/"><em><strong>See Samsung's full list of Black Friday deals</strong></em></a><em><strong> </strong></em></li></ul>
<p>With its two glorious AMOLED displays, a powerful Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 processor, and nearly-invisible folding hinge, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6</a> was easily one of the most impressive Android phones released this year. The only problem is that it was also one of the most expensive. Thanks to Samsung&apos;s Black Friday sale, the innovative foldable is more accessible than ever before.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-apos-s-foldable-masterpiece-just-crashed-into-budget-phone-territory-2">Samsung&apos;s foldable masterpiece just crashed into budget phone territory</h2>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="04d36997-ea33-4acf-9757-a5393cb674b9" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 256GB: $1,899.99" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 256GB: $1,899.99" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/smartphones/galaxy-z-fold6/buy/galaxy-z-fold6-256gb-unlocked-sm-f956uakaxaa/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:865px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:98.61%;"><img id="Qk9BrbQMCLYk6ofsRaMfP" name="samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-render-white.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Qk9BrbQMCLYk6ofsRaMfP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="865" height="853" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 256GB: </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/smartphones/galaxy-z-fold6/buy/galaxy-z-fold6-256gb-unlocked-sm-f956uakaxaa/" data-dimension112="04d36997-ea33-4acf-9757-a5393cb674b9" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 256GB: $1,899.99" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 256GB: $1,899.99"><del>$1,899.99</del> <strong>From $499.99 with eligible trade-in and select color variants at Samsung</strong></a></p>
<p>Pick up the Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 in <strong>White</strong> or <strong>Crafted Black</strong> and you'll get a straight $200 off plus up to $1,200 off with a trade-in during the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024-early-deals-and-how-to-prepare-for-the-big-sales">OEM's Black Friday sale</a>.</p>
<p>One of the most powerful <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">foldable phones</a> ever built, the AI-powered Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 boasts two stunning 120Hz displays, an ultra-efficient Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 processor, and seven years of guaranteed OS updates. </p>
<p><strong>Price comparison: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-z-fold6-256gb-unlocked-navy/6586742.p">Best Buy - $1,899.99</a> | <a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Smartphone-Handsfree-Interpreter-Manufacturer/dp/B0D18VM66K">Amazon - $1,378.22</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/smartphones/galaxy-z-fold6/buy/galaxy-z-fold6-256gb-unlocked-sm-f956uakaxaa/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="04d36997-ea33-4acf-9757-a5393cb674b9" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 256GB: $1,899.99" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 256GB: $1,899.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>I realize that this kind of offer isn&apos;t for everyone, but it&apos;s worth noting that Samsung is being surprisingly generous with its trade-in credit during the sale, <em>especially</em> if you&apos;re thinking of sending in an old Samsung phone. The Z Fold 5 and S24 Ultra will get you the full $1,200 off, for instance, while foldable phones dating back to the Galaxy Z Fold 3 will earn you a whopping $1,000 off the price. </p><p>I dug up my old Galaxy S20 FE and was surprised to see that I was eligible to get $500 off the Z Fold 6, which is way better than the paltry $50 usually offered on the site. </p><p>It&apos;s your call, but if you&apos;re a fan of trade-in deals, this Black Friday offer from Samsung is tough to beat. If you decide to go this route, your purchase will also include a bunch of free subscriptions to online services, such as three months of YouTube Premium, and two free months of Adobe Lightroom. It&apos;s the gift that keeps on giving!</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/surprise-grab-the-galaxy-z-fold-6-for-as-low-as-usd499-99-during-samsungs-black-friday-sale</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung just kicked off its Black Friday sale and the deals on display are no joke! ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">6xPckGcsdSCHCvyVz7ML57</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yocDkSssKZahVRHh532ZJY.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 20:09:32 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yocDkSssKZahVRHh532ZJY.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 on cobblestone road]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 on cobblestone road]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Chrome 131 for iOS adds 4 new features that could pull iPhone users into the Google ecosystem ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google is rolling out the Chrome 131 update for iOS and iPadOS with deeper integration for the company's services.</li><li>The changes will make it easier to use Google Chrome, Drive, Photos, and Maps on an iPhone or iPad.</li><li>By giving users more options to enter the Google ecosystem with their iOS device, Google may end up making it easier for iPhone users to switch to Android down the road.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.google/products/chrome/chrome-ios-updates-november-2024/" target="_blank">announced</a> today that it's rolling out Google Chrome 131 on iOS and iPadOS, which includes major upgrades to how the browser works with the company's other services. The update brings four key functions that Android users already have to the other side of the walled garden, and could make it easier for iPhone and iPad users to enter the Google ecosystem. These changes are rolling out gradually, with some features being limited to U.S. users for now.</p><p>The upgrades coming to Chrome 131 for iOS aim to help Google's portfolio of services more competitive with Apple's own offerings. For example, when iPhone users start to run out of storage, they are often prompted to buy more iCloud storage as part of a monthly subscription from Apple. Now, Google is providing a different solution in Chrome 131 for iOS. Users can save files directly from a website in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/top-google-chrome-tips-and-tricks">Chrome</a> to their <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-drive">Google Drive</a> cloud storage, eliminating the need to first save to their device storage.</p><p>New context menus will give users the option to save files to Google Drive instead of the native iOS Files app. Additionally, it is possible to upload photos directly to Google Photos with another context menu. Files that are uploaded to Drive from Chrome for iOS will be stored in their own folder.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4480px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="JrKXwbCDgPRcQvBc8x4kmb" name="Save-to-Drive" alt="Google Chrome 131 updates for iOS" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JrKXwbCDgPRcQvBc8x4kmb.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4480" height="2520" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google, like Apple, limits how much free storage space users can access in the cloud. You get 15GB of storage from Google and only 5GB from Apple, so there is a clear benefit to saving certain files directly to Google Drive. However, once that free space runs out, Google would probably rather you pay for extra storage space with a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-one">Google One</a> subscription rather than an iCloud Plus plan.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4480px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="NT8wo84xn54WAxVa9svRAc" name="Chrome-131-Maps-Drive" alt="Google Chrome 131 updates for iOS" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NT8wo84xn54WAxVa9svRAc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4480" height="2520" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>With this update, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-lens-search-ads-video-function-update">Google Lens</a> receives a boost. Users can now search using photos, screenshots, and text — all at the same time. This functionality is already on Android, but it's available in Chrome 131 for iOS for the first time. Additionally, <strong>Shopping Insights</strong> will tell people in the U.S. whether they're getting a great deal. This includes providing an easily-accessible price chart that shows whether the current sale price is really a fantastic discount using months-long price histories.</p><p>Finally, Chrome 131 for iOS adds support for quick <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-maps">Google Maps</a> previews. When you see an address on a website, one tap will open a map of the location and provide the most important details. From there, you can press again to get directions to the address in Google Maps. This feature is rolling out gradually over the next few months, so you may not see it immediately.</p><p>These Chrome 131 features are nothing new for Android users, but they may end up making it easier for iPhone users to make the switch to Android. After you become used to relying on Apple services, like iCloud Drive, iCloud Photos, and Apple Maps, it can become hard to switch. With Chrome 131 for iOS, Google is giving iPhone and iPad users an alternative way to get into the Google ecosystem with Chrome integration for Google Drive, Photos, and Maps.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/chrome-131-for-ios-adds-4-new-features-that-could-pull-iphone-users-into-the-google-ecosystem</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google Chrome is now a better Safari replacement, and the latest Chrome 131 update could pull iOS users to Android.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">9r9uM8oVGwyg2prSHw4z2J</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KtPrtg2G3Yyo6X8fzaABfn.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 19:57:07 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KtPrtg2G3Yyo6X8fzaABfn.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A graphic showing the four new features coming in Chrome 131 for iOS.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A graphic showing the four new features coming in Chrome 131 for iOS.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Home tipped to integrate support for dangerous air quality sensors ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A dive into a Google Home app "test version" highlighted several strings pointing toward CO/smoke detector support.</li><li>Various strings of code detail alerts for users about their home's dangerous air quality and sensor testing.</li><li>More devices have been added to Google Home since Matter support arrived, but its Nest app has been the only way to control its CO/smoke sensors.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google could have plans to incorporate new sensors that protect users from dangerous air conditions at home.</p><p>Google is reportedly developing new sensor support for the Home app, per a deep dive by AssembleDebug (<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/google-home-smoke-carbon-monoxide-sensors-apk-teardown-3498759/">Android Authority</a>). According to the tipster, various strings in a "test version" of Google Home suggest the app will implement support for CO (carbon monoxide) and smoke detectors.</p><p>This support will reportedly be joined by a series of new alerts delivered to a user's phone. The code showed signs of alerts that inform users if "smoke levels are too high." Additional alerts were discovered, informing users of dangerous CO and smoke levels detected by the sensor and to exit the home into "fresh air."</p><p>The Home app will seemingly let users test their sensors to ensure its functionality is good to go.</p><p>More importantly, the publication notes the existence of Google-created smoke and CO sensors under the "Nest" moniker. However, consumers with them can only utilize their functions via the Nest app. It's speculated that the app's hidden code could indicate upcoming integration between the Nest app and Google Home. If true, that would remove the necessity for this additional app and bring everything under the Home app's roof.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="ZWHDeZvTzDtWRXULrccVB5" name="google-home-app-favorites-02.jpg" alt="Viewing favorite devices in the Google Home app in 2024" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZWHDeZvTzDtWRXULrccVB5.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Consumers are undoubtedly familiar with the term "Matter," the new industry connectivity standard for linking smart home devices. In 2022, Google boarded the Matter train with the Home app as it <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/google-nest-matter-rollout-android-fast-pair">rolled out support</a> for the Home Mini, Hub Max, Wifi Pro, and Nest Audio. The company then expanded support for more smart home devices and brands.</p><p>It's not specifically mentioned that these air quality sensors will be wrapped in the Matter standard, but it's possible. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/matter-1-2-upgrade-details">Matter 1.2 upgrade</a> includes smoke and CO detector support as the CSA honed in reducing the amount of app "hubs" consumers need to control their devices. It's likely that Google's potential inclusion of its smoke and CO sensors <em>within </em>the Home app — not in a separate Nest app — will continue that "centralized hub" idea.</p><p>Unfortunately, without more concrete evidence, it's unclear if/when Google will roll this out. The post wonders if the company has a "future Nest Protect" in the pipeline for this support, but that's just speculation for now.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/google-home-tipped-co-smoke-sensor-support-integration</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google could incorporate CO sensor support into its Home app following a code discovery. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Sa9ECEGfA2gXtBx2fE9MX3</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qFAnemALauEPxVzPudvWw3.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 19:52:55 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Smart Home]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qFAnemALauEPxVzPudvWw3.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A Nest Protect illuminated in a dark hallway]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A Nest Protect illuminated in a dark hallway]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Android 16 could borrow this key feature from Windows 11 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Currently, the user-interface for switching audio inputs in Android is disjointed and varies on a per-app basis, or is absent altogether in some instances.</li><li>Android 16 could make the operating system more consistent by introducing a system-wide audio switcher.</li><li>The new UI interface, still in its early stages, would make Android 16 behave more like Windows 11.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Android might be taking a few notes from Windows 11. Google may be prepping an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16">Android 16</a> feature that introduces a system-wide audio switcher that, among other things, would make it possible to use an external microphone input in any Android app.</p><p>Mishaal Rahman discovered code in the latest <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-qpr1-beta-3-bluetooth-foldable-update">Android 15 QPR1 Beta 3</a> release that adds an audio input section to the current switcher that has been a staple since Android 11 (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/android-16-audio-input-switcher-3498579/" target="_blank">Android Authority</a>). Rahman managed to activate this feature, and you can see how it'll look in Android 16 in the screenshots below.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4480px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="z72YD7uHDH6FUU4SzzByCY" name="Microphone-Android-16-Settings" alt="The new audio switcher in Android 16." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/z72YD7uHDH6FUU4SzzByCY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4480" height="2520" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Mishaal Rahman / Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The first screenshot depicts how apps that support external microphones in Android 15 handle input switching. It requires the app developer to use the <strong>MediaRecorder API</strong>, and few apps support it. That's why an input switcher in Android's system-wide media dialog would be useful, but as the second screenshot shows, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a> currently only supports changing audio output. The final, far-right screenshot serves as an example of how audio switching might work in Android 16, which could add a separate section for changing your audio input.</p><p>Rahman notes that although the Android 16 media switcher was visible, it didn't work properly. Changing the system audio input didn't allow the use of an external microphone on an Android phone. Since the early version of the dialog references "<strong>This computer</strong>" instead of "This phone," Rahman suspects that this feature is designed specifically for PCs that run Android.</p><p>Being that Android 16 is quite far away, it's unclear whether this version of the media switcher will make it into the update's public release, or which devices will be supported. System-wide support of external microphones would be extremely helpful for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-tablets">high-end tablets</a> and PCs that run Android, and slightly less so for phones. However, a default switcher would eliminate the need for developers to use the MediaRecorder API, thus making the experience of using external audio inputs on the platform more consistent and streamlined.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16-could-borrow-this-key-feature-from-windows-11</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Switching between default audio inputs and outputs could be easier on Android, and the next update might address that.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">vYc7gZ6VdapcjWob6Kmxpg</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JtT6RUBnjWdpzsRzAkLpwS.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 18:38:46 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JtT6RUBnjWdpzsRzAkLpwS.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Pixel 9 Pro XL home page showing icons]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Pixel 9 Pro XL home page showing icons]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung might've clued us into the Galaxy S25 launch timeframe ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A user posted a screenshot of a recently received Samsung survey about its promotional run for the Galaxy S25.</li><li>The form states those who complete it will receive a "10% discount" on the Galaxy S25 on "January 5," potentially indicating an earlier launch timeline.</li><li>Oddly enough, the date marks a Sunday, though this could coincide with another expected announcement: the Galaxy S25 Reserve Program.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>We're eager for Samsung's next flagship series, but a rather innocent survey might be more important than we realize.</p><p>The Korean OEM was reportedly sending consumer surveys to random customers, as spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/pnk505/status/1856291194323767662">IMEI Pham</a> on X (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidpolice.com/leaked-samsung-galaxy-s25-release-date/">Android Police</a>). According to the post, the survey asked the user (in Vietnamese) about the "promotional" aspect of Samsung's upcoming Galaxy S25 series. The survey's introduction detailed the reward for users who complete the survey, which might've leaked its launch timeframe.</p><p>For completing the survey, the company states consumers will receive a "10% discount" on the Galaxy S25 series on "January 5." This January date reportedly concerns when Samsung will kickstart its "pre-orders."</p><p>This is a strange date considering January 5, 2025 is a Sunday. It's highly unlikely Samsung is gearing up for a weekend debut as the Galaxy S24 series was announced on January 17, which was a Wednesday. However, this discount delivery date <em>could </em>coincide with a more expected occurrence: Samsung's Reserve Program.</p><p>In January, the company kickstarted its Galaxy S24 Reserve Program <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-unpacked-galaxy-ai-january-confirmed">roughly two weeks <em>before</em></a><em> </em>the series launched during Unpacked. This seems plausible for the S25 series since Samsung started informing users about its 2024 phones shortly after New Year's Day.</p><p>As always, we'll have to wait and see what Samsung does when the time comes.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Galaxy S25 series will launch on Jan 5th, according from an online survey to customer about promotion when it ready to pre-order pic.twitter.com/SGmM3NNQho<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1856291194323767662">November 12, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>Galaxy S25 leaks have continuously surfaced regarding Samsung's alleged changes to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-leaked-renders-reveal-flat-design">make them flatter</a>.</p><p>A recent wave of leaks claimed to have narrowed down the company's potential <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-series-color-options-tipped">assortment of colors</a>. A post stated the Galaxy S25 could debut in Moon Night Blue, Silver Shadow, Sparkling Blue, and Sparkling Green colors. The Galaxy S25 Ultra could grab the unsurprising Titanium Black, Blue, Gray, and Silver options. Moreover, the post speculated that Samsung could stick with the same M13 OLED panel featured on the Galaxy S24 Ultra for the S25 version.</p><p>Supposedly, this could be done with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/DSCCRoss/status/1849655264984826017">consumers in mind</a> as upgrading to the M14 variant could "raise costs."</p><p>Another rumor claimed Samsung could <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-seamless-update-support-rumor">finally bring A/B seamless updates</a> to the Galaxy S25 series. The company notably skipped its flagship series with this function as it only provided such a feature to the Galaxy A55. Google started pushing for OEMs to adopt and implement the A/B update method on devices due to its less disruptive behavior. Users can continue playing with their phones while it downloads an update on a separate partition.</p><p>Once done, your device will prompt users to restart the phone as soon as possible to install the update. Google made <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-phones-system-updates-install-now-faster">these updates faster</a>, meaning they could download in as little as ten minutes.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-survey-galaxy-s25-launch-timeframe-rumors</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A user posted snapshots of a Samsung survey that might allude to the Galaxy S25's launch. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">MaUyvheNpGwivnimp3AdXV</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vVr5SJya6AsngNZWexn7Qi.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 18:34:39 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vVr5SJya6AsngNZWexn7Qi.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Hands-on with the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Hands-on with the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Break your Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold main screen? A replacement costs the price of a new phone ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-32">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>iFixit is now selling replacement parts and tools for the Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold, a large foldable retailing for $1,799.</li><li>The genuine Pixel 9 Pro Fold main screen costs $1,199, which is the same price as a brand-new iPhone 16 Pro Max and is more expensive than the Pixel 9 Pro XL.</li><li>With that being said, other components are available at a more reasonable price, like the Pixel 9 Pro Fold's batteries.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google and iFixit have <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-wants-to-design-pixel-phones-to-be-repairable-without-special-tools">partnered to deliver parts, tools, and repair guides</a> for Pixel phones, and they have finally become available for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-fold-review">Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold</a>. While the rest of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9">Google Pixel 9 series</a> received parts, tools, and guides months ago, the Pixel 9 Pro Fold model was the last phone to receive the same treatment. Naturally, parts for the $1,799 foldable were going to be expensive, but we didn't know exactly <em>how</em> pricey they'd be until now.</p><p>First spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/11/11/pixel-9-pro-fold-screen-repair/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a>, iFixit now has a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.ifixit.com/Parts/Google_Pixel_9_Pro_Fold" target="_blank">page</a> listing all 28 genuine parts and components you can buy for your Pixel 9 Pro Fold. With step-by-step repair guides, the idea is that anyone can do it — although some of the most intensive repairs have over 100 steps and require hours of labor. The parts are available as single units or as "fix kits," which include all the tools required to complete the repair.</p><p>The listing page on iFixit is live, but not all parts are available for purchase. The Pixel 9 Pro Fold's main screen, for example, costs $1,199 and is currently "out of stock." The 8-inch inner screen is arguably the most important part of the device. It includes the screen, but also the metal frame and hinge that holds the Pixel 9 Pro Fold together. That's probably why the part itself costs the same as a brand-new iPhone 16 Pro Max, more than a Pixel 9 Pro XL, and just under the price of a Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4480px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="xUFYhhaa2wpUj4RnWCa2xX" name="iFixit-Pixel-9-Pro-Fold-Screen" alt="The front and back of the Pixel 9 Pro Fold display on iFixit." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xUFYhhaa2wpUj4RnWCa2xX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4480" height="2520" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central / iFixit)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Regardless of the reason for the price, the high cost makes repairing the Pixel 9 Pro Fold a tough sell for customers. For reference, the original Pixel Fold's inner screen costs $899 as a replacement part. Now that the main screen costs more than half the cost of a Pixel 9 Pro Fold, it's likely that buyers consider purchasing a new device rather than spend time and an exorbitant amount of money repairing the one they already own.</p><p>It's not all bleak, though. Many of the Pixel 9 Pro Fold's replacement parts are reasonably priced, like the batteries. The base battery costs $66 for the fix kit, which is an insane value considering all it includes:</p>
<ul><li>New Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold Base Battery</li><li>Rear Cover Adhesive</li><li>Front Camera Foam</li><li>Graphite Sheet</li><li>mmWave Bracket</li><li>mmWave Bracket Foam</li><li>Loudspeaker Cable Adhesive</li><li>Loudspeaker Adhesive</li><li>Loudspeaker Top Conductive Fabric</li><li>Base Battery Adhesive</li><li>Loudspeaker Bottom Conductive Fabric</li><li>Charging Assembly Adhesive</li><li>iFixit Thermal Paste</li><li>Alcohol Pad</li><li>Plastic Dropper</li><li>iOpener</li><li>iFixit Opening Picks (Set of 6)</li><li>Spudger</li><li>iFixit Opening Tool</li><li>Suction Handle</li><li>Angled Tweezers</li><li>Blunt Tweezers</li><li>Precision Bit Driver</li><li>4 mm Precision Bits:<ul><li>Phillips #00</li><li>Torx T3</li><li>Torx T5</li></ul></li></ul>
<p>The flip battery is available for the same price, and oddly enough, it costs a dollar more to buy the each battery without the fix kit.</p><p>The high cost of genuine Pixel 9 Pro Fold parts might make Google Preferred Care, a device insurance plan, more enticing. One thing's for sure: you really don't want to break your Pixel 9 Pro Fold's inner screen.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/break-your-google-pixel-9-pro-fold-main-screen-a-replacement-costs-the-price-of-a-new-phone</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ iFixit is now selling replacement parts for the Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold, and they're sure to hurt your wallet. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">foEDyTQUba2VpxJ4ccNAzM</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7rjDMuoASB4nmdPX5tR2p7.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 17:50:55 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7rjDMuoASB4nmdPX5tR2p7.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold with Pixel Watch 3 and Pixel Buds Pro 2 in leaves]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold with Pixel Watch 3 and Pixel Buds Pro 2 in leaves]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Nothing Phone 2a gets its second taste of Android 15 beta ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-37">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The second Android 15 beta for Nothing Phone 2a brings bug fixes, performance tweaks, and introduces the "Shared Widgets" feature in Nothing OS 3.0.</li><li>"Shared Widgets" allows syncing widgets across devices, but it's still in the works.</li><li>For now, you can pair widgets with friends and family (who also have a Nothing phone) and share reactions and stickers.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>A fresh Android 15 beta is rolling out to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/nothing-phone-2a-review">Nothing Phone 2a</a>, bringing bug fixes, performance tweaks, and the new "Shared Widgets" feature in Nothing OS 3.0.</p><p>While Nothing OS 3.0 is getting closer to its full release, there’s still one big feature missing. When Nothing first teased its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a> plans, it hinted at "Shared Widgets," a new way to sync homescreen widgets across multiple devices.</p><p>You’ll be able to "pair" widgets with your friends and family, as long as they’ve got a Nothing phone too. One widget even lets you share reactions and stickers.</p><p>Yet, this feature hasn’t shown up yet on the Phone 2a, until now. This feature is now live in the second Android 15 beta for Nothing's latest <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-android-phones">mid-range phone</a> (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/11/12/nothing-phone-2a-android-15-beta-2-widgets/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a>).</p><p>The Shared Widgets feature first landed on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/nothing-phone-2-review">Phone 2</a> with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/nothing-phone-2-android-15-open-beta-start-detailed">start of Nothing’s Android 15 Open Beta earlier this month</a>.</p><p>Nothing has been on point with its Android 15 rollout, following the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/nothing-phone-2a-android-15-open-beta-start">release schedule it shared back in October</a>. The company has already rolled out Nothing OS 3.0 to the Phone 2 and Phone 2a, just as promised.</p><p>At first, Shared Widgets will offer the basics, mostly letting you share reactions between connected devices. But Nothing has big plans to take this feature to the next level down the line.</p><p>This update also tweaks the new Quick Settings and Smart Drawer features, and brings fixes for some bugs in the camera app.</p><p>Photography lovers will also be happy with this update, which brings better brightness in Ultra HDR and standard HDR, an optimized portrait mode, and smoother camera mode switching.</p><p>As with any beta, there could be some unexpected quirks, but this update is a big step forward. If you've got a compatible Nothing phone, you can check out the new beta on Nothing's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://nothing.community/d/17516-nothing-os-30-phone-2a-open-beta/858" target="_blank">website</a>.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-nothing-phone-2a-gets-its-second-taste-of-android-15-beta</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Phone 2a gets a new Android 15 beta with shared widgets. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">3wMnBHFw4Ssp28qBC35D38</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/s9uog29bNh6SkAxhM6eyJL.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 17:29:56 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/s9uog29bNh6SkAxhM6eyJL.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Nothing Phone (2a) with the stock glass red wallpaper]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Nothing Phone (2a) with the stock glass red wallpaper]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ EcoFlow is switching lanes with the tiny Rapid Magnetic Power Bank ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Gadget Weekly</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="DZLQ4jKZk9tEF5A3sqU5Jh" name="inspector-lloyd-square.jpg" caption="" alt="Inspector Lloyd" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DZLQ4jKZk9tEF5A3sqU5Jh.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">Join Namerah Saud Fatmi as she explores the cool, quirky, and sometimes downright odd world of smartphone accessories, gadgets, and other nerdy toys <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/gadget-weekly">every week</a>.</p></div></div>
<p>EcoFlow has done exceedingly well with its versatile array of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-portable-power-stations">portable power stations</a> and power kits. Our reviewers have always found the brand's products to be top-tier, especially the large-and-in-charge <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/ecoflow-delta-pro-review">EcoFlow Delta Pro</a>, and more recently, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/ecoflow-river-2-max-review">EcoFlow River 2 Max</a>. It seems that EcoFlow is now switching lanes and pivoting to smaller, more pocket-sized power solutions with its new launches.</p><p>The company just launched its first MagSafe and Qi2-compatible power bank called the EcoFlow Rapid Magnetic Power Bank (5000mAh). It's nice to EcoFlow try its hand at something different, especially because the on-paper specs look very attractive.</p><p>Other products released alongside the EcoFlow Rapid include a few USB-C chargers and the usual power stations and kits. The magnetic power bank stood out to me, so I decided to test it out for myself.</p>

<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4032px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="NPYtQVoJvScJzoHh6xucxC" name="EcoFlow-RAPID-Magnetic-Power-Bank-5000mAh-3.jpg" alt="EcoFlow RAPID Magnetic Power Bank (5000mAh)" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NPYtQVoJvScJzoHh6xucxC.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4032" height="2268" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>My go-to portable power bank is a credit card-sized one from Zendure. Ever since I got it last year, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/dont-sleep-on-these-zendure-charging-accessories-during-black-friday">Zendure SuperMini</a> has been in my purse and has traveled to at least three countries with me. Although I am really fond of my Zendure SuperMini, the 10,000mAh battery pack is heavier than it looks, which isn't ideal for portability.</p><p>So, I ditched the Zendure in favor of the EcoFlow Rapid Magnetic Power Bank for a weekend trip. Since I carry at least two phones with me at all times, having access to a power bank on the go is crucial for me. That said, swapping a generous 10,000mAh power bank for a 5,000mAh one made me nervous because it can only recharge one phone fully on a single charge.</p><p>However, I soon realized that you probably don't really need much more than a 5,000mAh power bank. Most people with regular jobs carry a single phone. Even if you carry two phones, you probably charge them fully before heading out or will likely only find yourself needing to charge one while you're out and about. That's what I do, as it makes sense to be prudent and reduces potential hassle.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4032px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="7m82cmrJyUJhbYJfTsbrjE" name="EcoFlow-RAPID-Magnetic-Power-Bank-5000mAh-7.jpg" alt="EcoFlow RAPID Magnetic Power Bank (5000mAh)" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7m82cmrJyUJhbYJfTsbrjE.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4032" height="2268" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The EcoFlow Rapid Magnetic Power Bank might have a smaller battery capacity, but it brings several key advantages in exchange for that sacrifice. A big pro is the built-in USB-C cable. This instantly reduced clutter in my purse as I didn't have to carry a cable.</p><p>You get a decent 30W wired charging speed with the built-in Type-C cable, which is more than enough juice for my <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-review">Pixel 8</a>. Most power banks this small usually only support around 20W wired charging speeds. For example, the Anker 633 Magnetic Battery only supports 20W charging.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4032px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="hJdUoTTXo7EkwA6ieXZG5E" name="EcoFlow-RAPID-Magnetic-Power-Bank-5000mAh-5.jpg" alt="EcoFlow RAPID Magnetic Power Bank (5000mAh)" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hJdUoTTXo7EkwA6ieXZG5E.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4032" height="2268" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It has a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/everything-you-need-know-about-usb-c">USB-C</a> port on the side for power input, which is also a speedy 30W, so you can recharge it quickly. There are LED indicators on the back to let you know how much power is left in the power bank and whether it is charging. And if you want to forgo the cable entirely, the EcoFlow Rapid Magnetic Power Bank also supports 15W Qi2 and MagSafe wireless charging. You can also charge two devices at once, one via cable and the other wirelessly.</p><p>The power bank's magnetism works in its favor in more than one way. Of course, it helps to align the wireless charging coils and keeps them in place. But it also acts as a grip to hold your phone when the EcoFlow Rapid's clip-shaped kickstand is in use. The kickstand can be used in both portrait and landscape orientations.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4032px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="HkmZZSzZVJnurWyxehS9KD" name="EcoFlow-RAPID-Magnetic-Power-Bank-5000mAh-2.jpg" alt="EcoFlow RAPID Magnetic Power Bank (5000mAh)" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HkmZZSzZVJnurWyxehS9KD.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4032" height="2268" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4032px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="2q58TyXQNFqqHyKLReHfgD" name="EcoFlow-RAPID-Magnetic-Power-Bank-5000mAh-4.jpg" alt="EcoFlow RAPID Magnetic Power Bank (5000mAh)" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2q58TyXQNFqqHyKLReHfgD.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4032" height="2268" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3499px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="pezd5gwHRQWbbujUNX4MPE" name="EcoFlow-RAPID-Magnetic-Power-Bank-5000mAh-6.jpg" alt="EcoFlow RAPID Magnetic Power Bank (5000mAh)" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pezd5gwHRQWbbujUNX4MPE.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="3499" height="1968" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>EcoFlow did a good job with the design. The mix of gray, ash, and silver hues combined with different textures looks awesome and it's functional too. Thanks to the blend of different materials used to make the EcoFlow Rapid Magnetic Power Bank, it has an anti-slip base that prevents your phone from slipping when propped up.</p><p>Another cool thing about the compact design is that the EcoFlow Rapid Magnetic Power Bank is just as small as popular alternatives like the Zendure SuperMini but weighs next to nothing in comparison. Of course, you only get half the power, which is a factor to consider.</p><p>I'm excited to know that EcoFlow will soon release a 10,000mAh version of this brilliant little magnetic power bank. I just hope it retains the size and doesn't add too much weight compared to the 5,000mAh variant. It is still a good buy, although the $69.99 price tag is a little steep.</p><p>Frugal buyers could wait until November 21 to take advantage of the early Black Friday sale, which EcoFlow has already announced on its website. The EcoFlow Rapid Magnetic Power Bank (5000mAh) is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://us.ecoflow.com/products/rapid-magnetic-power-bank">slated to go on sale for $39.99</a> once the deal goes live. Now that would make this already great purchase an absolute steal.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="5e7d16aa-31bb-4073-a7df-458a5364477f">
            <a href="https://us.ecoflow.com/products/rapid-magnetic-power-bank" data-model-name="EcoFlow RAPID Magnetic Power Bank 5000mAh"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dvSenGbk4Ngg3F82h488x8.jpg' alt="EcoFlow RAPID Magnetic Power Bank (5000mAh)"></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">EcoFlow RAPID Magnetic Power Bank (5000mAh)</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="90" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Smol bebe</strong></em></p><p>The EcoFlow RAPID Magnetic Power Bank (5000mAh) is a stylishly slim power bank with plenty more to offer beyond just looks. You get 30W wired charging, a built-in USB-C cable, 15W wireless magnetic charging, and a nifty little kickstand to boot.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/ecoflow-rapid-magnetic-power-bank-5000mah</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ EcoFlow, a famous power solutions' brand is trying its hand in the portable power bank department. It's a valiant first try. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">WW4JWa7gXMAm9ZjVnbJzhj</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TbZE5tQNkXHZmz9AAEEobC.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 17:19:58 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TbZE5tQNkXHZmz9AAEEobC.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[EcoFlow RAPID Magnetic Power Bank (5000mAh)]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[EcoFlow RAPID Magnetic Power Bank (5000mAh)]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>