<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 16:46:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung might drop a thinner, lighter Galaxy S25 Ultra next year ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A new rumor claims Samsung is working on a "thinner and lighter" Galaxy S25 Ultra that will beat out its previous Ultra model devices.</li><li>Without getting specific, the tipster claims the S25 Ultra will beat Google's Pixel 9 Pro XL and Apple's next iPhone 16 Pro Max in those respective areas.</li><li>Following the rumors, there were concerns about the device's battery and whether or not Samsung would change its materials to enable a large capacity in a smaller space.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Rumors continue to swirl about the Galaxy S25 Ultra as the latest speculates about some key changes.</p><p>A post on X from known tipster <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/UniverseIce/status/1828698013243769173">Ice Universe</a> claims that Samsung is working to build the "thinnest and lightest" Ultra model phone with the S25 Ultra (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidheadlines.com/2024/08/galaxy-s25-ultra-thinner-lighter-than-iphone-16-pro-max.html">Android Headlines</a>). According to the post, the device will feature specifications in those areas that may rival Google&apos;s Pixel 9 Pro XL and Apple&apos;s upcoming iPhone 16 Pro Max.</p><p>The post didn&apos;t go into specifics; however, the publication notes that Google&apos;s recent <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-series-hands-on">Pixel 9 Pro XL</a> weighs 221 grams. If Samsung is truly going for "lighter," then that&apos;s where things begin and not the 232 grams of the S24 Ultra. Moreover, the Pro XL measures 8.5mm in thickness while the S24 Ultra is 8.6mm.</p><p>This fact (and rumor) has sparked some curiosity from consumers with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/Urban_el_soul_2/status/1828698268454236305">one comment</a> wondering if there will be a battery swap. Samsung&apos;s current flagship Ultra offers a 5,000mAh battery, leaving the user to wonder if the next will utilize a silicon battery to keep it thin, yet powerful.</p><p>Elsewhere, Ice Universe <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://m.weibo.cn/detail/5071601329242163">took to Weibo</a> to post a couple of supposed renderings of the S25 Ultra (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/08/28/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-design-note/">9to5Google</a>). The imagery seemingly doubles down on what we&apos;ve seen previously as the device could sport slightly slimmer bezels and rounded corners instead of ones that dig into your palm.</p><p>Unfortunately, the brief side view of the device doesn&apos;t offer much in terms of the tipster&apos;s recently proposed "thinness."</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">The S25 Ultra will be the thinnest and lightest of all Ultra flagship phones to be released soon, including iPhone 16 Pro Max and Pixel 9 Pro XL.<a href="https://twitter.com/UniverseIce/status/1828698013243769173">August 28, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>Samsung was (unsurprisingly) <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsungs-galaxy-s25-ultra-wont-probably-blow-your-mind-with-its-battery-life">rumored to continue</a> to feature a 5,000mAh battery inside the Galaxy S25 Ultra. With reports claiming that the company plans to go thinner and concerns about its battery, it makes us think back to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-introduces-new-glacier-battery-featuring-6100mah">Glacier battery</a> from OnePlus. The Chinese OEM highlighted the new technology in June as it worked to pop a 6,100mAh battery into the Ace 3 Pro.</p><p>OnePlus used silicon-carbon material to keep the battery "smaller than the conventional 5,000mAh batteries found in most <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phones</a>." Of course, deciding to change the R&D behind the battery of the S25 Ultra will depend on <em>how </em>thin Samsung plans to go — if this is happening.</p><p>Another recent Galaxy S25 Ultra rumor suggested that it will feature a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-s25-ultra-narrow-body-frame-rumors">narrower aspect ratio</a>. This would join the alleged shift to rounded corners instead of squared ones, as Samsung may look to improve the one-handed experience of its top model.</p><p>It was also suggested that a few name changes could befall the S25 Ultra and S25 Plus, but that&apos;s still in the air.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-thinnest-lightest-model-rumor</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A rumor claimed that Samsung is working to create a thin and light Galaxy S25 Ultra. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Af5zWLyKdDsWyzLmKzqXkK</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YEvRkm3AKzKNVWSMzh3gZM.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 16:43:48 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YEvRkm3AKzKNVWSMzh3gZM.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[null]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The back of the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra in the Titanium Grey colorway]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The back of the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra in the Titanium Grey colorway]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ My favorite Dreamcast-era gaming trend is making a surprising comeback ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>When the Dreamcast came out in the Fall of 1999, most people were enamored with Soul Caliber&apos;s mind-blowing visuals and the fact that Sega eclipsed EA&apos;s long-running Madden series with a single release. But while I certainly enjoyed hours of Soul Caliber, I spent <em>hundreds</em> of hours breeding and evolving Chaos, cute little virtual pets cleverly hidden in Sonic Adventure&apos;s Chao Garden. And 25 years later, virtual pets are making a major comeback in new and interesting ways.</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">AC thVRsday</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="LGmZZrc8DWcxmZm6RRUYbC" name="ac-thvrsday-logo.jpg" caption="" alt="AC thVRsday logo" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LGmZZrc8DWcxmZm6RRUYbC.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">In his <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/ac-thvrsday">weekly column</a>, Android Central Senior Content Producer Nick Sutrich delves into all things VR, from new hardware to new games, upcoming technologies, and so much more.</p></div></div>
<p>The experience was made even better by the fact that I could put my Chaos on the Dreamcast&apos;s Visual Memory Unit—VMU for short—and take them along with me for the day. I spent more than a few hours earning points to further evolve my pets during many of my 8th grade classes, and later that year, Sega would release Seaman—one of the weirdest virtual pets of all time—that you could talk to (and would talk back to you) via a controller-mounted microphone. They&apos;re still some of my favorite gaming memories of all time.</p><p>Fast forward more than two decades and Sega might be a shell of its former self, but virtual pets are just as popular as they were back in the days of the Tamagotchi. The folks behind the ever-popular Pokemon Go, Niantic, released <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.nianticlabs.peridot">Peridot</a> last year and recently came out with a VR tie-in called <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.meta.com/en-gb/experiences/hello-dot/25825290007070369/">Hello Dot</a> on the Meta Quest, letting you play with your virtual pets in a palpable new way.</p><p>And some of the folks behind Job Simulator and Vacation Simulator are bringing modern LLM-based AI engines to NPCs and even virtual pets. That means the era of getting Leonard Nimoy to record hundreds or thousands of voice lines—as Sega did with Seaman—is no longer necessary. Virtual pets are back, and I couldn&apos;t be happier about it.</p>
<h2 id="give-me-a-pet-2">Give me a pet</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1440px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="9mwiYgFE3PmjT6XSAJDd5P" name="hello-dot-screenshot-01.jpg" alt="An official screenshot of someone playing with a Dot in Hello, Dot on a Meta Quest 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9mwiYgFE3PmjT6XSAJDd5P.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1440" height="810" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Niantic)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>My renewed interest in virtual pets began when my then-8-year-old son got a Tamagotchi for Christmas. A year later, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.meta.com/en-gb/experiences/neko-atsume-purrfect-kitty-collector/8401739766534648/">Neko Atsume Kitty Collector</a> made its mixed reality debut right after the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-3">Meta Quest 3</a> came out, and it had me dreaming of taking virtual pets on the go throughout the day and then coming home to play with them in VR.</p><p>That&apos;s where Peridot and Hello Dot come in. I reached out to Asim Ahmed, the global product marketing leader at Niantic, to find out more about the company&apos;s goals for Peridot and Hello Dot and whether the company was planning to further integrate both games into a cohesive virtual pet ecosystem.</p><p>I was elated with what I found out.</p><p>While most of Niantic&apos;s games are focused on getting people to "get outside more and explore the world around them," as Ahmed put it, Peridot does things a little differently. There&apos;s still that classic Niantic formula that&apos;s been around since the Ingress days where you&apos;re encouraged to walk around in the real world and discover new virtual creatures and items, but Peridot blends the real and virtual worlds in a way the company hasn&apos;t pushed since the original Pokemon Go days: through your smartphone&apos;s camera.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/f54R7_jR1To" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>Peridot uses your phone&apos;s spatial understanding of the real world to make it look like your virtual pet is walking alongside you but is only viewable through the magic window of your phone. When you&apos;re out and about, Peridot encourages you to take out your phone and let you play with your pet no matter where you&apos;re at, and new places might reveal new items or new evolutions you haven&apos;t seen before.</p><p>Imagine, then, what&apos;s going to happen with this when Google and Magic Leap <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/google-magic-leap-partnership">launch their first pair</a> of Android XR-based smart glasses, and you no longer have to hold a device to see your pet? You&apos;d have them with you all day instead of only when you remember to pull out your phone and launch the app.</p><p>In a way, Rec Room&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=clY7421VdDw">My Little Monsters update</a> already does this, but in a roundabout way. Rec Room is one of the most popular multiplayer VR games available, but it helps boost popularity by allowing non-VR players to join in on the fun. That means you can grow and evolve your pet on the go and then play around with them in VR when you get home. But it&apos;s a little more involved than what I&apos;m hoping a true Chao Garden successor will bring.</p><p>For now, Hello Dot is probably the closest thing I can get, but its early state is a bit of a barebones experience that&apos;s mostly fun to play for a few minutes at a time. It&apos;s the same basic gameplay loop as Peridot but offers a far more immersive way to interact with them. Instead of just tapping your phone&apos;s screen to pet them, you can actually reach down and pat their head, stroke their chin, or even pick them up for a cuddle.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>If virtual pets have gotten this good, wait until we have proper AR glasses and can have our passively meander around with us all day.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>Until Hello Dot and Neko Atsume, few games gave you the ability to do this. Most of the time, that restriction was simply because the pet was trapped inside some kind of electronic device. In a way, this is still the same restriction—the difference is that it feels more real to your brain because you can naturally move and interact with it as if it were real.</p><p>Ironically, given Niantic&apos;s penchant for getting folks outdoors, Hello Dot and Peridot don&apos;t have a good way to let you take your pet on the go—not yet, anyway. Ahmed says Niantic has a full roadmap for Hello Dot, hoping to build the game&apos;s future together with the mobile version, Peridot, creating new ways to interact with virtual pets not seen before.</p>
<h2 id="the-next-evolution-2">The next evolution</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="7JWiESfcy3qUFucqsB3DYH" name="peridot-oneplus-12.jpg" alt="Playing Peridot on a OnePlus 12" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7JWiESfcy3qUFucqsB3DYH.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While virtual pets almost always "evolve" to the next level instead of growing like normal real-life pets, the way we interact with virtual pets hasn&apos;t evolved since the 1990s. Tamagotchi let you care for your pet on the go, while games like Creatures on the PC gave players a far more detailed world to play around in. But we&apos;ve always been stuck clicking or tapping to interact with them.</p><p>That&apos;s all about to change with the advent of companies like AstroBeam, which are using the power of LLM-based AI engines so that in-game NPCs—short for non-player characters—feel more like interacting with real humans or creatures.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">The future of NPCs is coming! Introducing our multiplayer LLM powered NPCs. Multiple people can chat and interact with the same NPC in VR, in real-time! pic.twitter.com/A3dpxGRNoQ<a href="https://twitter.com/AstroBeamHQ/status/1826647309767336409">August 22, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>Using LLM-based AI models to power NPC interactions isn&apos;t something extraordinarily new—Skyrim players have been using ChatGPT to make smarter NPCs <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/virtualreality/comments/159n5b8/these_new_llm_ai_mods_for_skyrimvr_are_insane_you/">for over a year now</a>—but AstroBeam aims to take this concept and use it to make multiplayer games feel fuller.</p><p>I spoke with Devin Reimer, the founder of AstroBeam, prior CEO of Owlchemy Labs, and one of the brains behind Job Simulator, to find out more about how the paradigm of NPCs is about to change.</p><p>As Reimer puts it, the current way of implementing ChatGPT-style AI models into NPCs in existing games largely feels awkward and "really horrible." A big part of this is that, while it&apos;s cool to hear an NPC respond in what feels like a strangely intelligent human way, most implementations lack one key expectation: actions.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>Modern AI can redefine how we interact with characters in video games, including more natural speech, more believable responses, and better emotions.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>That&apos;s because all of these implementations are mods of existing games rather than games designed from the ground up with AI implementations. Reimer describes the work his company is doing as similar in concept to how Job Simulator was created.</p><p>"Early in VR, the first stuff that is tried is &apos;let&apos;s take what we currently have and jam them together&apos;...but it turned out that almost everything that was successful was built from the ground up for VR."</p><p>Talking to our phones or computers has yet to feel like talking to a person, but Reimer seems to believe that this can change with realistic reactions, movements, and contextual actions and responses—particularly when presented in VR. He points out how the robot in the video example above not only looks at the person it&apos;s talking to but also uses hand gestures and other expressions to make it feel "right."</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>Talking to our phones or computers has yet to feel like talking to a person, but Reimer seems to believe that this can change with realistic reactions, movements, and contextual actions and responses—particularly when presented in VR.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>When I think about the hours I spent on the Dreamcast version of Seaman, one of the most impressive (and disturbing) things about it was the emotional responses the fish-men delivered while talking to them. Of course, the game didn&apos;t really "understand" what I was saying in a human way; it was mostly looking for keywords to respond to in order to fake a human-like response.</p><p>What&apos;s better at that sort of thing than modern AI? Nothing to date, of course! LLMs like Google Gemini have proven to be able to understand not only what we say to it <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/google-project-starline-astra-ar-glasses">but also drawings</a> and things it can see through cameras. Imagine then how much better the concept of a virtual pet could be if it could actually understand you.</p><p>I don&apos;t need my pet to talk back to me like the fish do in Seaman, but how cool would it be if it could understand more than basic commands and, instead, evolve to understand language to the fullest extent? That&apos;s the real next generation of virtual pets, without a doubt.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/virtual-pets-in-the-era-of-ai</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Virtual pets were all the rage in the 1990s, but while the trend took a back seat for a few decades, AI and VR are giving it new life and evolving it in wonderful ways. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">brXquvTDcNVkrsRgc5NtoX</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mNXePRnWH978mHzyMTiM7T.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 16:07:44 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mNXePRnWH978mHzyMTiM7T.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Holding a Sega Dreamcast VMU with Chao Adventure on it]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Holding a Sega Dreamcast VMU with Chao Adventure on it]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Labor Day deal slashes $200 OFF the Galaxy S24 Plus at Best Buy — but for how long? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Samsung Galaxy phone deals are here just in time for Labor Day. For a limited time, you can get <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-s24-256gb-unlocked-onyx-black/6569843.p?skuId=6569843" target="_blank"><strong>$200 off the Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus at Best Buy</strong></a>, or $300 when you let them activate it for you. Best Buy will also give S24 Plus buyers three months free of Google One 100GB, so you can back up files, photos, email, and more.</p><p>The S24 Plus boasts a sleek design, a beautiful 6.7-inch display, and powerful cameras with a few useful Galaxy AI features. It also gives users a full day&apos;s worth of battery life, and the increase of RAM from previous models makes its performance super smooth.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="57e63bdd-dd9d-4e1b-bdf4-33330599144e" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$999.99" data-dimension48="$999.99" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-s24-256gb-unlocked-onyx-black/6569843.p?skuId=6569843" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1200px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="NqhoUu3WzqW2D7ngA6rmHK" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-render-square-crop-black.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NqhoUu3WzqW2D7ngA6rmHK.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1200" height="1200" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-s24-256gb-unlocked-onyx-black/6569843.p?skuId=6569843" target="_blank" data-dimension112="57e63bdd-dd9d-4e1b-bdf4-33330599144e" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$999.99" data-dimension48="$999.99"><del>$999.99</del> <strong>$799.99 at Best Buy</strong></a></p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-plus-review">Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus</a> is a great option for those who want premium performance but don't want to spend the extra money for the S24 Ultra. With an additional $200 off from Best Buy, it's hard to say no to the high-performance smartphone, especially if you already love the Galaxy ecosystem. Get up to $300 off when you let them activate it for you, and enjoy a free 100GB Google One subscription for three months.</p>
<p><strong>Price comparison:</strong> <a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/SAMSUNG-Galaxy-S24-Plus-Cell-Phone-256GB-AI-Smartphone-Unlocked-Android-50MP-Camera-Fastest-Processor-Long-Battery-Life-US-Version-2024-Onyx-Black/5262667714" target="_blank">Walmart - $799.00</a> | <a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Smartphone-Unlocked-Android-Processor/dp/B0CMDR2X3M" target="_blank">Amazon - $799.00</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-s24-256gb-unlocked-onyx-black/6569843.p?skuId=6569843" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="57e63bdd-dd9d-4e1b-bdf4-33330599144e" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$999.99" data-dimension48="$999.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>battery life is a priority for you when buying a phone; you&apos;re looking for an Android phone with a good camera; you want a phone with Samsung&apos;s Galaxy AI features.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>you&apos;re looking for something that&apos;s compatible with the Samsung S Pen; you prefer a small, lightweight phone; you have extra money to spend and would rather upgrade to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review">S24 Ultra</a>.</p><p>The Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus is a worthy upgrade from past models, offering 12GB of RAM instead of 8GB for a really great performance experience. Even when using power-intensive AI features, multi-tasking apps, or playing games, users report little to no lag. It&apos;s also well-liked for its photo and video capabilities, and for its large, bright display.</p><p>It also sports a full-day battery life, IP68 dust and water resistance, and the base model comes with 256GB of storage. At $200 off, what&apos;s not to like?</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/labor-day-deal-slashes-dollar200-off-the-galaxy-s24-plus-at-best-buy-but-for-how-long</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Best Buy is back with $200 off the capable Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus, or you can save even more when you let them activate it for you. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">8oQ84tvoF7wes7U2g9FG3b</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/H9uJ5yTZcUC5qbV6eB2BDK.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 15:36:38 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ zacharydvisconti@gmail.com (Zachary Visconti) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/H9uJ5yTZcUC5qbV6eB2BDK.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Tensor G4 benchmarked: Evaluating performance on the Pixel 9 and 9 Pro XL ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The Pixel 9 series sees the introduction of the Tensor G4, and it isn&apos;t markedly different to last year. Google is offering Arm&apos;s latest cores that are clocked marginally higher alongside a new Exynos modem, but other than that, you won&apos;t see any major changes in this year&apos;s silicon.</p><p>Obviously, that means the Tensor G4 is largely identical to the G3 in terms of day-to-day performance, and this is in line with my usage of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9">Pixel 9</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-review">Pixel 9 Pro XL</a>. The phones doesn&apos;t have any issues in most mundane tasks — just like the Pixel 8 series — but push the cameras or launch demanding games, and you&apos;ll see the inherent limitations of the Tensor G4.</p><p>As an overview, the G4 has a Cortex X4 core clocked at 3.1GHz, three Cortex A720 cores at 2.6GHz, and the usual set of four efficiency Cortex A520 cores that are designed to go up to 1.92GHz. It has a Mali-G715 GPU that contains six cores, and the base Pixel 9 comes with 12GB of RAM, with the Pro models getting 16GB as standard.</p><p>Annoyingly, Google decided to go with UFS 3.1 storage on all variants of the Pixel 9 series, so even if you opt for the 256GB or 512GB models, you won&apos;t get UFS 4.0 storage. This isn&apos;t a problem right now, but with these phones designed to last seven years, the move is shortsighted.</p><p>With that out of the way, let&apos;s take a look at how the Tensor G4-based Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro XL scores against their immediate rivals.</p>
<h2 id="tensor-g4-benchmarks-how-does-it-measure-up-to-the-snapdragon-8-gen-3-2">Tensor G4 benchmarks: How does it measure up to the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="pvCDAx8DLCz47TvnBWuBfP" name="pixel-9-9-pro-xl-4.jpg" alt="Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro XL next to Vivo X100 Ultra and Pixel 8 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pvCDAx8DLCz47TvnBWuBfP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I used Vivo&apos;s incredible X100 Ultra to showcase the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-3">Snapdragon 8 Gen 3</a>; it is one of the best phones I used in 2024, and comes with arguably the best overall camera package around today. Qualcomm did a great job in general with the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3, and the chipset has meaningful efficiency gains and offers a sizeable performance boost at the same time.</p>
<p>I&apos;m pitting the Pixel 9and Pixel 9 Pro XL against last year&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/i-switched-back-to-the-pixel-8-pro-and-i-couldnt-be-happier">Pixel 8 Pro</a> to highlight differences between the Tensor G4 and G3. </p>

<p>The switch to Arm&apos;s latest offerings has allowed the Tensor G4 to deliver better single results in Geekbench, but there&apos;s a clear gulf between the Pixel 9 and 9 Pro XL in this area even though they use the same silicon. Google has a tendency to set different power limits and thermal constraints on its devices, and with the Pixel 9 Pro XL getting a vapor chamber this time, that&apos;s likely the main contributor. The standard Pixel 9 misses out on the vapor chamber, with Google limiting it to the Pro models. </p><p>The Tensor G4 continues to be behind the curve when it comes to multi-core scores, and any sustained usage is throttled early. This isn&apos;t the case with devices powered by the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3, but on the upside, the Pixel 9 and 9 Pro XL don&apos;t get anywhere as hot. In fact, they recorded the lowest thermal scores of all devices I tested in 2024, and Google clearly made this a priority with the G4. </p><p>Talking about priorities, Google still doesn&apos;t care about gaming, and the Pixel 9 and 9 Pro XL don&apos;t see any meaningful changes in this area. While the Pixel 9 Pro XL had a stability score of 78.7% in 3DMark&apos;s demanding Steel Nomad Light stress test, it had the lowest scores of any flagship. </p>
<h2 id="tensor-g4-day-to-day-performance-better-than-before-with-a-gaming-caveat-2">Tensor G4 day-to-day performance: Better than before, with a gaming caveat</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="Br5AMsMAifmQ2PSg86wRqP" name="pixel-9-9-pro-xl-5.jpg" alt="Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro XL with Vivo X100 Ultra and Pixel 8 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Br5AMsMAifmQ2PSg86wRqP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While there aren&apos;t any groundbreaking features in the Tensor G4, it has a few advantages over last year&apos;s G3. The switch to the Exynos 5400 modem is a big deal, and it is noticeable in daily use. My Pixel 8 Pro consistently has issues picking up a cellular signal at home, and the low-power antenna struggles to maintain a reliable connection to the home 5GHz network.</p><p>The Pixel 9 Pro XL mitigates this issue; I had no trouble with cellular connectivity in the week I used the device, and it did much better on my home 5GHz network. That said, it still isn&apos;t on par with the Snapdragon X75 modem; all Snapdragon 8 Gen 3-powered devices delivered much better bandwidth, and had a stronger signal.</p><p>Google&apos;s latest phones are hobbled when it comes to taking photos, a routine task on most devices. While there&apos;s no shutter lag with regular shots, portrait photos take a second or two to save to the gallery, and it just isn&apos;t possible to take photos in quick succession in this mode. Again, this isn&apos;t an issue on any other high-end phone I tested in 2024, and I took thousands of portrait shots from the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oppo-find-x7-ultra-review">Find X7 Ultra</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/xiaomi-14-ultra-review">Xiaomi 14 Ultra</a>, Vivo X100 Ultra, and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12-review">OnePlus 12</a>.</p><p>The Pixel 9 Pro XL is still limited when it comes to gaming, and if anything, it tends to throttle a little sooner than its predecessor. That means you don&apos;t get consistent framerates in demanding titles, and it just doesn&apos;t measure up to the Adreno 750 — it&apos;s at least two generations behind.</p><p>That said, overheating isn&apos;t as big a problem this year, with the Pixel 9 Pro XL running cooler than the Pixel 8 Pro in the same titles. The Pixel 9 doesn&apos;t have the same benefits, and it gets warmer in extended gaming sessions — but still nowhere as much as previous generations. It looks like Google set overly aggressive power limits with the Tensor G4 to prevent overheating, and that comes at the cost of stable framerates.</p>
<h2 id="should-you-buy-the-pixel-9-2">Should you buy the Pixel 9?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="kpwXQ7avAaS9vB9H8gVcVP" name="pixel-9-9-pro-xl-3.jpg" alt="Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro XL beside Pixel 8 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kpwXQ7avAaS9vB9H8gVcVP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>After a week of use, it&apos;s clear that Google made a few welcome tweaks to the hardware. While the Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro XL still don&apos;t measure up to the likes of the X100 Ultra, they are better than previous years, and there aren&apos;t many annoyances in daily use. The biggest issue is still around gaming performance — these phones just aren&apos;t built to play visually-intensive games.</p><p>If you don&apos;t care about that, there&apos;s certainly a lot to like with the new Pixels. The build quality is much better than previous generations, and there are decent efficiency gains over the Tensor G3. Most of all, it&apos;s the AI features that give the Pixel 9 and 9 Pro XL a considerable edge over other flagships, and the cameras continue to be the most consistent of any device. </p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="b4821530-536f-444b-ae3b-7c683d98f619">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ohkjwKLGLdjmAzDvJWyXyk.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL official render - Rose Quartz - back"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 Pro XL</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>Overall, the Pixel 9 Pro XL is brilliant. The internal hardware may not be the best around, but you get terrific AI-backed utilities that make a real difference in daily use, and the cameras are great. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-tensor-g4</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Pixel 9 and 9 Pro XL are powered by the Tensor G4, and while it doesn't have many differences over last year's G3, there are a few tweaks that make a difference.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">mcyp8GTcisaskksFffAu2j</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VgH4GNj4umFySGJmenb9LP.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 07:21:18 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VgH4GNj4umFySGJmenb9LP.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro XL next to one another]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro XL next to one another]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Pixel 9 owners might not want to unlock the bootloader ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Users have started reporting experiencing problems with their Pixel 9 series device when rooting/unlocking its bootloader.</li><li>Many of Google's new AI features for the Pixel 9 stop working when one of these methods is applied to the device.</li><li>It's not clear why this is happening, though it's unfortunate, considering unlocking the bootloader and rooting a device can help solve problems users may have.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Attempting any sort of deeper customization on your Pixel 9 might result in some faulty or non-functioning features.</p><p>A few users on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://xdaforums.com/t/pixel-screenshots-other-ai-features-dont-work-with-unlocked-bl.4688190/">XDA forums</a> started a thread to mention that the Pixel 9&apos;s AI features break with an unlocked bootloader (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/pixel-ai-features-unavailable-bootloader-unlocked-3475527/">Android Authority</a>). The original poster states that Pixel Screenshots stopped working on their Pixel 9 Pro/Pro XL when using a bootloader. Instead, their device displays a persistent "downloading model" message.</p><p>The user managed to get it to work, though they had to "disable on-device AI." Pixel Weather&apos;s AI reports suffer when using an unlocked bootloader, similar to Call Notes on the latest series.</p><p>Regarding <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-pixel-studio">Pixel Studio</a>, the user states it initially displayed a "something went wrong" banner with an unlocked bootloader. However, a follow-up edit states that it <em>can </em>work, but it requires users to either "not spoof the device fingerprint with PIF or you&apos;re spoofing to an A15 Beta print for any of the Pixel 9 family devices."</p><p>One user with an unlocked and rooted Pixel 8 Pro <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://xdaforums.com/t/pixel-screenshots-other-ai-features-dont-work-with-unlocked-bl.4688190/post-89673364">reportedly got Pixel Studio to work</a>, but it didn&apos;t last long, as it soon stopped functioning.</p><p>It <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://xdaforums.com/t/pixel-screenshots-other-ai-features-dont-work-with-unlocked-bl.4688190/post-89677519">seems certain</a> that unlocking the Pixel 9&apos;s bootloader causes many of the recently described features to fail. It seems that users&apos; best bet is to lock and unroot their device if they&apos;re experiencing problems with its AI features.</p><p>Android Central has reached out to Google about these issues with an unlocked bootloader/rooting. We will update this article when we hear back.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="nk5VdRjzxQF4ZZxgSXGQ9d" name="google-pixel-9-pixel-studio-01.jpg" alt="Generating art using the Pixel Studio app on a Google Pixel 9 Pro XL" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nk5VdRjzxQF4ZZxgSXGQ9d.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Rooting a device has been known to hinder certain services (like streaming), but <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-pro-display-upgrade">some good comes from doing it</a>. Users sensitive to the flickering of a display, also known as <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-is-pwm-display-flicker-tips-and-tricks">PWM dimming</a>, are a prime example. Naturally, the Pixel 8 features a low 240HZ flicker rate, which can cause nausea, headaches, and other adverse feelings to some users. However, rooting the device and installing a custom ROM can let a (very intuitive) person rewrite the code to alter this frequency. Android Central&apos;s Nicholas Sutrich received some help and boosted the PWM rate to 4800Hz, ridding himself of those terrible feelings.</p><p>The specific reasoning behind these bootloader/rooting issues on the Pixel 9 isn&apos;t clear, leaving users wondering if there&apos;s a bug Google needs to squash. Moreover, the ability, or lack thereof, to root/unlock the device&apos;s bootloader seems to turn off many in the thread.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/pixel-9-rooting-unlocked-bootloader-problems-reported</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Users started reporting problems with the Pixel 9's AI features after rooting the device. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">vKCwJkvSyocHizadPwyJMi</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/X24ZT2npofmK28hhCxyqCe.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:03:22 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/X24ZT2npofmK28hhCxyqCe.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Theming the homescreen of the Google Pixel 9 Pro XL blue]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Theming the homescreen of the Google Pixel 9 Pro XL blue]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Gemini image generation gets a major upgrade, and custom Gems are finally rolling out ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google is rolling out a couple of updates today (August 28), beginning with Imagen 3 in Gemini apps.</li><li>Users can create "photorealistic" and high-quality images of animals, objects, plants, and more with Google stating that generation of people will come later.</li><li>Gemini also picks up custom Gems, which lets users create a tailor-made version of the AI for a specific need.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google is rolling out some updates today (August 28) for its AI model, Gemini, for image generation and custom Gems.</p><p>Users seeking assistance through Gemini apps are being treated to an Imagen 3 upgrade. Google reiterates that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/googles-imagen-3-is-now-open-to-everyone-in-the-us">Imagen 3</a> is its new "standard" for "generating images in just a few words." The company states users can create photorealistic landscapes and images that mirror oil-based paintings.</p><p>Additionally, Google touts Imagen 3&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-io-2024-gemini-model-highlights#:~:text=A%20new%20wave%20of%20video%20and%20image%20generation">ability to understand</a> a user&apos;s natural speech to understand the intent behind their description.</p><p>Imagen 3&apos;s rollout in Gemini apps will remain fixed on animals, plants, and other objects at the start. Google states that "in the coming days," it will work to bring the ability to describe and have Gemini create images of people. This is slated to arrive in early access for Gemini Advanced, Business, and Enterprise users in English.</p><p>Despite Imagen 3 giving the user full control over their <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/gemini/answer/14286560?visit_id=638603118036201008-476356290&p=b_gen_img&rd=1">text-to-image generation</a> process, Google has set limits for photos of people. For example, the software will not support photorealistic photos or "identifiable individual" creations.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="dkMXrTEKmFnNtP8nT7tLJE" name="google-gemini-imagen-3-rose-ai-creation.jpg" alt="An AI creation of a rose through Imagen 3." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dkMXrTEKmFnNtP8nT7tLJE.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="4Dc7GoZADEKtkaSTrh8MJH" name="google-gemini-imagen-3-dragon-ai-creation.jpg" alt="Imagen 3 can create image such as this, a baby dragon emerging from an egg." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4Dc7GoZADEKtkaSTrh8MJH.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>The final update, which involves Gemini Advanced, Business, and Enterprise users, brings "custom Gems" for the AI model. The press release states that these users can soon begin "creating and chatting" with their custom-made Gemini variant. This was a feature Google <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini#:~:text=GOOGLE%20GEMINI%20VERSIONS%20AND%20SPIN%2DOFFS">teased during I/O 2024</a>, which lets users fine-tune Gemini for a specific need.</p><p>As it rolls out over "the coming days," Google says users will find a few pre-made custom Gem options for Gemini. "Learning Coach" is said to help break down information for users who are learning a new or difficult topic for the first time. The "Brainstormer" option is geared toward offering inspiration for a range of topics.</p><p>The remaining pre-made options are as follows:</p>
<ul><li>Career guide: unlocks your career potential with detailed plans to refine your skills and achieve your career goals</li><li>Writing editor: can elevate your writing through clear, constructive feedback on everything from grammar to structure.</li><li>Coding partner: levels up your coding skills and can help you build projects and learn as you go.</li></ul>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:592px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:55.07%;"><img id="EqRYqB5Y2yiJpZBv4KGT4U" name="google-gemini-custom-gems-rollout.jpg" alt="Google rolls out custom Gems for Gemini, giving users a chance to create a personalized AI helper." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/EqRYqB5Y2yiJpZBv4KGT4U.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="592" height="326" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>More importantly, those creating a custom Gem should be as descriptive as possible. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.google/products/gemini/google-gemini-update-may-2024/#personalize-gems">Google explains</a> that users can instruct the custom Gemini variant on its purpose and "how it should respond."</p><p>Users can head into the Gemini app on desktop or mobile to find Gems and the ability to create their own. Most languages are supported as Google kickstarts its global rollout.</p><p>Those interested in trying what&apos;s new for Gemini before anyone else can sign up for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://gemini.google/advanced/">Gemini Advanced</a> or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://workspace.google.com/solutions/ai/">Gemini for Workspace</a>.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/gemini-image-3-custom-gems-update-detailed</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google started rolling out some new features for Gemini apps like Imagen 3 and custom AI creation. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">tEj43LiELShPVzZ3j5cGuS</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/aK7fsfNsYnnbrmsSazYp2L.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 22:21:44 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/aK7fsfNsYnnbrmsSazYp2L.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Gemini brings &quot;custom Gems&quot; to Gemini Advanced, Business, and Enterprise users.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Gemini brings &quot;custom Gems&quot; to Gemini Advanced, Business, and Enterprise users.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Pixel 9 Pro XL video teardown has me doubting you'll use this phone for seven years ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>This is why we love iFixit. We recently got to see a cool <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://youtu.be/v9uwCt59_yI?si=OaR8u6mAYYy3hLkA">teardown video from iFixit</a> for the Pixel 9 Pro XL. Most of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/pixel-9-pro-xl-teardown-shows-some-promising-changes-under-the-hood">reporting</a> surrounding this is about how Google designed the 9 series to be more durable and how it does better in drop testing, but for me, that&apos;s not the real story here.</p><p>The device gets a mediocre repairability score of 5, which is generous from what I see. A trained professional with all the right tools wasn&apos;t able to open the phone without breaking the display. Removing the battery was a nightmare for the very same professional. And this phone is supposed to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-explains-pixel-8-update-promise">last for seven years</a>?</p>
<p>Look, anything will last seven years (or longer) if you&apos;re willing to spend money on it. But <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-explains-pixel-8-update-promise">Google has made a big deal about</a> supporting its devices for seven years, so now it needs to build them in a way that is designed to be easy to keep alive for that long. I just ain&apos;t seeing it here.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-review">Pixel 9 Pro XL</a> design has a few (almost) saving graces. You don&apos;t have to remove the display to change the battery. That&apos;s good because the display will break while trying to remove it, and the battery will need replacing long before your seven years are up. Unfortunately, removing and replacing the battery is going to be unnecessarily difficult.</p>
<p>That doesn&apos;t account for all the other things that can easily wear out during the rated life of the phone. A great example is that your USB port is going to get loose and might need replacing. If you use the phone — or any phone — for seven years you&apos;ll probably need to replace or repair something.</p><p>It doesn&apos;t have to be this way.</p>
<h2 id="seven-years-is-dumb-anyway-2">Seven years is dumb anyway</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:70.00%;"><img id="aYM62tiYpPxLrDXQyrrwvd" name="android-update.jpg" alt="Android Update" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/aYM62tiYpPxLrDXQyrrwvd.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1000" height="700" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The idea of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/why-would-google-promise-seven-years-of-updates">using a phone for seven years is a bit silly</a> anyway. For some people (like me), having to only spend money and buy a phone every seven years is awesome. New stuff will come, and I might want some of it, but as long as it still does what it does today, I&apos;m good. </p><p>Most people don&apos;t see it that way. That new thing Google shows off that isn&apos;t going to work on your old phone is all the reason you need to buy a new one. That&apos;s how this works — even on the iPhone. New features will require new hardware, and you&apos;re going to be left out.</p>
<p>Google (and Samsung and Apple and every other phone maker) knows this. They count on it and show you things only to tell you that you need something newer to use them. I appreciate that companies support their products longer, but I don&apos;t pretend they do it because they are the good guy. They will get you to part with your money one way or another.</p>
<h2 id="the-better-way-2">The better way</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="cxpHRVBqYoLbDwGGzUL93i" name="Fairphone-4-disassembled-lifestyle.jpg" alt="Fairphone 4 disassembled" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/cxpHRVBqYoLbDwGGzUL93i.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Jerry Hildenbrand / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google doesn&apos;t have to invent anything here. I recently looked at the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/hmd-skyline-offers-something-other-phones-dont">HMD Skyline</a>. It&apos;s a pretty good mid-range phone with a cool camera. One thing special to me is that it&apos;s built so that you can open it and change the battery yourself. My problem is that it has a very short three-year support window.</p><p>Then there&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/i-wish-the-fairphone-5-was-coming-to-the-us">Fairphone</a>, which makes phones with a 100% repairability score. If you follow instructions and have the right tools, you can easily keep them running when parts break.</p><p>Even if you don&apos;t want to swap the battery or the USB port yourself, any shop is going to be able to do these repairs without breaking anything else or charging you more than it&apos;s worth.</p>
<p>A big reason why Google makes Pixel phones is to show everyone what it thinks a smartphone should be. They are the definition of a halo device.</p><p>Why not go a step further and design them so that your seven-year support promise means a little more? I probably won&apos;t drop my phone and break the screen, accidentally leave it in the sun, or do anything else to "break" my phone. I <em>will</em> use it enough that I&apos;ll need a new battery in a few years. </p><p>If it were easy to swap and something anyone could do themselves, it&apos;d be another selling point of a pretty damn good line of phones.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-xl-ifixit-teardown-gives-me-doubts</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A trained professional with all the right tools can't open the Pixel 9 Pro XL without breaking the display. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">GkGf8tsKjJG9DpYhddTh6f</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vVYYjY4JW9uei4MkoGAW8S.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 22:01:11 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vVYYjY4JW9uei4MkoGAW8S.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The back of the Hazel Google Pixel 9 Pro XL]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The back of the Hazel Google Pixel 9 Pro XL]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The best Pixel 9 colorway has one major drawback for me ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Gadget Weekly</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="DZLQ4jKZk9tEF5A3sqU5Jh" name="inspector-lloyd-square.jpg" caption="" alt="Inspector Lloyd" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DZLQ4jKZk9tEF5A3sqU5Jh.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">Join Namerah Saud Fatmi as she explores the cool, quirky, and sometimes downright odd world of smartphone accessories, gadgets, and other nerdy toys <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/gadget-weekly">every week</a>.</p></div></div>
<p>The cat&apos;s finally out of the bag with the squeaky new Pixel 9 family of smartphones. Google gave us not two, not three, but four new flagship phones in one go. That&apos;s quite a lot to process. While our final verdict is still pending, it&apos;s easy to say that the Pixel 9 series gets a lot right. There are plenty of upgrades and AI magic to make the devices enticing for anyone. Yet, despite all that, there&apos;s one problem with the Pixel 9 series that bums me out, and it has to do with the pink color option.</p><p>I won&apos;t lie; the biggest draw for me was purely superficial at first. My inner Elle Woods screamed in dignified delight when the leaks first showcased a pink Pixel. To top it off, it turned out to be an all-pink lineup of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phones</a> with pink accessories to match! How can a girl say no to that?</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="HdM9m3JvCLfJq2LSvZT75d" name="Elle_Woods-google-pixel-9-pink-2.jpg" alt="Elle Woods holding a Pixel 9 in Peony wearing all pink to match the pink phone." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HdM9m3JvCLfJq2LSvZT75d.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nick Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Now that we know for sure that three of the four Pixel 9 models come in pink, all I needed to decide was which model to buy. To me, Rose Quartz is the most interesting <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-color-google-pixel-9-pro-or-9-pro-xl-should-you-buy">shade of the upper-tier Pixel 9 Pro</a> series, followed by the deeper <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-color-google-pixel-9-should-you-buy">Peony hue of the basic Pixel 9</a>. The Pixel 9 Pro stood out as the obvious choice since it has practically no other difference compared to the 9 Pro XL in any aspect other than size. I prefer <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-small-android-phone">smaller phones</a> as they&apos;re easier to use one-handed.</p><p>My mind was pretty much made up about bumping my Pixel 8 over to the 9 Pro, but that&apos;s when I ran into an unexpected problem. When I&apos;m looking to buy a phone, naturally, I value other specs as well. Storage is a very important factor, especially because Pixels are famously superior photographers. So it was shocking to me that Google does not offer the Pixel 9 Pro or the 9 Pro XL in Rose Quartz with more than 256GB of storage.</p><p>That&apos;s a major roadblock for me because I&apos;ve already got around 200GB of images and videos on my current phone. If I were to upgrade to 256GB — not all of which is usable — I&apos;d run out of space on my brand-new phone in a few short months. It&apos;s not like I can use a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-micro-sd-card-android">nice microSD card</a> to fix that issue, seeing as most flagships like the Pixel 9 Pro and Pro XL have ditched expandable storage slots.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="tQMNQXwaV7Pomdj28HW7nV" name="google-pixel-9-with-buds-pro-2-peony-pink-01.jpg" alt="The Peony pink Google Pixel 9 next to the pink Google Pixel Buds Pro 2" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tQMNQXwaV7Pomdj28HW7nV.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="3HaYtacCH5UjinDya3ChvW" name="google-pixel-9-pro-9-and-xl-rose-pink-01.jpg" alt="Comparing all three Google Pixel 9 models in pink" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3HaYtacCH5UjinDya3ChvW.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="rj2RiPCrqxpXpK6XxBUkcF" name="google-pixel-9-rose-pink-01.jpg" alt="The Google Pixel 9 Pro next to a Google Pixel 9 Pro XL and an official Google case" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rj2RiPCrqxpXpK6XxBUkcF.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 4 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:42.87%;"><img id="TJ9VEMnDqD7sxFBkF3cWVe" name="google-pixel-9-peony-pink-02-21x9.jpg" alt="The Peony pink Google Pixel 9 next to some flowers" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TJ9VEMnDqD7sxFBkF3cWVe.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="878" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Even with the underwhelming performance of the Tensor G4 and the stuttering fingerprint sensor, I was onboard with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-review">Pixel 9 Pro</a>. The cameras and the Pixel UI are what I was willing to pay for, and of course, the sweet coat of pink paint. All things considered, storage simply isn&apos;t something I can compromise on.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-one">Google One</a> is one possible solution here, offering additional online storage and a few bonus features for a monthly or yearly fee. However, this requires you to be connected to the internet at all times. Additionally, relying on a cloud storage solution also means that any of the files that don&apos;t fit on your Pixel will have to be stored in the cloud fully, with no on-device availability. In areas with poor or no connectivity, this is a big drawback.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1986px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.19%;"><img id="ZTh3wtkgtMs7XGV7WArPUE" name="google-one-vpn-pixel-7-pro-1.jpg" alt="Google One VPN on Pixel 7 Pro - straight on view" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZTh3wtkgtMs7XGV7WArPUE.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1986" height="1116" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I don&apos;t know why Google passed on a 512GB option for the pink Pixel 9 phones, but based on experience and my gut, I&apos;m assuming it&apos;s because someone doubted the popularity of this color. When a brand doesn&apos;t have enough confidence in color, they don&apos;t offer larger storage options for it because it assumes that the demand will be low. I reached out to Google for clarification regarding color and storage options but did not get a response in time for publication. I will update the article if I hear back.</p><p>But let&apos;s be honest, 256GB doesn&apos;t cut it anymore. Each colorway should have enough storage to last for a phone that&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-pixel-9-software-updates">promised seven years of upgrades</a>. Samsung offers more than twice as many colorways on its phones, and you can go as high as 1TB on many of them. If Samsung can do it, why can&apos;t Google?</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="398285e0-3b9a-400d-803c-e260a0ad6fde">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Epz84yteXYHhCgKXftnMDm.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL official render - Rose Quartz - front and back"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 Pro</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Pinkalicious</strong></em></p>
<p>If you're a lover of pink things like me, you'll find it hard to ignore this sweet concoction. The Pixel 9 Pro packs all the best features of this Pixel generation but boasts a smaller size, making it easier to hold and use one-handed.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/best-pixel-9-colorway-only-256gb</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Pixel 9 series sure looks pretty in pink. I was immediately drawn to this blushing ensemble, but one thing is now holding me back. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">2iFFQUfCkk7o5TBopAoJrZ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/EoXNaGtnUZxHDdh2msjRXm.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 17:31:44 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/EoXNaGtnUZxHDdh2msjRXm.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9 Pro and 9 Pro XL in Pink]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9 Pro and 9 Pro XL in Pink]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ How to use Pixel Studio ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Pixel Studio is one of the more interesting AI features to arrive alongside the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-review">Pixel 9</a> devices. It&apos;s a new app powered by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/you-need-to-try-googles-imagefx-ai-image-generator">Google&apos;s Imagen 3 model</a>, giving users the ability to generate impressive images on-device just by typing in descriptive prompts. That includes being able to render text pretty accurately, something that seemed difficult for text-to-image models until now.</p><p>The idea is to create fun or interesting images straight from your phone, either from scratch or by using any of the samples present in the app. If you have a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-review">Pixel 9</a> series phone, you&apos;ll have access to this feature out of the box without needing to subscribe to any <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-one">Google One</a> subscription. Here&apos;s how you can get started creating your own images with Pixel Studio.</p>
<h2 id="getting-started-and-using-pixel-studio-2">Getting started and using Pixel Studio</h2>
<p>1. Open the app and follow the prompt to <strong>download the AI model</strong>. Once downloaded, you can scroll through the app to view the different example images, with different categories presented at the top.</p><p>2a. <strong>Select an image</strong>, then <strong>tap the</strong> <strong>text field</strong> to edit the prompt and begin changing it to your liking.</p><p>2b. When you&apos;re done, <strong>tap the checkmark</strong> and wait for the updated image to generate.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3440px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:73.37%;"><img id="QdRaNpxVJVAK6qJF79bqXD" name="Using-Pixel-Studio-1.jpg" alt="Using Pixel Studio to edit an existing image generation" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QdRaNpxVJVAK6qJF79bqXD.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="3440" height="2524" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>3. Alternatively, you can also create your own image from scratch by tapping the <strong>Create button</strong> on the main <strong>Pixel Studio home screen</strong>. Once an image is generated, you can press the <strong>circular arrow button</strong> at the bottom to regenerate an image. If you&apos;ve generated multiple images from the same prompt, you&apos;ll be able to scroll back to see what you&apos;ve already generated.</p><p>4. You can change the style of the image by <strong>tapping the middle icon</strong> in the text field. You can also add stickers, add captions, or edit images by tapping the <strong>Stickers and tools</strong> button at the bottom.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3440px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:73.37%;"><img id="n72saUJW8vY8ut7oWz9jCH" name="Using-Pixel-Studio-2.jpg" alt="Using Pixel Studio to generate a new image" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/n72saUJW8vY8ut7oWz9jCH.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="3440" height="2524" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>5. Once you&apos;ve generated an image you like, you can select from the options in the top right corner to: copy the image, share it, download it, or delete it.</p><p>6. From the main <strong>Pixel Studio home page</strong>, tap the <strong>folder icon</strong> in the top left corner to access your previous creations.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3440px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:73.37%;"><img id="r8JrC65HjRjXALoA4mFhKF" name="Using-Pixel-Studio-3.jpg" alt="Viewing your image generations in Pixel Studio" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/r8JrC65HjRjXALoA4mFhKF.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="3440" height="2524" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>You also have the option to import your own images for editing, although this function is much more limited, as it only lets you move or erase objects and add captions or stickers.</p>
<h2 id="reporting-bad-pixel-studio-image-generations-2">Reporting bad Pixel Studio image generations</h2>
<p>1. Tap the <strong>three dots</strong> in the text field bar.</p><p>2. Tap <strong>Bad generation</strong>.</p><p>3. <strong>Fill out the form</strong> by choosing a reason you selected the image as bad and provide any additional feedback in the text field. <strong>Tap the check mark box</strong> at the bottom to agree to send a copy of the image and related content (i.e., the text prompt) to Google.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3440px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:73.37%;"><img id="Mb98fpLqiPQ5WjMMh9AYpB" name="Pixel-Studio-bad-generation.jpg" alt="Reporting a bad generation in Pixel Studio" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Mb98fpLqiPQ5WjMMh9AYpB.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="3440" height="2524" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Alternatively, you can follow the same steps to report a good generation and provide Google feedback on why you think so.</p>
<h2 id="pixel-studio-is-a-work-in-progress-2">Pixel Studio is a work in progress</h2>
<p>Pixel Studio is intended to be a fun feature that allows a user&apos;s imagination to run wild. However, given that this is a preview, it&apos;s important to note that the results won&apos;t always be perfect. The company notes that it is working on the ability to generate humans. It also warns that Pixel Studio "might misinterpret your prompt" and that you should be as specific as possible.</p><p>Additionally, while Google has <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/pixelphone/answer/15236074?visit_id=638599394150771349-2108561604&p=pixel_studio_restrictions&rd=1#image-restrictions">safeguards</a> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://policies.google.com/terms/generative-ai/use-policy">in place</a> to help keep Pixel Studio from generating potentially offensive content, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-pixel-9-not-the-only-way-to-create-unhinged-ai-photos" target="_blank">some things may slip through the cracks</a>. Google is continuously working to address this with the app, but fortunately, you can rate individual generations and report ones you think are bad for whatever reason. This way, Google can better filter out certain types of content from being generated in Pixel Studio.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="48e49e00-b00e-4eed-8c89-562a89537c6b">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/B22jKfVHKzg8nbRGgwTHSP.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro official render - Rose Quartz - Front and Back"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 Pro</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Pretty in pink</strong></em></p>
<p>The Google Pixel 9 Pro is one of the best "small" flagship phones you can buy right now, sporting a powerful new Tensor chip capable of powering tons of fun generative AI features like Pixel Studio and much more.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-pixel-studio</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Pixel Studio is a new app introduced on the Pixel 9 series that lets users generate images using AI. All you have to do is imagine it, type it up, and the app does the work. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">CzG7i3h4qjbpJWbBij36zU</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/no7QVAxMzTCCHcyZQH6SSd.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 17:29:46 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ derrek.lee@futurenet.com (Derrek Lee) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/no7QVAxMzTCCHcyZQH6SSd.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Generating art using the Pixel Studio app on a Google Pixel 9 Pro XL]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Generating art using the Pixel Studio app on a Google Pixel 9 Pro XL]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Does the Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold support stylus input? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <section class="article__schema-question"><h3>Does the Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold support stylus input?</h3><article class="article__schema-answer"><p><strong>Best answer: </strong>No, the Pixel 9 Pro Fold does not support stylus input. Despite Google completely overhauling the design of its second-generation foldable phone, the Pixel 9 Pro Fold does not support the use of a stylus.</p></article></section>
<h2 id="no-stylus-support-here-2">No stylus support here</h2>
<p>Although it was a bit of a long shot, there was still hope that the original Pixel Fold would offer the ability to use the phone with a stylus. That same sentiment held true after rumors began picking up that Google was working on a new iteration of its book-style foldable phone.</p><p>Unfortunately, Google didn&apos;t answer the call with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-fold-2">Pixel 9 Pro Fold</a>, as the company&apos;s latest foldable doesn&apos;t support stylus input. That leaves the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Galaxy Z Fold 6</a> as the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">best foldable phone</a> for those who want to use a stylus.</p><p>While the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/using-oppo-pen-with-oneplus-open">OnePlus Open</a> can technically be included, the only way you can acquire a stylus that works is by importing an Oppo Pen from abroad. This is due to the fact that while the OnePlus Open and Oppo Find N3 are practically identical, there&apos;s no official stylus support from the OnePlus side of things.</p><p>That being said, it&apos;s still a bit disappointing to see the Pixel 9 Pro Fold miss out on such a useful capability. However, Google is continuing to put more of a focus on keeping its foldable phones as slim as possible. In order to make its phone compatible with a stylus, the company would have to rely on a different type of digitizer layer.</p><p>For example, the Galaxy Z Fold 6 uses an "active digitizer," which recognizes the tip of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/does-the-samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-support-the-s-pen">S Pen Fold Edition</a>. So while we&apos;re talking about extremely thin layers of materials, even making this one change could result in Google needing to take a different approach.</p><p>There is hope for stylus support in the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-10-pro-fold">Pixel 10 Pro Fold</a>, provided that Google follows a similar path to Samsung. S Pen support didn&apos;t arrive for Samsung&apos;s foldable phones until the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-3-review">Galaxy Z Fold 3</a>, but this also required a different type of S Pen to be created and released. With any luck, Google will make similar improvements with its next foldable phone.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="3a2919c1-56c3-429b-a7ae-68c373104293">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/eN3jfcnhHLaPsGfQNGHWdf.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold Official Render - Porcelain - Tabletop"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Incredible in many ways</strong></em></p>
<p>After a rather disappointing entrance into the foldable phone space, Google is righting the ship with the Pixel 9 Pro Fold. The company introduced an all-new design, while packing it full of fun and useful AI features. However, you'll have to look elsewhere if you were hoping to see stylus support added to the mix.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/does-the-google-pixel-9-pro-fold-support-stylus-input</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ With the Pixel 9 Pro Fold, some were hoping to see Google take the fight to Samsung by adding stylus support. However, with all of the other changes that were made, making it compatible with a stylus just wasn't on the list. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">q3qwKgWgaGp8zpibU8HnJH</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HBYM6PMPzpGEUSZaCA2uRT.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 17:20:18 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ andrew.myrick@futurenet.com (Andrew Myrick) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HBYM6PMPzpGEUSZaCA2uRT.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[New apps on the Pixel 9 Pro Fold]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[New apps on the Pixel 9 Pro Fold]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>