<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 20:09:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Huawei's tri-fold phone breaks cover, spotted with its former CEO ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A photo of Huawei's former CEO, Richard Yu, has started circulating social media because it seems he's holding a tri-folding phone.</li><li>A Weibo tipster stated the device is similar to a prototype they've seen with a 10-inch inner display alongside speculation that it could launch before Q4 2024.</li><li>An early report claimed that Huawei started "mass-producing" a tri-fold phone in February and that it would feature a display similar to the running theory.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>The foldable world could be in for a shake-up as a photo suggests Huawei&apos;s tri-fold device is very real.</p><p>According to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.gizmochina.com/2024/08/09/huaweis-tri-foldable-phone-spotted-in-real-launching-soon/">Gizmochina</a>, a photo of Huawei&apos;s former CEO Richard Yu preparing for a flight shows him supposedly holding a tri-fold phone. Enhancing the image offers a vague look at where the device might bend (or fold) to open/close. Additionally, it looks like the far left of the device is slightly bent, potentially indicating the first hinge&apos;s placement.</p><p>Chiming in is Chinese Weibo leaker <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.weibo.com/6048569942/Orr2aF2z9?pagetype=profilefeed">Digital Chat Station</a> (DCS), who claims that the device in question is the real deal. They claim the photographed device is similar to a previously witnessed prototype with a double hinge design. More importantly, the device is rumored to feature a 10-inch inner display when open.</p><p>A punch-hole selfie camera is speculated for the "far left" of the internal display. A specification rumor states the tri-fold phone will contain HiSilicon&apos;s Kirin 9 series SoC. Additionally, DCS suggests this tri-fold device will debut "earlier than the Huawei Mate 70."</p><p>The publication states that the Mate 70 isn&apos;t expected to hit the shelves until Q4 2024, which <em>could </em>mean we&apos;re closer to the world&apos;s first tri-folding device than we realize. Take this with a grain of salt, but speculation states we could see anywhere from now until September.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:451px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:133.04%;"><img id="uDiBwM5RvxexCJU3Fq72ff" name="huawei-tri-fold-former-ceo-spotted.jpg" alt="Huawei's former CEO was supposedly spotted holding the tri-fold phone." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uDiBwM5RvxexCJU3Fq72ff.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="451" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Gizmochina)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Huawei&apos;s tri-folding phone is expected to debut with a "premium" price tag. Users on Weibo have also started wondering if the company will include a stylus due to its size.</p><p>The idea of a "tri-fold" phone piqued consumer interest reports claimed <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-huawei-new-foldable-phone-push">Huawei started developing such a device</a> earlier this year. That post stated the Chinese company started "mass-producing" a device that would fold twice to form a "Z" shape. Similarly, early rumors claimed the device would offer a 10-inch internal display, which continues to be the running theory.</p><p>Unfortunately, the device never arrived during the first half of the year as the report claimed. So, we&apos;ll have to see if this next rumored timeframe pans out.</p><p>The other side of that report dealt with Samsung who were supposedly putting the "rollable" phone idea back on the table. The Korean OEM did show off a prototype of a rolling phone <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-display-foldable-rollable-tech-concepts-ces-2024">during CES 2024</a>, so maybe that theory holds water.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/huawei-tri-fold-phone-former-ceo-photographed</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Social media posts claimed to have spotted Huawei's tri-fold phone in public. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">ZFmGrkGg2pwiwyY4THytCB</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ofxgUJmnrtB3STK24ALVUU.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 19:27:05 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ofxgUJmnrtB3STK24ALVUU.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Huawei logo on the MatePad]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Huawei logo on the MatePad]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ There's one thing missing from the Pixel Watch, and Google doesn't have to look far to find the answer ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>When Google took the wraps off of the latest iteration of the Nest Learning Thermostat, there was something very familiar about it. After a few minutes of pondering, I finally figured it out — it&apos;s a blown-up Pixel Watch on the wall. Well, it&apos;s missing the crown, but instead, it adopts a rotating dial around the display, something the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-3">Pixel Watch</a> team could adopt from the Nest team.</p><p>Based on the leaks, Google is already aiming to solve one of my complaints about the Pixel Watch, as we&apos;re now hopefully going to see a larger model released. Now, I&apos;m hoping Google will adopt this Nest Thermostat design feature to future Pixel Watch models.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="uxuyBUSfwF6bNdVougL4km" name="nest-learning-thermostat-4th-gen-changing-temp-promo.jpg" alt="Nest Learning Thermostat (4th Gen) changing temperature lifestyle" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uxuyBUSfwF6bNdVougL4km.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2500" height="1406" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I&apos;m no engineer, so I don&apos;t know if it would actually be feasible, but I would love to see a Pixel Watch with the ability to navigate the menus by swiping your finger around the outer casing.</p><p>This is basically the premise of navigating menus or adjusting the temperature on the thermostat. After spending a few minutes playing around with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/the-new-nest-thermostat-has-a-better-display-and-you-can-personalize-its-home-screen">4th Gen Nest Thermostat</a>, this kind of interaction makes much more sense than smudging up the screen. I can&apos;t help but wonder why Google hasn&apos;t done this with the Watch, especially when it&apos;s obvious that there&apos;s a bit of "one hand washes the other" going on internally. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="PnHSbKEWSgsYou9iZNzpai" name="Google-Pixel-Watch-2-white-band-purple-watchface-turn-crown.jpg" alt="Turning the crown on the Google Pixel Watch 2" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PnHSbKEWSgsYou9iZNzpai.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Ultimately, I&apos;d love it if we saw some type of physical rotating bezel akin to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-6-review" target="_blank">Galaxy Watch 6 Classic</a>, but that&apos;s unlikely. I can&apos;t imagine Google making a watch large or bulky enough for something like that to even be implemented.</p><p>Speaking of Samsung, it has used a touch-sensitive bezel in different Galaxy Watch models over the years. We&apos;ve also seen physical rotating bezels on the likes of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/samsung-galaxy-watch-3-review">Galaxy Watch 3 Classic</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/samsung-galaxy-watch-4-review">Watch 4 Classic</a>, and Watch 6 Classic. Rather disappointingly, Samsung opted against bringing it back with its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-ultra-review">Galaxy Watch Ultra</a>. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2047px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.33%;"><img id="wCDxcFpMAiC2vpNqrjhACD" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Watch-5-Pro-03.jpg" alt="Hands-on with the Samsung Galaxy Watch 5 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wCDxcFpMAiC2vpNqrjhACD.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2047" height="1153" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Admittedly, I&apos;ve found that the touch bezel solution is <em>very</em> hit or miss, seemingly only working when it wants to. But since there isn&apos;t a digital crown on any Galaxy Watch besides the Ultra, the only other way to interact with your watch is to swipe up, down, and around on the screen. </p><p>It&apos;s really not <em>that</em> big of a deal unless you&apos;re someone like me who has sausage links for fingers. My fat fingers get in the way of being able to see everything, and it&apos;s frankly just a frustrating experience, especially when dealing with such small crowns like the one on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-2-review">Pixel Watch 2</a>.</p><p>Perhaps that&apos;s the reason why we have yet to see anything like what the Nest Thermostat offers being integrated into Google&apos;s wearable. Samsung and Google have supposedly been working closely together on the platform ever since the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/samsung-wear-os-google-smartwatch">partnership</a> was announced alongside Wear OS 3. Because of that, I can only assume that Google has some kind of idea about the benefits and pain points of the touch bezel.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1066px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.29%;"><img id="pZLb4Hc2w9aWhQRGpoLVvj" name="google-pixel-watch-3-xl-render-01.jpg" alt="Pixel Watch 3 XL renders" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pZLb4Hc2w9aWhQRGpoLVvj.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1066" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Headlines/ via OnLeaks)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Don&apos;t get me wrong, I&apos;m not expecting anything drastically different from the Pixel Watch 3 series. Hell, I&apos;m just happy that all signs point to Google releasing a larger version, almost as excited as I am about a new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-fold-2">Pixel Fold</a> (odd name notwithstanding). </p><p>I also don&apos;t want to go so far as to presume that this is something that Google has in the cards for a future Pixel Watch model. Who&apos;s to say that the company "gives up the hardware goose" after this year and just lets Samsung become the only real choice if you want an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch">Android smartwatch</a>? It&apos;s not outside the realm of possibility, especially if Google ends up needing to find more projects to send to the graveyard.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1116px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="R7C6ufdj4KpNNvdZhGqkXL" name="pixel-watch-2-nest-thermostat-4-face-render.jpg" alt="Pixel Watch 2 vs. Nest Learning Thermostat (4th Gen)" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/R7C6ufdj4KpNNvdZhGqkXL.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1116" height="628" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>No matter what, seeing the similarities between the 4th Gen Nest Thermostat and Pixel Watch has me a little excited. Instead of "the left hand not knowing what the right hand is doing," it <em>feels</em> like there&apos;s some cross-pollination happening. If you need any additional evidence of this, just check out the design of the different screens on the Thermostat. You can&apos;t tell me that they don&apos;t look like Pixel Watch faces. </p><p>Hopefully, this will become a trend with Google devices, as long as it makes sense and is not done just for the sake of it. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/future-google-pixel-watch-models-should-steal-this-nest-learning-thermostat-design-feature</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Slowly, but surely, it feels as though Google is perfecting the Pixel Watch. However, there's still something missing, and it's one of the best features of the new Nest Learning Thermostat. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Uq6J7zdtc3eQ6UXVVF4KGN</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tMEFCGBoap5cMVmAeZSkb9.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 19:12:31 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ andrew.myrick@futurenet.com (Andrew Myrick) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tMEFCGBoap5cMVmAeZSkb9.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Google Nest Learning Thermostat (Gen 4)]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Google Nest Learning Thermostat (Gen 4)]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Authenticator redesign adds a 'Privacy screen' lock and search ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google started rolling out version 7.0 of the Authenticator app, which overhauls its UI to fit its Material 3 design.</li><li>The redesign adds two new features: Privacy Screen and a search option for app security and convenience.</li><li>Google shifted to storing your one-time codes within your account instead of your device last year as it pushes toward a "passwordless" world.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google Authenticator, the helpful one-stop shop for your two-factor passwords, just picked up a big redesign with new features, seemingly rolling out soon for all users.</p><p>The folks at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/08/08/google-authenticator-material-you-redesign/">9to5Google</a> quickly spotted the redesign (v7.0) rolling out on Android, which brings the app up to Material 3 code. Because the Authenticator app holds the (literal) key to our accounts, Google has rolled out a new "Privacy Screen" feature. The company intends to bolster the app&apos;s security with this feature by restricting access using your lock screen credentials.</p><p>Activated within the app&apos;s settings, users can enable Privacy Screen which will use your previously set PIN or biometric as its own. Users can then set how quickly the Authenticator app requires another password entry.</p><p>The app offers the following options: immediately, after 10 seconds, after one minute, and after 10 minutes.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:276px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:217.39%;"><img id="6gxrxwbUdm2X2igMihKB3" name="google-authenticator-privacy-screen-feature-debut.jpg" alt="Version 7.0 of the Authenticator app brings "Privacy Screen."" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6gxrxwbUdm2X2igMihKB3.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="276" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: 9to5Google)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:274px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:218.98%;"><img id="sY3AzXk7SLVGnGyHvjote9" name="google-authenticator-qr-code-scanner-revamp.jpg" alt="The latest Authenticator version slightly changes the QR scanner." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sY3AzXk7SLVGnGyHvjote9.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="274" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: 9to5Google)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>The second addition involves the ability for Android users to search for content between Google accounts. Moreover, the publication states the app has now integrated the hamburger menu icon with the account switcher.</p><p>Some smaller changes join the update via the QR code scanning viewfinder. Google added some privacy information, stating the image captured isn&apos;t shared, only the "scan results." <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-lens-visual-search-ui-grid-view">Unlike Lens</a>, Google doesn&apos;t keep the image you&apos;ve snapped stored anywhere (or for any purpose). The QR code scanner also adds a flash option at the top right corner for illuminating darker codes.</p><p>Several screens and the accompanying UI across the Authenticator app have been overhauled to fit Google&apos;s Material design. The post states that version 7.0 of the app hasn&apos;t become available for most Android devices. When it does, users can download it via the Play Store.</p><p>Google&apos;s work with the Authenticator app has been kept relatively quiet other than the app&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-authenticator-account-sync">one-time code sync for accounts</a>. The feature aimed to solve user frustration behind losing their device or having it stolen. Google moved the codes used for 2FA (two-factor authentication) to your account instead of storing them natively within the device.</p><p>If users don&apos;t like that idea, they can always disable the sync option or not sign into a Google account. This is all part of Google&apos;s efforts to create a "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-fido-passwordless-security">passwordless</a>" world as it introduces new options like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-account-passkey-access-by-default">passkeys for accounts</a>.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-authenticator-security-material-you-redesign</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Google Authenticator app started picking up a redesign that includes new features for Android. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">jStXTEEfyiSoxgdwMzQXHf</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/cSCtHrZGgn2TEKk3K3Mamk.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 19:02:31 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/cSCtHrZGgn2TEKk3K3Mamk.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Authenticator&#039;s latest update adds account sync for one-time codes.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Authenticator&#039;s latest update adds account sync for one-time codes.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Made by Google 2024: How to watch the Pixel 9 launch and what to expect ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The annual Made by Google event is almost here, and we expect the company will unveil more devices than usual this time around. Following the launch of a new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/the-new-nest-thermostat-has-a-better-display-and-you-can-personalize-its-home-screen">Nest Thermostat</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/the-google-tv-streamer-launch">Google TV Streamer</a>, the company is expected to have several different phones, a new smartwatch, and possibly some new flagship earbuds at the upcoming event. Of course, there have been plenty of rumors, and Google itself has already revealed some of the devices that will appear at the launch.</p><p>Here's what we know and what we think we know about the upcoming Made by Google event, which is expected to be a big one.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-watch-the-made-by-google-2024-keynote-2">How to watch the Made by Google 2024 keynote</h2>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/N_y2tP9of8A" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>Google is hosting its annual Made by Google event earlier this year. Normally slated for early October, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/made-by-google-event-2024-date-announced">Pixel 9 Made by Google event</a> keynote is set for August 13, 2024, at 10 a.m. PT / 1 p.m. ET. The event will be held at Google&apos;s headquarters in Mountain View, California.</p><p>While invites were sent out to the media, the keynote will also be available to watch online. You can view the livestream on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://GoogleStore.com" target="_blank">Google Store website</a>, but it will also be available on YouTube. You can click on the "Notify me" button on the video above to set a reminder to watch the keynote when it goes live.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="google-pixel-9-series-2">Google Pixel 9 series</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1052px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="9buZxQrsjgWuGrwLRNrBmB" name="google-pixel-9-pro-teaser.jpg" alt="The Google Pixel 9 Pro." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9buZxQrsjgWuGrwLRNrBmB.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1052" height="592" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google is making some interesting changes to the Pixel series this year. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9">Google Pixel 9</a> will not only feature a brand-new design, evolved from the current design, but it will apparently come in three variants, marking the return of the XL model. There have long been rumors that Google will give us a Pixel 9, Pixel 9 Pro, and Pixel 9 Pro XL, and it seems the rumors are likely true.</p><p>Google itself has already begun teasing its devices, revealing the design of the Pixel 9 Pro. The device will have a very flat frame, a flat back panel, and a free-floating camera visor that protrudes from the back and is no longer attached to the frame. It also appears that the corners will be fairly rounded, and the phone will retain a triple camera setup with the temperature sensor on the rear.</p><p>In the teaser below, the phone also appears in what looks like a Porcelain colorway.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OMVpP-Zam1A" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>Based on leaks and rumors, the Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro will be roughly the same size, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/sennheiser-ie900-review">featuring 6.3-inch displays</a>, with the main visual difference being the lack of a third camera lens on the Pixel 9. Meanwhile, the rumored Pixel 9 Pro XL will apparently feature a larger 6.8-inch display, giving you two sizes of Pro phone to choose from.</p><p>All phones are set to be powered by the Tensor G4, which is rumored to offer a mild performance boost over the Pixel 8 series. We also expect to see 50MP primary cameras across the board, with a 48MP ultrawide and a 48MP telephoto for the Pro phones.</p>
<h2 id="google-pixel-9-pro-fold-2">Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1276px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="jgwCNBLT2zkiKn6VrnzE9i" name="Pixel-9-Pro-Fold.jpg" alt="Pixel 9 Pro Fold teaser" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jgwCNBLT2zkiKn6VrnzE9i.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1276" height="718" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Made by Google / YouTube)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-fold-review">Pixel Fold</a> is going through a bit of identity crisis, as the successor is switching up its naming and instead going with something a bit longer: <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-fold-2">Pixel 9 Pro Fold</a>. It&apos;s a bit of a mouthful compared to "Pixel Fold 2" but it will seemingly bring the device closer to its Pixel 9 siblings in name, while the device also adopts a design closer to the other phones.</p><p>We&apos;ve already seen plenty of leaks showing off the design of the phone, but Google has also teased the device, giving us a good look at the new rectangular camera housing. The phone has a flat frame and what appears to be a wider body with more expansive internal display. Official teasers haven&apos;t yet shown the outer display, but rumors suggest it will be identical to the Pixel 9 and 9 Pro at 6.3-inches, while the internal display will measure eight inches.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NC_A3EHFKF4" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>Like the other phones, it will likely be powered by the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-tensor-g4-rumors">Tensor G4</a> chipset and come with 16GB of RAM, although it could feature a smaller battery than its predecessor.</p><p>The cameras may be downgraded compared to the rest of the Pixel 9 series. The primary camera is rumored to be a 48MP unit, with two 10.8MP sensors for the ultrawide and telephoto cameras. We&apos;re also expecting 10MP sensors for the inner and external selfie cameras.</p>
<h2 id="google-pixel-watch-3-2">Google Pixel Watch 3</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="J4fNuhsWX3briTEWU67ava" name="pixel-watch-3-promo.jpg" alt="Pixel Watch sizes" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/J4fNuhsWX3briTEWU67ava.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OnLeaks/ Android Headlines)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While Google has yet to officially tease its next Pixel Watch, we've seen plenty of leaks that tell us what we need to know. It seems that this year, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-3">Pixel Watch 3</a> may finally be <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/pixel-watch-3-leaks-again-in-promo-video">offered in two sizes</a>, which should accommodate people with larger or smaller wrists. Not only are the sizes increasing, but so is the display, with the bezel shrinking as a result. The smaller watch may sport the same 1.2-inch panel, while the 45mm variant may come with a 1.4-inch display, both with up to 2,000 nits of brightness.</p><p>As for the chipset, it's rumored Google is sticking to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/qualcomm-snapdragon-w5-platform-announcement">Snapdragon W5 Gen 1</a>, which proved to be quite performant on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-2-review">Pixel Watch 2</a>. The downside, however, is that there won't seem to be much in the way of battery gains, with leaks suggesting we'll see 36 hours per charge when used in Battery Save mode.</p>
<p>Otherwise, the Pixel Watch 3 may gain some new fitness features, with an increased focus on running, as well as other capabilities such as a live view of Nest Doorbell feeds.</p>
<h2 id="google-pixel-buds-pro-2-2">Google Pixel Buds Pro 2</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1907px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="BWUaxTrwh2Tj4WPuMJpRUE" name="pixel-buds-pro-2-design-leak-reddit" alt="Leaked photo of the Pixel Buds Pro 2 with a cover for the case" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BWUaxTrwh2Tj4WPuMJpRUE.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1907" height="1073" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Living_Series8400 / Reddit)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google may finally grace us with a new flagship pair of Pixel Buds this year, which could come with a new design. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/earbuds/pixel-buds-pro-2-leaked-ad-design">Pixel Buds Pro 2</a> were recently leaked, showing off the case, which looks more or less the same as before. However, the buds may be offered in some fun new colors, including Raspberry, Porcelain, Haze, and Mojito.</p><p>It's also rumored that these may be the first earbuds to feature <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/earbuds/google-pixel-buds-gemini-capabilities-spotted">Gemini compatibility</a>, which would let you talk to the new chat assistant straight without taking out your phone. This would be quite an interesting step as Google is seemingly working to replace Google Assistant, and it could be the first of many Gemini-compatible earbuds.</p>
<h2 id="gemini-and-google-ai-2">Gemini and Google AI</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3775px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="jaQ7QUPbCTMyoW6rJa3GCa" name="Motorola-Razr-Plus-2024-review-08.jpg" alt="Gemini on the Motorola Razr Plus 2024 cover screen" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jaQ7QUPbCTMyoW6rJa3GCa.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3775" height="2123" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It goes without saying that AI will have a big presence at the Made by Google event, as it will be injected into just about everything that gets launched. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/pixel-9-new-google-ai-features-claims">According to a leak</a>, the Pixel 9 series is set to gain some interesting Google AI features, including Add Me, Studio, and Pixel screenshots. The first appears to be able to capture a group of people in a single shot, which may include someone not in the photo, like whoever&apos;s taking the picture.</p><p>Studio appears to be some type of image generator, while Pixel screenshots may be some new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.windowscentral.com/software-apps/windows-11/windows-recall-faq-everything-you-need-to-know">Recall</a>-like feature that will be the new home for your screenshots, allowing the phone to analyze and remember information stored on the images to bring up later.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:384px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:160.42%;"><img id="ToduuzxfpBG9SLSbhuZYHV" name="google-pixel-9-google-ai-rumored-overview.jpg" alt="Sources claim the Pixel 9 will receive "Google AI," a collection of AI features." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ToduuzxfpBG9SLSbhuZYHV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="384" height="616" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It'll be interesting to see what new capabilities Google intends to surprise us with, as the rumored features sound quite interesting already. Of course, we'll learn more about what these new Pixel devices can do at the event.</p>
<h2 id="android-15-and-wear-os-5-2">Android 15 and Wear OS 5</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="a7NZY6fiEXh9Dfx4A7Xwkg" name="android-15-logo-wide.jpg" alt="Android 15 logo on Pixel 8" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/a7NZY6fiEXh9Dfx4A7Xwkg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>One thing that we may or may not get at the Pixel 9 Made by Google event is Android 15. The beta is already on its last legs, having reached <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-beta-3-platform-stability-rollout">platform stability</a> in June. It seems like a matter of time until we get the stable version of the software, but it remains unclear if that&apos;ll be the case, with rumors swirling that the Pixel 9 series may launch with Android 14.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/wear-os-5">Wear OS 5</a> is expected to arrive on the Pixel Watch 3, and Google has already teased new capabilities and battery-saving features for the update. Samsung smartwatches have had <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/first-one-ui-6-watch-beta-hits-us-galaxy-watches">access to the beta</a> for some time, with the company&apos;s One UI Watch flavor sitting on top. Hopefully, Pixel Watch users won&apos;t have to wait much longer to update their devices.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/made-by-google-pixel-9-how-to-watch-what-to-expect</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The upcoming Pixel 9 Made by Google event is expected to feature plenty of devices. Here's everything we expect to appear during the launch. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">nZEGu2XntDNUoK6caAfBkd</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rP5vL6oB4YGhSGvTX29TpL.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 18:29:16 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ derrek.lee@futurenet.com (Derrek Lee) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rP5vL6oB4YGhSGvTX29TpL.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Google Pixel 9 Pro and 9 Pro Fold]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Google Pixel 9 Pro and 9 Pro Fold]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google's Wear OS 5.1 reportedly runs an entirely new version of Android ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google has reportedly started testing a Wear OS 5.1 update on the Pixel Watch 2 based on Android 15.</li><li>A rumored insider stated that the build ID numbers for the software changed from "AW2A" to "AP4A," strengthening the theory.</li><li>Google has seemingly committed to annual Wear OS update cycles as the company launched OS 4 in 2023 and has brought OS 5 this year.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google was spotted testing a new build of Wear OS that supposedly runs off the next major Android version.</p><p>The existence of a test build was reported to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/wear-os-5-1-android-15-3469455/">Android Authority</a> by a rumored "insider," stating Google has started developing a Wear OS 5.1 update. It was stated that the new build swapped out its initial lettering, opting for "AP4A" instead of Wear OS 5&apos;s "AW2A" number.</p><p>This new Wear OS 5.1 build is reportedly based on Android 15, a theory seemingly bolstered by the shift in build ID number. Wear OS 5, by comparison, is still on Android 14.</p><p>More importantly, the unknown insider said that Google was testing the upcoming software on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-2-review">Pixel Watch 2</a> internally. The company&apos;s Wear OS software has always lagged behind the <em>current </em>Android software — and was never so consistent. Wear OS 4 debuted in August 2023 and with Wear OS 5 arriving first on the Galaxy Watch 7, it seems that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-io-2024-schedule-teases-wear-os-5-what-that-means">Google hit its stride</a>.</p><p>With that in mind, there&apos;s uncertainty about whether or not Google will keep the update as "Wear OS 5.1" or if it&apos;s just testing Wear OS 6 early. Mishaal Rahman writing for the publication states that the specifics of the 5.1 update are unknown. However, if Google were to update its "APIs or app-facing system behaviors," that could warrant a major number increase.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="6PyGvvbynS4SbCMDtYo4J8" name="Google-Pixel-Watch-2-wearing-01.jpg" alt="Google Pixel Watch 2 hands-on" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6PyGvvbynS4SbCMDtYo4J8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>We&apos;ve got a toss-up regarding when Google could launch the Pixel Watch 3 as it has yet to tease it. The company is gearing up for an earlier <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/made-by-google-event-2024-date-announced">hardware event on August 13</a>, so we&apos;ll see when the device will launch. Google&apos;s Pixel Watch 3 is expected to arrive sporting Wear OS 5, which was said to come "later this year" during its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://developer.android.com/training/wearables/versions/5">developer preview</a> in May.</p><p>While we await the "stock" version of Wear OS 5, Google previously clued us into <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/wear-os/wear-os-5-will-bring-major-upgrades-to-battery-life-fitness-and-watch-faces">a few of its key upgrades</a>. When running default settings, Google stated the software will utilize 20% less power when compared to last year&apos;s version.</p><p>Additionally, Android Health will deliver improved running data and goals alongside Health Connect upgrades. Another critical aspect of the base Wear OS 5 software is that it runs off last year&apos;s Android 14. With Google seemingly more <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-io-2024-schedule-teases-wear-os-5-what-that-means">committed to annual Wear OS release cycles</a>, perhaps this 5.1 update is a testament to that. We&apos;re still waiting for the stable launch of Android 15, so maybe the company&apos;s looking to sync up these launches.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/wear-os/google-wear-os-5-1-android-15-rumor</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A supposed insider claimed that Google has started testing a Wear OS 5 update based on Android 15. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">eH2VPh4x9ctgiGszoZDCsi</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uBekpNzFgvVRtJ7nZcuYkf.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 18:05:54 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wear Os]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uBekpNzFgvVRtJ7nZcuYkf.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Promo image showing new Wear OS 5 features]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Promo image showing new Wear OS 5 features]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Here's how to get 50% off your phone bill for an ENTIRE YEAR when you buy the Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 6 from Mint Mobile ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>I&apos;ve seen plenty of back-to-school deals over the past few weeks, but Mint Mobile has just now joined the fray with a pair of compelling offers on Samsung&apos;s latest foldable phones. Bundle the purchase of the Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 6 (or the Z Fold 6) with any six-month data plan at Mint, and the T-Mobile-owned MVNO carrier will <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/samsung-galaxy-z-flip6/6473480/"><strong>hook you up with a $100 discount AND six additional months of wireless service</strong></a> for free. </p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="007612a3-aa31-4506-a5df-cc5f5b078e65" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,100" data-dimension48="$1,100" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/samsung-galaxy-z-flip6/6473480/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1501px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="iLprTioaxZni7NSNL4dEmP" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Z-Flip-6-official-render-silver-shadow.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/iLprTioaxZni7NSNL4dEmP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1501" height="1501" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 6 256GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/samsung-galaxy-z-flip6/6473480/" data-dimension112="007612a3-aa31-4506-a5df-cc5f5b078e65" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,100" data-dimension48="$1,100"><del>$1,100</del> <strong>$1,000, plus six months of FREE wireless with any six-month data plan at Mint Mobile</strong></a></p>
<p>Just in time for back-to-school season, pick up a new Samsung foldable alongside ANY six-month data plan at Mint Mobile and you'll score a straight $100 off the phone plus six extra months of wireless service for free. </p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-6-review">Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 6</a> is a cutting-edge clamshell device with a durable folding hinge, super-efficient Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 performance, and seven years of software support straight out of the box. We've already seen quite a few <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-6-deals">Z Flip 6 deals</a>, but this is the first time Mint has gotten involved. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/samsung-galaxy-z-flip6/6473480/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="007612a3-aa31-4506-a5df-cc5f5b078e65" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,100" data-dimension48="$1,100">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="76e5e228-460a-448f-8803-28a722f98e08" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 256GB: $1,900" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 256GB: $1,900" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/samsung-galaxy-z-fold6/6473054/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1469px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="jwm5ZtKAaoUvTRXAtPquhV" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Z-Fold-6-official-render-silver-shadow.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jwm5ZtKAaoUvTRXAtPquhV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1469" height="1469" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 256GB: </strong><a href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/samsung-galaxy-z-fold6/6473054/" data-dimension112="76e5e228-460a-448f-8803-28a722f98e08" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 256GB: $1,900" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 256GB: $1,900"><del>$1,900</del> <strong>$1,800, plus six months of FREE wireless with any six-month plan at Mint Mobile</strong></a></p>
<p>Just like the Z Flip 6, if you pair the purchase of the premium Z Fold 6 with any six-month data plan at Mint Mobile, you'll get a $100 discount alongside six free months of coverage. </p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6</a> is like a premium smartphone and tablet all rolled into one, coming complete with a nearly-invisible center crease, a ton of AI features, and top-of-the-line Snapdragon performance. It's also very expensive, which is why <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/best-samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-deals">Galaxy Z Fold 6 deals</a> should be taken seriously.  <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/samsung-galaxy-z-fold6/6473054/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="76e5e228-460a-448f-8803-28a722f98e08" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 256GB: $1,900" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 256GB: $1,900">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>you&apos;re sick of paying phone bills every month; you want to use one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">best foldable phones</a> in the industry; you have good T-Mobile coverage in your area. </p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if:</strong> you don&apos;t want to be stuck with a single wireless carrier for a year; you&apos;re already locked into a contract; you can find a good trade-in deal elsewhere. </p><p>If you&apos;re not totally sold on this Mint Mobile deal just yet, let me break it down so you see why it stands out from other <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/carriers/best-mvno-deals-of-month-year-is-it-time-to-switch">MVNO promotions</a>. For starters, it&apos;s important to note that Mint Mobile operates with a "buy in bulk" plan system. Customers pay for their wireless service in 3, 6, and 12-month increments of time, picking from four simple data plans powered by T-Mobile&apos;s vast 5G network. Once their time allotment has reached an end, customers have the option to purchase another data plan or cancel their account without penalty. </p><p>The nice thing about this system is that you can simply pay for a year of wireless in advance and not have to worry about another phone bill for the next 12 months. For example, even if you signed up for six months of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/mint-mobile-review">Mint Mobile</a>&apos;s <em>most expensive </em>Unlimited data plan and bought the Galaxy Z Flip 6, you&apos;d make a single payment of $1,180 (or $50 per month with affirm) and be hooked up with a great 2024 device AND an entire year of wireless service. No more phone bills, no confusing eligibility requirements, and once the year is over you&apos;re free to switch carriers again or update your plan with zero hassle. </p><p>It&apos;s basically the perfect deal for anyone who wants to pair an innovative new phone with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-mvno-carrier">best MVNO carrier</a> in the business, as long as you don&apos;t mind being stuck with a single carrier for a year. </p>


<p><em>Heading back to campus? Don&apos;t forget to check out our guide to the </em><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/i-found-the-best-back-to-school-deals-for-android-users-see-early-discounts-on-tablets-tvs-smartphones-and-more"><em>best back-to-school deals</em></a><em> for Android users. </em></p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/heres-how-to-get-50-off-your-phone-bill-for-an-entire-year-when-you-buy-the-samsung-galaxy-z-flip-6-from-mint-mobile</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Mint Mobile is now including the Galaxy Z Flip 6 and Z Fold 6 in its list of bundle deals, just in time for back-to-school season! ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">xXnsDoWET2jbucXdf5XsXH</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zBSMCZRmwevDeSqeynmJeA.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 17:34:35 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zBSMCZRmwevDeSqeynmJeA.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 6 cover screen]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 6 cover screen]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Tons of new Quest games are getting announced at next week's VR Games Showcase ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The inaugural VR Games Showcase will feature 7 studios and 15 games for all available VR platforms, including Meta Quest 3 and PlayStation VR2.</li><li>We're expecting brand new games from Vertigo Games, Fast Travel Games, Flat2VR Studios, and nDreams at the show.</li><li>Other updates include first footage of Hitman 3 VR: Reloaded, Escaping Wonderland, a big Silent Slayer update, and more.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>VR Gamers, it&apos;s time for the next big gaming showcase! The inaugural VR Games Showcase takes place on August 15 at 9am PT, 12pm ET, 5pm BST, and 6pm CET.</p><p>You&apos;ll be able to check the feed out on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/@VRGamesShowcase">VR Games Showcase YouTube channel</a>, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/@FutureGamesShow">Future Games Show YouTube channel</a>, or the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/@IGN">IGN YouTube channel</a>. The show will last between 20 and 30 minutes but is expected to be packed with announcements from nDreams, Fast Travel Games, Vertigo Games, Schell Games, Flat2VR Studios, Beyond Frames & Combat Waffle Studios, and more.</p><p>Host Jamie Feltham calls it "the biggest VR Gaming event of the year," and it&apos;s any wonder why with many of the major VR development studios participating.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Abe-cAd8HGU" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>Several <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/upcoming-meta-quest-games">upcoming Meta Quest games</a> will be appearing on the virtual stage including the first real gameplay footage of Hitman 3 VR: Reloaded, which we got a sneak peek of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/summer-games-fest-has-already-begun-for-the-meta-quest-3">back in June</a>. This one&apos;s a total rebuild of the game designed for VR, which should be quite exciting <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/hitman-3-psvr-hands-on">given the potential</a> the PSVR version of Hitman 3 had.</p><p>First Escaping Wonderland gameplay should be making an appearance, hopefully solving the mystery of how the game is played. Combat Waffle Studios, the folks behind the ever-successful Ghosts of Tabor, will be showing off Grim and Silent North, two new multiplayer games that are sure to keep players coming back regularly for more.</p><p>Studio nDreams will be sharing updates on announced projects and are even revealing a brand new title, plus Vertigo Games is said to be announcing a surprise game announcement that we&apos;re sure to love. Flat2VR Studios, the folks behind <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/flat2vr-studios-hires-talented-vr-modders-for-licensed-quest-ports">incredible VR ports of classic PC games</a> like Doom and Half-Life, will be giving everyone a sneak peek of what&apos;s coming next from them. Even Schell Games will be there, sharing updates for Silent Slayer, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/these-games-are-a-stake-through-the-heart-of-the-horror-genre">my favorite horror game</a> of the year so far.</p><p>All of it is timed alongside Gamescom 2024 which takes place annually in Germany. Thankfully, you won&apos;t have to buy a plane ticket to see it with this showcase in store! Stay tuned for the show on August 15.</p>
<hr>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="281d2e37-835a-4bf9-9e05-8f3a57ff7158">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/E75vg2n9urJXwhnVrgFvsQ.jpg' alt="Meta Quest 3 headset and controller render on a white background"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Meta Quest 3</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>Cutting edge graphics, a sleeker design, more ergonomic controllers, and exclusive games make the Meta Quest 3 the best way to play VR today!</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/vr-games-showcase-2024-announcement</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The first VR Games Showcase debuts on August 15 and is said to feature 15 games from 7 different studios. Here's how to watch! ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">UA4DC9pRLMsFUUojKGgENU</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Jff7BafwPXtgHEwCtUqTT8.png" type="image/png" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 14:43:23 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/png" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Jff7BafwPXtgHEwCtUqTT8.png">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[VR Games Showcase]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The official VR Games Showcase logo and art]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The official VR Games Showcase logo and art]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google's new weather app for the Pixel 9 is showing up early  ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google’s new weather app is up for early testing via APKMirror, but expect some bugs.</li><li>The app, which started as a feature in the Clock app, is now a standalone app and might be exclusive to Pixel devices.</li><li>The app provides easy access to hourly and 10-day forecasts, plus details like wind speed and humidity.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google&apos;s updated weather app, set to launch soon on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9">Pixel 9</a> series, is already available for early testing ahead of the tech giant&apos;s big event on August 13.</p><p>As reported by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/pixel-9-weather-app-sideload-apk-available-3469072/" target="_blank">Android Authority</a>, you can now manually install the beta version of Google’s updated Weather app through <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.apkmirror.com/apk/google-inc/weather-14/weather-14-1-0-20240318-637962058-release/weather-1-0-20240318-637962058-android-apk-download/" target="_blank">APKMirror</a>. It works on devices running <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review">Android 14</a> or later, but expect some glitches since it’s still in development.</p><p>Google is about to roll out a new, feature-packed Weather app as a standard part of the Pixel 9. What started as a feature in the Clock app will soon become its own standalone app. However, it might end up being a Pixel-exclusive when it officially launches.</p><p>The app features a sleek, rounded design for a fresh look, but the weather data it provides is pretty much the same as what you’ve seen in previous widgets.</p><p>Leaked screenshots show the new Weather app has a clean, user-friendly design with easy access to hourly and 10-day forecasts. It also highlights wind speed, visibility, air pressure, and humidity. Plus, you can customize most tiles, though the 10-day forecast tile stays put, as per <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/08/07/pixel-weather-leak-install/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a>.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:346px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:216.76%;"><img id="UfbttPDbB45Gkbg7sSYToi" name="Pixel-Weather-app-leak-icon.jpg" alt="Updated Google Weather app for Pixel 9" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/UfbttPDbB45Gkbg7sSYToi.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="346" height="750" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: 9to5Google)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:346px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:216.76%;"><img id="E7dJqZFKKxDkqtNbCMBPhi" name="Pixel-Weather-app-leak-widget.jpg" alt="Updated Google Weather app for Pixel 9" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/E7dJqZFKKxDkqtNbCMBPhi.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="346" height="750" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: 9to5Google)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:346px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:216.76%;"><img id="on3ovY39GW7nZLDuMeuFbi" name="Pixel-Weather-app-leak-interface.jpg" alt="Updated Google Weather app for Pixel 9" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/on3ovY39GW7nZLDuMeuFbi.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="346" height="750" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: 9to5Google)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 4 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:346px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:216.76%;"><img id="4HCM2XvbLwiENkG5QZaqRi" name="Pixel-Weather-app-leak.jpg" alt="Updated Google Weather app for Pixel 9" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4HCM2XvbLwiENkG5QZaqRi.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="346" height="750" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: 9to5Google)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Fortunately, the new Weather app is easy to use without needing a Google account. But if you want to sync your saved locations across devices, logging in with a Google account is the way to go.</p><p>Keep in mind that this early version of the app might miss some features planned for the final release. Leaker <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/AssembleDebug/status/1821418757685686710" target="_blank">AssembleDebug</a> suggests that AI-driven weather summaries and detailed maps could be part of the full version. Given Google’s recent focus on AI, it’s likely these advanced features will be included.</p><p>Sideloading means installing apps from outside the Google Play Store, skipping Google’s security checks, so be very cautious: only use apps from trusted sources and be aware of the risks involved.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/googles-new-weather-app-for-the-pixel-9-is-showing-up-early</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ You can get your hands on this Google Pixel 9 app before it officially drops. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">UXk4bmpmohQvfZvwiw3EVR</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gKEEYScNVCnkUtYAynGpBJ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 11:27:37 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gKEEYScNVCnkUtYAynGpBJ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The new Google Weather folding/tablet UI on the Google Pixel Fold ]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The new Google Weather folding/tablet UI on the Google Pixel Fold ]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung Galaxy Watch 7 vs. Galaxy Watch 6: Mostly unchanged, with nine key differences ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[         <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="71c95343-c04c-4286-add7-4db04d1c48ce">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/twg3XFZJ889G3SKztd3TTj.jpg' alt="Render of the green Samsung Galaxy Watch 7"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy Watch 7</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="90" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Better performance, health, and fitness</strong></em></p>
<p>The Galaxy Watch 7 kept the same design as last year (only slightly thicker) and shed the classy Classic upgrade option, which you may not like. But the Watch 7's revamped BioSensor will make the watch more useful for health monitoring, the new Exynos chip loads apps faster, and LTE fans will appreciate the doubled storage for better on-wrist music playlists.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Faster, more efficient Exynos chip</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Better HR and GPS accuracy</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>New and upcoming health features like AGEs index</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Doubled storage</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>No price increase</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No Classic option</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No more Wireless PowerShare</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Same display, battery, etc. as Watch 6</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="e15a5127-4832-44a6-a135-684b4be93efa">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LenQPkuoNpvx6bijynpVy3.jpg' alt="samsung galaxy watch 6 render"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy Watch 6</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="90" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Only a step behind</strong></em></p>
<p>The Galaxy Watch 6 and 7 could be twins, at least on the surface. If you were hoping the Watch 7 would make changes to things like the display, battery capacity, or overall <em>look</em> — or if you have the Watch 6 Classic and love your rotating bezel — then you may want to stick with your Watch 6 for now, as it's still an excellent smartwatch.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Comparable design, display, capacity, etc.</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Supports Wireless PowerShare</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Same Wear OS software through 2027</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Thinner, with more band options</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Had a Classic upgrade</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No dual-band GPS</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No multi-color LEDs for future Samsung Health metrics</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Slower performance</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Not much storage space</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<p>The Samsung Galaxy Watch 7 follows a similar template to the Galaxy Watch 6. Most Galaxy Watch 7 vs. Galaxy Watch 6 upgrades can be found in its performance, storage, and health/fitness tracking.</p><p>Changes to the colors and bands aside, you&apos;d have a lot of trouble telling the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-7">Galaxy Watch 7</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-6">Galaxy Watch 6</a> apart; they have the same display sizes, protection, digital bezel, and overall look, with their weights differing by less than a gram.</p><p>Below, we&apos;ll compare the Galaxy Watch 7 vs. Watch 6 to help you decide whether to trade in your Watch 6 for the Watch 7 or to hold out for the Galaxy Watch 8. Even though the Galaxy Watch 7 is the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch">best Android watch</a> available today, you may not find enough major differences to justify an upgrade.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-watch-7-vs-galaxy-watch-6-specs-2">Samsung Galaxy Watch 7 vs. Galaxy Watch 6: Specs</h2>

<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-watch-7-vs-galaxy-watch-6-everything-that-apos-s-unchanged-2">Samsung Galaxy Watch 7 vs. Galaxy Watch 6: Everything that&apos;s unchanged</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="GHreUhv4uUWBDwgqsskxyJ" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Watch-7-vs-6-4.jpeg" alt="The Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 (left, black) and Samsung Galaxy Watch 7 (right, silver) side-by-side" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GHreUhv4uUWBDwgqsskxyJ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>If you own the Galaxy Watch 6, these aspects of your current watch will remain unchanged with the Galaxy Watch 7:</p><p><strong>Displays:</strong> Both watches ship in 40mm and 44mm case sizes, with matching 1.3-inch and 1.5-inch displays. They have the same resolution (432x432 or 480x480, based on the size) and the same 2,000 nits of brightness, which is fairly standard for flagship watches and is only beaten by the 3,000-nit <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-ultra-review">Galaxy Watch Ultra</a>.</p><p>Plus, both rely on a digital touch bezel, letting you scroll your finger along the display edge to slide down menus or across Tiles. We&apos;re ignoring the Watch 6 Classic and its physical bezel for this comparison. </p><p><strong>Memory</strong>: Both watches have 2GB of RAM, the current max we&apos;ve seen in smartwatches.</p><p><strong>Weight</strong>: Technically, the Watch 7 40mm and 44mm weigh 0.1g and 0.5g more than their Watch 6 counterparts, but your wrist could never tell the difference. It&apos;s the same physical profile.</p><p><strong>Protection: </strong>Both watches have the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/what-do-waterproof-dustproof-rugged-ip-rating-numbers-mean">maximum ingress protection</a> for dust and water resistance, specifically lasting for up to 30 minutes in 1.5 meters of water or 10 minutes in 50 meters of depth.</p><p>They also have equal sapphire display scratch protection. Samsung claims they both passed MIL-STD-810H tests for high/low temperature, altitude, humidity, immersion, salt, fog, dust, vibration, and drops.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="iCkVz8cRTnrZaEt4JzpcyF" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Watch-7-vs-6-5.jpeg" alt="The Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 (left, black) and Samsung Galaxy Watch 7 (right, silver) side-by-side" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/iCkVz8cRTnrZaEt4JzpcyF.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="caption-text">My 40mm Galaxy Watch 6 and 44mm Galaxy Watch 7 </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Battery capacity:</strong> While the Galaxy Watch 7 might last longer than the Watch 6 (more on that below), the actual capacity remains unchanged for both sizes. The 44mm Watch 7 and 6 have 125mAh extra capacity, but the larger display mostly cancels this out.</p><p><strong>Connectivity: </strong>Either watch provides the same efficient Bluetooth 5.3 standard, NFC payments via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-wallet-vs-google-wallet">Google Wallet or Samsung Wallet</a>, WiFi 2.4 and 5 GHz, and LTE connectivity. For the latter, you have to pay for the cellular Watch 6 or 7 upfront for $50 extra, then add it to your cellular plan.</p><p><strong>Software:</strong> As of early August, the Galaxy Watch 6 hasn&apos;t updated to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/wear-os-5">Wear OS 5</a>, but that should change soon after the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-3">Pixel Watch 3</a> launch, according to rumors. From that point onwards, the Watch 7 and 6 will have the same software and security updates until mid-2027, when the Watch 6 runs out of support. That means another three years of comparable software perks, if you don&apos;t upgrade.</p><p><strong>Sensors:</strong> While the Watch 7 did get an important sensor upgrade, what it tracks is mostly unchanged from past generations: resting and current heart rate, heart rate variability (HRV), passive atrial fibrillation (AFib) detection, active AFib detection (ECG), skin temperature, blood oxygen (SpO2), nighttime breathing rate, and menstrual cycles.</p><p>You also get the same accelerometer and gyroscope for workout tracking, barometer for elevation data, geomagnetic sensor for navigation, and ambient light sensor to auto-adjust the display to your surroundings. </p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-watch-7-vs-galaxy-watch-6-nine-key-differences-2">Samsung Galaxy Watch 7 vs. Galaxy Watch 6: Nine key differences</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="ubr3aUgtSFHaXthdqnK6fZ" name="samsung-galaxy-watch-7-review-app-drawer.jpg" alt="The Samsung Galaxy Watch 7's app drawer" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ubr3aUgtSFHaXthdqnK6fZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4000" height="2250" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ara Wagoner / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Why upgrade from the Galaxy Watch 6 to the Galaxy Watch 7? Here are the main differences, based on differences between our <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-7-review">Galaxy Watch 7 review test</a> and our <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-6-review">Galaxy Watch 6 review</a> (and my subsequent months using the last-gen watch):</p><p><strong>Better heart rate accuracy:</strong> The Galaxy Watch 7 has 13 heart rate sensor LEDs to the Watch 6&apos;s four LEDs. Where the Watch 6 had green, red, and IR sensors, the Watch 7 adds new colors — Blue, Yellow, Violet and Ultraviolet — while needing fewer photodiodes to power them all.</p><p>Samsung claims that the Watch 7&apos;s "optimal allocation" of green, red, and IR LEDs "more accurately measures health metrics such as heart rate, sleep quality, blood pressure, blood oxygen levels, and stress levels" than the Watch 6. In particular, it&apos;s supposed to be 30% more accurate during high-intensity workouts.</p><p>I performed a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-ultra-fitness-test">Galaxy Watch Ultra fitness test</a> — the Ultra and Watch 7 share sensors — and it did very well for heart rate accuracy, though it still struggled a bit to track heart rates in the 170+ bpm range. Still, my <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/galaxy-watch-6-fitness-hands-on">Galaxy Watch 6 fitness test</a> gave me less accurate results, so athletes will be happy with this change.</p><p><strong>More accurate dual-band GPS:</strong> The Galaxy Watch 7 is the first Samsung watch to have dual-band GPS, which tracks you from multiple satellite types (older L1s and newer L5s) to circumvent signal blockage or reflections off of buildings, mountains, tree cover, and so on.</p><p>Again, the Watch Ultra did extremely well compared to a dual-band Garmin watch in our tests, only 0.01 miles off after nearly 10 miles. This accuracy should apply to the Watch 7, as well.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3802px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.26%;"><img id="ZQgQLnZaJLZph7TTjf2yRe" name="samsung-galaxy-watch-7-review-health-sensor-curvature.jpg" alt="The new health sensor curvature on the Samsung Galaxy Watch 7" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZQgQLnZaJLZph7TTjf2yRe.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3802" height="2139" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ara Wagoner / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>AGEs index (and future health data): </strong>With those extra LED colors, Samsung tracks your body&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/galaxy-watch-7-to-get-a-new-sensor-that-boosts-health-tracking">advanced glycation end products (AGEs) index</a>, or the products that form in your bloodstream in response to excess sugar; a high AGEs index can be a warning sign for serious health conditions like diabetes or heart disease.</p><p>Samsung&apos;s announcement claims that this new metric is "one of the many new advanced features planned for the next Galaxy Watch" enabled by the new LED colors. In other words, any new health metrics Samsung works on will come to the Watch 7, but <em>not</em> the Watch 6 because of its limited LED colors. </p><p>We can&apos;t say whether this health data will be worth the update, and the Watch 6 already catches several health warning signs. The Galaxy Watch 7 is future-proofed for health data, but you could probably wait another year for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-8">Watch 8</a>, when Samsung has implemented more of these mysterious health features.</p><p><strong>A thicker Galaxy Watch 7:</strong> Samsung says that the Galaxy Watch 7 and Watch 6 are 9.7mm and 9.0mm thick, respectively. Neither is that skinny; Samsung doesn&apos;t include its BioSensor when measuring its watches, which is quite misleading. In truth, the Watch 6 is about 12mm thick, while the Watch 7 is at least 13mm thick. </p><p>Our Watch 7 reviewer noted that "The dome of the array curves higher, making the watch sit higher on lanky wrists like mine, but for thicker wrists, you shouldn&apos;t notice much of a difference." In other words, the new and improved health data has a visual impact on how it looks in real life, even if it&apos;s identical from the top-down.</p><p><strong>Colors and watch band options:</strong> The Watch 6 shipped in Graphite, Gold, and Silver, while the Watch 7 comes in Green, Cream, and Silver. </p><p>Aesthetics aside, the Watch 6 had more band options at launch: Sport, Extreme Sport, Hybrid Leather D or Leather T, and Fabric. The Galaxy Watch 7 has three core options: Fabric, Sport, and Athleisure. As always, there are plenty of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch/best-samsung-galaxy-watch-7-bands">third-party Galaxy Watch 7 band options</a>, but fans of leather or more breathable sport bands might be disappointed.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="9UNAC8Hicc5fbuv4o2dZTb" name="samsung-galaxy-watch-7-review-media-playback-youtube-music.jpg" alt="The Samsung Galaxy Watch 7's media playback controls" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9UNAC8Hicc5fbuv4o2dZTb.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4000" height="2249" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ara Wagoner / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Performance:</strong> The Galaxy Watch 7 uses one ARM Cortex-A78 1.6GHz core and four Cortex-A55 1.5GHz cores; the Watch 6 uses dual Cortex-A55 1.4GHz cores. As you might expect, this gives the Watch 7 much more capacity for high-end processing and faster app loading times.</p><p>In practice, our Watch 7 reviewer noted that it&apos;s "the zippiest smartwatch I&apos;ve ever used, but it&apos;s not magnitudes faster" than the Watch 6, "at least during everyday activities." That&apos;s similar to my experience with the Watch Ultra, which shares the Watch 7 chip; it loads apps very quickly, but the Watch 6 was also quite fast thanks to the comparable RAM.</p><p>Some of its extra performance capacity goes directly into running the extra LED sensors, which require more power to run. Otherwise, the Exynos W1000 is more future-proofed for future Wear OS updates, which might take more advantage of the extra power.</p><p><strong>Storage: </strong>The Galaxy Watch 6 has 16GB of storage, or less than 6GB once you account for default Wear OS software. That doesn&apos;t leave much wiggle room if you like to download music, podcasts, or audiobooks for streaming on the go while leaving your phone behind. Thankfully, the Watch 7 has boosted storage space up to 32GB, giving you more wiggle room for media and apps.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="VcwY8W9VvwdEcBmz8Zfejh" name="samsung-galaxy-watch-7-review-step-count.jpg" alt="Daily step count on the Samsung Galaxy Watch 7" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VcwY8W9VvwdEcBmz8Zfejh.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4000" height="2250" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ara Wagoner / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>(Slight) battery life boost: </strong>Samsung never gave us an official battery life estimate for the Galaxy Watch 7. Our reviewer found that it lasted two days (48 hours) with standard use and sleep tracking, while it lasted closer to 33–36 hours with more outdoor use (which uses more nits of brightness) and one dual-band GPS workout.</p><p>The Galaxy Watch 6 was rated to last 40 hours at launch, and yours has probably lost a little of its capacity since then. Our Watch 7 reviewer credits the Exynos W1000&apos;s "improved efficiency" as being able to handle certain tasks without as much battery burn, and it&apos;s fair to say that the Watch 6 will be less capable of handling demanding app tasks moving forward.</p><p>As a side note, some early Galaxy Watch 7 users have reported the opposite, with their watch barely lasting a day per charge. We&apos;re hoping this stems from early Wear OS 5 bugs that&apos;ll be resolved soon, since they would presumably affect the Watch 6, too.</p><p>If you&apos;re not much of an active Wear OS user and primarily use your Galaxy Watch 6 to check notifications and the weather, you&apos;re probably fine. Power users will benefit from a little extra capacity, but you&apos;ll need the Ultra for a true boost.</p><p><strong>No more Wireless PowerSharing: </strong>An unintended side effect of the Galaxy Watch 7&apos;s health sensor redesign is that it prevented Samsung from making it compatible with its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-use-wireless-power-share-on-a-samsung-galaxy-phone">Wireless PowerSharing</a> standard. </p><p>You can no longer charge the Watch 7 (or Ultra) by placing it atop your flagship <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-samsung-phones">Samsung phone</a>, while you still can do so with the Galaxy Watch 6. It&apos;s a useful trick if your Watch 6 dies and you don&apos;t have a charging puck on hand, though quite finicky if your phone has a protective case.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-galaxy-watch-7-vs-galaxy-watch-6-should-you-upgrade-2">Samsung Galaxy Watch 7 vs. Galaxy Watch 6: Should you upgrade?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="KRotNvqeMknorvCre7tVzD" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Watch-7-vs-6-1.jpeg" alt="The Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 (left, black) and Samsung Galaxy Watch 7 (right, silver) side-by-side" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KRotNvqeMknorvCre7tVzD.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Samsung is offering a trade-in deal of a $99 Watch 7 and a free second band in exchange for your Watch 6. As long as that deal&apos;s available, you have plenty of reasons to upgrade. If you&apos;re paying full price or own the Watch 6 Classic, it&apos;s harder to justify the switch.</p><p>The Galaxy Watch 7 is significantly better than the Watch 6 in key areas, with only a couple of minor drawbacks with its thickness and disabled PowerSharing in exchange for better health and fitness data. It&apos;s not <em>that</em> much faster than the Watch 6, and Samsung has to figure out the current battery drain issue, but it&apos;s more than we expected, given many Android watches keep the same CPU across generations. </p><p>If you have the Watch 6 Classic, you&apos;ll lose your stylish steel design and better bezel controls in exchange for all of the above perks and a lighter fit. That&apos;s probably a tough pill to swallow unless you <em>don&apos;t</em> like your Classic.</p><p>As for standard Galaxy Watch 6 owners, you may want to wait another generation for the differences to be more significant. This could depend, however, on whether you believe the rumors that Samsung wants to switch to a squircle design with future watches. If the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-8">Galaxy Watch 8</a> ends up with a squircle display — which Apple users love and plenty of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wear-os-watch">Wear OS watch</a> owners hate — then maybe there&apos;s no reason to wait.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="96f0292e-c872-47d0-9b74-cda441da8e46">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/twg3XFZJ889G3SKztd3TTj.jpg' alt="Render of the green Samsung Galaxy Watch 7"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy Watch 7</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="90" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Better performance, health, and fitness</strong></em></p>
<p>Choose the Galaxy Watch 7 if you really care about its improved health and GPS accuracy, or if you're a power user that wants the fastest possible performance every year. Skip it if you like your Classic design or if you're not impressed enough with the changes; the Watch 8 will arrive before you know it.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="709a0918-3d5a-4798-ab55-3f5dee92b38b">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LenQPkuoNpvx6bijynpVy3.jpg' alt="samsung galaxy watch 6 render"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy Watch 6</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="90" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Only a step behind</strong></em></p>
<p>Stick with your Galaxy Watch 6 if you're not impressed enough with the changes in performance, if you don't pay close attention to your Samsung Health data, or if you're happy with your Watch 6 Classic. Upgrade to the Watch 7 if you find a good trade-in deal and want all of the latest perks.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-7-vs-galaxy-watch-6</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Though you'd have trouble differentiating between a Galaxy Watch 7 and Watch 6 at first glance, the newer watch has some major upgrades beneath the surface, including some that have yet to be revealed. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">ixo2EpcKMYGNvkyfRRAbLY</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GHreUhv4uUWBDwgqsskxyJ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 05:23:33 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Watch]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GHreUhv4uUWBDwgqsskxyJ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 (left, black) and Samsung Galaxy Watch 7 (right, silver) side-by-side]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 (left, black) and Samsung Galaxy Watch 7 (right, silver) side-by-side]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Best NAS for Plex 2024 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Quick menu</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="CgHnSG9xvby8NcFpW7RCjg" name="synology-diskstation-ds224-plus-12.jpg" caption="" alt="Synology DiskStation DS224+ review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CgHnSG9xvby8NcFpW7RCjg.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text"><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="#section-at-a-glance">At a glance</a><br>
<strong>1.</strong> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="#section-best-overall">Best overall</a><br>
<strong>2.</strong> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="#section-best-4-bay-nas">Best 4-bay NAS</a><br>
<strong>3.</strong> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="#section-best-hardware">Best hardware</a><br>
<strong>4.</strong> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="#section-best-value">Best value</a><br>
<strong>5.</strong> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="#section-best-software">Best software</a><br>
<strong>6.</strong> <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="#section-best-budget">Best budget</a><br>
<strong>7. </strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="#section-faq">FAQ</a><br>
<strong>8. </strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-nas-plex#section-how-to-choose">How to choose</a><br>
<strong>9. </strong><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-nas-plex#section-how-we-test">How we test</a></p></div></div>
<p>The best NAS for Plex should let you stream your media collection to all connected devices in your home. Plex is a terrific platform that lets you manage your media library with ease, and the service has a ton of useful extras when it comes to video playback. The best part is that the Plex client is available on just about every platform, making it straightforward to stream your content. And you don&apos;t need to pay anything to get started. </p><p>Plex has a paid tier called Plex Pass that gives you a ton of additional features, including the ability to use hardware transcoding. If you have a lot of older media that needs to be transcoded before being played back on TVs or phones, you may want to go this route. But for a majority of users, the free Plex media server is going to be more than adequate. </p><p>You can do plenty of other things with a NAS, including backing up photos and videos from all of your phones, setting up virtual machines, accessing powerful productivity software that doesn&apos;t need any monthly fee, and a whole lot more. NAS servers designed for Plex tend to have powerful hardware in general, unlocking a suite of enticing use cases in addition to streaming media.</p><p>I tested dozens of NAS models over the last three years, and these are the best Plex NAS servers you can buy today.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-at-a-glance"><span>At a glance</span></h3>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="a21642d9-7d64-469f-b3a7-a9b366bd9ac9">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ANMBBe25r4MxC6YnhCkjbZ.jpg' alt="Synology DiskStation DS224+"><span class='featured__label hero__label'>Best overall</span></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">1. Synology DiskStation DS224+</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="90" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best overall</strong></em></p>
<p>The DiskStation DS224+ is the best choice if you want a powerful NAS with standout software. The NAS can easily handle Plex transcodes, the Intel hardware is terrific in daily use, and the 2-bay server is affordable enough while still offering all the features you'll actually use.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-nas-plex#section-best-overall"><em>Read more below.</em></a></p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="4bfe5faa-6500-49bc-97d7-aec54e30b759">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/S6jx2nTEcapFavm3coYvK.jpg' alt="Synology DiskStation DS423+"><span class='featured__label hero__label'>Best 4-bay NAS</span></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">2. Synology DiskStation DS423+</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="90" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best 4-bay NAS</strong></em></p>
<p>The DiskStation DS423+ runs the same Intel hardware as the DS224+, so it holds up just as well for Plex media streaming. The difference is that you get four drive bays here, and the dual M.2 slots allow you to add SSD storage.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-nas-plex#section-best-budget-nas"><em>Read more below.</em></a></p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="d4aee7c3-f101-4620-b2b7-67e145e74fd9">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/e8vrjsdpzqj9dsxxJWWrkY.jpg' alt="ASUSTOR AS5402T"><span class='featured__label hero__label'>Best hardware</span></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">3. ASUSTOR AS5402T</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="90" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best hardware</strong></em></p>
<p>The AS5402T has the best hardware in this segment, and the Intel-powered NAS is a stellar choice if you need a Plex NAS with transcodes, dual 2.5 Gigabit Ethernet ports, an HDMI port that lets you connect to your TV, and four M.2 slots.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-nas-plex#section-best-premium-pick"><em>Read more below.</em></a></p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="21bf7fc4-5e37-41e9-8a84-1f376be2a565">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/htxPJsgy8ibeyqQfvWTay5.jpg' alt="TerraMaster F4-423"><span class='featured__label hero__label'>Best value</span></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">4. TerraMaster F4-423</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="80" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best value</strong></em></p>
<p>The F4-423 offers the best value if you want a 4-bay NAS server with Plex transcodes, dual 2.5GbE connectivity, and an HDMI port. The TOS6 software is better than ever before, and on the whole, this is the best value if you need a powerful Plex NAS.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-nas-plex#section-best-value"><em>Read more below.</em></a></p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="d3770917-1b61-4a94-a158-c64f9c21634d">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3jAsm5k3zrDCfHGE7BUXD8.jpg' alt="Synology DiskStation DS923+"><span class='featured__label hero__label'>Best software</span></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">5. Synology DiskStation DS923+</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="90" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best software</strong></em></p>
<p>The DiskStation DS923+ is a powerful 4-bay server that does an amazing job as a Plex media server. The Ryzen hardware is more powerful than its Intel rival, but the downside is that you miss on Plex transcodes. If you don't need the feature, the DS923+ is a fantastic choice.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-nas-plex#section-best-software-features"><em>Read more below.</em></a></p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_hero" data-id="2e6159ba-7af4-44a8-971c-172c2eceb806">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/b3xQJZtEWc4RZWHpThi9BM.jpg' alt="Synology DiskStation DS223j"><span class='featured__label hero__label'>Best budget</span></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">6. Synology DiskStation DS223j</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="80" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Best budget</strong></em></p>
<p>If you need a Plex server on a budget, the DS223j has a lot to offer. It misses out on some of the advanced features that you get in costlier NAS servers, but as a basic home media streaming solution, it ticks all the right boxes.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-nas-plex#section-best-for-content-creators"><em>Read more below.</em></a><em> </em></p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-best-overall"><span>Best overall</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="e25rymzGSo4ZYoa6RFUdbi" name="synology-diskstation-ds224-plus-13.jpg" alt="Synology DiskStation DS224+ review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/e25rymzGSo4ZYoa6RFUdbi.jpg" mos="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tFNHgs2iLW58U9TL8Zqjdn.jpg" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<div class="buying-guide-block"><h3 id="1-synology-diskstation-ds224-2"><span class="title__text"><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/synology-diskstation-ds224-plus-review">1. Synology DiskStation DS224+</a></span><span class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span></span></h3><div class="_hawk subtitle"><p>The best 2-bay Plex NAS</p></div><p class="specs__container"><strong>Internal drive bays: </strong>Two (18TB each bay), 3.5-inch HDD, 2.5-inch HDD/SSD, M.2 storage | <strong>CPU: </strong>Quad-core 64-bit 2.0GHz Intel Celeron J4125 | <strong>RAM: </strong>2GB DDR4 ECC, two SODIMM slots, up to 6GB total | <strong>USB ports: </strong>2 x USB 3.1 Gen1 | <strong>Dimensions: </strong>165 x 108 x 232.2mm</p><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Terrific as a Plex media server</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Handles transcodes well</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Best software features in its category</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Proven design</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">Doesn&apos;t have M.2 slots</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">Limited to Gigabit Ethernet</div></div>
<p>If you&apos;re new to Plex and just want a NAS that lets you stream your media collection, you should get the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/synology-diskstation-ds224-plus-review">DiskStation DS224+</a>. The NAS has two drive bays, is powered by Intel&apos;s reliable Celeron J4125 platform, and comes with 2GB of RAM as standard. You get dual Gigabit Ethernet ports, two USB ports, and the design has good passive ventilation along with a 92mm fan at the back that manages thermals well.</p><p>That said, the hardware isn&apos;t the best you&apos;ll find in this segment; you don&apos;t get any M.2 drives, and you miss out on multi-Gigabit connectivity. But it&apos;s all about achieving the right balance, and the DS224+ definitely manages to do that. Although it misses out on a few things, there are no issues with performance, and for most users, Gigabit Ethernet is still more than adequate.</p><p>Where the DS224+ truly shines is its ability as a Plex media server. The NAS has a native Plex client, and configuring it takes less than five minutes. And as it uses an Intel platform, you get hardware-based transcoding — if you have Plex Pass. Most users don&apos;t need to transcode content, but if you want to share your Plex library and have devices that can&apos;t play back the content natively, it comes in handy.</p><p>I tested Plex extensively on the DS224+, and the NAS does a terrific job playing back high bitrate 4K content without any issues. And if you need the feature, it holds up well with transcodes as well. Another standout feature is the software itself; the DS224+ runs DiskStation Manager (DSM), and it has an extensive suite of utilities that make a genuine difference — you won&apos;t get this level of polish with other brands. DSM also has useful mobile apps that let you access your data on the go.</p><p>Ultimately, the DS224+ is a powerful server that&apos;s a great choice for Plex, and you can&apos;t really go wrong with the NAS.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-best-4-bay-nas"><span>Best 4-bay NAS</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="z5cyogzc8Hxy6hVnTsP4aV" name="synology-diskstation-ds423-plus-1.jpg" alt="Synology DiskStation DS423+ review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/z5cyogzc8Hxy6hVnTsP4aV.jpg" mos="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oJ38HVGa4tEYpW4KHcju3A.jpg" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<div class="buying-guide-block"><h3 id="2-synology-diskstation-ds423-2"><span class="title__text"><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/synology-diskstation-ds423-plus-review">2. Synology DiskStation DS423+</a></span><span class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span></span></h3><div class="_hawk subtitle"><p>A standout 4-bay Plex NAS</p></div><p class="specs__container"><strong>Internal drive bays: </strong>Four (18TB each bay), 3.5-inch HDD, 2.5-inch SSD | <strong>CPU: </strong>64-bit Quad-core Intel Celeron J4125 | <strong>RAM: </strong>2GB DDR4 non-ECC, soldered, SODIMM slot up to 4GB | <strong>USB ports: </strong>2 x USB 3.1 Gen1 | <strong>Dimensions: </strong>166 x 199 x 223mm</p><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Just as great as the DS224+ at Plex</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Great with Plex transcodes</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Dual M.2 slots</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Terrific software</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">Limited to Gigabit Ethernet</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">Cannot add more drives down the line</div></div>
<p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/synology-diskstation-ds423-plus-review">DiskStation DS423+</a> is nearly identical to the DS224+, and the key difference between the two is that the DS423+ has four drive bays, giving you the ability to house twice as much storage. You also get two M.2 slots on the underside, and that lets you use NVMe SSDs in addition to traditional hard drives.</p><p>The rest of the features are identical; the DS423+ uses the same Intel Celeron J4125 as the DS224+, you get 2GB of RAM, dual Gigabit Ethernet ports, and two USB ports. As it is a larger unit, there are two 92mm fans at the back. I would have liked to see at least one multi-Gigabit port — a lot of other 4-bay servers offer it as standard these days — but other than that, the hardware is pretty decent.</p><p>As the DS423+ uses the same Intel platform, it handles Plex in much the same fashion as the DS224+. I didn&apos;t run into any issues playing back 4K content, and transcoding worked reliably as well. And just like the DS224+, you get the same great feature-set within DSM, allowing you to do so much more in addition to Plex streaming.</p><p>If you like the look of the DS224+ but need M.2 slots or additional drive bays, the DiskStation DS423+ is the ideal choice.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-best-hardware"><span>Best hardware</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="ErmVL7WijMdekUSA2GwvgN" name="asustor-as5402t-1.jpg" alt="ASUSTOR AS5402T review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ErmVL7WijMdekUSA2GwvgN.jpg" mos="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dtxgU4Ja5XhqVX43VkWRj7.jpg" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<div class="buying-guide-block"><h3 id="3-asustor-as5402t-2"><span class="title__text"><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/asustor-nimbustor-2-gen2-as5402t-review">3. ASUSTOR AS5402T</a></span><span class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span></span></h3><div class="_hawk subtitle"><p>The best Plex NAS hardware</p></div><p class="specs__container"><strong>Internal drive bays: </strong>Two (24TB each bay), 3.5-inch HDD, 2.5-inch HDD/SSD | <strong>CPU: </strong>Quad-core 64-bit 2.0GHz Intel Celeron J5105 | <strong>RAM: </strong>4GB DDR4 non-ECC, upgradeable to 16GB | <strong>USB ports: </strong>2 x USB 3.2 Gen2, 10Gbps | <strong>Dimensions: </strong>170 x 114 x 230mm</p><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Fabulous as a Plex server</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Handles transcodes really well</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Dual 2.5GbE ports as standard</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Four M.2 slots</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">Software isn&apos;t as polished</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">M.2 drives aren&apos;t easily accessible</div></div>
<p>ASUSTOR&apos;s AS5402T has the best hardware in its category, and the 2-bay NAS has everything you need in a Plex server. The Intel Celeron J5105 is outstanding in daily use, you get 4GB of RAM, four M.2 slots in total, and dual 2.5GbE ports as standard. Interestingly, there&apos;s also an HDMI port at the back that lets you connect the NAS straight to your TV — a good option if you don&apos;t want to stream over the network.</p><p>Basically, the AS5402T doesn&apos;t have anything missing on the hardware front, so if you want multi-Gigabit connectivity and plenty of M.2 bays, the NAS is the way to go. The Celeron J5105 is great at transcodes too, so if you have Plex Pass, you can use hardware transcodes on devices that can&apos;t natively play back content.</p><p>The ADM software is decent too; you get a native Plex client, containerization, and a ton of useful utilities. The interface isn&apos;t quite as polished as DSM, and the mobile clients aren&apos;t as refined, but on the whole, ASUSTOR is doing a good job on the software side of things as well.</p><p>The AS5402T has better hardware than other 2-bay servers in this segment, so if that is your main consideration, you&apos;ll find plenty to like with the NAS.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-best-value"><span>Best value</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="DRULT2R7CQt4hpmVze3mY" name="terramaster-f4-423-7.jpg" alt="TerraMaster F4-423 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DRULT2R7CQt4hpmVze3mY.jpg" mos="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/iMt4dTLKQPTtARur59fYuS.jpg" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<div class="buying-guide-block"><h3 id="4-terramaster-f4-423-2"><span class="title__text"><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/terramaster-f4-423-review">4. TerraMaster F4-423</a></span><span class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span></span></h3><div class="_hawk subtitle"><p>Easily the best value</p></div><p class="specs__container"><strong>Internal drive bays: </strong>Four (maximum 18TB each bay) 3.5-inch HDD 2.5-inch HDD 2.5-inch SSD | <strong>CPU: </strong>Quad-core 2.0GHz Intel Celeron N5095 64-bit | <strong>RAM: </strong>4GB ECC DDR4, upgradeable to 32GB | <strong>USB ports: </strong>2 x USB 3.2 Gen1 | <strong>Dimensions: </strong>227 x 225x 136mm</p><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Powerful Intel hardware</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Great at transcoding</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Dual 2.5GbE connectivity</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Two M.2 slots</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">Software isn&apos;t great</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">Limited upgradability</div></div>
<p>I&apos;ve used enough TerraMaster NAS servers over the years to know that the brand prioritizes value, and that&apos;s no different with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/terramaster-f4-423-review">F4-423</a>. The 4-bay NAS server manages to undercut its rivals by a considerable margin, offering Intel&apos;s Celeron N5095, 4GB of RAM, dual 2.5 Gigabit Ethernet ports, HDMI connectivity, and two M.2 slots.</p><p>Considering you get all of that at under $400 is a bargain in and of itself, and the NAS holds up incredibly well in daily use. It has a native Plex client, handles 4K content and transcodes without any issues, and the HDMI port lets you connect the NAS to your TV.</p><p>TerraMaster&apos;s biggest limitation in the past was the software, but that has changed in recent months with the introduction of TOS6. The new interface is cleaner and easier to use, and it has useful features. It still doesn&apos;t quite have the same level of polish as other vendors, and the mobile utilities are lacking. That said, you get the basics, and it&apos;s clear that TerraMaster is intent on tweaking its software.</p><p>So if you want the best bargain out of a Plex server, just get the F4-423.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-best-software"><span>Best software</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="8H4XG8zH74V5MubFfC3dx5" name="diskstation-ds923-plus-review-20.jpg" alt="Synology DiskStation DS923+ review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8H4XG8zH74V5MubFfC3dx5.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<div class="buying-guide-block"><h3 id="5-synology-diskstation-ds923-2"><span class="title__text"><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/synology-diskstation-ds923-plus-long-term-review">5. Synology DiskStation DS923+</a></span><span class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span></span></h3><div class="_hawk subtitle"><p>Best software features</p></div><p class="specs__container"><strong>Internal drive bays: </strong>Four (18TB each bay), 3.5-inch HDD, 2.5-inch HDD/SSD, M.2 storage  | <strong>CPU: </strong>Dual-core 2.6GHz AMD Ryzen R1600, 64-bit | <strong>RAM: </strong>4GB DDR4 ECC, two SODIMM slots, up to 32GB total | <strong>USB ports: </strong>2 x USB 3.1 Gen1 | <strong>Dimensions: </strong>166 x 199 x 223mm</p><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Great as a 4-bay Plex media server</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Powerful Ryzen hardware</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Two M.2 slots and 4GB RAM</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Class-leading software features</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">Doesn&apos;t handle Plex transcodes</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">No 2.5GbE ports as standard</div></div>
<p>The DiskStation DS9xx series has always been a best-seller, and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/synology-diskstation-ds923-plus-long-term-review">DiskStation DS923+</a> maintains that streak. The NAS now uses Ryzen hardware in lieu of Intel, and because it doesn&apos;t have an integrated GPU, you lose out on Plex transcoding. So if you absolutely need to use the feature, you should consider the DS423+ instead.</p><p>Although most models in this category have 2.5GbE or even 10GbE, the DS923+ is limited to dual Gigabit Ethernet ports. If you want multi-Gigabit connectivity, you&apos;ll need to pay another $100 to get a 10GbE network card and slot it into the NAS. So why should you consider the NAS? For starters, the AMD hardware is outstanding; it is noticeably faster in daily use, and that makes the DS923+ better-suited for demanding tasks.</p><p>And while you don&apos;t get Plex transcodes, the DS923+ is a standout choice for media streaming. It handles Plex playback without any issues whatsoever, doing a great job with high bitrate content across two devices at the same time. The DSM software is the best around, and because you get 4GB of RAM, you can run virtualization tasks and containers with relative ease.</p><p>There&apos;s also the ability to add more drive bays down the line; the DS923+ has four bays as standard, but you can buy an external housing like the DX517 and connect up to five additional drives to the NAS. It&apos;s this extensibility combined with the powerful hardware that gives it an edge over servers like the DS423+.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-best-budget"><span>Best budget</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="9p5bjazVJrDcLqHab4wQm8" name="synology-diskstation-ds223j-12.jpg" alt="Synology DiskStation DS223j review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9p5bjazVJrDcLqHab4wQm8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<div class="buying-guide-block"><h3 id="6-synology-diskstation-ds223j-2"><span class="title__text"><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/synology-diskstation-ds223j-review">6. Synology DiskStation DS223j</a></span><span class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span></span></h3><div class="_hawk subtitle"><p>Best budget Plex NAS</p></div><p class="specs__container"><strong>Internal drive bays: </strong>Two bays, 32TB total storage | <strong>CPU: </strong>1.7GHz 64-bit quad-core Realtek RTD1619B | <strong>RAM: </strong>1GB RAM | <strong>USB ports: </strong>2 x USB 3.1 Gen1 ports | <strong>Dimensions: </strong>165 x 100 x 225.5mm</p><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="hawk-wrapper"></div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Reliable hardware</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Comes with 1GB of memory</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Good as a Plex server</div><div class="icon icon-plus_circle _hawk">Robust software</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">Single Gigabit Ethernet port</div><div class="icon icon-minus_circle _hawk">No upgradability</div></div>
<p>The DiskStation DS223j doesn&apos;t have powerful hardware, but it still manages to do a great job when it comes to Plex. You can install the native Plex client and stream content to devices on your home network, but the Realtek hardware doesn&apos;t have transcoding.</p><p>You may think 1GB of RAM is too low, but it&apos;s more than adequate for the DSM software, and it is double that its predecessor — the DiskStation DS220j — offered. As it is an entry-level model, the DS223j doesn&apos;t have any upgradability; the RAM modules are soldered, and you can&apos;t add multi-Gigabit connectivity.</p><p>That said, if you just need an affordable NAS server to store your media collection and back up photos and videos, the DS223j is a good choice to consider. The DSM software is easily the best in this category, and while you don&apos;t get the more advanced features, all the basics are covered.</p>
<ul><li><a href="#main"><strong>Back to the top^</strong></a></li></ul>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-faq"><span>FAQ</span></h2>
<h2 id="what-makes-plex-such-a-good-media-server-2">What makes Plex such a good media server?</h2>
<p>As a high-level overview, Plex is a free media server utility that catalogs your media collection and makes it available for streaming on all of the connected devices in your home. </p><p>It is often considered to be the best media server around, and there are a few reasons for that. First up is the fact that it&apos;s available on just about any ecosystem: Android, iOS, Windows, macOS, Android TV, all streaming dongles, and most smart TVs. Basically, you can install Plex on all the devices you own. </p><p>Plex also does a great job with media organization. It sorts your music, movies, and TV shows into relevant categories, and adds high-resolution album art, covers, trailers, and metadata automatically. Also, as the content is streamed locally within your home network, it doesn&apos;t count toward your internet bandwidth costs.</p>
<h2 id="what-is-plex-transcode-and-how-does-it-work-2">What is Plex transcode, and how does it work?</h2>
<p>The biggest reason for Plex&apos;s dominance has to do with the fact that it can play any file on any device. Plex has a powerful transcoding service baked in, and if you have the paid <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/plex-pass">Plex Pass</a> plan, you can unlock hardware acceleration — that makes a huge difference for transcoding 4K files.</p><p>Even if you&apos;re using an iPhone, iPad, Amazon tablet, an older smart TV, or an Android phone, you can confidently play your media library on any device without any issues. Plex handles transcodes automatically, so there&apos;s no intervention needed from your side — and that makes it a fantastic media streaming service. </p><p>Plex streaming generally falls into three categories:</p>
<ul><li><strong>Direct Play</strong>:<strong> </strong>This is when the Plex client (your TV or streaming box) natively handles the video container and just streams the file as-is without any issues. This uses minimal resources. </li><li><strong>Direct Stream</strong>: In this scenario, the client device you're using can play the video and audio streams, but does not work with the container (like .mkv or .m4a), so Plex will copy those streams to a compatible container and send it to your device. This mode uses a few resources, but it isn't demanding on the server. </li><li><strong>Transcode</strong>: This is where things get interesting. Plex will transcode files when a client device is unable to play the video or audio streams at all. This is due to the lack of audio or video codecs (like H.265, HEVC, H.264) on the client device, and in this situation Plex converts the video to a file that can be played on the device. This is the most CPU-intensive option and needs a powerful NAS. </li></ul>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-how-to-choose"><span>How to choose</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="zwiFAa2FkXip8r9xKenRHi" name="synology-diskstation-ds224-plus-14.jpg" alt="Synology DiskStation DS224+ review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zwiFAa2FkXip8r9xKenRHi.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>There are a few things you&apos;ll need to pay attention to if you&apos;re interested in a Plex NAS. </p>
<h2 id="cpu-2">CPU</h2>
<p>This is a key consideration when choosing a Plex NAS, as you&apos;ll need a powerful CPU for transcodes. Most servers over $400 meet this criteria, but as a general rule, you&apos;ll need a recent Intel chipset — Celeron models are good for home use, but if you&apos;re sharing your Plex server with friends and family and need more bandwidth, you&apos;ll need to look at servers featuring Intel Core hardware.</p><p>While AMD has made inroads into the NAS category , Intel is still king here. If you want the ability to transcode 4K content in Plex, you&apos;ll need to buy a NAS server with a recent-gen Intel Celeron or Core CPU.</p>
<h2 id="memory-2">Memory</h2>
<p>Basically, you&apos;ll need a decent amount of RAM to make sure there are no bottlenecks. Plex isn&apos;t memory-intensive, but if you have a lot of other services running on the NAS, it could become an issue. Generally, 2GB of RAM is the bare minimum in this category, and if you&apos;re looking to run a lot of services, I&apos;d suggest getting an 8GB memory module and slotting it in. </p><p>Most NAS servers let you upgrade the RAM with ease, so you shouldn&apos;t have any issues slotting in 8GB or more memory within the server should you need it. </p>
<h2 id="connectivity-2">Connectivity</h2>
<p>Most NAS servers have two Gigabit ports as standard, and that should be adequate for home use. But if you&apos;re sharing your Plex instance and need additional bandwidth, you should look at a server with 2.5GbE or even 10 Gigabit Ethernet connectivity. </p><p>That said, if you switch to a NAS with multi-Gigabit connectivity, you&apos;ll need to simultaneously upgrade your switch and router to take full advantage of the additional bandwidth on offer. It isn&apos;t as costly as it used to be to switch to a 10GbE home network, but you&apos;ll have to take those additional costs into consideration. For now, Gigabit Ethernet is more than adequate for handling a few Plex 4K streams without any issues. </p><p>Some NAS models feature an HDMI port that lets you connect the server to a TV or monitor. This is useful as you can then play the media stored on the NAS directly without having to stream it wirelessly on your home network. </p>
<h2 id="what-is-the-best-plex-server-2">What is the best Plex server?</h2>
<p>There are plenty of options if you want the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-nas-home">best NAS for home</a> use, and you can choose between entry-level picks that have a single or two drive bays, and there are four-bay models that are designed to last. </p><p>But if you&apos;re in the best Plex server, there are a few additional points to consider. For one thing, Plex transcoding is a very CPU-intensive task, so you will need to look at NAS enclosures that have a powerful chipset. Thankfully, the biggest NAS manufacturers — Synology, QNAP, and ASUSTOR — deliver models catered for Plex media streaming. </p><p>Synology&apos;s DiskStation DS224+ illustrates this point perfectly — the two-bay NAS server features the Intel Celeron J4125 and handles Plex native streaming as well as transcoding without breaking a sweat. </p><p>If you want a little more room, the DiskStation DS423+ has four bays that can hold up to 64TB of storage in total. The rest of the features as the same as the DS224+, but you get two M.2 slots. </p>
<h2 id="which-plex-nas-should-you-buy-2">Which Plex NAS should you buy?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="CgHnSG9xvby8NcFpW7RCjg" name="synology-diskstation-ds224-plus-12.jpg" alt="Synology DiskStation DS224+ review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CgHnSG9xvby8NcFpW7RCjg.jpg" mos="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6mrSaiQnv5ZxrNjv8yjAJS.jpg" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Right now, if you&apos;re looking to pick up a NAS for Plex streaming, the best option is the DiskStation DS224+. The upgraded internal hardware makes it an enticing model in this category, and with two Gigabit Ethernet ports and robust software features, the NAS has all the basics covered.</p><p>ASUSTOR&apos;s AS5402T is a really good contender as well, and it delivers the best hardware package in this segment. </p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-how-we-test"><span>How we test</span></h3>
<h2 id="our-testing-methodology-for-the-best-plex-server-2">Our testing methodology for the best Plex server</h2>
<p>There are a few things I consider when deciding what NAS servers to recommend for Plex streaming. First up is the CPU; I run a few synthetic tests to determine its performance potential, looking at single and multi-core scores. </p><p>Then I set up a native Plex install on the NAS and run multimedia streaming tests to see resource usage in real-world scenarios when streaming 720p, 1080p, and 4K files on the local network. </p><p>I also evaluate transcoding potential by streaming a 4K file to a device that doesn&apos;t handle the native container — this is a great way to determine if the NAS can handle on-the-fly transcodes for 4K files with high bitrates. </p><p>Finally, I look at sequential read/write potential by transferring an image library containing over 5,000 files (all under 1MB), and a dozen media files over 1GB in size. </p><p>Ultimately, the best Plex server needs to be able to stream your local media library to all devices on your home network (and over the internet), and it should be able to do so consistently for several years. </p><p>All of the NAS models highlighted in this post can do just that, so if you&apos;re looking to get your hands on a Plex NAS server, you can go ahead and pick up any models in this list with confidence. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/best-nas-plex</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Looking for the best NAS for Plex streaming? You've come to the right place. Plex lets you stream your media collection on any connected device, and there are plenty of great NAS enclosures tailored to deliver great performance when using Plex. These are the best NAS for Plex. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">3jUYKvjQ9D3MH7JPFtUv25</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rSc3FQoKFPYm9K5DGxptLf.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 03:58:23 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Smart Home]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rSc3FQoKFPYm9K5DGxptLf.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Synology DiskStation DS220+]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Synology DiskStation DS220+]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>