<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 16:56:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Oppo Find X8 will likely have narrower bezels, just like the iPhone ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Oppo's upcoming Find X8 series should likely incorporate similarities to the latest iPhone 16 series.</li><li>The Find X8 models could include flat sides, rounded corners, a camera control button dubbed Quick Action, and narrow bezels.</li><li>The Find X8 series are rumored to launch with Dimensity 9400 SoC in the coming weeks.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Oppo&apos;s Find X8 series is the company&apos;s much-awaited launch, which is slated to happen later this year. Ahead of the anticipated launch, the company&apos;s Chief Product Officer, Pete Lau, has shared a teaser image of the device placed right next to Apple&apos;s latest iPhone 16 series.</p><p>The same image has also been shared by Oppo&apos;s Find Series Product Manager, Zhou Yibao, on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://weibo.com/5313402944/OxPHpDPg0">his Weibo account</a>. While Lau&apos;s X post doesn&apos;t specify which phones are being showcased in the shard image, it is still understandable as one is the latest Pro model of the iPhone 16 lineup, which has slimmer screen bezels all around than the predecessor models. The phone sitting next to it is evidently the upcoming Find X8 series device, which also features an identical narrow bezel similar to the iPhone.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">pic.twitter.com/rvNQiHr6Tg<a href="https://twitter.com/PeteLau/status/1836965936001159246">September 20, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>Per the shared image, both phones look identical, to say the least, with narrower bezels, as mentioned. Tipster Ice Universe, however, noted in the comments, suggesting that the said comparison in the images is between the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/everything-the-iphone-16-and-apple-watch-series-10-stole-from-android">iPhone 16 Pro</a> and the Oppo Find X8, which is believed to have narrower bezels than the former, notes the tipster. While the iPhone 16 Pro bezels have been reduced significantly, it will be interesting to see <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android counterparts</a> jumping on the bandwagon so early.</p><p>The similarities don&apos;t seem to end just with the bezels. This year, the iPhone 16 Pro and other models in the lot are equipped with a new Camera Control button that gives users several camera controls with just a tap.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">What iPhone 16 has, OPPO Find X8 series also has. 😏 pic.twitter.com/5Ie4FTSyUM<a href="https://twitter.com/UniverseIce/status/1828612467746054291">August 28, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div></div>
<p>Earlier, Ice Universe shared the image of the Find X8 series, which also includes a similar button right along the volume rockers and the power button. This button is likely to be dubbed the Quick Button and should include similar, if not better, functionalities. That could be another reason behind Pete Lau&apos;s new shared image on X.</p><p>The other interesting details from the previously shared image include a giant camera visor at the back of the Oppo Find X8. It is rumored to include a 50MP primary camera next to a 50MP ultra-wide angle lens and an additional 3x periscope zoom camera.</p>
<p>The other rumored device specs (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.gsmarena.com/oppo_find_x8_will_oneup_the_iphone_16_pro_in_one_key_area_-news-64623.php">GSMArena</a>) comprise a 6.7-inch LTPO display featuring Full HD Plus resolution and a 120Hz refresh rate. Underneath, the device is expected to be powered by MediaTek&apos;s latest Dimensity 9400 SoC, and keeping the lights on would be a whopping 5600mAh battery capacity.</p><p>It additionally supports 100W superfast charging speeds. According to the latest rumors, other nifty add-ons for the upcoming Find X8 that match Apple include Oppo&apos;s version of Dynamic Island and magnetic wireless charging. </p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oppo-find-x8-series-to-sport-narrow-bezels</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Find X8 series is likely to take on Apple's latest iPhone 16 series in terms of design. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">T7e4tPwPVcNrJSnxyGemgj</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NrnibESzjbqaNsAEcSrviN.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 16:54:18 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NrnibESzjbqaNsAEcSrviN.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Pete Lau on X]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Oppo Find X8 teaser image]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Oppo Find X8 teaser image]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Pixel Watch's upcoming 'Performance Loop' band could be exactly what it needs ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>An unannounced Pixel Watch band, referred to as the "Performance Loop Band," has appeared for a second time.</li><li>After accidentally showing up in an Amazon listing last month, the bands popped up yet again on Best Buy and Amazon's online Canadian sites. </li><li>The existence of a soft Performance Loop band would fill a massive gap in the Pixel Watch ecosystem, offering an alternative to Apple's Sport Loop bands.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google recently launched the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-3-review">Pixel Watch 3</a>, but there&apos;s still one more thing wearable fans have been waiting for. Shortly after the Pixel Watch 3 was officially announced, an Amazon listing appeared for a "Performance Loop Band," which was seemingly posted in error. It was pulled, and Google never officially acknowledged the existence of the Performance Loop band. However, as spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.droid-life.com/2024/09/19/pixel-watch-3-performance-loop-band-shows-up-again/" target="_blank">Droid Life</a>, the band recently appeared in another pair of retail listings before being quickly removed. </p><p>The listings were posted to Best Buy Canada and Amazon Canada on Sept. 19 and were fairly detailed. There are band options in at least four colors, called <strong>Dark</strong>, <strong>Light</strong>, <strong>Mojito</strong>, and <strong>Cosmic</strong>. The first two are basic black and white colorways, but the latter are bright green and pink hues. Here&apos;s how Best Buy describes the Performance Loop in the most recent listing (via Droid Life): </p><p>"Functionality and style comes with the Google Pixel Watch 3 (41mm) Performance loop band. Your new run buddy is micro-adjustable for the perfect fit, featuring the right amount of stretch during workouts. It’s made with comfortable recycled fabric."</p><p>Although this description only notes that the Performance Loop is for the Pixel Watch 3 (41mm), that&apos;s just because there are separate listings for sizes and colors. A few product pages appeared for the 45mm Pixel Watch 3, signaling that this fresh strap will support <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-3">the entire Pixel Watch family</a>. It is marketed as a fitness-first smartwatch band with superb breathability and comfort, kind of like the Sport Loop band that Apple sells for the Apple Watch. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1700px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:111.94%;"><img id="tKYsXeoHmdHsx3PKLbo6Fj" name="Pixel-Watch-3-Performance-Loop-Band.jpg" alt="The images of Performance Loop bands from a pulled online retailer listing." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tKYsXeoHmdHsx3PKLbo6Fj.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1700" height="1903" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Droid Life)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Similarly to the Sport Loop, the Performance Loop has a fabric material and an elastic strap design, using a "micro-adjustable" Velcro closure mechanism. However, compared to the Woven Band, it has thinner and tighter stitching. The entire band uses nylon, recycled polyester, and elastane yarn. </p><p>All signs are pointing to the Performance Band costing around $60, if not cheaper. The first Amazon listing priced the strap at $43.04 in U.S. dollars, while the second set of product pages priced it at $79.99 in Canadian dollars. If the Performance Loop matches the price conversions of existing Pixel Watch bands between U.S. and Canadian dollars, it would cost $59.99 in U.S. dollars. This is all to be confirmed because Google hasn&apos;t even officially announced this band yet. </p><p>While we still don&apos;t have an official release date, the fact that the Performance Loop has appeared once again in multiple listings could mean a launch is imminent.</p>
<h2 id="where-are-all-the-pixel-watch-bands-2">Where are all the Pixel Watch bands?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.20%;"><img id="DCLtSuH9PjfKsbHMBVYe3J" name="google-pixel-watch-bands-lineup-lifestyle.jpg" alt="Google Pixel Watch Bands lineup lifestyle" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DCLtSuH9PjfKsbHMBVYe3J.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1686" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>A Sport Loop competitor feels long overdue for the Pixel Watch band lineup, as Google offers a few other competing versions of popular Apple Watch bands. The Stretch Band, a continuous loop of similar fabric material to the unreleased Performance Loop, matches up well with Apple&apos;s Solo Loop. The Active Sport Band compares to Apple&apos;s Sport Band, and so on. However, for people who don&apos;t find Google&apos;s first-party Active Sport Bands or Stretch Bands comfortable for workouts, something was missing. </p><p>Being that the Pixel Watch product category is only a few generations old, the market for third-party watch bands isn&apos;t as robust as for, say, Apple or Samsung watches. It doesn&apos;t help that the Pixel Watch uses a proprietary band connection system. It&apos;s specific to the Pixel Watch family, much like the Apple Watch system. Since the Pixel Watch simply doesn&apos;t command the same sales as the Apple Watch, there is less incentive for watch band manufacturers to support the lineup. </p><p>Apple succeeds in the first and third-party band markets because it moves enough volume to sell an assortment of different SKUs, and Apple Watch owners are willing to pay for great third-party bands. Samsung, on the other hand, avoided the Pixel Watch&apos;s current problem by not using a proprietary band connection system at all. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-7-review">Galaxy Watch 7</a> uses standard 20mm watch bands, just like previous Galaxy Watch models. </p><p>There are pros and cons to going with a proprietary band connection system or choosing to stick with a standard. Historically, the watch lugs of a Galaxy Watch don&apos;t look as seamless as the design of a Pixel Watch or Galaxy Watch. With that being said, Galaxy Watches can tap into a rich market of third-party watch bands, which is a real plus. </p><p>I&apos;ve tried a Pixel Watch, and the disappointing band selection was one of the many things that pushed me back to watches from Apple and Samsung. Hopefully, Google can start improving this by making the rumored Performance Loop available for Pixel Watch owners soon. </p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="1079bb26-80b5-4c55-93cd-5f3d103e3370">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4BD26EjLWStMJGQGXfA4va.jpg' alt="Google Pixel Watch 3 45mm Official Render - Active Band - Hazel - side"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel Watch 3</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Better than ever</strong></em></p>
<p>The Pixel Watch 3 may not look like much of an upgrade, but it's arguably the best Wear OS smartwatch on the market.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/the-pixel-watchs-upcoming-performance-loop-band-could-be-exactly-what-it-needs</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The people want the Pixel Watch Performance Loop, and it keeps popping up despite the band not even being official yet. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">7Yu7RyhkoKbmiwbrDD3wad</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hRKq93eeHS98iwunGtXR2R.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 15:44:08 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hRKq93eeHS98iwunGtXR2R.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Three Google Pixel Watch 3s on display at the Made by Google 2024 event.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Three Google Pixel Watch 3s on display at the Made by Google 2024 event.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Chrome's latest update includes a Google Calendar overview on the new tab page ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Chrome profiles gain improvements as part of the new feature rollout this week.</li><li>Admins get the latest customization and granular policy controls for user groups in the organization.</li><li>Tab experiences on Chrome also receive customization options and integration of Google Calendar on the new tab page.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>This week, Google Chrome Enterprise gained some new productivity capabilities to help Google Workspace users who rely on their browsers for everyday work with services like Gmail and Google Docs.</p><p>In a recent <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/chrome-enterprise/chrome-enterprise-improves-management-and-productivity-capabilities-for-google-workspace-users/">Google Cloud blog post</a>, the search giant shared all the new changes, including new Chrome profile management capabilities for IT teams that manage browsers and some productivity features for Workspace consumers.</p><p>Admins managing profiles get the latest benefits, such as the ability to "Tailor Chrome settings and policies for specific user groups or roles within your organization."</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:959px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:62.57%;"><img id="kW7zXXcmiqqjP3MJC2DtPQ" name="chrome-enterprise-work-profiles-view.jpg" alt="Google Chrome update" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kW7zXXcmiqqjP3MJC2DtPQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="959" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>They can also impose security policies at the profile level, which ensures the protection of sensitive data on personal devices for users signed in to Chrome. They can provide secure browsing environments for personal and contractor devices.</p><p>Users can further separate their work and personal data with relevant profiles in Chrome to improve their productivity and user experience.</p>
<p>Workspace consumers will also have more visibility into Chrome user profiles in their organizations thanks to new profile listings and the ability to report with Google Cloud Identity. There&apos;s now a unified view that showcases users&apos; profiles of their organization, browser version, applied policies, and installed extensions, among other things. This feature is said to be generally available in the coming months.</p><p>Another interesting addition is for admins, who can "also benefit from new Device Trust Connectors with Okta, Ping, and Cisco Duo for context-aware access. Chrome can share device signals with partners when a user is signed in to Chrome (or when a user is in a Chrome Profile)." </p><p>The aim is to free up admins from having to maintain the device and create context-aware access controls for their expanded workforce. Consumers can further limit access to Workspace and other SaaS applications and exchange signals using Workspace context-aware access restrictions or Chrome Enterprise Premium.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:889px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:67.49%;"><img id="mmCLDCvdqhSaSjriEHCYTS" name="google-chrome-new-sign-in-flow.gif" alt="Google Chrome update" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mmCLDCvdqhSaSjriEHCYTS.gif" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="889" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>A new sign-in flow window for Chrome is also expected to roll out in the coming weeks. This window claims to give more transparency to business users. It should make it easier to manage personal and work profiles. Business users can also see the types of data their organization has access to. </p><p>Additionally, they are allowed to move their current bookmarks, extensions, and other relevant browser data between personal and work profiles, or they can choose to keep them separate altogether.</p><p>Going further, Chrome Enterprise users will now be able to see an overview of their daily Google Calendar or Drive in the new tab page, giving them easier access. This feature is already rolling out, so if you are one of them, you should be on the lookout.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:747px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:80.32%;"><img id="h5mNCm5vd9MLVsuQCBS4HQ" name="google-calendar-intergration-chrome.jpg" alt="Google Chrome update" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/h5mNCm5vd9MLVsuQCBS4HQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="747" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Admins will be able to create site shortcuts directly on the address bar. "These can be tailored to specific groups, such as giving the entire sales team easy access to Salesforce." This is also currently rolling out and will be available for all users, even if they are now Workspace users.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1239px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:48.43%;"><img id="rLjQ3JBXgmevffy9BPDcBQ" name="chrome-enterprise-site-search-new.jpg" alt="Google Chrome update" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rLjQ3JBXgmevffy9BPDcBQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1239" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>After Chrome Desktop allowed syncing tab groups across multiple desktops, a new feature allows them to save and sync across all devices, including <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android devices</a> and iOS handsets. Chrome will also proactively suggest pages to revisit based on your previous tab activity—these were part of the latest <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-chrome-update-brings-better-organization-of-tabs">Google Chrome update</a>, which has already rolled out. These are some of the tab improvements that are coming for Chrome users and Enterprise users across platforms.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-chrome-enterprise-get-new-handy-tools</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google has also rolled out new functionalities for IT admins who manage work profiles on Chrome. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">vgctA5TBNJ49WBEXYbg8XD</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yW898rfyAU8H93z54gtmpN.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 15:13:14 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yW898rfyAU8H93z54gtmpN.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Chris Wedel / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Chrome lifestyle]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Chrome lifestyle]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ How to use Sketch to Image on a Samsung Galaxy phone ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Once you discover how to use Sketch to Image, it might turn into one of the things you do to help you pass the time. This fun feature can turn drawings into proper pictures, creating something you might use on your social media accounts or share with friends. Galaxy AI makes it possible to make the most out of freehand scribbles, converting wiggly lines into beautiful artwork.</p><p>At the time of writing, you can only use the feature on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6</a> and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-6-review">Galaxy Z Flip 6</a>, but Samsung plans to roll it out to other <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-samsung-phones">Samsung phones</a> in the future. Sketch to Image is easy to use, but you need to have the Drawing Assist feature enabled in settings before using it.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-turn-on-drawing-assist-2">How to turn on Drawing Assist</h2>
<p>Enabling Drawing Assist is important because it&apos;s the feature that allows you to use Sketch to Image. If you don&apos;t have Drawing Assist on, you can&apos;t use Sketch to Image; therefore, it is important to go into your Android phone&apos;s settings to check it&apos;s on.</p><p>1. Go to <strong>Settings</strong>.</p><p>2. Choose <strong>Galaxy AI</strong>.</p><p>3. Select <strong>Drawing Assist,</strong> and on the next page, you should see the option to toggle it on. There will also be text describing what the feature does.</p><p>Now you can turn on Sketch to image, and then have some fun with the feature!</p>
<h2 id="how-to-use-sketch-to-image-2">How to use Sketch to Image</h2>
<p>You can access the Sketch to Image feature through <strong>Edge panels</strong>. If it isn&apos;t enabled, you can go to <strong>Settings > Display</strong>.</p><p>1. <strong>Swipe left</strong> on the top right side of the screen.</p><p>2. Tap on the <strong>Sketch to Image icon</strong>. You can also access it using the S Pen&apos;s Air command menu.</p><p>3. <strong>Draw something</strong> on the canvas, but to change the transparency of the background screen, tap on the square icon to the left of the three dots.</p><p>4. <strong>Choose the style</strong> you want to give the image. There are five options: Watercolor, Illustration, Sketch, Pop Art, and 3D Cartoon.</p><p>5. Tap the <strong>Generate button</strong>. Swipe to see the various results, and if you want to save one, tap on the dots.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2062px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:38.80%;"><img id="629Bs3QoZtCP7khKTBEW8W" name="Sketch-to-Image-Z-Fold-6-Edge-Panel.jpg" alt="Steps to use Sketch to Image on Galaxy Z Fold 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/629Bs3QoZtCP7khKTBEW8W.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="2062" height="800" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>You can also use <strong>Sketch to Image</strong> by using the <strong>Samsung Notes app</strong>. Once you have it open, do the following.</p><p>1. Create a <strong>new note</strong> by tapping the pencil option at the bottom.</p><p>2. If you&apos;re using the <strong>S Pen</strong>, you can <strong>start drawing immediately</strong>. But if you want to <strong>draw using your finger</strong>, tap the <strong>overflow menu</strong> in the top right corner and choose <strong>Finger drawing</strong>.</p><p>3. When you&apos;re done drawing, tap the <strong>Galaxy AI option</strong> resembling a star pair.</p><p>4. Tap the <strong>Sketch to Image</strong> option from the list. If you tap the Galaxy AI option before you draw anything, you won&apos;t see the Sketch to Image option.</p><p>5. <strong>Circle your drawing</strong>; you should see a frame around it with the style option at the bottom. You&apos;ll see the same style options: Watercolor, Illustration, Sketch, Pop art, and 3D cartoon.</p><p>6. <strong>Tap the Generate</strong> button and select the best result. You&apos;ll have different options. Tap the Replace or Add to Note option to save your favorite.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2062px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:38.80%;"><img id="UY5FgF4pTR7f7gXTAH4d7K" name="Sketch-to-Image-Samsung-Z-Fold-6.jpg" alt="Using Sketch to Image using Samsung Notes." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/UY5FgF4pTR7f7gXTAH4d7K.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="2062" height="800" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p> If you choose the Replace option, your sketch will disappear, and you&apos;ll only see the AI-generated image. The Add to Note option keeps both possibilities, and the AI-generated image will be added below the sketch. If you&apos;re not happy with the results, you can tap the Generate button again to create a new batch.</p>
<h2 id="which-phones-have-sketch-to-image-2">Which phones have Sketch to Image?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="EmSigZ7prjRbed97djK7QZ" name="samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review-22.jpg" alt="Galaxy Z Fold 6 "Sketch to Image"" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/EmSigZ7prjRbed97djK7QZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2500" height="1406" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Currently, the Sketch to Image feature is limited to the Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 and Galaxy Z Flip 6 running One UI 6.1.1. Hopefully, users of other Samsung Galaxy models will soon be able to use it.</p>
<h2 id="keep-on-sketching-2">Keep on sketching</h2>
<p>While AI like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-gemini-app-android" target="_blank">Gemini Advance</a> can create images, it cannot convert your sketches into art. With Sketch to Image, you can create images using the S Pen or your finger. But if you need more out of drawing, you can always go with one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-drawing-apps-android">best drawing apps</a> for your Android phone.</p><p>There are <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/best-android-tablets-drawing">Android tablets for traditional drawing</a>, which you can use if you&apos;re OK with using a bigger device. But keep in mind that even if you get a Samsung tablet, it won&apos;t have the Sketch to Image feature.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="15612be6-5536-4190-a276-da9d7b9c9ff4">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kBS2j2Pcq5xNYFf9FWBeCi.jpg' alt=" The Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="80" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The one with the massive screen</strong></em></p>
<p>With the Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6, you get a fantastic Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 processor and a 1TB storage option. Enjoy countless hours of fun with all the Galaxy AI features it comes with, enabling you to bring your sketches to life.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-to-use-sketch-to-image-on-a-samsung-galaxy-phone</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Learn how to use Sketch to Image on your Galaxy phone so can turn those scribbles into images with the power of AI. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">BDPGv79BJkrPdqgoPV5Xy4</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/EmSigZ7prjRbed97djK7QZ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 14:32:35 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ yorknectar@gmail.com (Judy Sanhz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/EmSigZ7prjRbed97djK7QZ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Galaxy Z Fold 6 &quot;Sketch to Image&quot;]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Galaxy Z Fold 6 &quot;Sketch to Image&quot;]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Apple iPhone 16 Pro Max vs. Google Pixel 9 Pro XL: Battle of intelligence ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[         <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="7ffbdf13-a3e8-4b10-afa0-19c2fceb6a7e">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VbwZvYREDXRTG6jtQhC29n.jpg' alt="iPhone 16 Pro Max"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Apple iPhone 16 Pro Max</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="80" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Going big</strong></em></p>
<p>The iPhone 16 Pro Max has the largest display ever shipped on an iPhone and features a new hardware camera button, better battery life, and 4K 120fps capability for the main camera.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Massive display</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Durable titanium construction</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>New 48MP ultrawide lens</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>4K 120fps ProRes recording</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Powerful performance</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Expensive</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Apple Intelligence AI features yet to come</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Not a massive upgrade over 15 Pro Max</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="90166ae6-7691-4c6b-b588-e63959bd9afd">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KuP5kCbWwCMJf95Fcb6Twb.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL official render- Obsidian - front and back"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 Pro XL</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="75" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>AI masterclass</strong></em></p>
<p>The Pixel 9 Pro XL offers some of the best AI features, cameras, and battery life of any Pixel to date. All of these things sort of make up for the average SoC performance and higher price compared to last year's model.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Seven years of software support</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Brilliant AI features that you can use today</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Highly dependable cameras</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Quicker charging speed</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>A bit pricey</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Tensor SoC is a letdown for gaming</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>128GB base storage is unacceptable</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<p>Doing an Apple vs. Android comparison is always tricky since they are based on completely different software platforms, and based on your current ecosystem of devices, you’re almost forced to go in just one direction, even if you’re not too happy with it. But if you’re just starting off or don’t care about ecosystem benefits, which is the best flagship phone to buy today? Apple’s best showcase is the newly launched iPhone 16 Pro Max. This is the top-of-the-line model with the largest display and the best specs. On the other side, we have Google’s Pixel 9 Pro XL which is arguably the best way to experience Android, the way Google intended it.</p><p>Both phones are priced roughly the same and boast cutting-edge hardware. For better or worse, AI is here to stay and that’s the current hook every manufacturer is grabbing on in order to sell their expensive devices. The iPhone 16 Pro Max and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-review">Pixel 9 Pro XL</a> support the best AI advancements from each camp. The question is, which one should you give your money to?</p>
<h2 id="apple-iphone-16-pro-max-vs-google-pixel-9-pro-xl-design-and-display-2">Apple iPhone 16 Pro Max vs. Google Pixel 9 Pro XL: Design and display</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="m7ZEgmEamVVUGYiDhqRRzj" name="google-pixel-9-pro-obsidian-and-pixel-9-pro-xl-hazel-display-02.jpg" alt="Comparing the display sizes of the Google Pixel 9 Pro to the Google Pixel 9 Pro XL" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/m7ZEgmEamVVUGYiDhqRRzj.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>If you love holding large slabs of glass and metal, you’ll love both these phones. The Pixel 9 Pro XL is a true successor to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-pro-review">Pixel 8 Pro</a> since it has similar dimensions. Google has changed the design quite a bit this year and it looks pretty epic in my opinion. The flattened side frame actually makes it look more like an iPhone than ever, and the aluminum and scratch-resistant glass gives it a very premium feel in the hand. It’s a bit heavy at 221g, but not too chunky.</p><p>The iPhone 16 Pro Max is pretty much indistinguishable from its predecessor at first glance. It’s grown a bit larger due to the bigger screen, and it’s slightly bigger than the 9 Pro XL in hand. It’s also heavier at 227g, but surprisingly slimmer than the Pixel at 8.3mm in depth. The Pro Max uses a sturdier titanium material for the frame and Apple’s own concoction for a scratch-protective glass which it calls Ceramic Shield. The phone gets a new dedicated camera button with haptic feedback, which lets you control various camera settings depending on how you press it.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1200px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="5rFsy2ZAZBs8Y467fpDE6K" name="iphone-16-pro-max-render_all-colors.jpg" alt="iPhone 16 Pro Max render all colors" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5rFsy2ZAZBs8Y467fpDE6K.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1200" height="675" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apple )</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Both phones have an IP68 rating, for dust and water resistance. Neither has expandable storage, so you need to think long and hard before picking a variant. Apple and Google use USB Type-C (USB 3.2) so file transfer speeds should be similar.</p><p>The displays on both phones are quite impressive. The Pixel 9 Pro XL has a 6.8-inch OLED display with a high resolution of 2,992x1,344 pixels. There’s LTPO tech, which means the refresh rate can vary from 1Hz to 120Hz. The display has a 20:9 aspect ratio, full support for HDR playback, and a peak brightness of up to 3,000 nits.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="EsQHpXFataHsUtdR7WU6Fe" name="google-pixel-9-pro-xl-hazel-back-03.jpg" alt="The back of the Hazel Google Pixel 9 Pro XL" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/EsQHpXFataHsUtdR7WU6Fe.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The iPhone 16 Pro Max’s display is particularly impressive this year as it’s a whopping 6.9 inches, with razor-slim bezels. The resolution has increased to 2,868x1,320 so as to keep the same pixel count as the previous model. The other new feature is that the brightness can now drop to 1 nit for the always-on mode, so there’s extra power saving. Other specs have remained the same like ProMotion 120Hz refresh rate, 1,000 nits of max typical brightness and up to 2,000 nits of peak brightness when using it outdoors during the day.</p>
<h2 id="apple-iphone-16-pro-max-vs-google-pixel-9-pro-xl-hardware-and-specs-2">Apple iPhone 16 Pro Max vs. Google Pixel 9 Pro XL: Hardware and specs</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1200px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="cwzcPjjSGaom2cFv4uLqNh" name="iphone-16-pro-max-render-showing-apple-intelligence.jpg" alt="iPhone 16 Pro in hand glowing" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/cwzcPjjSGaom2cFv4uLqNh.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1200" height="675" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apple )</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The iPhone 16 Pro Max starts at $1,199 for 256GB of storage and 8GB of RAM. In fact, all iPhone 16 models are confirmed to have 8GB of RAM in order to be able to run Apple Intelligence features. This might seem like a joke in the Android world, but it’s actually a big deal in iPhone land and it’s the first time we’re seeing the entire lineup with the same amount of RAM. It’s not an upgrade for the 16 Pro Max though, since the 15 Pro Max also had 8GB RAM.</p><p>There are four colors on offer – Desert Titanium, Natural Titanium, White Titanium, and Black Titanium. Internal storage can go up to 1TB, which costs $1,599. It’s fairly expensive, but the 9 Pro XL is no different. Google’s offering starts a little lower at $1,099, but this is for 128GB of storage. You’d ideally want at least 256GB which will set you back $1,199, same as the iPhone. There’s 512GB and 1TB options too (only in the Obsidian color) for $1,549. All variants come with 16GB of RAM, which is what we’d expect for a top-tier Android phone. The Pixel comes in four colors — Porcelain, Rose Quartz, Hazel, and Obsidian.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1853px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="wi5AHaiCwrBHXZVwrBa9KM" name="capture-button-iphone-16-pro.jpeg" alt="Capture Control button on the iPhone 16 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wi5AHaiCwrBHXZVwrBa9KM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1853" height="1042" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apple)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Wireless and 5G connectivity is similar across Apple and Google. The 16 Pro Max and 9 Pro XL support all the major 5G bands and carriers in the U.S., along with Wi-Fi 7, Bluetooth 5.3, NFC, Ultra Wideband, and satellite SOS service. You get secure biometric authentication on both, like an ultrasonic fingerprint reader on the Pixel and Face ID on the iPhone.</p>

<p>The iPhone 16 Pro Max is powered by the A18 Pro SoC which we have no doubt will be blisteringly powerful. Apple is claiming big gains in GPU computing and memory bandwidth compared to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/apple-iphone-15-pro-max-long-term-review"><u>iPhone 15 Pro Max</u></a>, which was stellar to begin with. Apple is promising improved battery life of up to 33 hours with the 16 Pro Max with video playback. The phone can be fast-charged up to 50% in 30 minutes, or quicker when paired with a higher-wattage adapter. It also supports <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-magsafe-accessories-for-android-phones">MagSafe</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/qi2">Qi2</a> wireless charging standards.</p><p>The Google Pixel 9 Pro XL is powered by the Tensor G4 SoC, which is the most power-efficient processor yet. In our ongoing review, we found that the thermals are much better controlled, although it still throttles hard when playing heavy games. It’s not a big step forward in terms of compute performance, and will certainly trail behind Apple’s offering. The 9 Pro XL does, however, boast of a 24+ hour battery life thanks to the large 5,060mAh capacity. Charging speeds have improved over the previous model and it can be charged up to 70% in 30 minutes using Google’s 45W charger. Fast wireless charging is also present if you use the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/pixel-stand-2nd-gen-charger-review">Pixel Stand (2nd Gen)</a> charger.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1305px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="MpegUgV4anbGrULwFq3Cuc" name="4k-120fps-video-recording-iphone-16-pro.jpeg" alt="4K/120FPS video recording on iPhone 16 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MpegUgV4anbGrULwFq3Cuc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1305" height="734" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apple)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Both phones should be almost evenly matched this generation when it comes to camera output. The Pixel 9 Pro XL and iPhone 16 Pro Max feature quality camera sensors, and will probably differ mainly when it comes to the image&apos;s color tone. The Pixel should still rule the house when it comes to capturing good details in zoom shots, thanks to its 48MP periscope telephoto camera. The iPhone has 5x optical zoom too, but it’s only a 12MP sensor.</p><p>The Pixel should also have an upper hand with selfies with its larger 42MP sensor. The 16 Pro Max does have one really cool trick up its sleeve, and that is its ability to shoot 4K 120fps Dolby Vision videos with the main camera. That’s a powerful tool for video creators, making this generation’s Pro series the best yet for video recording.</p>
<h2 id="apple-iphone-16-pro-max-vs-google-pixel-9-pro-xl-software-2">Apple iPhone 16 Pro Max vs. Google Pixel 9 Pro XL: Software</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="jdAzmevPuZciPCj5ocCH4o" name="google-pixel-9-pro-xl-hazel-camera-bar-01.jpg" alt="The shiny side rails and raised camera bar of the Hazel Google Pixel 9 Pro XL" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jdAzmevPuZciPCj5ocCH4o.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Apple and Google want you to ultimately buy their phones for the software experience. For Apple, there’s only one choice and that’s the iPhone. iOS 18, Apple’s latest version of its mobile OS, was just rolled out to the public and it features some major UI changes like the ability to add a custom color to all your app icons and new ways to interact with the shortcuts and toggle switches. The highlight addition though is Apple Intelligence, because simply calling it AI is too mainstream for Apple.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2251px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="JiGWg6FLwSwhLrrUz2F7mH" name="iphone-16-pro-emoji-creation-promo.jpg" alt="Create new emoji on iPhone 16 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JiGWg6FLwSwhLrrUz2F7mH.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2251" height="1266" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apple)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Apple’s AI feature will work across the range of iPhone 16 models and only the Pro models in the last gen, along with select models of the iPad and Mac. Many of the “new” features are already things <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/everything-ios-18-stole-from-android"><u>we’ve seen on Android phones</u></a>. The kicker though is that none of these features will be there on the iPhone 16 Pro Max the day you buy it. That’s right, Apple Intelligence will be coming this fall to all supported devices as an update, while other AI features won’t be here till early next year. That’s a big leap of faith for early adopters. One thing’s for sure, the 16 Pro Max will have at least five years of software support, considering the 2018 iPhone XR is also getting iOS 18.</p><p>The Google Pixel 9 Pro XL is promised to get seven years of OS upgrades, which is incredible and not just for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phone</a>. While it doesn’t ship with the latest version of Android (because it’s not rolled out yet), you do get all the AI features from day one. The Pixel line has survived all these years despite having basic hardware, purely on the prowess of Google’s software. The 9 Pro XL gets exclusive AI features like Reimagine and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/pixel-9-add-me-feature-is-quintessentially-google">Add Me</a> that no other previous-gen Pixel gets, which is a good incentive for users with an older Pixel to upgrade.</p>
<h2 id="apple-iphone-16-pro-max-vs-google-pixel-9-pro-xl-which-one-should-you-get-2">Apple iPhone 16 Pro Max vs. Google Pixel 9 Pro XL: Which one should you get?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="X24ZT2npofmK28hhCxyqCe" name="google-pixel-9-pro-xl-hazel-display-homescreen-01.jpg" alt="Theming the homescreen of the Google Pixel 9 Pro XL blue" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/X24ZT2npofmK28hhCxyqCe.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The iPhone 16 Pro Max is easily the finest mobile hardware Apple has produced, and if you’re in the ecosystem and have been waiting for it to upgrade from an older iPhone, then chances are you’ve already pre-booked it and are already using it. For the rest who don’t really have a platform preference and just want the best phone above $1,000, I’d put my money on the Pixel 9 Pro XL. Now before you sound off in the comments saying “Android Central chose an Android phone as the winner over an iPhone, big surprise!”, hear me out.</p><p>I fully concede that the iPhone 16 Pro Max will decimate the Pixel in tasks like gaming and it is superior for any kind of video work (as iPhones generally tend to be). But other than the new SoC, camera button, and new ultrawide sensor, it’s not too different from the 15 Pro Max, which should start seeing big discounts soon as Apple has officially discontinued it from its online store. This older model should be able to run Apple Intelligence just as well, whenever this feature does drop.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2137px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="NGcReMYfg9WS2zztqBMDFd" name="visual-intelligence-iphone-16-pro-3.jpeg" alt="Apple Visual Intelligence on iPhone 16 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NGcReMYfg9WS2zztqBMDFd.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2137" height="1202" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apple)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Pixel 9 Pro XL’s processor may lack the brute force of the iPhone’s chip, but it makes up for that in several other ways. For starters, it’s way cooler to look at and everyone will know it’s the latest Pixel. Secondly, the new AI features in Google’s first-party apps are scarily good and super useful. It also matches an iPhone in terms of longevity of software updates. We know the cameras are excellent for still photos and battery life is solid.</p><p>While you can make a case for the iPhone 16 Pro Max at launch if you’re one of those niche users that would actually take advantage of the hardware improvements, I think most users would get more use out of the 9 Pro XL’s superb AI features, which have a wider appeal.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="7f6c5e77-2073-4930-9986-6978c6423960">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Epz84yteXYHhCgKXftnMDm.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL official render - Rose Quartz - front and back"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 Pro XL</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The flagship for most people</strong></em></p>
<p>The Pixel 9 Pro XL features many worthy improvements over its predecessor and has some of the finest AI features, making it the better choice against the 16 Pro Max.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="4c6a4ba5-fb34-4043-8cc2-f4c50e4e4253">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SyPJPwQSfMgX5TEFK67cng.jpg' alt="iPhone 16 Pro render square "></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Apple iPhone 16 Pro Max</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Not yet intelligent</strong></em></p>
<p>The iPhone 16 Pro Max has incredibly powerful hardware and superb camera features that cinematographers will love. But its major highlight feature is coming later via an update, making it a hard sell at the moment.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/apple-iphone-16-pro-max-vs-google-pixel-9-pro-xl</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The iPhone 16 Pro Max and the Pixel 9 Pro XL are two powerful, premium smartphones. But only one has features that nearly all will appreciate. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">HRf8Zdh5mBbbDtMNDmGLGn</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/P9wDVkyG4gAJ6oyDvh7WWS.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 13:30:19 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ roydon.cerejo@gmail.com (Roydon Cerejo) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/P9wDVkyG4gAJ6oyDvh7WWS.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The back of the Hazel Google Pixel 9 Pro XL]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The back of the Hazel Google Pixel 9 Pro XL]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Massive COROS update fixes its new bike computer, ends support for one of its best watches ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The COROS PACE 2, VERTIX 1, and APEX Pro will no longer receive firmware updates after September, though they'll still receive app updates.</li><li>All COROS watches now receive Gear Tracking and Sleep Quality analysis through the app, while the newer watches get all-day sleep tracking, new pool swim and bike modes, plus other updates.</li><li>The COROS DURA, originally due out in July, now has real-time elevation, back-to-start guidance, and a ton of other new features. It launches on September 26.</li><li>All updates roll out to the public beta on September 23 and launch officially in October.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>COROS&apos; September update adds a few features to its watches and app that&apos;ll look familiar to Garmin fans, including gear tracking for your shoes and bikes, nap detection, and pool swim drills and intervals. Unfortunately, the update won&apos;t make it to <em>every</em> COROS watch.</p><p>Unlike other fitness brands that restrict the best software to pricier watches, COROS generally updates every watch it can. But the 2019 VERTIX and APEX Pro, plus the 2020 <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/coros-pace-2-review">COROS PACE 2</a>, have "reached their hardware&apos;s storage limit and will no longer receive future firmware updates."</p><p>Four years of active support for a $200 watch is nothing to sneeze at, and the PACE 2 will still receive app-based updates. But some runners will want to turn to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/coros-pace-3-review">COROS PACE 3</a> instead, since it will keep receiving new features and offer dual-band GPS.</p><p>Meanwhile, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/coros-dura-bike-computer-announced-garmin-edge-rival">COROS DURA bike computer</a>, announced in July but delayed due to "a small risk of mounting tab failures" and some reviewer complaints about missing software features, is arriving on September 26 with a host of new features that make it more competitive against other bike computers.</p><p>If you want to test these features now, you&apos;ll need public beta access. Click <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://ctrk.klclick.com/l/01J7Y4AAG26D4AW1AF9C33AESE_4"><strong>this link</strong></a> on either Android or iOS — you&apos;ll need Testflight on iPhones — and you&apos;ll get access. Otherwise, they&apos;ll roll out to all users sometime in October.</p>
<h2 id="new-coros-watch-features-2">New COROS watch features</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="RAejavBoiW6cxUkcuUjjJH" name="coros-gear-tracking.jpg" alt="A COROS watch and a phone showing gear tracking options from the September 2024 update." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RAejavBoiW6cxUkcuUjjJH.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: COROS)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The new COROS <strong>gear tracking</strong> tool is simple: You input the name of your current pairs of running shoes, track spikes, or hiking boots and assign them to specific activities (Run, Indoor Run, Trail Run, Track Run, Hike, or Walk). Then, every time you finish an activity, COROS will add the mileage to the shoe&apos;s total, with a customizable "max distance" for when it&apos;s time to replace your shoes. You can also manually pick any pair of shoes before an activity.</p><p>You can even track mileage for your bike(s) for Road, Indoor, Gravel, Mountain, or E-Bike activities. For context, Garmin Connect also has Gear tracking, but it doesn&apos;t let you split them off to specific sports, only grouping by Running, Cycling, Hiking, Swimming, Walking, and Other. I prefer COROS&apos; specificity, since I often wear different shoes for trail runs versus regular and track runs. My one complaint is that when I tested the beta for myself, it didn&apos;t retroactively assign miles from past activities, even when I say it was "First used" months ago. Moving forward, it should be very handy.</p>
<p>COROS improved sleep tracking with this update. In July 2024, it finally started tracking <strong>sleep stages</strong> like deep and REM; with the September update, it&apos;ll judge the <em>quality</em> of your sleep, warning you if you didn&apos;t get enough time spent in these stages to recover properly. Plus, it&apos;ll <strong>track sleep "24/7"</strong> to catch naps, though only rests of 3+ hours will get sleep-quality data.</p><p>Now that COROS tracks daily stress and sleep quality, I wonder if an equivalent to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-body-battery">Garmin Body Battery</a> or Fitbit Daily Readiness is coming next.</p><p>As for other COROS September updates, your watch will now support the following:</p>
<ul><li><strong>Drill</strong> and <strong>Interval Modes</strong> for Pool Swim activities</li><li><strong>Gravel Bike</strong> and <strong>Mountain Bike (MTB)</strong> activities</li><li>Mid-activity data fields for <strong>% FTP</strong>, <strong>% Max HR</strong>, <strong>% HRR</strong>, or <strong>% LTHR</strong></li><li>Integrations with new partners: <strong>Wikiloc</strong>, <strong>Ride with GPS</strong>, <strong>ROUVY</strong>, and <strong>Final Surge</strong></li></ul>
<h2 id="coros-dura-update-2">COROS DURA update</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="wP5XU5KxnF2sSS9E6E3X8H" name="coros-dura-september-update-new-views.jpg" alt="Three COROS DURA bike computer views showing real-time elevation profile, upcoming climbs, and workout stats." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wP5XU5KxnF2sSS9E6E3X8H.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: COROS)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>You&apos;ll rarely see an "update" for a device that hasn&apos;t launched yet, but COROS clearly wanted to spruce up its first bike computer before it reached consumers&apos; hands.</p><p>With the September update, the COROS DURA adds a <strong>Real-Time Elevation Profile</strong> mapping your hill progress thus far and a <strong>View Upcoming Climbs</strong> screen to see the remaining climb distance, elevation gain, and average grade for this climb, plus how many climbs you have left after that.</p><p>During a workout, you can check your heart rate, power, cadence, and time left on the <strong>Workout Progress view</strong>, and if you&apos;re riding on a designated course with multiple laps, the DURA will now <strong>auto-count laps</strong> every time you return to start. Then you can check the new <strong>Lap Summary</strong> view to compare your current lap time against past times.</p><p>Initial DURA testers complained that it didn&apos;t warn you quickly enough if you deviated off course, so COROS says its new <strong>Deviate Route Alert</strong> "has been improved" to be more accurate and immediate. It also added new <strong>Back to start options</strong> so you can choose whether to reverse back or take a "newly generated route," which is nice for variety.</p><p>Lastly, the COROS DURA now shows a <strong>Status Bar</strong> when you tap on the screen mid-workout for info on connected devices and battery status — though with 70 hours of dual-band tracking, battery life probably won&apos;t be a major concern. What matters more is battery life for connected devices, so COROS will let you set activity fields for battery life for power meters, lights, radars, HRMs, and so on.</p><p>You can read more about each feature on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://us.coros.com/stories/latest-news/c/september-2024-dura">COROS blog</a>.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="0e2e3d66-bed0-4a72-b06c-958dec64d7eb">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/imVp7mdpKkdvqGix89Bozi.jpeg' alt="Render of the COROS PACE 3 Track Edition"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">COROS PACE 3</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Built to last</strong></em></p>
<p>The COROS PACE 3 lasts 15 days with stress tracking, 38 hours with GPS, or 15 hours with dual-band GPS. It's due to receive new software features for years to come, backed by in-depth EvoLab and Training Hub metrics and guidance to help you become a better runner.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/coros-september-update-adds-gear-tracking-sleep-analysis-dura-fixes</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ COROS watches get some much-needed tools familiar to Garmin fans like Gear tracking, all-day sleep data, sleep quality analysis, and an improved running fitness test. And the delayed DURA bike computer receives some major new features. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">tZ5UiGyGrVEy2aRCakaxgG</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SdgdxENzyAPcqwmD8kibA3.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 13:00:28 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SdgdxENzyAPcqwmD8kibA3.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[COROS]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Press photo of the COROS DURA bike computer]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Press photo of the COROS DURA bike computer]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ How to use Instant Slow-Mo on a Samsung phone ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Thanks to Galaxy AI, you can use features such as Instant Slow-Mo to make your videos look even cooler. There are so many features to use and have fun with, but if you love taking pictures and videos like me, you probably pay extra attention to the editing features.</p><p>Instant Slow-Mo basically uses <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-galaxy-ai">Galaxy AI</a> to create new frames in videos captured on Galaxy phones, keeping them as smooth as the original footage but slowing them down. You can <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-s24-instant-slow-mo-galaxy-ai-pure-magic">have a lot of fun with Instant Slow-Mo</a>, for example when your cat looks at the camera, you can slow down the video to make it look more dramatic. If you have a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-samsung-phones">Galaxy phone</a> with this feature and can&apos;t wait to get started, here&apos;s how to use Instant Slow-Mo on your Samsung Galaxy phone.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-how-to-use-instant-slow-mo-on-a-samsung-galaxy-phone"><span>How to use Instant Slow-Mo on a Samsung Galaxy phone</span></h3>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> This feature was tested using a Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra.</p><p>Using Instant Slow-Mo on your Galaxy phone with One UI 6.1.1 is quick and easy. To get started:</p><p>1. Open the <strong>Gallery app</strong>.</p><p>2. <strong>Choose a video</strong> to which you want to apply the Instant Slow-Mo feature. You can also record a new video and choose the preview. Galaxy AI will briefly preview your video&apos;s appearance with Instant Slow-Mo by long-pressing on the screen.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:338px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:177.51%;"><img id="bSvEbJpynj4cx2RPnj4SMj" name="Samsung-Instant-Slow-Mo.gif" alt="Instant Slow-Mo in action" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bSvEbJpynj4cx2RPnj4SMj.gif" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="338" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>3. Tap the <strong>Pencil icon</strong> and the <strong>Adjust speed</strong> option to choose a speed option.</p><p>4. You can choose from <strong>speed options</strong> such as 1/8, 1/4, 1/2, 1, or 2.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:666px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:120.12%;"><img id="TtjiRjpqG5Y3rmeU3APWPX" name="Instant-Slow-Mo-Samsung.jpg" alt="Adjusting speed for Instant Slow-Mo on Galaxy phone" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TtjiRjpqG5Y3rmeU3APWPX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="666" height="800" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>5. <strong>Adjust the timeline</strong> so you can apply the Instant Slow-Mo to the part of the video you want. But be careful to use the smaller one right below the video. You&apos;ll be editing the video if you use the one with the bigger and broader ends.</p><p>The timeline lets you slow down any part of the video for as long as you want. You can widen the timeline to the whole video or a specific part. Above this timeline, you&apos;ll see the speed you added, but you can change the speed at any time by tapping the visible speed option.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:333px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:240.24%;"><img id="qiiHGc7VcQnpZUgL9kiZaD" name="Samsung-Instant-Slow-Mo-Slider.jpg" alt="Instant Slow-Mo slider on Galaxy S24 Ultra." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qiiHGc7VcQnpZUgL9kiZaD.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="333" height="800" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-how-to-save-your-instant-slow-mo-clips"><span>How to save your Instant Slow-Mo clips</span></h3>
<p>You have two options when you save your clips. You can save it as a copy or apply the changes to the original. If you want to save as a copy:</p><p>1. Tap the <strong>three dots</strong> at the <strong>top right</strong>.</p><p>2. Choose <strong>Save as copy</strong>. Wait a few seconds; the copy should be in the Gallery app.</p><p>If you want to apply the changes to the original, tap the save option, and you&apos;re good to go.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-which-samsung-devices-are-compatible-with-instant-slow-mo"><span>Which Samsung devices are compatible with Instant Slow-Mo?</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="iouYCH9oNkF972nW6VAoMT" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-Ultra-vs-Galaxy-S23-Ultra-camera-lenses-03.jpg" alt="Comparing the camera lens bumps on the Samsung Galaxy S23 Ultra vs S24 Ultra" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/iouYCH9oNkF972nW6VAoMT.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Instant Slow-Mo feature is not exclusive to the latest Samsung Galaxy S23 family of phones, such as the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review">Galaxy S24 Ultra</a>. It can also be found in Samsung&apos;s 2023 flagship series, the S23 lineup. Unfortunately, you won&apos;t find it on older Samsung phones, such as the Galaxy S22 and S21 series, since they lack the necessary processing power.</p><p>Other devices that have the feature include two generations of Samsung&apos;s foldable phones, namely the Galaxy Z Fold 5, Galaxy Z Flip 5, Galaxy Z Fold 6, and Galaxy Z Flip 6. Select tablets also get in on the fun since the feature is also available on the Galaxy Tab 9 series.</p><p>The Instant Slow-Mo feature is restricted to 8-bit videos, 720p to 8K videos, and MP4 files. Time will tell if Samsung plans on making any changes.</p>
<h2 id="keep-slowing-things-down-2">Keep slowing things down</h2>
<p>The Instant Slow-Mo feature is a lot of fun and gives your videos a different look. Once you&apos;ve added the effect, you can add other fun stuff, such as stickers, and decorate the videos.</p><p>Remember, you can also use other Galaxy AI features, such as <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-circle-to-search" target="_blank">Circle to Searc</a>h and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-samsung-galaxy-s24-live-translate" target="_blank">Live Translate</a>, on the aforementioned devices. It&apos;s always a good idea to check for system updates so you never miss out on the latest features Samsung rolls out to its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">flagship phones</a>.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="90893c60-457b-4d97-a20a-059a0b91024d">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PBHvpjpX26yLAmUkjL5o3W.jpg' alt="Galaxy S24 Ultra in Titanium Yellow"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="90" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Galaxy AI fun</strong></em></p>
<p>The latest Samsung flagship phone gives you fantastic cameras and Galaxy AI to make those pictures and videos better. The processor lets you enjoy 4K videos and multitask without any lag.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/how-to-use-instant-slow-mo-on-a-samsung-phone</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Thanks to the Instant Slow-Mo feature on your Galaxy phone, you can make your videos look even better by making certain moments last a little longer. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Xrtm45Lbk44jBby259DVke</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YEvRkm3AKzKNVWSMzh3gZM.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 12:40:49 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ yorknectar@gmail.com (Judy Sanhz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YEvRkm3AKzKNVWSMzh3gZM.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[null]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The back of the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra in the Titanium Grey colorway]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The back of the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra in the Titanium Grey colorway]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Pixel 9 Pro Fold is leveling up your Google Meet video calls ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The Pixel 9 Pro Fold is getting a new update for Google Meet, letting you use both front and back cameras during video calls.</li><li>The feature, called "Dual Screen on Meet," can only be activated once you’re in a call.</li><li>Right now, it's exclusive to the Pixel 9 Pro Fold, but other foldables like the Galaxy Z Fold 6 might get it soon.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>The Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold is picking up a neat upgrade for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/top-10-google-meet-tips-and-tricks-you-need-know">Google Meet</a> video calls, allowing you to use both the front and back cameras at the same time during video calls.</p><p>Google&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://workspaceupdates.googleblog.com/2024/09/release-notes-09-20-2024.html" target="_blank">blog post</a> explains that the "Dual Screen on Meet" feature lets <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-fold-review">Pixel 9 Pro Fold</a> users fire up both selfie cameras at once during video calls. However, you can only turn it on once you&apos;re already in a call.</p><p>Google announced this update over the weekend, alongside a bunch of other changes for Google Chat and Sheets.</p><p>The company says that using this feature will display meeting participants on both the inner and outer screens, ensuring that everyone has a clear view of the people on the call.</p><p>You’ll see a new icon pop up when you tap to access the controls. This icon makes it easy to turn on Dual Screen along with Dual Display, which you can switch off if you want. Once activated, Google Meet will split your screen, showing your video on one side and your surroundings on the other.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:357px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:224.09%;"><img id="SDksrjnpSk843auPXhBiwE" name="Pixel-9-Pro-Fold-Google-Meet-dual-screen.jpg" alt="Google Meet dual screen feature for video calls on the Pixel 9 Pro Fold" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SDksrjnpSk843auPXhBiwE.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="357" height="800" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:772px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:103.63%;"><img id="Q5VhcwzrEo6AjZsR3RRjmE" name="Pixel-9-Pro-Fold-Google-Meet-video-call-inner-screen.jpg" alt="Google Meet dual screen feature for video calls on the Pixel 9 Pro Fold" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Q5VhcwzrEo6AjZsR3RRjmE.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="772" height="800" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Basically, during your video conference, people will be able to see you through the internal camera while also getting a view of your surroundings via the camera on the external display.</p><p>It’s worth pointing out that this feature doesn’t use the Pixel 9 Pro Fold&apos;s rear camera. Instead, it taps into the cameras on the cover display and the inner screen. You can check out the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/meet/answer/15454341?fl=1" target="_blank">support page</a> for a detailed rundown on how this functionality works on the Pixel 9 Pro Fold.</p><p>Right now, Dual Screen is an exclusive feature for the Pixel 9 Pro Fold, but that might not last long. With the tech capabilities of other <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">foldable phones</a> like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Galaxy Z Fold 6</a>, it&apos;s likely they’ll support the Dual Screen feature soon too.</p><p>Google gave a sneak peek of this feature during the Pixel 9 Pro Fold launch in August, but it’s only now becoming available. The Dual Screen functionality is available for users with both personal and Workspace accounts.</p>
<hr>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="67e848bb-e5a2-4a67-9743-03a1f530ecd6">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7nEJ4MLpp4jMPGiG3yvSmf.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold Official Render - Porcelain - Unfolded"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>Google's second-gen foldable is lighter and thinner than the last model, plus both the inner and outer screens are way brighter. It comes with great hardware, an impressive camera setup, and a design that matches the Pixel 9 Pro. With a smooth software interface and tons of cool AI features, this foldable really shines in all the right places.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-pixel-9-pro-fold-is-leveling-up-your-google-meet-video-calls</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Pixel 9 Pro Fold is now the only phone with this exclusive Google Meet feature. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">6rQ9oAtEUMwYadppvwvXRN</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KPqSRwHenUh77DRbuHm3qf.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 12:25:03 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KPqSRwHenUh77DRbuHm3qf.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold Inner Screen]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold Inner Screen]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Suunto Race review: Near the finish line ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>I received a Suunto Race review unit in mid-May, only for Suunto to release a newer Race S the following month with doubled heart rate LEDs, a lighter design, and few downgrades for $100 less. That, along with a bundle of Wear OS watches from Samsung, Google, and OnePlus to test all summer, put it on my back burner.</p><p>So yes, this Suunto Race review is nearly a year out of date from its late 2023 launch. It stayed in my mind, though, because it has most of the main ingredients I want in a modern running watch: a bright AMOLED display (sorry, MIP fans), a 16-day battery life, dual-band GPS, training load data borrowed straight from TrainingPeaks, downloadable topographic maps, and a unique app store for downloading niche training tools.</p><p>Once I found the time to put it through its paces, the Suunto Race software — particularly its SuuntoPlus apps — took a long time to master, but it rewards you for the effort. Perhaps my biggest issue with the Suunto Race is with the fundamentals: when I tested its HR and GPS accuracy, they didn&apos;t quite live up to my expectations. </p><p>That said, this is a very strong watch for the $450 price range, giving the equally-priced Garmin Forerunner 265 and COROS APEX 2 Pro a run for your money.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-suunto-race-review-price-availability-and-specs"><span>Suunto Race review: Price, availability, and specs</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="ECJKGRGPUaTwn5uggvRi4J" name="Suunto-Race-side-view.jpeg" alt="A front view of the Suunto Race showing the silicone band and Suunto logo on titanium." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ECJKGRGPUaTwn5uggvRi4J.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Suunto Race was released in October 2023. The newer Race S launched in June 2024, adding a few new software features that also arrived on the Suunto Race. </p><p>It starts at $449 for the stainless steel version and $549 for the titanium version, which weighs slightly less and has double the map storage space. The steel versions ship in All Black, Midnight Blue, Birch White, and "UTMB World Series," which has a black case and unique strap. The titanium edition ships in Charcoal and Amethyst.</p>

<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-suunto-race-review-what-you-ll-like"><span>Suunto Race review: What you'll like</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="vd8ZpiUMevqYPFWSXuMEjA" name="Suunto-Race-run-intensity-zones.jpeg" alt="Heart rate intensity chart summary on the Suunto Race." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vd8ZpiUMevqYPFWSXuMEjA.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Most fitness watch brands are <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fitness-watches-mip-to-amoled-transition-long-overdue">transitioning from MIP to AMOLED displays</a>, and the Suunto Race is exhibit A for why it&apos;s a good thing. You&apos;re getting a watch that lasts over two weeks per charge or about 40 hours, using four satellite systems and dual-band GPS simultaneously, and still getting a 1,000-nit, high-res display. I don&apos;t begrudge people who need <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/best-smartwatches-for-battery-life">max battery life</a> like the 90-day Garmin Enduro 3, but I&apos;d say the Suunto Race has hit the good-enough threshold for most athletes.</p><p>The Suunto Race uses a rotating crown and start/back buttons, giving you three customizable shortcuts for the crown press and top/down long-presses. You can prioritize functions like the flashlight, music controls, notifications, alarms, or weather. The crown shortcut highlights one pinned widget, so you can jump quickly to data like your training progress widget or workout logbook, or open the compass or map quickly.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="AMzxhNK7uaTbKNEakzJtkD" name="Suunto-Race-training-load-progress.jpeg" alt="The Suunto Race training load progress widget." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AMzxhNK7uaTbKNEakzJtkD.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Suunto app splits off between a Home feed of your workouts, a Calendar view, a Training Zone — which summarizes your recent Training Load, Intensity, Impact, and Recovery — and a map view with heat maps that show where Suunto users train. Unlike other apps that put more focus on health, sleep, paid coaching, or tie-ins to other products, Suunto keeps things focused on training, which I appreciate.</p><p>In particular, the Training Zone section is pretty neat. You get a Suunto Coach text summary that clearly describes your recent progress, before you dive into the charts and numbers. You see a weekly summary of your training load and training stress (aka intensity) that&apos;s compared against your chronic training load for a form (Training Stress Balance) score. It all may sound complicated at first, but once you memorize the acronyms, it provides a ton of useful context for serious runners.</p><p>I especially like how Suunto provides an Intensity chart that shows how much time you spend in HR zones 1–5 across the week, as well as pace zones and running power zones. I wrote about wanting <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-training-load-focus-needs-one-obvious-fix">better training load zone analysis</a> recently, and Suunto checks many of those boxes.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="VbVom3xR46ckhk74G9etSC" name="Suunto-Race-elevation-gain.jpeg" alt="The Suunto Race showing the author's elevation gain atop a hill." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VbVom3xR46ckhk74G9etSC.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>You can download offline maps across hundreds of countries and territories, with the maps split up for the larger countries. In the U.S., for example, I downloaded Northern California (2GB), but most other states (and many countries) are smaller. Most people will be able to make do with the standard 16GB of storage unless you frequently travel for training; downloading maps is painfully slow, so you&apos;re not going to want to swap map packs often.</p><p>Next you can create a route, either by using the simple map creation tool and tapping waypoints or importing a GPX file from third-party apps like Strava. You can also find other people&apos;s public routes using heatmaps, though you may not find many except in major population areas or national parks. Uploading them to your watch is quick and managing your route library is painless.</p><p>Speaking of third-party integrations, Suunto offers plenty of SuuntoPlus apps made by third-party tech brands or community members, filling the gaps left behind in Suunto&apos;s software. You can add SuuntoPlus apps on the watch itself, naturally integrating the new tech into your favorite sports modes. They also let you sync with certain devices, including the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/core-body-temperature-sensor-thermal-load">CORE Body Temp sensor</a> I tested earlier this year.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-suunto-race-review-hr-and-gps-accuracy"><span>Suunto Race review: HR and GPS accuracy</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="5EDkgQGApPJbz6JNvoudRK" name="Suunto-Race-and-garmin-forerunner-965-hike-comparison.jpeg" alt="The Garmin Forerunner 965 (left) and Suunto Race (right) showing their post-hike differences. Suunto measured a longer hike than Garmin did, which was a trend." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5EDkgQGApPJbz6JNvoudRK.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<h2 id="suunto-race-gps-accuracy-tests-2">Suunto Race GPS accuracy tests</h2>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">How I test</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">For GPS accuracy, I use my <strong>Garmin Forerunner 965</strong>, which beat other dual-band GPS watches from COROS, Polar, Samsung, and Apple in previous tests. For testing optical HR accuracy, I use my <strong>COROS Heart Rate Monitor</strong>, which <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/why-im-done-with-heart-rate-monitor-chest-straps">compared favorably</a> against a HRM chest strap.</p></div></div>
<p>At the end of multiple runs and a long hike, the Suunto Race added at least one-tenth of a mile to each activity compared to what my <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-forerunner-965-review">Garmin Forerunner 965</a> tracked. Given how well the latter usually does for dual-band GPS accuracy, that had me worried about the Suunto Race&apos;s own accuracy. Analyzing the charts, though, the answer is a little more complicated.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="a72oLckiAqXC3AkxCRW56o" name="Suunto-Race-vs-Garmin-Forerunner-965-GPS-comparison-1.jpeg" alt="A GPS map showing the author's running path, with blue and orange lines tracked by the Suunto Race and Garmin Forerunner 965, respectively. The blue line wobbles back and forth while the orange line stays straight and on path." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/a72oLckiAqXC3AkxCRW56o.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="za7Dos97GWioV2QuXYbg34" name="Suunto-Race-vs-Garmin-Forerunner-965-GPS-comparison-3.jpeg" alt="A GPS map showing the author's running path, with blue and orange lines tracked by the Suunto Race and Garmin Forerunner 965, respectively. The blue line wobbles back and forth while the orange line stays straight and on path." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/za7Dos97GWioV2QuXYbg34.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="BygLx3QUarkEmM8WZUQ3n" name="Suunto-Race-vs-Garmin-Forerunner-965-GPS-comparison-2.jpeg" alt="A GPS map showing the author's running path, with blue and orange lines tracked by the Suunto Race and Garmin Forerunner 965, respectively. The blue line wobbles back and forth while the orange line stays straight and on path." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BygLx3QUarkEmM8WZUQ3n.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>In each of the GPS paths above, the Suunto Race (<em>blue line</em>) generally matches my location, sometimes doing better than Garmin (<em>orange</em>) at knowing which side of the trail I&apos;m on. The immediately obvious problem is how every one-second reading seems to fling me from one diagonal to another, like I&apos;m a running back practicing my juking skills.</p><p>I&apos;m still moving forward and avoiding the drastic tracking issues I see with GPS-only watches like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-3-review">Pixel Watch 3</a>; I don&apos;t want to give the impression that Suunto does terribly here. But without fail, after every mile Suunto is an extra one-hundredth of a mile ahead of Garmin, and by the end of a long workout the gap adds up. </p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="mXgYkCZ6E4oAX4N2nyj72g" name="Suunto-Race-vs-Garmin-Forerunner-965-GPS-comparison-4.jpeg" alt="A GPS map showing how the Garmin Forerunner 965 (orange line) and Suunto Race (blue line) compare on a hike with plenty of satellite signal blockage." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mXgYkCZ6E4oAX4N2nyj72g.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="HSEMk7Md8DPUHnxxoENnbc" name="Suunto-Race-vs-Garmin-Forerunner-965-GPS-comparison-6.jpeg" alt="A GPS map showing how the Garmin Forerunner 965 (orange line) and Suunto Race (blue line) compare on a hike with plenty of satellite signal blockage." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HSEMk7Md8DPUHnxxoENnbc.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="hsMqXyrnt54STCLyenvNJe" name="Suunto-Race-vs-Garmin-Forerunner-965-GPS-comparison-8.jpeg" alt="A GPS map showing how the Garmin Forerunner 965 (orange line) and Suunto Race (blue line) compare on a hike with plenty of satellite signal blockage." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hsMqXyrnt54STCLyenvNJe.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 4 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="MQtJDJdjLUjfSfDUc384oZ" name="Suunto-Race-vs-Garmin-Forerunner-965-GPS-comparison-5.jpeg" alt="A GPS map showing how the Garmin Forerunner 965 (orange line) and Suunto Race (blue line) compare on a hike with plenty of satellite signal blockage." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MQtJDJdjLUjfSfDUc384oZ.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 5 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="qgxUekgqrmYpcH6kx3sz7b" name="Suunto-Race-vs-Garmin-Forerunner-965-GPS-comparison-7.jpeg" alt="A GPS map showing how the Garmin Forerunner 965 (orange line) and Suunto Race (blue line) compare on a hike with plenty of satellite signal blockage." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qgxUekgqrmYpcH6kx3sz7b.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>I also took both watches out on a ten-mile hike; by the end, Suunto had added two-tenths of a mile. You can see in the screens above how well it does tracking me in dense foliage, never losing me the way most smartwatches would. But whether my signal is obscured or direct, you see that same frantic zig-zagging effect at random moments.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="ovD2fw35H2jmZ9vfxt75Qf" name="Suunto-Race-vs-Garmin-Forerunner-965-GPS-comparison-9.jpeg" alt="A GPS map showing how the Suunto Race (blue line) and Garmin Forerunner 965 (orange line) compare for a track workout." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ovD2fw35H2jmZ9vfxt75Qf.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Suunto Race doesn&apos;t have a track run activity, but it did pretty well at matching my lane-3 sprints around my local track, despite some wobbliness. It ended up adding about 80m to my total after ten laps. (Garmin&apos;s track line is artificially centered because of its Track Run activity, so ignore it.)</p><p>This watch is old enough that Suunto is probably past the point of algorithm fixes, but I feel like Suunto is <em>close</em> to nailing its tracking, in some ways better than other dual-band watches at avoiding straying lines.</p>
<h2 id="suunto-race-hr-accuracy-tests-2">Suunto Race HR accuracy tests</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1429px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:48.99%;"><img id="YsPPPN9BBmxxaPjkBfJYSK" name="Suunto-Race-vs-Garmin-Forerunner-965-HR-comparison-1.jpeg" alt="A heart rate chart showing how the COROS Heart Rate Monitor and Suunto Race optical HR sensor compare for accuracy." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YsPPPN9BBmxxaPjkBfJYSK.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1429" height="700" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>With the Suunto Race&apos;s optical heart rate monitor, I&apos;d already heard that Suunto doubled the LED sensors in its Race S successor watch and tweaked its algorithm in response to Race HR criticism. So I compared it against my <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/coros-heart-rate-monitor-review">COROS Heart Rate Monitor</a> to see how it matches against a reliable optical sensor (the above chart says "Garmin Forerunner" because my COROS synced to that watch).</p><p>For all four activities, the Suunto&apos;s HR average fell 1–2 bpm short. During the 15K run above, the Race always stays close, but it&apos;s apparent how its reading never quite catches up to my actual heart rate, averaging 2 bpm short (166 vs. 164).</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1420px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:51.20%;"><img id="8azd6tNLGLccn2ATQzg8eK" name="Suunto-Race-vs-Garmin-Forerunner-965-HR-comparison-2.jpeg" alt="A heart rate chart showing how the COROS Heart Rate Monitor and Suunto Race optical HR sensor compare for accuracy." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8azd6tNLGLccn2ATQzg8eK.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1420" height="727" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>During a shorter 10K, the gap was only 1 bpm, but the shorter timeline makes it easier to see moments where Suunto&apos;s reading dips and rises at odd increments while the secured COROS band has my heart rate staying steady. That has me suspecting that the Suunto Race does have small tracking blips that add up, and that the Race S&apos; extra LEDs might help with that.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1749px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:41.45%;"><img id="4VFAHTTBvah65HkZbJL86e" name="Suunto-Race-vs-Garmin-Forerunner-965-HR-comparison-3.jpeg" alt="A HR chart showing how the COROS HRM and Suunto Race compare for optical HR results." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4VFAHTTBvah65HkZbJL86e.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1749" height="725" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>For my final track workout, the Suunto Race struggled. Some gaps might be due to inconsistent pausing after laps, but that doesn&apos;t explain the Race registering me at my max 200 bpm during my first 800m; trust me, I wasn&apos;t running that hard yet. Otherwise, there were two clear moments where its HR was ten bpm above my actual rate, and two moments where it was ten bpm <em>below</em>. The overall average was just 2 bpm off, but I wasn&apos;t thrilled with the data.</p><p>Overall, I&apos;d say the Suunto Race&apos;s GPS accuracy is good enough to get by and better than whatever GPS-only watch you currently have, but it could be better. As for heart rate, this is a watch where I&apos;d probably recommend you keep wearing an external heart rate monitor if you need hyper-accurate results, but it&apos;s otherwise good enough to give you accurate HR zones for your training load data.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-suunto-race-review-what-you-won-t-like"><span>Suunto Race review: What you won't like</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="7fKThvT2HK2txDCYD9afQG" name="Suunto-Race-crown.jpeg" alt="A side view of the Suunto Race focused on the crown and buttons." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7fKThvT2HK2txDCYD9afQG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1687" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Aside from my complaints about accuracy, my biggest note with the Suunto Race is its weight. Suunto sent me the titanium model, and at 69g, it&apos;s on the heavy side for a running-focused watch; most other flagships weigh in the mid-50s with a silicone band, or use a nylon band to hit that range. I feel a little bit of wobble when pumping my arms hard, though it&apos;s still not as heavy as, say, a Samsung or Apple Ultra watch.</p><p>My issue is that most buyers will choose the 83g stainless steel Race to save money. For people used to all-steel watches, they won&apos;t mind, but many runners will find that weight onerous. That&apos;s why many runners will prefer the 60g Race S, accepting the smaller and less-protected display.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="Uao2EY9PjAcpCTeVPADCB9" name="Suunto-Race-run-summary.jpeg" alt="A post-run summary screen on the Suunto Pace." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Uao2EY9PjAcpCTeVPADCB9.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While I never mind running with my phone, the Suunto Race mandates it if you want music playlists or contactless payments. Some of this is outside of Suunto&apos;s control — it&apos;s hard for smaller brands to get banks and streaming services to play ball — yet many runners will choose other brands because they can&apos;t do without music storage and NFC.</p><p>While I praised most of the main Suunto app tools, one conspicuous absence is any kind of free training plan software that adapts to your recent workouts, like you get with Garmin or COROS. Suunto has a list of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.suunto.com/en-us/Support/faq-articles/suuntoplus/which-partners-offer-suuntoplus-guides/">SuuntoPlus app integrations for training guides</a>, but most of them (like TrainingPeaks) require a payment or syncing your data regularly with another platform. I&apos;d argue Suunto needs its own native equivalent.</p><p>As for other missing features other fitness brands offer, Suunto doesn&apos;t have safety tools like location sharing, challenges, gear tracking, or the option to pre-select multisport options. You won&apos;t find any ECG or skin temp readings, either.</p><p>Lastly, I&apos;m not the biggest fan of Suunto&apos;s watch face system. You can only save nine to the watch, and they&apos;re hidden in the SuuntoPlus store with only 21 total options by my count, none of them especially pretty or creative. You can&apos;t add a custom background, most faces only let you add three complications at most, and syncing faces to the watch is weirdly slow.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-competition"><span>Competition</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="SzhM3mmF7vqMjhPtRaoLzA" name="Garmin-Forerunner-265-performance.jpeg" alt="Post-run recovery and VO2 Max data on the Garmin Forerunner 265" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SzhM3mmF7vqMjhPtRaoLzA.jpeg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-forerunner-265-review">Garmin Forerunner 265</a> is ranked as our <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-running-watches">best running watch</a> because it offers great training tools without costing as much as flagship models. Compared to the Suunto Race, it has some deficiencies: its Gorilla Glass 3-protected display isn&apos;t as bright or scratch-proof. It only has breadcrumb navigation, with maps reserved for the 965. Its plastic bezel doesn&apos;t look nearly as classy. And while their daily battery isn&apos;t so different (16 vs. 13 days), the Suunto Race crushes the Forerunner 265 for dual-band GPS hours (40 vs. 14 hours).</p><p>Still, it has its perks! The Forerunner 265 is significantly lighter, even if you don&apos;t buy the smaller 265S, and it has the upside of contactless payments and music storage if you want to go phone-less for your run. It also does slightly better on the GPS accuracy front, and offers both daily suggested workouts and adaptable Garmin Coach training plans. Whether you prefer the up/down buttons or Suunto&apos;s crown is a matter of preference.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="JcwZzVTuMAcL5STahGKxMb" name="Coros-Apex-2-Pro-map.jpeg" alt="The map app on the COROS APEX 2 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JcwZzVTuMAcL5STahGKxMb.jpeg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Aside from Garmin, Suunto&apos;s biggest fitness-watch rivals are COROS and Polar. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/coros-apex-2-pro-review">COROS APEX 2 Pro</a> also costs $449, and thanks to its MIP display it can last 30 days per charge, though its 26-hour dual-band GPS tracking still falls short of Suunto&apos;s. It has a titanium bezel, ECG readings, 32GB for downloadable maps, comparable training load software, and downloadable training plans.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/polar-vantage-v3-review">Polar Vantage V3</a> is a pricier $599, making it a hard ask unless you&apos;re considering the titanium Suunto Race. It, too, has all the training guidance, recovery recs, accurate GPS and heart rate data, and full-color maps on an AMOLED display that you could ask for. I especially like its tests for things like muscle soreness and current VO2 Max. </p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-suunto-race-review-should-you-buy-it"><span>Suunto Race review: Should you buy it?</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.27%;"><img id="poiTbkCrYXns9pzS9aFksL" name="Suunto-Race-active-calories.jpeg" alt="An active calories pop-up on the Suunto Race for hitting 500 kcal." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/poiTbkCrYXns9pzS9aFksL.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1688" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>You should buy the Suunto Race if...</strong></p>
<ul><li>You need a long-lived AMOLED running watch with in-depth training metrics.</li><li>You want premium features at a mid-range running watch price.</li><li>You want the Suunto Race's 10ATM water resistance, sapphire glass, and extra week of battery life compared to the Suunto Race S. </li></ul>
<p><strong>You shouldn&apos;t buy the Suunto Race if...</strong></p>
<ul><li>The Suunto Race S, with its revamped HR data, lighter design, and lower price, appeals to you more.</li><li>You need music storage or contactless payments.</li><li>You want an adaptive training program that sends workouts to your wrist based on past activities.</li></ul>
<p>My review title says it all: The Suunto Race is near the finish line for me. </p><p>The Suunto Race S allegedly fixed some of the optical HR issues and made it even more affordable and more comfortably lightweight. Once Suunto catches up on adaptive training plans and a couple of other areas, it&apos;ll have everything I&apos;d want in a running watch at a lower price tier than other brands, like COROS except with AMOLED instead of MIP displays.</p><p>Still, as comparatively minor as the Suunto Race accuracy issues are compared to other mainstream smartwatches, they&apos;re big enough that I&apos;ll happily turn to other brands that avoid those issues.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="12778777-2ad0-446e-b569-44e4d64342cf">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Qdc58yoW9rYZqgSbmv7Jm8.jpg' alt="Render of the All Black stainless steel Suunto Race"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Suunto Race</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Marathoner AMOLED</strong></em></p>
<p>The Suunto Race arguably beats other $450 running watches like the Garmin Forerunner 265 and COROS APEX 2 Pro in key areas. It has a 16-day battery life, dual-band GPS, advanced training metrics, downloadable offline maps, and strong water and scratch protection.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/suunto-race-review</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Suunto Race arguably beats other $450 running watches like the Garmin Forerunner 265 and COROS APEX 2 Pro in key areas. It just needs a few fixes to challenge its running watch rivals for supremacy. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">h6U88TQh4hp6KYj4KepbgY</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AWqja4VhfbHcz3fapffmoN.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 15:04:05 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AWqja4VhfbHcz3fapffmoN.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[One of the default watch faces on the Suunto Race.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[One of the default watch faces on the Suunto Race.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Who needs the Pixel 9? Amazon just returned the Google Pixel 8 to its lowest price EVER ahead of October Prime Day ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>You can usually find some great phone deals all year, but Amazon&apos;s upcoming Prime Day event has already brought with it some impressive early discounts. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-Unlocked-Smartphone-Advanced/dp/B0CGTD5KVT/" target="_blank"><strong>Amazon has just cut $200 off last year&apos;s Google Pixel 8</strong></a><strong> </strong>as part of its early Amazon Prime Day deals, marking 29% in savings and bringing this capable phone back to its lowest price ever. The Pixel 8 remains well-liked for its promise of seven years of Android OS updates, great camera quality, and its overall good-looking design. Plus, it offers a super-bright OLED screen with a 120Hz refresh rate, and a wide range of Google&apos;s Gemini AI features.</p><p>Can&apos;t wait until Big Deal Days? We&apos;re already gathering many of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/prime-day-is-back-next-month-faq-early-deals-and-everything-you-need-to-know-about-the-big-sale"><strong>best early Prime Day deals</strong></a> before the sitewide sale kicks off on October 8th. </p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="853b3303-5e0b-49f6-b422-bba4c0778f2f" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$699.00" data-dimension48="$699.00" href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-Unlocked-Smartphone-Advanced/dp/B0CGTD5KVT/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="jT3wKyTXdJGKEjFzSD4DbG" name="google pixel 8 400x500 render 2.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jT3wKyTXdJGKEjFzSD4DbG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Google Pixel 8 (128GB):</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-Unlocked-Smartphone-Advanced/dp/B0CGTD5KVT/" target="_blank" data-dimension112="853b3303-5e0b-49f6-b422-bba4c0778f2f" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$699.00" data-dimension48="$699.00"><del>$699.00</del> <strong>$499.00 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-review">Google Pixel 8</a> is back to its lowest price ever ahead of next month's Prime Day event, marking $200 off the purchase price for 29% off. Those in need of a smartphone with a strong camera and many years of software updates should definitely consider this deal, especially if they already like the Google Pixel ecosystem.</p>
<p><strong>Price comparison:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google-pixel-8-128gb-unlocked-obsidian/6559236.p?skuId=6559236" target="_blank">Best Buy - $499.00</a> | <a href="https://store.google.com/config/pixel_8" target="_blank">Google - $699.00</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-Unlocked-Smartphone-Advanced/dp/B0CGTD5KVT/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="853b3303-5e0b-49f6-b422-bba4c0778f2f" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$699.00" data-dimension48="$699.00">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>high-quality cameras are a major priority for you when it comes to buying a phone; you don&apos;t mind a last-gen device; you want access to Google&apos;s latest AI features; you&apos;re looking for a phone that offers several years of Android OS updates.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>you&apos;d rather go with an affordable phone subscription through your wireless carrier; you have extra money to spend and would rather upgrade to the Pixel 8 Pro or Pixel 9 to get industry-leading cameras.</p><p>The Google Pixel 8 is a high-quality last-gen phone, and with an extra $200 off, it isn&apos;t a hard purchase to justify. Those hoping to upgrade to the Pixel 8 Pro or the newer-generation Pixel 9 lineup may want to consider those options, but those needing high performance at a budget, last-generation price will be likely to get what they need out of this phone. It offers a beautiful 6.2-inch OLED display with a refresh rate of 120Hz, offering some top-tier video and gaming. It also comes with 128GB of storage for this deal, or you can upgrade to 256GB while still getting 12% off.</p><p>Beyond being generally a good-looking phone and display, users love the Pixel 8&apos;s camera, Gemini AI features, and its incredibly user-friendly interface. Its powerful performance is backed by the Google Tensor G3 chipset and 8GB of RAM, and useful battery-saving features can get users as much as 24 hours of battery life per charge.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/who-needs-the-pixel-9-amazon-just-returned-the-google-pixel-8-to-its-lowest-price-ever-ahead-of-october-prime-day</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ For a limited time, Amazon has cut the price of the Google Pixel 8 back to its lowest price ever, weeks ahead of the retailer's next Prime Day sales event. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">uwuppsWJ9FBfBo4cGoWMEW</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YC8hoYh837VKLXJKTSg2YK.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 13:00:51 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ zacharydvisconti@gmail.com (Zachary Visconti) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YC8hoYh837VKLXJKTSg2YK.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Pixel 8 review]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Pixel 8 review]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>