<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 08:38:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Sennheiser Momentum True Wireless 4 review: Superb sound with a promising future ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The title for this Sennheiser Momentum True Wireless 4 review should be “Momentum 4 the future.” See what I did there? I didn’t go with that because it would sound like a press release, but when you drill down to what Sennheiser has done here, that’s exactly what stands out most about these earbuds, which support lossless streaming over Bluetooth (if you also have a phone that supports it). I’ll dive into that future in detail in a bit, but first, I’m going to tell you that you should never buy based on what a product may be but what it is right now! </p><p>Confused? Don’t be. </p><p>What Sennheiser’s Momentum True Wireless 4 earbuds are today is outstanding. They don’t include spatial audio, and some competitors may have a stronger feature here or there, but Sennheiser does high-end sound so well that these Momentums and the strength of their features make them a serious contender in a market that already has some tough competition in the $300 price range.</p>

<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-sennheiser-momentum-true-wireless-4-price-availability"><span>Sennheiser Momentum True Wireless 4: Price & availability</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="wmGaTf28Fe6GoQjjYEyN5M" name="sennheiser-momentum-true-wireless-4-buds-on-pixel-7-pro.jpg" alt="Sennheiser Momentum True Wireless 4 on Pixel 7 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wmGaTf28Fe6GoQjjYEyN5M.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Sennheiser announced the Momentum True Wireless 4 earbuds on January 8, 2024, with a pre-order date of February 15th and availability on March 1. Priced at $299.99, that’s a $50 increase over the $249.95 launch of the Momentum True Wireless 3 in 2022. </p><p>You have three colors you can choose from: black copper, metallic silver, and graphite. I have the graphite pair for review. They have a long list of features, but you should know they won’t ship with all of them. We’ll get into that momentarily. </p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-sennheiser-momentum-true-wireless-4-what-i-like"><span>Sennheiser Momentum True Wireless 4: What I like</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="CZZvi2m8oCsk8DJTxsG3tN" name="sennheiser-momentum-true-wireless-4-eartips-wings.jpg" alt="Sennheiser Momentum True Wireless 4" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CZZvi2m8oCsk8DJTxsG3tN.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>As I said earlier, this article could be titled “Momentum 4 the future,” but much like Veruca Salt, I want what I want and I want it now! And Sennheiser delivers that in spades, er, musical notes. </p><p>Cracking the box open, you’re met with what looks nearly identical to the previous generation earbuds—that sweet, sweet tweed charging case. The Momentum True Wireless 3’s body is black, but I like the new graphite more.</p><p>The shape of the earbuds is nearly identical, but the earbud tips have a new trick this year. The previous model had a “+” with mesh beneath it, which wasn’t easy to clean. This year, a perforated silicon surface was molded into the inner portion of the ear tip, which I think handles wax buildup from workouts better.</p><p>In addition to the usual sizes, you get a set of extra small tips for those with baby-like ear canals like me. You’ll also get a total of three ear fins to help with sizing, which is a nice addition as they add some friction where the buds sit against the concha. All of this made the Momentum True Wireless 4s comfortable for extended periods of wear.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="DRxmCgmH3m6vUAfDqEd6PN" name="sennheiser-momentum-true-wireless-4-comparing-momentum-3-eartips.jpg" alt="Sennheiser Momentum True Wireless 4 eartips compared with Momentum True Wireless 3 eartips" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DRxmCgmH3m6vUAfDqEd6PN.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>You’ll also get the USB-C charge cable in the box, which you won’t need if you’re going to charge wirelessly overnight. When charging over the cable, it will take an hour and a half to get to a full charge, and eight minutes of quick charging will give you an hour of playback. Sennheiser says you’ll get up to seven and a half hours of playback with ANC off and seven with it on. That held pretty true to spec for my use, but more long-term testing will reveal how consistent that is as I listen to more hi-res audio files. </p><p>When it comes to power, one of the options I appreciate in these lithium ion-equipped earbuds is a new “Battery Protection Mode” in the Smart Control app. This feature charges the unit slower and prevents charging to 100% to prolong the lifespan of your battery. I charge on a Qi wireless enabled pad at night, and the fully charged case will get you up to 30 hours of additional listening time so this slower Qi charging is a non-issue for me.</p>

<p>There are truly <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-earbuds">wireless earbuds</a> on the market with more effective noise canceling, but these still did a solid job in my testing. As I walked neighborhood side streets and a busy main street, the MTW4s did a great job of canceling or dampening the majority of sound with their improved adaptive noise canceling, although this is notably something I only do when testing earbuds. Usually, I walk with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/transparency-mode-killed-open-ear-headphones-for-me">transparency modes</a> activated to maintain my situational awareness. Sitting in my office and blasting 80dB of airplane cabin noise on YouTube, with no music playing, that noise was significantly hushed but not canceled. With music playing, that cabin noise was barely noticeable. </p><p>The transparency mode isn’t just “on,” but it also has a slider in the app that allows you to set the level of transparency from “Low” to “High.” It sounds pretty natural, and though I tested it at various levels, I keep it at “High.” Placing it on “Low” feels more like it’s an ANC slider than transparency and defeats the point.</p><p>Still, in terms of earbuds that I’ve listened to in the last year, these are among the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-noise-canceling-true-wireless-earbuds">best for ANC</a> implementation, even if they don’t place first or second for their effectiveness.</p><p>You’ll get pretty solid call quality out of the six MEMS and beamforming microphones (three on each bud) when you do make calls. During one of my test calls, my buddy on the other end couldn’t tell I was using a Bluetooth earpiece, and that was in my car with the windows down at times. On the other hand, I tested mic quality standing next to a water feature in front of a luxury high-rise on a major street, and I sounded “robotic.” The MTW4 did an excellent job of removing some serious background noise, but my actual vocal quality was middling. </p><p>Your location will matter in terms of how natural you sound, but in the oft-quiet room conditions we take Zoom or Google Meet calls from, you should be fine. Your mileage may vary if you find yourself in a noisy cafe.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="ZB9684L6HVNJsqdnvGBtXo" name="sennheiser-momentum-true-wireless-4-in-ear-close-up.jpg" alt="Sennheiser Momentum True Wireless 4 in ear" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZB9684L6HVNJsqdnvGBtXo.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The best way for me to test audio, which has been improved over the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/earbuds/sennheiser-momentum-true-wireless-3-review">Momentum True Wireless 3</a>, was to hit Tidal and the locally stored FLAC files on my <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-7-pro-review">Pixel 7 Pro</a> and utilize the aptX codec supported by the MTW4s. Playing audio back in standard aptX at CD quality (16bit, 44.1kHz) is a delightful experience and one of the reasons why Sennheiser continues to be my “go-to” for active listening. Despite being what I call “boom bap balanced,” Sennheiser produces a large soundstage regardless of musical genre. This is evident when listening to Paul Simon’s “Diamonds on the Souls of Her Shoes.” Ladysmith Black Mambazo’s acapella intro has a heavenly quality, and when the instrumentation finally kicks in around a minute and ten seconds into the song, the meticulously layered stereo image is absolutely beautiful.</p><p>Boom bap balanced is a reference to hip-hop-inspired tuning, which shines through on what is arguably among the best produced and engineered rap songs, “Still D.R.E.,” making Dr. Dre’s tracks and samples crystal clear. His and Snoop Dogg’s vocals are bright and never muddy, and the way Dr. Dre plays with the panning between the song’s body and Snoop’s smooth delivery of the chorus is a Master Class in rap track engineering. But I digress.</p><p>The out-of-the-box sound experience on the Momentum True Wireless 4s is an excellent boom bap balanced base to begin with, but going through the guided EQ customization of the Smart Controls app&apos;s Sound Personalization feature elevates the overall experience. I pulled the mids and highs a bit more forward by the end of the personalization routine, resulting in one of the best Bluetooth earbud listening experiences I’ve had with Beyonce’s “Texas Hold ‘Em.” But it doesn&apos;t stop there.</p><p>The Smart Control app provides additional customization options. Tapping “edit” on the Equalizer tile allows you to utilize a variety of Sennheiser presets, use its five-band equalizer to adjust frequency nodes, or use the Sound Check feature to tailor multiple EQs to accommodate specific genres you listen to.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="bPxuwvTrNm6T9s5wctgMd" name="sennheiser-momentum-true-wireless-4-decoding-aptx.jpeg" alt="Sennheiser Momentum True Wireless 4 streaming with aptX codec" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bPxuwvTrNm6T9s5wctgMd.jpeg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>For you music nerds out there or those trying to learn more, the app will even show you data about the music while it’s playing, which can come in handy.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-sennheiser-momentum-true-wireless-4-momentum-4-the-future"><span>Sennheiser Momentum True Wireless 4: Momentum 4 the future</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="jCMHyPtEzXM67aU9FMEyEo" name="sennheiser-momentum-true-wireless-4-buds-and-pixel-7-pro.jpg" alt="Sennheiser Momentum True Wireless 4 and Pixel 7 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jCMHyPtEzXM67aU9FMEyEo.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="caption-text">Sennheiser True Wireless 4 with Pixel 7 Pro </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The MTW4&apos;s chipset is Qualcomm’s S5 Sound Gen 2 platform with Snapdragon Sound with Bluetooth 5.4 and support for aptX Lossless, aptX Adaptive Audio, Bluetooth LE Audio, LC3, and Auracast. That&apos;s what will enable those future upgrades and future-proof these earbuds.</p><p>The claim is that the chipset will enable “bit-by-bit flawless audio transmission.” Sweet! However, if you’re the average smartphone consumer in North America, you likely don’t currently own a phone that supports aptX Lossless or Adaptive Audio. Boo!</p><p>Nontheless, LE Audio will eventually include an updated LC3 codec in the MTW4s. The Bluetooth SIG says this codec will improve battery life by streaming audio at lower data rates without compromising quality.</p><p>Then there&apos;s Auracast, which is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-bluetooth-le-audio-stream-discovery">your Bluetooth connection to the world</a>. It enables a single-source public address system to broadcast audio to what they claim will be a limitless number of devices, kind of like FM radio (if you’re FM radio years old and know what that is). So you can easily pick up audio from TVs at the gym or that self-led docent tour at your favorite museum. </p><p>What&apos;s most exciting is what Auracast enables for those who wear hearing aids. They&apos;ll get direct audio feeds without the hearing aids having to process ambient sound so users can hear TVs and music. Auracast support is also coming to the Momentum True Wireless 4 earbuds via a future firmware update.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-sennheiser-momentum-true-wireless-4-what-could-use-some-work"><span>Sennheiser Momentum True Wireless 4: What could use some work</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="c23FbjTTgB87EkJsBDeRQm" name="sennheiser-momentum-true-wireless-4-outside-charging-case-showing-contacts.jpg" alt="Sennheiser Momentum True Wireless 4" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/c23FbjTTgB87EkJsBDeRQm.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In addition to the earbuds not having all the features at launch, the Momentum True Wireless 4&apos;s case is larger than some of its competition, making it a tight fit in your jeans coin pocket and a bit bulky in a pants pocket. It isn&apos;t terrible, but you feel that difference if you&apos;ve been using something a bit more svelte.</p><p>The ANC, though well implemented, doesn&apos;t allow you to just crank it to the max and stay there. This is, after all, adaptive noise canceling, which, as the name implies, automatically adjusts to your surroundings. It&apos;s a plus for battery life when you don&apos;t need aggressive canceling, and the level scales down along with battery usage, but sitting at my quiet desk typing this with it on and no music playing, I can hear my delightfully clicky and loud mechanical keyboard. However, when pressing play on "Texas Hold&apos; Em" again, the clicky keys are barely perceptible.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="rwjaYZ3YFQoUrB7zio8wsL" name="sennheiser-momentum-true-wireless-4-closed-case-closeup.jpg" alt="Sennheiser Momentum True Wireless 4 charging case close up" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rwjaYZ3YFQoUrB7zio8wsL.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Something else I don&apos;t care about is that the charge port for the case is on the front, while the charge cables on my desk are routed through the back. So, if I turn it around and plug it up, I can’t see the charging indicator. I imagine this design decision was likely made because of the wireless charging, but it still seems... backward.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-sennheiser-momentum-true-wireless-4-competition"><span>Sennheiser Momentum True Wireless 4: Competition</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="cDn639EshTRyu6vhQ4TaQP" name="sennheiser-momentum-true-wireless-4-with-technics-az80-cases-open.jpg" alt="Sennheiser Momentum True Wireless 4 next to Technics AZ80" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/cDn639EshTRyu6vhQ4TaQP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="caption-text">Right: Technics EAH-AZ80 </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>One of my favorite earbuds this year, so far, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/technics-eah-az80-review">Technics EAH-AZ80</a>, beats Sennheiser in the multipoint race, being the first to support three device simultaneous connections. And for those looking for something with a bit more swag in terms of design, its brushed metal aesthetic is eye-catching. Then, of course, when we’re talking about noise canceling as a priority in your purchasing decision, you’re going to look at Sony’s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/sony-wf-1000xm5-review">WF-1000XM5</a> and the Bose QuietComfort Ultra earbuds. There’s also the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/beats-fit-pro-review">Beats Fit Pro</a> if workouts are a central part of your life- another favorite of mine.</p><p>Looking at that competition, you just really need to know what’s most important to you. Technics’ sound profile is more treble forward out of the box, Beats are definitely heavier in the bottom end than Sennheiser, and Bose is absolutely neutral when compared to the Sennheiser curve.</p><p>Other than standing out with Bluetooth 5.4, Sennheiser also has the highest durability rating at IP54, upgrading from the IPX4 found in the previous generation and the current competition.</p>
<h2 class="article-body__section" id="section-sennheiser-momentum-true-wireless-4-should-you-buy-it"><span>Sennheiser Momentum True Wireless 4: Should you buy it?</span></h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="HvK4yyNQgmcY543hSBkFe8" name="sennheiser-momentum-true-wireless-4-on-pixel-7-pro-hero.jpeg" alt="Sennheiser Momentum True Wireless 4 on top of Pixel 7 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HvK4yyNQgmcY543hSBkFe8.jpeg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>You should buy this if...</strong></p>
<ul><li>Big, airy, warm sound is important to you </li><li>You like and listen to everything. All the genres </li><li>You like living on the bleeding edge of tech and are willing to bet on being able to access future enhancements</li></ul>
<p><strong>You shouldn&apos;t buy this if...</strong></p>
<ul><li>Noise canceling is your top priority</li><li>You don't care about lossless audio</li><li>Your wallet weeps at the thought of spending $300 for earbuds</li></ul>
<p>Bluetooth 5.4, multipoint pairing, an exhaustive list of codec support, and Sennheiser sound are among the many reasons to take a hard look at Sennheiser’s Momentum True Wireless 4 earbuds for your next audio gear purchase. They check all the right boxes for me, including the most important one: sound quality. Sure, there are better noise-canceling earbuds on the market, but when we talk about cancellation effectiveness, how many of you engage in an activity and use your earbuds with no audio? With audio playing, the difference in quality between Sennheiser and its competitors is negligible, and you don’t have to sacrifice audio quality for it.</p><p>If Sennheiser and the Bluetooth SIG deliver on their technological promises, that could make these the earbuds to beat in the near future if you’re outside the U.S. Stateside though, only time will tell as we wait for handset manufacturers to implement all that Bluetooth 5.4 offers.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="8d20263f-051d-47f1-88f6-b5046025f562">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.10%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/w2VhknkrGW3ro4bypadKDA.jpg' alt='Sennheiser Momentum True Wireless 4'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Sennheiser Momentum True Wireless 4</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>More to come</strong></em></p>
<p>The Sennheiser Momentum True Wireless 4 are some of the best sounding earbuds you can buy, with support for plenty of audio codecs for high-res audio. And with more features on the way, these earbuds are practically future-proof.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/earbuds/sennheiser-momentum-true-wireless-4-review</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Sennheiser Momentum True Wireless 4 are top tier competitors for wireless earbuds right now, but what they may do in the future could make them even better. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">7mUmmBYDv5zcL53nxWAbVc</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Jixq34LZe6UvsLmpj74t7m.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 08:00:44 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Earbuds]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ klpmediallc@gmail.com (Tshaka Armstrong) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Jixq34LZe6UvsLmpj74t7m.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Tshaka Armstrong]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Sennheiser Momentum True Wireless 4]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Sennheiser Momentum True Wireless 4]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ reMarkable's new update takes advantage of the cloud  ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What You Need To Know</h2>
<ul><li>Users with a Connect subscription can archive large files and store them in the cloud.</li><li>The desktop app has a more traditional notebook feel to it. </li><li>Type Folio users will have access to new keyboard shortcuts. </li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Users of reMarkable paper tablets will now be able to take advantage of having unlimited cloud storage as part of the company’s 3.10 software release. The update, which is rolling out, also brings new updates for the desktop app as well as a slew of other improvements, including new sorting features and keyboard shortcuts, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://news.remarkable.com/remarkables-new-software-release-adds-cloud-archiving-and-handwriting-conversion-in-the-desktop-app">per the company&apos;s blog</a>. </p><p>The most noteworthy feature is the aforementioned cloud storage capabilities that users will be able to take advantage of. Users will now be able to archive large or unused files and place them in the cloud. Those archived files will always be accessible on the reMarkable mobile and desktop apps along with the device itself. While the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/remarkable-2-review">reMarkable 2</a> provides 8GB of onboard storage, freeing up large or unwanted files is always a safe bet, especially if those files can be easily accessed later on. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2427px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="zo5V8S5xbgM8BKwkkMFWR8" name="reMarkable-archive-files.jpg" alt="Archiving files on a reMarkable device" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zo5V8S5xbgM8BKwkkMFWR8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2427" height="1365" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: reMarkable)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It’s important to note that to take advantage of this new feature, users must have an active Connect subscription. Connect provides users with unlimited cloud storage along with note-taking on desktop and mobile and extra protection for the device. It costs $2.99 a month or $29.90 annually, though consumers are given a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.remarkable.com/s/article/Information-about-Connect">one-year Connect trial</a> when they purchase the reMarkable 2 on the company’s shop. </p><p>reMarkable users will also notice that the desktop app has a new look following the 3.10 software release. The app is now more in line with a traditional notebook, featuring paper-like background colors and a Serif font. </p><p>Additionally, those who are subscribed to Connect can now convert their handwritten notes into typed text directly from the desktop app, where they can edit them in full. Handwritten notes can be converted into text from an entire page, a range of pages, or single pieces within a page. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2427px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="aCPWC5bzmU6dHUXy9pCMd8" name="reMarkable-files.jpg" alt="Viewing files on a reMarkable device" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/aCPWC5bzmU6dHUXy9pCMd8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2427" height="1365" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: reMarkable)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Rounding out the update are new sorting features on the table itself that allow users to organize files alphabetically or by their last modified date. Tablet users who have a Type Folio keyboard will also have access to new shortcuts that make browsing documents even easier. Lastly, handwritten notes that are converted using the selection tool will no longer be saved to the clipboard and will instead be pasted onto the page. </p><p>reMarkable also notes in its blog that multiple tablets can be paired to one account, therefore allowing users to see updates made from a reMarkable 2 on a first-gen tablet and so forth. In all, these updates continue the Norwegian company’s commitment to changing the way consumers take notes, read, and edit documents. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/remarkable-software-update-cloud-file-management</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The update is rolling out today, and brings multiple quality of live improvements.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">XZr8twKHHue6sbYyjDK3YA</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GJg6GHZ2kVc6SvRDdra9Co.png" type="image/png" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 06:51:58 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/png" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GJg6GHZ2kVc6SvRDdra9Co.png">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[reMarkable]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[reMarkable update 3.10]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[reMarkable update 3.10]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Pixel 8a leak reveals upgrades that make it almost as good as the Pixel 8 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google's upcoming Pixel 8a is a budget smartphone based on the Pixel 8, and it could debut in a few months. </li><li>The smartphone was recently spotted in FCC databases, which is a clear indicator that the Pixel 8a is on the way. </li><li>Now, a major leak confirms that the Pixel 8a will feature a 120Hz display, a Tensor G3 chip, and more upgrades. </li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google&apos;s budget lineup of A-series phones has seen significant upgrades over the past few years, bringing the Pixel devices in line with Pixel flagships. The Pixel 7a, for example, was <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-7a-vs-7">so similar to the Pixel 7</a> that some wondered whether Google would even release a Pixel 8a this year. Nevertheless, a Pixel 8a is all but confirmed, and a major leak just gave us a bunch of details about the upcoming smartphone. </p><p>The leak comes from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/google-pixel-8a-specs-exclusive-3426314/" target="_blank">Android Authority</a>, which confirms a few things we already knew about the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a">Pixel 8a</a> and adds some fresh detail as well. For starters, the display is going to reach flagship quality thanks to the boost to 120Hz. The Pixel 6a had a 60Hz refresh rate, and the Pixel 7a got the upgrade to 90Hz. Now, with the Pixel 8a projected to get 120Hz, it&apos;s on par with many of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a> available.</p><p>Namely, it&apos;s identical to the Pixel 8&apos;s display specifications. Android Authority also reports that the Pixel 8a will be brighter, supporting 1,400 nits at peak brightness. The Pixel 8a is also expected to keep the same 6.1-inch screen size as the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-7a-review">Pixel 7a</a>, but the corner radius is reportedly changing to match the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-review">Pixel 8</a> series. In all, the display is getting a big upgrade, and it&apos;s going to be even closer to flagship quality than ever. </p><p>In a more unsurprising move, the Pixel 8a should be powered by the Tensor G3 chip. That&apos;s the same as the Pixel 8 and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-pro-review">Pixel 8 Pro</a>. However, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-not-getting-gemini-nano">as we&apos;ve learned</a> with some AI features, the inclusion of the Tensor G3 chip doesn&apos;t guarantee the Pixel 8a will have the same feature set as other Pixel 8 series devices. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:555px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:133.33%;"><img id="fPsRXSJ5mYLKggjqJpWbfV" name="google-pixel-8a-retail-box.jpg" alt="Pixel 8a retail box showing a black version of the phone" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fPsRXSJ5mYLKggjqJpWbfV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="555" height="740" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: @chunvn8888 / X)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Pixel 8a is tabbed to get functional display output over USB-C, joining the other Pixel 8 series devices. Though Google enabled DisplayPort at the hardware level on the Pixel 8 lineup this year, it only <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-qpr3-beta-2-pixel-8-display-out">recently activated the feature in beta software</a> releases.</p><p>Something that isn&apos;t changing is the camera system. The Pixel 7a got an upgrade to its main camera sensor last year, and Google is using the same one in the Pixel 8a.  </p><p>The Pixel 8a is likely to launch soon, perhaps at the Google I/O event slated for early May 2024. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-reaches-us-fcc-listing">FCC approved multiple models of the Pixel 8a</a> on Monday, March 18, which is a sign that new devices are close to release.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-leaked-display-upgrade</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Google Pixel 8a could debut as early as in a few months, and leaks suggest that big upgrades could be on the way.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">K96mGzSoLiD3wrBCmArEX3</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YgCoruYwPuJQaXupVMkJmA.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 06:27:24 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YgCoruYwPuJQaXupVMkJmA.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Abhishek Yadav/ via X]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Pixel 8a hands-on leak]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Pixel 8a hands-on leak]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ A new type of Kindle might be on the horizon, but not the kind we need ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Gadget Weekly</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="DZLQ4jKZk9tEF5A3sqU5Jh" name="inspector-lloyd-square.jpg" caption="" alt="Inspector Lloyd" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DZLQ4jKZk9tEF5A3sqU5Jh.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">Join Namerah Saud Fatmi as she explores the cool, quirky, and sometimes downright odd world of smartphone accessories, gadgets, and other nerdy toys <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/gadget-weekly">every week</a>.</p></div></div>
<p>Amazon doesn&apos;t refresh its best-selling Kindle lineup very often. Unlike Android phones and tablets, e-readers see updated models once in two to three years. It probably doesn&apos;t make sense to upgrade such devices as often as phones because the improvements would be too minimal.</p><p>Every single one of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-amazon-kindle">Amazon&apos;s Kindle e-readers</a> have had black and white displays to date. It&apos;s not like the technology for color e-paper doesn&apos;t exist, though. Competitors like Onyx Boox and Pocketbook have long since taken advantage of the E Ink Corporation&apos;s color e-paper displays.</p><p>Now that color e-ink displays are several generations old, it seems like Amazon might cash in.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3938px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="buq6EuQNRDatmJBKwQjAgc" name="Onyx-Boox-Nova-Air-C-5.jpg" alt="Onyx Boox Nova Air C" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/buq6EuQNRDatmJBKwQjAgc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3938" height="2215" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div></figure>
<p>Earlier this month, analyst Ming-Chi Kuo — who mainly focuses on Apple products and trends — predicted that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://medium.com/@mingchikuo/%E5%85%83%E5%A4%AA%E5%8F%AF%E6%9C%9B%E9%A1%AF%E8%91%97%E5%8F%97%E6%83%A0%E6%96%BCamazon%E6%8E%A1%E7%94%A8%E5%BD%A9%E8%89%B2%E9%9B%BB%E5%AD%90%E7%B4%99%E8%88%87walmart%E6%8E%A1%E7%94%A8%E5%9B%9B%E8%89%B2esl-e-ink-expected-to-benefit-significantly-from-amazons-e458370ee119">Amazon is likely to roll out color E Ink devices</a> as early as 2025. Despite the high cost associated with color e-paper screens, Kuo&apos;s predictions suggest that color Kindles will come with the latest Advanced Color ePaper (ACeP) display.</p><p>Amazon generally plays it very safe with its e-readers, but Kuo&apos;s insight leans towards a potentially risky move. See, the cost of e-paper screens is the most expensive part of any e-paper device. Color e-ink displays cost more than double the price of B&W e-ink screens.</p><p>This means that a color Kindle would probably cost nearly twice as much as a regular old Amazon e-reader and that spells trouble for the brand. One of the major selling points of a Kindle is that it is darn cheap and accessible. Feature-wise, it loses out to competitors like Onyx Boox in nearly every single category except for waterproofing.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3210px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="zSTRyQjiVK6piJedRd4zqX" name="Amazon-Kindle-2022-review-text-display.jpg" alt="Kindle (2022) display text" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zSTRyQjiVK6piJedRd4zqX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3210" height="1805" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Amazon limits the potential of its Kindles, filling them with ads and removing access to the Google Play Store. On the other hand, other popular e-readers like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/onyx-boox-palma-review">Boox Palma</a> give you unfettered access to the Play Store, and you are free to install whatever app you want. Then there are other factors like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-e-ink-tablet">e-ink tablets</a> with styli, speakers, a mic, and microSD card slots.</p><p>When such fully-featured e-readers exist, the only reason why people buy Amazon&apos;s limited paper tablets is obviously money. And when an expensive color Kindle rolls around with just as narrow a use case as all the rest of the Kindles, it just won&apos;t make sense to the consumer anymore.</p><p>If you don&apos;t believe me, just take a look at the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/amazon-kindle-scribe-review">Kindle Scribe</a>, which comes in at around $340 apiece. For the same amount of money, you can purchase something from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/onyx-boox-tab-x-review">Onyx Boox with far superior specs</a> and a stylus that supports better pressure sensitivity levels with unrestricted access to the Play Store. Add a little more money and you can even score one with a color screen.</p><p>There was a lot of talk about a Kindle with a stylus up to its release, but once everyone saw the price of the Scribe, they weren&apos;t as interested anymore. The general consensus is that the device doesn&apos;t deliver much value for money.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3459px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.26%;"><img id="uJp2bfxLpBkot3zHm5QWXX" name="onyx-boox-tab-x-lifestyle-8.jpg" alt="Onyx Boox Tab X E Ink tablet" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uJp2bfxLpBkot3zHm5QWXX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3459" height="1946" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Aside from the price, the only other factor keeping Kindles at the top is the battery life. As we have tested and discovered time and time again, color e-paper tablets don&apos;t last anywhere near as long as monochrome black-and-white ones.</p><p>Naturally, you won&apos;t be able to squeeze out weeks upon weeks of battery life from a color Kindle, at least not unless you are very miserly with your usage or Amazon bumps up the battery capacity significantly. Neither of those scenarios is optimal because you either sacrifice performance or the price goes up even more because of the larger battery.</p><p>At the end of the day, I am forced to ask a simple question. Who benefits from a color Kindle? Is this even something we want to see? Based on my own judgment, I wouldn&apos;t say so.</p><p>Instead, I would much rather see a Kindle with the Play Store, speakers, more apps, a microSD slot, or something else practical along those lines. Give me fast charging or better stylus support. I want a better Kindle, not the same old thing in color.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/rumored-color-amazon-kindle-not-what-we-need</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Rumors fly amock about a color Kindle. Whether this is true or not is secondary. What you should really be asking is whether we even need one. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Fdb6JeTTRDzCh56mdwivFP</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hZGvWJGCREENwEymTCJwNa.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 06:00:41 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hZGvWJGCREENwEymTCJwNa.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A color Kindle mockup]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A color Kindle mockup]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung patent highlights a more personal Galaxy AI feature ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A new Samsung patent has reportedly been spotted, detailing a more personal AI summarization feature for Galaxy AI.</li><li>The patent users would be able to tell the AI how long or short they'd like the summary to be and what tone of voice it should use.</li><li>The AI would base its informational responses on a user's search history, preferences, and more.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Information has surfaced regarding a new Galaxy AI feature Samsung is currently developing.</p><p>According to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://biz.chosun.com/it-science/ict/2024/03/18/FBLRRYLHZ5ANBBHWO3A5ZXWWHQ/">ChosunBiz</a> (Korean),  Samsung has submitted a patent to the South Korean government detailing an upgraded AI summarization feature (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.sammobile.com/news/new-galaxy-ai-features-are-coming-with-next-gen-foldable-phones/">SamMobile</a>). The KIPRIS patent system states Samsung has designed this feature to provide a more personalized summary experience.</p><p>The AI is said to examine a user&apos;s "usage history" to provide answers appropriately. The patent reportedly adds that the AI will take into account a user&apos;s preference, level of knowledge on various subjects, and more. Additionally, the AI will understand a user&apos;s interests and "non-interests" by using their search history.</p><p>Users may also be able to customize how the AI provides a summary on a given topic. The publication states that Samsung aims for users to tell the AI how long they&apos;d like the summary to be and its tone of voice. An example the Korean OEM provided in its patent reads, "please summarize in a long and negative tone."</p><p>Speculation states Samsung could roll out this new feature on the Galaxy Z Flip 6 later this year. Only time will tell, as this could simply be a feature Samsung playtests but never releases for consumers.</p><p>What&apos;s interesting about this "enhanced" AI summarization is that Samsung already rolled out a version of this with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-galaxy-ai">Galaxy AI</a>. The Galaxy S24 series can summarize lengthy pieces of text, like a document or web page, for users. However, the patent details a feature that may bring a new level of customization to users.</p><p>We&apos;re <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-s23-march-security-patch-2024">still waiting for</a> several Galaxy AI features to arrive on Samsung&apos;s past-gen devices, like the S23 series. The company <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-ai-features-coming-to-older-galaxy-phones">detailed its plans</a> to do so back in January, stating users will gain Circle to Search, live translation, Chat Assist, and the current summary feature. These are slated to arrive with its One UI 6.1 update, which still has yet to roll out.</p><p>If Samsung plans to release this feature in its next clamshell, it could happen in July. A rumor at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-unpacked-summer-2024-rumor">the end of February</a> suggested as much and also purported Samsung could hold its event in Paris, France.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-galaxy-ai-summary-patent-spotted</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A recently discovered Samsung patent details a more personal Galaxy AI feature. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">HmPmNgQthy2uKjVc3LocwD</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/m2Kcau6uMkxdqAt6SSqgVU.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 21:36:35 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/m2Kcau6uMkxdqAt6SSqgVU.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Samsung]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy AI]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy AI]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Maps picks up its easy public transit directions on Wear OS ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google has started pushing a server-side update for Maps that brings its public transit directions to Wear OS 3 or above devices.</li><li>Users can search for a place and find navigation methods like driving, walking, trains, and more.</li><li>Maps will offer "recommended routes" and all routes, letting users decide which they prefer, along with the steps they'll need to take.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google is beginning its rollout of a new feature in Maps that should give users hands-free directions.</p><p>As spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/03/19/google-maps-wear-os-transit-directions/">9to5Google</a>, Google Maps&apos; latest update is rolling out today (Mar. 19) as a server-side update as part of version 11.119.0702 on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wear-os-watch">Wear OS</a>. Users can now search for a place on their watch and find directions for different methods of public transportation. Maps will display options for walking, driving, trains, and more.</p><p>Once you&apos;re ready to navigate, users can decide between Maps&apos; "recommended routes" or all available routes.</p><p>Tapping on either will expand a list of ways users can reach their destination with information on train times and more. A "Preview Route" option awaits users in a route&apos;s list of steps, letting you see every train stop and which is yours before selecting it.</p><p>The publication states Google Maps&apos; new public transit directions Wear OS&apos; tile to start navigating to "Home" or "Work." Additionally, exiting Maps&apos; new public transit directions will display a train icon at the bottom of your watch face. Tapping this sends you back to the app for an update on where you&apos;re going.</p><p>As this is a server-side update, it may take a little while for your Wear OS 3 device or above to display the new feature.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:599px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.17%;"><img id="QKFX5ywiiBFbVLFAQ8qEDc" name="google-wear-os-public-transit-directions-example.jpg" alt="An example of a user looking a recommended route on a train from a Wear OS device." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QKFX5ywiiBFbVLFAQ8qEDc.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="599" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: 9to5Google)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1389px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:40.60%;"><img id="ka53EHpYc5yqWa3jRkB29Y" name="google-wear-os-google-maps-directions-update.jpg" alt="Google's latest Android updates brings transit directions to Wear OS devices." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ka53EHpYc5yqWa3jRkB29Y.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1389" height="564" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Google briefly highlighted Wear OS&apos; <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-highlights-android-updates-mwc-2024">public transit directions</a> in Maps during MWC 2024. The company stated users could mirror directions they&apos;ve started looking at on their phone to their <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-2-review">Pixel Watch 2</a> or other Wear OS device for a hands-free experience. Wear OS&apos; update for Maps will likely work well with the Android app&apos;s public transit update, which rolled out <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-maps-public-transit-emoji-update">in November</a>.</p><p>Meanwhile, this was one of a few updates we&apos;ve been waiting on for Wear OS ever since Google detailed the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-pixel-devices-get-march-feature-drop">March feature drop</a>. Original Pixel Watch owners received some Watch 2 features like Pace training, heart zone training, and the auto workout mode. The Fitbit Relax app also made its way to the first-gen watch, bringing with it guided breathing exercises for a wellness break.</p>
<ul><li> <strong>Smartwatch deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/searchpage.jsp?st=smartwatch&_dyncharset=UTF-8&_dynSessConf=&id=pcat17071&type=page&sc=Global&cp=1&nrp=&sp=&qp=&list=n&af=true&iht=y&usc=All+Categories&ks=960&keys=keys"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/search?q=smartwatch"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=smartwatch&crid=19YAPQ38561AK&sprefix=smartwatch%2Caps%2C138&ref=nb_sb_ss_ts-doa-p_1_10"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/watches-audio-accessories-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.dell.com/en-us/search/smartwatch"><u><strong>Dell</strong></u></a></li></ul>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="16091b71-9fc1-481d-b869-bb641b99e8a6">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/onRVssvukH2fYPesKaH49U.jpg' alt='google pixel watch 2 square render 1'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel Watch 2</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The Apple Watch for Android</strong></em></p>
<p>Google's Pixel Watch 2 takes what consumers have enjoyed about the first iteration and pushed it further. The device offers the same recognizable domed-glass display but with improved sensors. Google and Fitbit have redesigned its heart rate sensors for a more accurate telling of your heart's health during workouts and more.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-maps-wear-os-public-transit-directions-rollout</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google Maps has started rolling out its public transit directions on Wear OS devices. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">CLVPEHL9SX4JK2pyntpshX</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9Sw4Jg6698WXgSrkTGaJq4.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 21:23:11 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9Sw4Jg6698WXgSrkTGaJq4.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Pixel Watch 2 hands-on]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Pixel Watch 2 hands-on]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Mint Mobile launches new BOGO deal — here's how to claim three months of free wireless  ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>It&apos;s typically pretty easy to find Mint Mobile deals that&apos;ll lower your phone bill, but you&apos;ve probably never seen an offer quite like this. Switch to Mint Mobile from Verizon or AT&T and sign up for any three-month data plan, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/best-value-wireless/"><strong>the carrier will give you a second identical plan for 100% free</strong></a>. </p><p>Plenty of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/mint-mobile-deals-promo-codes">Mint Mobile deals</a> hook you up with "free" wireless service, but this is the first BOGO opportunity I&apos;ve ever seen from the carrier. All data plans are eligible for the deal — including the Unlimited plan — and since all of Mint&apos;s plans are just $15 per month for the first three months (for a limited time), this means that you can cover TWO users with excellent coverage for three months and <strong>only pay $45 upfront. </strong>Seriously. </p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="ab32f7a5-8d99-48d7-9ba0-9d24b36b787b" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Buy one plan, get a second plan FREE at Mint Mobile" data-dimension48="Buy one plan, get a second plan FREE at Mint Mobile" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/best-value-wireless/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="BPWiQe3vKGWbwqwX3mVeqG" name="mint-mobile-logo.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BPWiQe3vKGWbwqwX3mVeqG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="0" height="0" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><a href="https://www.mintmobile.com/best-value-wireless/" data-dimension112="ab32f7a5-8d99-48d7-9ba0-9d24b36b787b" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Buy one plan, get a second plan FREE at Mint Mobile" data-dimension48="Buy one plan, get a second plan FREE at Mint Mobile"><strong>Buy one plan, get a second plan FREE at Mint Mobile</strong></a></p>
<p>Bring your number over from AT&T or Verizon and sign up for any three-month data plan, and Mint Mobile will hook you up with a second identical plan for 100% free. This BOGO offer will apply to any of Mint's plans, including the Unlimited tier (currently just $45 for three months). </p>
<p>All of Mint's data plans are powered by T-Mobile's vast 5G network, plus you get unlimited talk and text, free calls to Mexico and Canada, a free mobile hotspot, and much more. You're also only paying for three months of wireless service. If you decide you don't want to stick with Mint after that time, simply cancel your account and you'll only be down $45. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/best-value-wireless/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="ab32f7a5-8d99-48d7-9ba0-9d24b36b787b" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Buy one plan, get a second plan FREE at Mint Mobile" data-dimension48="Buy one plan, get a second plan FREE at Mint Mobile">View Deal</a></p></div>
<h2 id="need-a-new-phone-too-2">Need a new phone too?</h2>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="2d6b99e8-9fca-4165-a9f9-9ff4e25d0322" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy S24 128GB: $800" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy S24 128GB: $800" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/samsung-galaxy-s24/5418243/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1200px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="NqhoUu3WzqW2D7ngA6rmHK" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-render-square-crop-black.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NqhoUu3WzqW2D7ngA6rmHK.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1200" height="1200" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy S24 128GB: </strong><a href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/samsung-galaxy-s24/5418243/" data-dimension112="2d6b99e8-9fca-4165-a9f9-9ff4e25d0322" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy S24 128GB: $800" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy S24 128GB: $800"><del>$800</del> <strong>$700, plus six months free with any six-month plan</strong></a></p>
<p>If you need a new phone to pair with your new carrier, check out this deal that gives you $100 off the Samsung Galaxy S24 along with six months of free wireless when you sign up for any six-month plan at Mint. To put it another way, you could be getting an outstanding 2024 device and an entire year of phone service for as little as $33 per month when you pay using Affirm. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/samsung-galaxy-s24/5418243/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="2d6b99e8-9fca-4165-a9f9-9ff4e25d0322" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Samsung Galaxy S24 128GB: $800" data-dimension48="Samsung Galaxy S24 128GB: $800">View Deal</a></p></div>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/amazon-spring-sale-2024-early-deals-predictions-and-what-to-expect"><strong>Amazon's Big Spring Sale starts March 20th:</strong> check out the best deals so far</a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/carriers/mint-mobile-launches-new-bogo-deal-heres-how-to-claim-three-months-of-free-wireless</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Mint Mobile has just announced a deal that'll hook you up with a second identical line for free when you buy any three-month plan.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">VHKSe8Y9YuN2uCHhfsrtei</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="http://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QYaWj3isE7uepq9ox8duKC.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 19:52:51 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Carriers]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QYaWj3isE7uepq9ox8duKC.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Mint Mobile home page on Pixel 6]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Mint Mobile home page on Pixel 6]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google's Liz Reid wants more AI and 'SGE' as she becomes head of Search ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Today (Mar. 19), Google appointed Liz Reid as its new head of Search.</li><li>Reid has a history of working with AI, specifically in Search, through Search Labs' SGE (search generative experience).</li><li>Reid stated she wants to implement more "SGE" and AI overviews into Google Search as the company improves its capability of understanding context-rich queries.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Today (Mar. 19), Google has a new head of Search who will take the reigns to "shape the future."</p><p>Announced via a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/elizabeth-reid-56356724_today-im-taking-on-a-new-role-leading-search-activity-7175645922851262465-oYX6/">LinkedIn</a> post, Liz Reid is Google&apos;s new head of Search, and one of her primary goals is to plug more AI into the product (via TheVerge). Reid has been with Google since 2003, and the bulk of her work involved Search&apos;s AI, known as its "Search Generative Experience" (SGE) and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-search-food-restaurants-multisearch-integration">multisearch</a>.</p><p>Reid states that we&apos;ve entered an "exciting time" for Search as user positivity behind queries reportedly grows in Google&apos;s "major markets." During her time with the company, she mentioned some of the features Search has recently gained, such as Google Lens (visual search), Circle to Search, and SGE&apos;s AI overviews.</p><p>AI will lead Search further, as Reid states, "with SGE, we are able to serve a wider range of information needs and answer new types of questions, including more complex questions, like comparisons or longer queries." She teases, "More coming soon!"</p><p>The publication recounted a discussion with Reid before <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-opens-access-to-search-labs">Search Labs</a> launched in 2023, during which she mentioned "lowering the bar to asking Google your real questions." Essentially, Google is looking to AI to help its Search experience better understand context-rich queries and produce responses.</p><p>In addition to Reid&apos;s new position, Cheenu Venkatachary is now overseeing Google Search&apos;s ranking and quality. Google News and Discover&apos;s Cathy Edwards is now said to have joined the company&apos;s long-term bets team.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.28%;"><img id="H668jKUNrYyRWCJvQL4z3D" name="google-SGE-hero.jpg" alt="Google generative AI in Search" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/H668jKUNrYyRWCJvQL4z3D.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1800" height="1013" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Jay Bonggolto / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>SGE&apos;s colorful text boxes were shown alongside Search Labs&apos; introduction in 2023. Google said SGE would scour the web for the<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-opens-access-to-search-labs"> most relevant answers</a> before allowing users to dive deeper with alternatives. However, AI is prone to hallucinations, which pushed Google to start testing <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-tests-source-linking-generative-ai-search">source links for SGE</a>. Enrolled testers discovered in-line links to where the company&apos;s AI gathered the information so users could fact-check it.</p><p>Most recently, Google&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-circle-to-search-ai-powered-multisearch-rollout">AI overviews</a> started arriving in its main Android app for all users. In addition to multisearch, users can snap a photo of an item they&apos;re unsure about and run it through Google&apos;s engine for a complete breakdown. Much like Reid is interested in bringing more AI to Search, so is Google.</p><p>The company stated it will look to roll out SGE experiments "more broadly" to users regardless of their enrollment in Search Labs. Google adds this should help it understand what users need.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-liz-reid-appointed-head-of-search</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google appointed Liz Reid as its new head of Search and she detailed her quest to bring more AI to the engine. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">bZfHymj3xwNNQWWEy3iPia</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="http://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4TPzihga6W989NvTvMFhqP.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 18:45:52 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4TPzihga6W989NvTvMFhqP.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Logo]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Logo]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Microsoft nabs Google DeepMind co-founder to lead its AI mission ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Microsoft has hired Google DeepMind's co-founder Mustafa Suleyman to oversee all things AI.</li><li>He co-founded DeepMind back in 2010, which Google then acquired in 2014. Following this, he was appointed as Google's vice president of AI product management and AI police.</li><li>Suleman, along with his Chief Scientist Karén Simonyan, will now form a new organization called Microsoft AI.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Microsoft announced on Tuesday (Mar.19) that it has hired Mustafa Suleyman, the co-founder of Google DeepMind, to lead its consumer AI division.</p><p>As spotted by the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/3/19/24105900/google-deepmind-microsoft-mustafa-suleyman-ai-ceo">Verge</a>, Suleman took to X to announce his new role, stating that "I’ll be leading all consumer AI products and research, including Copilot, Bing, and Edge." According to the post, Suleyman will also serve as executive vice president of Microsoft AI and join the company’s senior leadership team. </p><p>Suleyman co-founded DeepMind in 2010, which Google later acquired in 2014. Suleyman was also involved in a controversy in 2019, after which Google placed him on leave. Later, he was <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.cnbc.com/2022/01/28/mustafa-suleyman-deepmind-co-founder-quits-google-ai-role-to-be-vc.html">appointed</a> Google&apos;s vice president of AI product management and AI police. </p><p>In 2022, Suleyman departed Google and co-founded a startup called Inflection AI, which he says will "continue on its mission under a new CEO and look to reach more people than ever by making its API widely available to developers and businesses the world over."</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I’m excited to announce that today I’m joining @Microsoft as CEO of Microsoft AI. I’ll be leading all consumer AI products and research, including Copilot, Bing and Edge. My friend and longtime collaborator Karén Simonyan will be Chief Scientist, and several of our amazing…<a href="https://twitter.com/mustafasuleyman/status/1770123596121432351">March 19, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>Microsoft&apos;s CEO Satya Nadala also sent out a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2024/03/19/mustafa-suleyman-deepmind-and-inflection-co-founder-joins-microsoft-to-lead-copilot/">memo</a> to his employees announcing the recent addition to the AI table. </p><p>"This is about science, engineering, product, and design coming together and embracing a learning mindset to push our innovation culture and product-building process forward in fundamental ways."</p><p>Nadala confirmed that Suleyman and Karén Simonyan, also from AI Inflection, will join Microsoft to form a new organization called Microsoft AI. This organization will focus on advancing Copilot and other consumer AI products and research. "Mustafa will be EVP and CEO of Microsoft AI and join the senior leadership team (SLT), reporting to me. Karén is joining this group as Chief Scientist, reporting to Mustafa," he added.</p><p>This move came after Microsoft <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/microsoft-hired-chatgpt-ceo-president">tried to hire OpenAI&apos;s CEOs</a>, Sam Altman and Greg Brockman, to lead its AI team in November 2023. However, that acquisition didn&apos;t go as planned. </p><p>Microsoft is currently the largest shareholder in OpenAI, investing over <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/microsoft-hired-chatgpt-ceo-president">$13 billion</a> in the company since 2019, according to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://time.com/6337503/sam-altman-joins-microsoft-ai/">Time</a>. OpenAI&apos;s ChatGPT tech, which rivals Google&apos;s own AI efforts such as <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini</a>, currently powers features such as <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/microsoft-bing-milestone-100-million-dau">Bing Chat</a>, and it looks like Microsoft is planning to shift gears and further its own AI tech in the near future.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-deepmind-co-founder-joins-microsoft</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Microsoft announces that Google DeepMind's co-founder will now run its consumer AI division, including Copilot, Bing, and Edge. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">AYUhQ9AUCSyD2trmjoSe26</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bbaAgjdsQaQCW7HL5rCiQS.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 18:23:18 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nandika.iyerravi@futurenet.com (Nandika Ravi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bbaAgjdsQaQCW7HL5rCiQS.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Microsoft Copilot logo on a phone screen]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Microsoft Copilot logo on a phone screen]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Pixel 8a spotted at the FCC listing ahead of Google IO 2024 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-32">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google Pixel 8a bearing G8HHN, GKV4X, G6GPR, and G576D models spotted at FCC.</li><li>The listing confirms the device launch is sooner, presumably at Google I/O 2024.</li><li>One of the model numbers matches with the Pixel 8a earlier retail packaging.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>With the Google I/O event right around the corner, we expect the Pixel 8a to be seen next to the launch of the Pixel Fold 2. While the latter&apos;s details are still scarce, the former just showed up at the U.S. FCC listing.</p><p>As noted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/03/18/google-pixel-8a-fcc/">9to5Google</a>, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a">Pixel 8a</a> bearing multiple model numbers has reached FCC approval on Monday (Mar. 18). They include <strong>G8HHN</strong>, <strong>GKV4X</strong>, <strong>G6GPR</strong>, and <strong>G576D</strong> — all of which are believed to be different variants of the same device. </p><p>As 9to5 indicates, this is a fairly common practice for every smartphone before launching since they are catered to different countries and carriers. Hence, the difference in model numbers is evident, which can be further different due to their connectivity options, such as 5G.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1707px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.06%;"><img id="nvF3cJYeeEGW93qF45oi6c" name="google-pixel-8a-leaked-tilted-render.jpg" alt="Leaked renders of the Pixel 8a." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nvF3cJYeeEGW93qF45oi6c.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1707" height="957" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: SmartPrix)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Previous leaks have showcased the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-leaked-renders">Pixel 8a renders</a> revealing its design alongside <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-retail-box-leaks">retail box leak</a>, which has further revealed the model number <strong>G6GPR</strong>. It evidently coincides with the latest FCC listing, confirming the device is indeed the Pixel 8a. </p><p>Aside from the FCC listing, the alleged Pixel 8a was also seen hitting a Denmark-based battery <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-rumored-to-have-a-bigger-battery">certification</a> last month. The device featured a <strong>GH2MB</strong> model number featuring a 4942mAh battery capacity, which could be touted as either 5000mAh or 5500mAh battery when the device launches. </p><p>While the model doesn&apos;t appear familiar to the aforementioned model numbers, previous leaks have indicated that it matches one of the Pixel 7a models, its predecessor in some regions.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:555px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:133.33%;"><img id="fPsRXSJ5mYLKggjqJpWbfV" name="google-pixel-8a-retail-box.jpg" alt="Pixel 8a retail box showing a black version of the phone" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fPsRXSJ5mYLKggjqJpWbfV.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="555" height="740" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: @chunvn8888 / X)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:555px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:133.33%;"><img id="W7A3Fd8gct4movd2qbsjmV" name="google-pixel-8a-retail-box-1.jpg" alt="Pixel 8a retail box showing a black version of the phone" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/W7A3Fd8gct4movd2qbsjmV.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="555" height="740" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: @chunvn8888 / X)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Apart from the certifications, the previous renders have given us the Pixel 8a in all its glory. It features a familiar design with a dual camera setup at the back and is believed to be coming in some kind of rose gold colorway next to the traditional black variant. Since the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-7a-review">Pixel 7a</a> was also seen in colors like blue and orange, we can expect something similar to its predecessor. </p><p>Earlier reports have further indicated that the Pixel 8a should feature a 6.1-inch screen on the front with a punch-hole cutout. Underneath, we could also spot a Tensor G3 that powered the Pixel 8 series. </p><p>Other rumors <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-rumored-to-have-higher-price">have indicated</a> that the device could be priced higher than before. It is not just that a Google software engineer <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-coming-with-android-battery-stats">recently confirmed</a> its existence while responding to a user bug report. All in, we could see the Pixel 8a at Google I/O 2024, which is slated for May 14.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8a-reaches-us-fcc-listing</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google I/O 2024 is set for May 14, where we will see the search giant's software and AI prowess next to some hardware announcements, and Pixel 8a might be one of them. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">5d9LhXBuVMNe4hzZdcb8uT</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4mrpgmzJRQvxGdGB9a4f9Z.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 18:04:44 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4mrpgmzJRQvxGdGB9a4f9Z.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[SmartPrix]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Leaked renders of the Pixel 8a.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Leaked renders of the Pixel 8a.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>