<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 14:11:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Don't buy the Galaxy Z Fold 6 — here's what you should get instead this Black Friday ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>I wasn&apos;t keen on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Galaxy Z Fold 6</a> when it launched; I didn&apos;t like the boxy design, and there weren&apos;t many useful upgrades. But after using the phone, I changed my initial assessment — the specs may not have changed, but the device feels better to use, and it is a decent enough choice — particularly now that it is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D18VM66K">down to $1,317</a>.</p><p>But that isn&apos;t the best foldable you can buy right now. That honor goes to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-open-apex-edition-review">OnePlus Open</a>; while the phone is over a year old, it continues to be a terrific choice. Notably, it wins out in key areas against the Galaxy Z Fold 6; the in-hand feel is much better, the crease in the middle isn&apos;t anywhere as noticeable, the cameras take better photos, the battery lasts longer, and doesn&apos;t take as long to charge.</p><p>While the Galaxy Z Fold 6 is technically the better phone if you just look at the spec sheet, it doesn&apos;t measure up in real-world use. Having used both phones next to one another, I recommend the OnePlus Open without any hesitation. The best part is that the Open is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-Dual-SIM-Unlocked-Smartphone-Hasselblad/dp/B0CHN7M531">now on sale for just $1,199</a>, $500 less than its retail price. That&apos;s for the 512GB edition — the same model of the Galaxy Z Fold 6 will set you back <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D198N6Y6">to the tune of $1,514</a>.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="d5ef2456-106a-45c2-b125-23c5c9b659b5" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,199 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$1,199 at Amazon" href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-Dual-SIM-Unlocked-Smartphone-Hasselblad/dp/B0CHN7M531" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="db8e4ZK7FdFTw2qtqKaRyW" name="oneplus-open-2024-bg.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/db8e4ZK7FdFTw2qtqKaRyW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>OnePlus Open (16GB/512GB): </strong><del><strong>$1,699</strong></del><strong> </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-Dual-SIM-Unlocked-Smartphone-Hasselblad/dp/B0CHN7M531" data-dimension112="d5ef2456-106a-45c2-b125-23c5c9b659b5" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,199 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$1,199 at Amazon"><strong>$1,199 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>The OnePlus Open trounces the Galaxy Z Fold 6 in key areas; it looks better, has a smoother hinge, better cameras at the back, and the battery lasts longer. It may be the older device, but it outshines the Z Fold 6, and the $500 discount makes it the default choice if you're ready to switch to a foldable.</p>
<p><br><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-Dual-SIM-Unlocked-Smartphone-Hasselblad/dp/B0CHN7M531" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="d5ef2456-106a-45c2-b125-23c5c9b659b5" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,199 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$1,199 at Amazon">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>You want a foldable with an elegant design, usable inner and outer panels, barely any crease, great cameras at the back, and the best battery life in this category.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if:</strong> You need long-term software updates — Google and Samsung offer twice as many Android OS updates.</p>
<p>Samsung racked up an early lead in the foldable segment, but the brand didn&apos;t deliver meaningful upgrades in recent years, and that has allowed its rivals to catch up. OnePlus didn&apos;t even bother launching a foldable this year, but it did enough with the Open to outmatch what Samsung has to offer with the Galaxy Z Fold 6, a phone that launched nine months later — that&apos;s the scale of Samsung&apos;s inaction in this segment.</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Black Friday deals</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare"> Black Friday Google Pixel deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals"> Black Friday OnePlus deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more"> Black Friday Motorola deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/samsung-black-friday-2024-deals"> Black Friday Samsung deals</a></p></div></div>
<p>The OnePlus Open has a gorgeous design with a leather back (on the black model), and it just feels better to use. The hinge has smoother articulation, and the crease isn&apos;t anywhere as noticeable as the Z Fold 6. What I also like is that the outer screen is just the right size; while Samsung made amends in this area, the outer panel on the Z Fold 6 still feels awkward to use.</p><p>While the hardware is a year old, I don&apos;t see any issues in daily use, and the Open manages to hold its own in demanding games. The cameras are terrific as well, and the phone takes outstanding photos in challenging situations. I easily get a day&apos;s worth of use out of the Open even with heavy use, something that just isn&apos;t feasible on the Z Fold 6. And when it comes to charging, the 67W charging tech takes just under 45 minutes to charge the battery.</p><p>The software is quite good too, and while there are annoyances — there&apos;s still no 5x6 grid on the home screen — it has been smooth sailing. The interface is packed with useful multitasking features, and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a> update is rolling out soon, bringing a ton of AI features to the device.</p><p>So even though the Open is a year old, it still has plenty to offer, and if you&apos;re interested in a foldable, this is the one to get during Black Friday — the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-Dual-SIM-Unlocked-Smartphone-Hasselblad/dp/B0CHN7M531">discount to $1,199</a> makes it that much more enticing.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/dont-buy-the-galaxy-z-fold-6-heres-what-you-should-get-instead-this-black-friday</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Looking to get a foldable this Black Friday? Samsung's Galaxy Z Fold 6 is heavily discounted, but you should get the OnePlus Open instead.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">VPNNX3Sbn6896fvDqmJ6Tn</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SKUr5PNUfgSteGYfKDjmX6.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 13:48:53 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SKUr5PNUfgSteGYfKDjmX6.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus Open and Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 against a colorful background]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus Open and Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 against a colorful background]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The best 4-bay Plex NAS is heavily discounted for Black Friday — but this deal won't last ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Synology had a particularly quiet 2024; we didn&apos;t get any new launches, and the brand has been content to sell its existing portfolio. By contrast, TerraMaster and ASUSTOR rolled out several new products, and UGREEN made its debut in the category with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/ugreen-dxp4800-plus-nas-review">DXP4800 Plus</a>, with the NAS touting terrific hardware.</p><p>As a result, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/synology-diskstation-ds923-plus-long-term-review">DiskStation DS923+</a> is starting to show its age. The NAS was unveiled two years ago, and while it didn&apos;t have the best hardware back then — you just get Gigabit Ethernet connectivity — where it differentiated itself was the software, and that continues to be true today as well. Most of the 4-bay servers I tested this year had much better hardware, but when it comes to ease-of-use and a strong software foundation, the DS923+ still has a definite edge.</p><p>So it&apos;s no wonder that the NAS is still the best-selling model in this category, and for Black Friday, it is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.newegg.com/synology-ds923/p/0YH-0064-00009">available for $509 at Newegg</a> — a $90 discount from its retail price. If it goes out of availability at Newegg, you can try B&H instead — the retailer is selling the NAS <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.bhphotovideo.com/c/product/1735213-REG/synology_ds923_4_bay_nas_enclosure.html">for the same price</a>. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Synology-4-Bay-DiskStation-DS923-Diskless/dp/B0BM7KDN6R">Amazon deal is sold out</a> already, so if you&apos;ve been eyeing this NAS, you should act right now.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="47f5cda6-318c-4571-9a0d-6ccf111268a2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$509 at B&amp;H Photo" data-dimension48="$509 at B&amp;H Photo" href="https://www.bhphotovideo.com/c/product/1735213-REG/synology_ds923_4_bay_nas_enclosure.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="3jAsm5k3zrDCfHGE7BUXD8" name="ds923-plus-bg.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3jAsm5k3zrDCfHGE7BUXD8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Synology DiskStation DS923+: </strong><del><strong>$599</strong></del><strong> </strong><a href="https://www.bhphotovideo.com/c/product/1735213-REG/synology_ds923_4_bay_nas_enclosure.html" data-dimension112="47f5cda6-318c-4571-9a0d-6ccf111268a2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$509 at B&amp;H Photo" data-dimension48="$509 at B&amp;H Photo"><strong>$509 at B&H Photo</strong></a></p>
<p>The DS923+ doesn't have the same caliber of hardware as its rivals. That said, the Ryzen R1600 hardware is still going strong, and the software continues to be the best in the industry. If you need a reliable 4-bay Plex server, the DS923+ is still my go-to recommendation, and while the $90 discount isn't as enticing as the deal we got last year (where it was $120 off), it's still a decent deal considering the NAS doesn't usually go on sale. It's also on Newegg <a href="https://www.newegg.com/synology-ds923/p/0YH-0064-00009">at the same price</a>. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bhphotovideo.com/c/product/1735213-REG/synology_ds923_4_bay_nas_enclosure.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="47f5cda6-318c-4571-9a0d-6ccf111268a2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$509 at B&amp;H Photo" data-dimension48="$509 at B&amp;H Photo">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>You need a 4-bay NAS server for Plex. The DS923+ has the best software in this segment, and the Ryzen R1600 is fast enough in daily use that there are no issues.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if:</strong> You want multi-Gigabit connectivity. The DS923+ lets you slot in a 10GbE card, but it&apos;s an additional $100, and all other NAS servers in this category now come with at least 2.5GbE as standard.</p>
<p>There isn&apos;t much to say about the DiskStation DS923+; the NAS has been around for two years, and is a known quantity by this point. It is powered by the Ryzen R1600, has 4GB of RAM out of the box, and you get dual Gigabit Ethernet ports at the back. There&apos;s a way to upgrade to a 10GbE port, but it costs an additional $100, so you have to consider that if you&apos;re thinking about switching to the NAS.</p><p>While the hardware isn&apos;t the best, the DiskStation Manager software is what gives the DS923+ the edge in this category. You get a clean interface with native clients for most utilities, and it does a terrific job backing up data from connected phones and other devices. A few brands still struggle with the basics, but that isn&apos;t a problem here, and that&apos;s one of the reasons why the DS923+ continues to outsell just about every other model.</p><p>It&apos;s also a great choice if you&apos;re looking to set up a Plex server. It can easily stream high-bitrate content without breaking a sweat, and while transcoding isn&apos;t available on this model, that hasn&apos;t proved to be an issue when I tested the DS923+. Ultimately, the $90 discount makes the NAS an easy recommendation, so if you&apos;re mulling an upgrade, you should get the DS923+ while it&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.bhphotovideo.com/c/product/1735213-REG/synology_ds923_4_bay_nas_enclosure.html">still available for $509</a>. The brand usually reserves select quantities during deals, so best act fast.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/the-best-4-bay-plex-nas-is-heavily-discounted-for-black-friday-but-this-deal-wont-last</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The DiskStation DS923+ is discounted for Black Friday, so if you're looking to upgrade, now is the time to do it.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">oNvrXWdvcqtAhVkKQYWDX8</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8H4XG8zH74V5MubFfC3dx5.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 12:34:06 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Smart Home]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8H4XG8zH74V5MubFfC3dx5.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Synology DiskStation DS923+ review]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Synology DiskStation DS923+ review]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ My favorite wireless earbuds of the year are on sale for Black Friday ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>EarFun is one of the most underrated audio brands of today, in my opinion. The brand has been impressing me year in, year out. In fact, my favorite wireless earbuds of the year are none other than the EarFun Air Pro 4. These comfortable Bluetooth buds sit real snug in your ears and the brand includes a wide range of ear tips in the box for the perfect fit.</p><p>The EarFun Air Pro 4 buds have it all, leaving you little to very no reason to buy anything else. The wireless earbuds usually retail at $89.99, but this <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/black-friday-2024">Black Friday deal</a> reduces that to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D5M9SH1X"><strong>$62.99 on Amazon</strong></a>.</p><p>Equipped with touch controls, wireless charging, a useful companion app, and loads of premium audio features like LDAC and hi-res audio support. I fell in love with these buds when <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/earfun-air-pro-4-review">testing them for my review</a> earlier this year.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="585e9f93-6e7e-42ab-987c-cecfa9e2c333" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="EarFun Air Pro 4: $89.99" data-dimension48="EarFun Air Pro 4: $89.99" href="https://amazon.com/dp/B0D5M9SH1X" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1484px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="rewm52LKkCXKUKd5gioayM" name="EarFun Air Pro 4 render square.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rewm52LKkCXKUKd5gioayM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1484" height="1484" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>EarFun Air Pro 4: </strong><a href="https://amazon.com/dp/B0D5M9SH1X" data-dimension112="585e9f93-6e7e-42ab-987c-cecfa9e2c333" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="EarFun Air Pro 4: $89.99" data-dimension48="EarFun Air Pro 4: $89.99" data-dimension25=""><del>$89.99</del><strong> $62.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>EarFun continued to impress me with the Air Pro 4 earbuds when they were released earlier this year. These comfortable buds come with high-end features such as LDAC support and hi-res audio, as well as future-proofing in the form of Bluetooth Auracast. Snag a sweet 30% discount on these excellent earbuds while this Black Friday deal lasts.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://amazon.com/dp/B0D5M9SH1X" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="585e9f93-6e7e-42ab-987c-cecfa9e2c333" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="EarFun Air Pro 4: $89.99" data-dimension48="EarFun Air Pro 4: $89.99" data-dimension25="">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>you&apos;re an audiophile who wants LDAC support, hi-res audio, wireless charging, a long battery life, and an ergonomic design.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>you want a robust IP rating for rough use.</p><p>I test dozens of earbuds every year and let me tell you, EarFun never disappoints. Black Friday sale aside, the Air Pro 4 buds are already super affordable to begin with. The set up process is quick and easy thanks to Google Fast Pair. Once Bluetooth Auracast is everywhere, you won&apos;t have to worry because these earbuds are Auracast-ready.</p><p>These IPX5 splash-proof buds support codes like Qualcomm aptX Adaptive, LDAC, and hi-res audio. This translates to lovely, crispy, and very high-quality sound production.</p><p>To go with sound quality that good, EarFun extended the fun with an enormous battery life. You can generously squeeze two days&apos; worth of playtime from a single charge with medium to heavy use. Light users could stretch that to three days. There&apos;s not much else you could want from a pair of wireless earbuds.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/earbuds/my-favorite-wireless-earbuds-of-the-year-are-on-sale-for-black-friday</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ I adore the EarFun Air Pro 4 earbuds, which is why I'm ecstatic that they're 40% off with this Black Friday deal. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">jxPGH3eHNQf7B4JNpHjseD</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7GqwEQfp6GVzU8eVBXaHq6.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 11:43:19 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Earbuds]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7GqwEQfp6GVzU8eVBXaHq6.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[EarFun Air Pro 4 wireless earbuds in black]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[EarFun Air Pro 4 wireless earbuds in black]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The best ANC earbuds I used in 2024 are down to just $63 for Black Friday ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>I get to use dozens of earbuds over the course of a given year, and the state of the audio industry is such that you can get a great-sounding set of earbuds without shelling out too much cash. Tagry&apos;s X08 do a great job in this regard, and they <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/TAGRY-Bluetooth-Headphones-Earphones-Waterproof/dp/B09DT48V16">cost just $25</a>. So what do you get with earbuds that are priced thrice as much? Most of the time, it&apos;s noise isolation, high-res audio codecs, and the ability to customize the sound to a greater extent.</p><p>All of that is true of the SoundPEATS Capsule3 Pro+, but they also have a unique addition: xMEMS drivers. As I talked about in the past, xMEMS is a brand that&apos;s positioning <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/earbuds-with-solid-state-audio-drivers-are-about-to-go-mainstream">solid-state audio drivers</a>, and having used buds like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/creative-aurvana-ace-2-review">Creative Aurvana Ace 2</a> last year, I can attest to the driver&apos;s effectiveness. The silicon driver manages better detail retrieval and clarity, and the difference is immediately evident.</p><p>The Capsule3 Pro+ use a combination of a 12mm dynamic driver along with the xMEMS driver to produce outstanding sound, and these may just be the best earbuds I used in 2024. The earbuds debuted for $99, and they&apos;re now <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0D62Q8NYY/">available for $63</a> during Black Friday, making them a terrific value.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="dfd15915-b03d-44d6-bf3d-e17aed634531" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$63 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$63 at Amazon" href="https://www.amazon.com/SoundPEATS-Capsule3-Pro-Earbuds-Cancelling/dp/B0D62Q8NYY" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:840px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:152.02%;"><img id="2EB4bDVu4AmBtyYo4BctbK" name="sound.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2EB4bDVu4AmBtyYo4BctbK.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="840" height="1277" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>SoundPEATS Capsule3 Pro+: </strong><del><strong>$99</strong></del><strong> </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/SoundPEATS-Capsule3-Pro-Earbuds-Cancelling/dp/B0D62Q8NYY" data-dimension112="dfd15915-b03d-44d6-bf3d-e17aed634531" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$63 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$63 at Amazon"><strong>$63 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>The Capsule3 Pro+ feature a custom xMEMS driver that allows much better clarity in the higher frequencies, and they pair it with a dynamic driver that gives you an energetic bass and vibrancy. You get excellent ANC, the design is lightweight, and they have a low-latency mode. There isn't much missing with these buds, and at $63, they're a steal.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/SoundPEATS-Capsule3-Pro-Earbuds-Cancelling/dp/B0D62Q8NYY" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="dfd15915-b03d-44d6-bf3d-e17aed634531" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$63 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$63 at Amazon">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>You want the best audio quality in this category. The Capsule3 Pro+ also have terrific ANC, and they have a lightweight design that doesn&apos;t cause any fatigue even with extended use.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>You need AptX codecs. While these earbuds get a lot right, you don&apos;t get high-res codecs other than LDAC. If AptX codec integration is a must-have, you should consider getting the Air4 Pro instead — they&apos;re <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/SoundPEATS-Air4-Pro-Cancelling-Multipoint/dp/B0CHS56Z85">down to $62 right now</a>.</p>
<p>The sound quality is where the Capsule3 Pro+ have a distinct edge over most other earbuds in this category. You get a clean and energetic bass that lends itself well to various genres, and that&apos;s backed by clear mids, and a soaring treble. Most earbuds have a muddled treble extension, but by using the xMEMS driver, that isn&apos;t an issue here — you can easily make out the difference once you start using the earbuds.</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Black Friday deals</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">- <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Black Friday Google Pixel deals</a><br>
- <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Black Friday OnePlus deals</a><br>
- <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Black Friday Motorola deals</a><br>
- <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024">Black Friday Samsung deals</a></p></div></div>
<p>Everything is just that little bit clearer, and you get a level of immediacy that&apos;s missing on other earbuds. In short, the sound quality is addictive, and I&apos;d suggest getting these earbuds on the basis of that alone. Thankfully, there are other niceties; it has ANC, and it does a great job tuning sound by up to 45dB — that&apos;s more than what other earbuds achieve. I tested the earbuds for nearly a month, and it did a stellar job tuning out the ambient noise in my vicinity.</p><p>Coming in at just 5g, each earbud is light enough that you don&apos;t notice you&apos;re wearing anything at all, and the stalk-like design is similar to what you get with most other products. What I like in this area is that you get a matte texture over the stalk and case, and that means there aren&apos;t anywhere as many smudges as other earbuds.</p><p>The earbuds last over five and a half hours between charges, and while that isn&apos;t the best in this category, it is in line with most products I tested recently. You get the usual Bluetooth 5.3 connectivity along with SBC and AAC codecs and LDAC, but there&apos;s no AptX. That&apos;s about the only omission, and if you have a recent device, you should be able to use LDAC — it was baked into Android five years ago.</p><p>Ultimately, the Capsule3 Pro+ nail the basics, and the sound quality is a big differentiator. With the earbuds <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0D62Q8NYY/">now on sale for just $63</a>, you&apos;re getting a fabulous value as well.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/capsule3-pro-standout-audio</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ SoundPEATS's Capsule3 Pro+ are innovative earbuds that use solid-state audio tech. They sound great, have a lightweight design, and come with all the additional features you need. The best part? They're just $63 right now.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Gnx7iUaXyd35BXR7KybwBn</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DvqAn8FDWTTvQcr346g5DN.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 10:28:32 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DvqAn8FDWTTvQcr346g5DN.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[SoundPEATS Capsule3 Pro+ earbuds in-hand]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[SoundPEATS Capsule3 Pro+ earbuds in-hand]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ I tested over 70 phones in 2024 — these are my Black Friday picks ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>It&apos;s been a great year for phones in general, and I was able to use an overwhelming majority of the devices launched over the last 12 months. I tested 73 phones in 2024, ranging from localized entry-level choices to the latest foldables and everything in between.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/pixel-9-pro-xl-two-months-later">Pixel 9 Pro XL</a> is one of my favorite phones of the year, and while I usually recommend Pixels, Google ticked all the right boxes this year — the phone is much better in key areas, and it has better fluidity with the Android 15 update. Google does a good job discounting its phones, and for Black Friday, the Pixel 9 Pro XL is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-Pro-XL-Smartphone/dp/B0D7HSJ7ZP">down to $849</a>, a $250 discount from its launch price.</p><p>Then there&apos;s the Pixel 9 Pro, which I actually ended up liking more than the XL variant purely because of the manageable size, and it is now <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-Pro-Unlocked-Smartphone/dp/B0D7HVCD91">available for $799</a> as part of Black Friday, which is $200 less than what it goes for usually. If you don&apos;t want to spend that much and still get a great phone, last year&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/i-switched-back-to-the-pixel-8-pro-and-i-couldnt-be-happier">Pixel 8 Pro</a> is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-Pro-Smartphone-Telephoto/dp/B0CGTJ12Z9">going for just $592</a>, and that&apos;s an unbeatable value when you consider the phone will get seven years of software updates.</p><p>Although not as feature-rich, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12-review">OnePlus 12</a> is still one of the best phones of the year. It has a gorgeous design — better even than the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-13">OnePlus 13</a> — and a vibrant AMOLED with useful eye protection tech, top-notch hardware, and much better cameras. But what&apos;s particularly interesting is that the OnePlus 12 <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-Dual-SIM-Smartphone-Processor-Hasselblad/dp/B0CQ5MYYZL">down to just $549</a>, an all-time low.</p><p>If you need a mid-ranger, the Pixel 8a continues to be my go-to choice, and that phone is now <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-8a-Unlocked-Advanced/dp/B0CYQ916ZY">available for just $399</a>, making it an even better value. At the other end of the scale is the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-open-apex-edition-review">OnePlus Open</a>; it is over a year old, but it continues to be the best foldable you can get in the U.S. — it easily outshines the Galaxy Z Fold 6. With the Open <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-Dual-SIM-Unlocked-Smartphone-Hasselblad/dp/B0CHN8FNW3">now available for $1,199</a>, you are getting a good bargain.</p><p>I&apos;m highlighting six deals in this post, and incidentally, all six phones are down to their lowest price. So if you need a new device, this is the absolute best time to upgrade.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="8f4b89f5-d06c-4a60-9079-be6c438c0bd8" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$799 at Amazon" href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-Pro-Unlocked-Smartphone/dp/B0D7HVCD91" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="R6LSZJjgkpJt5yhjZxf4P9" name="google-pixel-9-pro-render-space.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/R6LSZJjgkpJt5yhjZxf4P9.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Google Pixel 9 Pro (128GB): </strong><del><strong>$999</strong></del><strong> </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-Pro-Unlocked-Smartphone/dp/B0D7HVCD91" data-dimension112="8f4b89f5-d06c-4a60-9079-be6c438c0bd8" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$799 at Amazon"><strong>$799 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>I really liked using the Pixel 9 Pro XL, but it is a massive phone. Thankfully, the Pixel 9 Pro remedies this problem, and it is the device I now recommend if you're looking to switch to the latest Pixels — it has all the best features of the 9 Pro XL, and is much better to hold and use. And at $799, you're getting a great bargain.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-Pro-Unlocked-Smartphone/dp/B0D7HVCD91" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="8f4b89f5-d06c-4a60-9079-be6c438c0bd8" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$799 at Amazon">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="fb4ce097-ef02-470a-8683-391bfb84fcaa" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$549 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$549 at Amazon" href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-Dual-SIM-Smartphone-Processor-Hasselblad/dp/B0CQ5MYYZL" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="avx5Y8NfgjdVQ6zueytxV3" name="oneplus-12-render-4x5.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/avx5Y8NfgjdVQ6zueytxV3.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>OnePlus 12 (12GB/256GB): </strong><del><strong>$799</strong></del><strong> </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-Dual-SIM-Smartphone-Processor-Hasselblad/dp/B0CQ5MYYZL" data-dimension112="fb4ce097-ef02-470a-8683-391bfb84fcaa" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$549 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$549 at Amazon"><strong>$549 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>The OnePlus 12 is still one of the most powerful phones available, and it has versatile cameras alongside a long-lasting battery and ultra-fast charging tech. It also has the distinction of being the only device outside of Pixels to get the stable Android 15 build, and you get a host of useful AI additions. I recommended it when it went down to $599 earlier in the year, and at $549, it's an easier choice — you won't get the same caliber of hardware on any other sub-$600 phone today.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-Dual-SIM-Smartphone-Processor-Hasselblad/dp/B0CQ5MYYZL" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="fb4ce097-ef02-470a-8683-391bfb84fcaa" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$549 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$549 at Amazon">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="2f01ad37-621c-42e2-b726-2481b42c383e" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$592 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$592 at Amazon" href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-Pro-Smartphone-Telephoto/dp/B0CGTJ12Z9" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="uNFYVqag7jTBJv8hQKjkd4" name="google pixel 8 pro render 400x500.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uNFYVqag7jTBJv8hQKjkd4.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Google Pixel 8 Pro (128GB): </strong><del><strong>$999</strong></del><strong> </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-Pro-Smartphone-Telephoto/dp/B0CGTJ12Z9" data-dimension112="2f01ad37-621c-42e2-b726-2481b42c383e" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$592 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$592 at Amazon"><strong>$592 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>While it isn't the latest, the Pixel 8 Pro still has a lot to offer in 2024 (and beyond). You're still getting a vibrant OLED, decent hardware, terrific cameras, and the best software along with seven years of updates. At $592, the phone is an unbeatable value.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-Pro-Smartphone-Telephoto/dp/B0CGTJ12Z9" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="2f01ad37-621c-42e2-b726-2481b42c383e" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$592 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$592 at Amazon">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="5cdd4a6a-c6ac-4549-9fab-2ea3e7bc57f5" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$399 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$399 at Amazon" href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-8a-Unlocked-Advanced/dp/B0CYQ916ZY" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="b8vNGDnGts2FBbfmSAoSR4" name="google-pixel-8a-render-green.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/b8vNGDnGts2FBbfmSAoSR4.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Google Pixel 8a (128GB): </strong><del><strong>$499</strong></del><strong> </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-8a-Unlocked-Advanced/dp/B0CYQ916ZY" data-dimension112="5cdd4a6a-c6ac-4549-9fab-2ea3e7bc57f5" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$399 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$399 at Amazon"><strong>$399 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>The Pixel 8a has a great camera at the back, handles day-to-day tasks effortlessly, and has a good 120Hz OLED panel. You get the same great software as other Pixels, and what makes it stand out is that it will also get seven years of software updates.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-8a-Unlocked-Advanced/dp/B0CYQ916ZY" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="5cdd4a6a-c6ac-4549-9fab-2ea3e7bc57f5" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$399 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$399 at Amazon">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="fd7503d1-3264-470a-81d2-83d94c59fe92" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$399 at Best Buy" data-dimension48="$399 at Best Buy" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oneplus-12r-128gb-unlocked-iron-gray/6571130.p?skuId=6571130" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="2sPhPxJXeggHuy5Q4cqz9L" name="oneplus-12r-render-4x5.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2sPhPxJXeggHuy5Q4cqz9L.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>OnePlus 12R (8GB/128GB): </strong><del><strong>$499</strong></del><strong> </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oneplus-12r-128gb-unlocked-iron-gray/6571130.p?skuId=6571130" data-dimension112="fd7503d1-3264-470a-81d2-83d94c59fe92" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$399 at Best Buy" data-dimension48="$399 at Best Buy"><strong>$399 at Best Buy</strong></a></p>
<p>The OnePlus 12R is a solid alternative to the Pixel 8a if you need a mid-range phone designed for gaming. While the auxiliary cameras aren't as good as the OnePlus 12, the main 50MP lens is fantastic in its own right, and you get an even bigger battery.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oneplus-12r-128gb-unlocked-iron-gray/6571130.p?skuId=6571130" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="fd7503d1-3264-470a-81d2-83d94c59fe92" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$399 at Best Buy" data-dimension48="$399 at Best Buy">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="33c131bd-0ef5-4bf4-bcbe-a402955251d3" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,199 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$1,199 at Amazon" href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-Dual-SIM-Unlocked-Smartphone-Hasselblad/dp/B0CHN8FNW3" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="db8e4ZK7FdFTw2qtqKaRyW" name="oneplus-open-2024-bg.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/db8e4ZK7FdFTw2qtqKaRyW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>OnePlus Open (16GB/512GB): </strong><del><strong>$1,699</strong></del><strong> </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-Dual-SIM-Unlocked-Smartphone-Hasselblad/dp/B0CHN8FNW3" data-dimension112="33c131bd-0ef5-4bf4-bcbe-a402955251d3" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,199 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$1,199 at Amazon"><strong>$1,199 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>The OnePlus Open is over a year old, and that makes it ancient by modern phone standards. Thankfully, the foldable is just as good today as it was when it launched, and if anything, Samsung's lack of innovation did OnePlus a huge favor. I still like the Open quite a bit, and think it is the foldable you should get; the design is better than the Z Fold 6, the crease isn't as visible, the AMOLED panels are among the best, and the cameras continue to shine. And with the discount to $1,199, it is much more accessible. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-Dual-SIM-Unlocked-Smartphone-Hasselblad/dp/B0CHN8FNW3" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="33c131bd-0ef5-4bf4-bcbe-a402955251d3" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,199 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$1,199 at Amazon">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>Obviously, there are devices I liked didn&apos;t end up on this list, and it has to do with global availability. Vivo&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/vivo-x100-ultra-long-term-review">X100 Ultra</a> continues to be the best overall camera package I used this year, but the phone is limited to China, and I wouldn&apos;t recommend going through the hassle of getting one. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oppo-find-x8-pro-review">Find X8 Pro</a> does a great job in its own right, and the phone is now on sale in several global markets. I thoroughly enjoyed using the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-v3-long-term-review">Magic V3</a> foldable as well; the ultra-thin design makes it feel like a regular phone, and it has excellent cameras at the back.</p><p>But it&apos;s the Pixel 9 Pro XL that was particularly noteworthy. The phone has much better build quality than previous years, the brightest OLED panel of any device I used this year, great cameras, and the best software with class-leading AI features. While I grumbled about the state of the hardware on previous Pixels, that hasn&apos;t been a problem on the 9 Pro XL, and that alone is a refreshing change of pace.</p><p>Although it doesn&apos;t have the best cameras — the Chinese trio of Vivo, OPPO, and Xiaomi have Google beat in this area — it still delivers consistently-great photos and videos, and the software is unmatched. And while I didn&apos;t like the premium Google introduced this year, Black Friday addresses that to a great extent, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-Pro-XL-Smartphone/dp/B0D7HSJ7ZP">$849 is a good deal</a> considering what you&apos;re getting.</p><p>Having said that, I think you should get the Pixel 9 Pro instead; I used it after the 9 Pro XL, and ended up liking the device a lot more. It doesn&apos;t miss out in any area; you get the same set of cameras at the back, same OLED (albeit smaller), and the same software with all the AI extras. While it has a smaller battery, I got a day&apos;s worth of use out of it, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-Pro-Unlocked-Smartphone/dp/B0D7HVCD91">coming in at $799</a>, it is a better overall choice.</p><p>Then there&apos;s the OnePlus 12. I keep coming back to this device because of the design and battery life, and with OxygenOS 15, you get a lot of useful additions, including AI-backed features you&apos;ll actually end up using. This is the best OnePlus phone by a sizeable margin (I should know), and although the OnePlus 13 is set to launch soon, I don&apos;t think you should wait for it — not with the OnePlus 12 <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-Dual-SIM-Smartphone-Processor-Hasselblad/dp/B0CQ5MYYZL">down to just $549</a>.</p><p>If you need a mid-range phone, the Pixel 8a and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-12r-review">OnePlus 12R</a> are both good choices; I recommend the Pixel 8a because I like Google&apos;s software better, but if you need a powerful phone, the 12R is a better pick. Rounding out this list is the OnePlus Open; I was going to recommend the Galaxy Z Fold 6, but using it alongside the Open made me realize the latter is still the better all-round device.</p><p>The Open has a better design by far, and the crease in the middle isn&apos;t anywhere as visible. I also like its cameras better, and the battery lasts noticeably longer than the Galaxy Z Fold 6. It&apos;s still on Android 14, but should get the Android 15 update shortly, and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/OnePlus-Dual-SIM-Unlocked-Smartphone-Hasselblad/dp/B0CHN8FNW3">discount to $1,199</a> makes it a straightforward recommendation.</p><p>Ultimately, there&apos;s no shortage of great phone deals this Black Friday, and regardless of what device you go with out of the options outlined above, you&apos;re getting a fabulous device. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/i-tested-over-70-phones-in-2024-these-are-my-black-friday-picks</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ I've been testing phones for over a decade now, and I used 73 phones over the course of 2024. I'm here to assist you in picking up the best phone for your needs during Black Friday.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">iirQPb5QJpLHfLzBjEUxwV</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/83ZTZzSSRj6YZ3BhRpTPYX.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 08:43:46 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/83ZTZzSSRj6YZ3BhRpTPYX.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Pixel 9 Pro XL next to Pixel 9 Pro, Pixel 8 Pro, Pixel 8a, OnePlus Open, OnePlus 12, and OnePlus 12R]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Pixel 9 Pro XL next to Pixel 9 Pro, Pixel 8 Pro, Pixel 8a, OnePlus Open, OnePlus 12, and OnePlus 12R]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ I'm hyped over Dbrand's Black Friday sales, especially the leather skins ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Are you rocking a Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra? Or Perhaps you just snagged a sweet <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Black Friday deal on the Google Pixel 9 Pro</a>. Regardless, Dbrand&apos;s cowhide products are available for plenty of Samsung Galaxy and Google Pixel models. These genuine <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://dbrand.com/shop/limited-edition/leather"><strong>leather skins and cases are on sale for a whopping 40%</strong></a> off as long as you get two or more items.</p><p>Dbrand&apos;s sale is only live until the end of Cyber Monday. Before stock runs out on your favorite leather color, you want to treat yourself with these elegant phone covers. We have <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/dbrand-leather-skin-review">reviewed the Dbrand leather skin</a> and it feels and looks phenomenal.</p><p>Since leather ages over time, it only looks better with age. Dbrand&apos;s Grip Case has scored sides, impact absorption, and MagSafe support. So if you want more protection as opposed to the slim leather skin, you can always get the leather case instead.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="4933f12f-347b-4ad0-847b-0ecd34d24a50" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Buy any two Dbrand leather cases or skins to get 40% off" data-dimension48="Buy any two Dbrand leather cases or skins to get 40% off" href="https://dbrand.com/shop/limited-edition/leather" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1893px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="bfFv9rm9sFSZDkUoUVVGGT" name="dbrand leather case and skin render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bfFv9rm9sFSZDkUoUVVGGT.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1893" height="1893" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><a href="https://dbrand.com/shop/limited-edition/leather" data-dimension112="4933f12f-347b-4ad0-847b-0ecd34d24a50" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Buy any two Dbrand leather cases or skins to get 40% off" data-dimension48="Buy any two Dbrand leather cases or skins to get 40% off" data-dimension25=""><strong>Buy any two Dbrand leather cases or skins to get 40% off</strong></a></p>
<p>Dbrand's top grain leather covers and skins are available for plenty of Android and iOS phones, including brands like Samsung, Google, and Apple. The skin adds an unbelievably thin protective layer while the grip case comes with more protection and MagSafe optionality.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://dbrand.com/shop/limited-edition/leather" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="4933f12f-347b-4ad0-847b-0ecd34d24a50" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Buy any two Dbrand leather cases or skins to get 40% off" data-dimension48="Buy any two Dbrand leather cases or skins to get 40% off" data-dimension25="">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>you want highest-grade leather in various color options, MagSafe support, and both skin and case alternatives.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>you want a kickstand built-in or something below $25.</p><p>Dbrand&apos;s 40% off Black Friday sale applies to all of its leather goods, so you could get something for your PlayStation 5 or your Nintendo Switch as well. There are plenty of unique skins and cases from the brand, so be sure to check their catalogue thoroughly before going through with your purchase.</p><p>Other sales from the brand include <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://dbrand.com/shop/cases">40% off Grip Cases</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://dbrand.com/shop/prism/">Prism Screen Protectors</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://dbrand.com/shop/catalog/killswitch">40% off Killswitch kits</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://dbrand.com/shop/limited-edition/ps5">35% off PlayStation 5 Darkplates</a>, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://dbrand.com/shop/limited-edition/keycaps">50% off Keycaps</a>.</p><p>Apart from this, everything else on the Dbrand website is a flat 15% off. While this isn&apos;t as steep of a discount, it can save you a few dollars here and there which is always nice.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/im-hyped-over-dbrands-black-friday-sales-especially-the-leather-skins</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ All of Dbrand's leather goodies are 40% off for Black Friday, provided you buy at least two. Get your hands on these timeless real leather skins and cases for your phone. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">smeqtxopgbrvjf3ZxDAiQN</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Xp43ZSaQNQN46rEBcG25NK.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 08:02:38 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ namerah.saud-fatmi@futurenet.com (Namerah Saud Fatmi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Xp43ZSaQNQN46rEBcG25NK.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nick Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Dbrand leather skin for smartphones]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Dbrand leather skin for smartphones]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The iPad Pro M4 FINALLY goes on sale for Black Friday, but you'll need to act now ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>While I prefer using Android phones, I turn to the iPad whenever I need a bigger screen. I used most models released in the last ten years, and while my go-to has been the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/ipad-pro-2022-productivity">iPad Pro 12.9</a> over the last 12 months, I switched to the 13-inch iPad Pro M4 two months ago, and it is nothing short of incredible.</p><p>I&apos;ve always wanted an iPad with an OLED panel, and the iPad Pro M4 delivers on that front. Thanks to a tandem OLED — where two OLED panels are sandwiched together — you get the best of both worlds: outstanding color fidelity, and increased brightness levels. If you&apos;re using an iPad and are mulling an upgrade, the iPad Pro M4 is the ideal choice, and thanks to Black Friday, it&apos;s finally on sale — the 11-inch model is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-Pro-11-Inch-Intelligence/dp/B0D3J6L2ZC">down to $849 on Amazon</a> (by using a $50 coupon), and the 13-inch variant is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D3J98W75">available for $1,099</a>, a $200 discount.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="2fe86bc3-feeb-4f5d-815d-043cc5ca78a1" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$849 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$849 at Amazon" href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-Pro-11-Inch-Intelligence/dp/B0D3J6L2ZC" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="8x6oWanY7Dn7CcoPRohR5b" name="apple ipad pro m4.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8x6oWanY7Dn7CcoPRohR5b.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Apple iPad Pro M4 11-inch: </strong><del><strong>$999</strong></del><strong> </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-Pro-11-Inch-Intelligence/dp/B0D3J6L2ZC" data-dimension112="2fe86bc3-feeb-4f5d-815d-043cc5ca78a1" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$849 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$849 at Amazon"><strong>$849 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>The iPad Pro M4 isn't just the best iPad ever made — it's also one of the best Apple products I've used. You'll need to hold the tablet to understand just how sleek the design is, and the M4 hardware runs rings around any other tablet available today. Obviously, the OLED panel is the biggest reason to get the iPad Pro M4, and even from the 12.9-inch iPad Pro, the difference is startling. And with a $150 discount, now is the best time to make the switch.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-Pro-11-Inch-Intelligence/dp/B0D3J6L2ZC" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="2fe86bc3-feeb-4f5d-815d-043cc5ca78a1" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$849 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$849 at Amazon">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="25faf878-a378-4545-8e01-104111d0f422" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,099 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$1,099 at Amazon" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D3J98W75" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="8x6oWanY7Dn7CcoPRohR5b" name="apple ipad pro m4.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8x6oWanY7Dn7CcoPRohR5b.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Apple iPad Pro M4 13-inch: </strong><del><strong>$1,299</strong></del><strong> </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D3J98W75" data-dimension112="25faf878-a378-4545-8e01-104111d0f422" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,099 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$1,099 at Amazon"><strong>$1,099 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>The 11-inch model is great by itself, but I got used to a bigger screen, so I went with the 13-inch iPad Pro M4. It has the distinction of being even thinner than the 11-inch model, and it is a joy to hold and use. Honestly, this is the best iPad you can get right now, and while it still costs a sizeable amount of cash, a $200 discount makes it a smidgen more accessible.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D3J98W75" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="25faf878-a378-4545-8e01-104111d0f422" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,099 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$1,099 at Amazon">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>You&apos;ve been waiting to switch to an OLED iPad. The iPad Pro M4 has a lot of other upgrades, but the OLED screen is the headlining addition this year, and it makes using the tablet that much more enjoyable.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>You don&apos;t need an OLED panel. If you&apos;re just looking for a reliable iPad, I&apos;d suggest going with the iPad Air — that model is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D3J617D7">down to $499</a> now for the 11-inch version and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D3J6RTCT">$699 for the 13-inch option</a>.</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Black Friday deals</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare"> Black Friday Google Pixel deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals"> Black Friday OnePlus deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more"> Black Friday Motorola deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024"> Black Friday Samsung deals</a></p></div></div>
<p>The OLED panel makes the iPad Pro M4 that much more enticing; it&apos;s a definite visual upgrade, and I found my usage increasing after switching to this model. The M2 is plenty fast, but the latest M4 silicon is in a league of its own, and it does a fantastic job with gaming in general. You get other niceties; the front camera&apos;s positioning is much better, you get 256GB of storage as standard on the base model, and it has great battery life.</p><p>I like the 13-inch model as it has greater screen real estate and doesn&apos;t take up too much room, and it is even thinner. The sleek design is a big differentiator this year, and the new Pencil Pro (now <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D3J71RM7">down to $94</a>) makes sketching on the device an absolute joy. You can also get the tablet with an anti-glare coating, and as always, there&apos;s cellular connectivity that costs an additional $200. Oh, and Apple Intelligence is going live shortly, so you&apos;ll get a whole suite of exciting AI-backed features on the tablet.</p><p>Switching to the 13-inch iPad Pro M4 from the 12.9-inch iPad Pro with the M2, the three biggest differences are the OLED panel, location of the front camera, and thinner design. If you&apos;re using an older iPad and considering an upgrade, the iPad Pro M4 is an instant recommendation — particularly <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-Pro-11-Inch-Intelligence/dp/B0D3J6L2ZC">now that it is down to $849</a>.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/the-ipad-pro-m4-finally-goes-on-sale-for-black-friday-but-youll-need-to-act-now</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The iPad Pro M4 is fantastic, and a lot of that is down to the new OLED panel. There are other upgrades, but the OLED panel by itself is notable enough that you should consider making the switch not that it's on sale for just $849.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">c5UK4yTZG4JnneTxpDbGzA</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GjEHzU4LBegZdvvxNHrWHm.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 03:02:36 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GjEHzU4LBegZdvvxNHrWHm.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[13-inch iPad Pro M4 with Magic Keyboard on a table]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[13-inch iPad Pro M4 with Magic Keyboard on a table]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ This Black Friday deal just gave the Pixel 9 a free Pro upgrade! ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The Pixel 9 series has only been available for three months, but Google's latest and best phones are already on sale for Black Friday. No, you didn't read that wrong; the Pixel 9 Pro just had its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D7HVCD91/">price slashed by 20%</a>, thanks to this Black Friday sale.</p><p>The phone launched in August, priced at $999. For Black Friday, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-review">Pixel 9 Pro</a> gets a $200 discount, bringing the price down to $799. That's the same price as the regular <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-review">Pixel 9</a>, meaning you can get a Pro upgrade at no extra cost!</p>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare"><em><strong>Check out the best Google Pixel Black Friday deals</strong></em></a></li></ul>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="4d632ff2-ad58-4234-80c5-9acac0370de1" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="The Pixel 9 Pro is a small and powerful flagship with the best that Google has to offer in a phone. At $999, the phone isn't particularly cheap, but this 20% off Black Friday deal gives you a sweet $200 discount." data-dimension48="The Pixel 9 Pro is a small and powerful flagship with the best that Google has to offer in a phone. At $999, the phone isn't particularly cheap, but this 20% off Black Friday deal gives you a sweet $200 discount." data-dimension25="$799" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D7HVCD91/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="UD8dzz6ZtqsbyAGYpz4DtN" name="google-pixel-9-pro-official-render-obsidian-front-back.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/UD8dzz6ZtqsbyAGYpz4DtN.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="500" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>The Pixel 9 Pro is a small and powerful flagship with the best that Google has to offer in a phone. At $999, the phone isn't particularly cheap, but this 20% off Black Friday deal gives you a sweet $200 discount.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D7HVCD91/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="4d632ff2-ad58-4234-80c5-9acac0370de1" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="The Pixel 9 Pro is a small and powerful flagship with the best that Google has to offer in a phone. At $999, the phone isn't particularly cheap, but this 20% off Black Friday deal gives you a sweet $200 discount." data-dimension48="The Pixel 9 Pro is a small and powerful flagship with the best that Google has to offer in a phone. At $999, the phone isn't particularly cheap, but this 20% off Black Friday deal gives you a sweet $200 discount." data-dimension25="$799">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Black Friday</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Black Friday Google Pixel deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Black Friday Motorola deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024-early-deals-and-how-to-prepare-for-the-big-sales">Black Friday Samsung deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Black Friday OnePlus deals</a></p></div></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if:</strong> You want a powerful phone that gets all the latest Android features, AI capabilities, and gets updated before anyone else.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>You want a phone that excels in gaming performance and has fast charging speeds.</p>
<p>The Google Pixel 9 Pro is one of the best phones we've reviewed this year. While we're normally impressed with Pixel phones, the Pixel 9 Pro stands out as a petite flagship, giving us Pro features at the same size as the standard Pixel 9. You get a triple camera system with some of the best imaging we've seen on a smartphone, plus tons of impressive <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/why-on-device-ai-processing-is-important">on-device AI</a> features thanks to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-tensor-g4">Tensor G4</a> chipset.</p><p>And if you want something larger, Google is offering the Pixel 9 Pro XL with a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D7HSJ7ZP/">sweet Black Friday discount</a>, which gives you all the best of the Pixel 9 series, but with a larger battery and even faster charging. The 6.8-inch display is also perfect for watching media, and all of this can be had for less than $900, which is a discount of $250!</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="50c3fec5-396b-4db3-a12d-96793ac3f103" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="The larger Pixel 9 Pro XL just grabbed a massive discount for Black Friday, slashing the price from $1099 to less than $850. This is an incredible deal for a fantastic phone that you don't wanna miss out on." data-dimension48="The larger Pixel 9 Pro XL just grabbed a massive discount for Black Friday, slashing the price from $1099 to less than $850. This is an incredible deal for a fantastic phone that you don't wanna miss out on." data-dimension25="$849" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D7HSJ7ZP/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="bES27Em9ivhDZB88WYAtKk" name="google-pixel-9-pro-xl-official-render-hazel-front-back.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bES27Em9ivhDZB88WYAtKk.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="500" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>The larger Pixel 9 Pro XL just grabbed a massive discount for Black Friday, slashing the price from $1099 to less than $850. This is an incredible deal for a fantastic phone that you don't wanna miss out on.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D7HSJ7ZP/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="50c3fec5-396b-4db3-a12d-96793ac3f103" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="The larger Pixel 9 Pro XL just grabbed a massive discount for Black Friday, slashing the price from $1099 to less than $850. This is an incredible deal for a fantastic phone that you don't wanna miss out on." data-dimension48="The larger Pixel 9 Pro XL just grabbed a massive discount for Black Friday, slashing the price from $1099 to less than $850. This is an incredible deal for a fantastic phone that you don't wanna miss out on." data-dimension25="$849">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>These aren't the only Pixel devices on sale for Black Friday. Check out this <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-amazon-black-friday-sale-has-finally-fixed-the-google-pixel-9s-price-problem">deal on the standard Pixel 9</a> or this <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/i-use-a-foldable-phone-every-day-and-black-friday-is-the-perfect-time-for-you-to-get-one">$300 discount on the Pixel 9 Pro Fold</a>, one of our favorite foldable phones of the year. No matter where you look, there's a Pixel on sale somewhere, so you're bound to find what you're looking for this Black Friday!</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/this-black-friday-deal-just-gave-the-pixel-9-a-free-pro-upgrade</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Pixel 9 Pro and 9 Pro XL are on sale for Black Friday, giving you Google's best for hundreds less. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">AJdaqifyVs4SPzv2G5WZiN</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dNKHwufvhCnpyQRwHdtFKC.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 01:27:15 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ derrek.lee@futurenet.com (Derrek Lee) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dNKHwufvhCnpyQRwHdtFKC.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9 Pro and Pixel 9 Pro XL angled view]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9 Pro and Pixel 9 Pro XL angled view]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ I'm surprised to see my favorite gaming Chromebook on sale for Black Friday ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>When it was announced, the Acer Chromebook 516 GE was one of the first gaming-centric Chromebooks to hit the market. Despite it being more than a year old, this is still one of my favorite Chromebooks, and for Black Friday, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Chromebook-2560x1600-i5-1240P-LPDDR4X-CBG516-1H-53TD/dp/B0CV61RWHF"><strong>it's on sale for $100 off</strong></a>.</p><p>That might not seem like much of a discount, but when you look at the whole package, your opinion might be changed. For one, it features a huge 15.6-inch QHD display and is one of the few <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/black-friday-chromebook-deals-2024-score-major-savings-on-acer-lenovo-samsung-and-more">Chromebooks</a> to sport a 120Hz refresh rate.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="e19253d3-501a-4b1f-9d2c-6f51fc502025" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="The Acer Chromebook 516 GE might not the be most recent version of this laptop, but it's still incredibly performant. Plus, you can save $100 for Black Friday, and get a powerful Chromebook with all of the RGB you could want." data-dimension48="The Acer Chromebook 516 GE might not the be most recent version of this laptop, but it's still incredibly performant. Plus, you can save $100 for Black Friday, and get a powerful Chromebook with all of the RGB you could want." data-dimension25="$499.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/Chromebook-2560x1600-i5-1240P-LPDDR4X-CBG516-1H-53TD/dp/B0CV61RWHF" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2200px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="WbXFjwteraZMd9eJKKogZH" name="acer-chromebook-516-ge-square-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WbXFjwteraZMd9eJKKogZH.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2200" height="2200" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>The Acer Chromebook 516 GE might not the be most recent version of this laptop, but it's still incredibly performant. Plus, you can save $100 for Black Friday, and get a powerful Chromebook with all of the RGB you could want.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/Chromebook-2560x1600-i5-1240P-LPDDR4X-CBG516-1H-53TD/dp/B0CV61RWHF" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="e19253d3-501a-4b1f-9d2c-6f51fc502025" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="The Acer Chromebook 516 GE might not the be most recent version of this laptop, but it's still incredibly performant. Plus, you can save $100 for Black Friday, and get a powerful Chromebook with all of the RGB you could want." data-dimension48="The Acer Chromebook 516 GE might not the be most recent version of this laptop, but it's still incredibly performant. Plus, you can save $100 for Black Friday, and get a powerful Chromebook with all of the RGB you could want." data-dimension25="$499.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">More Black Friday deals</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Black Friday Google Pixel deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Black Friday Motorola deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024">Black Friday Samsung deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Black Friday OnePlus deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/black-friday-chromebook-deals-2024-score-major-savings-on-acer-lenovo-samsung-and-more">Black Friday Chromebook deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/black-friday-ssd-and-hard-drive-deals-2024-early-discounts-on-storage-devices-plus-some-holiday-shopping-tips">Black Friday SSD deals</a></p></div></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>You want one of the best Chromebooks that money can buy, even if you could care less about the RGB and gaming-centric design.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>You need a Chromebook with a touchscreen or a convertible design.</p>
<p>Under the hood, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/acer-chromebook-516-ge-review">Chromebook 516 GE</a> is powered by the Intel Core i5-1240P, paired with 16GB of RAM and 256GB of storage. This makes for an impressive combination, especially when you remember that you can actually install Steam on here.</p><p>Only having 256GB of storage limits the number of games that you can install, but that's where cloud gaming comes in. This is one area that the Chromebook 516 GE excels, as you can enjoy the likes of NVIDIA GeForce Now, Xbox Game Pass, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://luna.amazon.com/home">Amazon Luna</a>, and other services.</p><p>Although Acer has released the Chromebook Plus 516 GE, it's more of an iterative update than anything else. Plus, it's not currently on sale, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Chromebook-2560x1600-i5-1240P-LPDDR4X-CBG516-1H-53TD/dp/B0CV61RWHF">making this an easy recommendation</a> for Black Friday.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/im-surprised-to-see-my-favorite-gaming-chromebook-on-sale-for-black-friday</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Acer's Chromebook 516 GE is still a great laptop, and while it's not the most recent iteration, you can save some cash on it for Black Friday. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">q33ymWv9HNrsujVM9KX3HN</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gFPejNC9vmezuxHLbeHX2A.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 22:23:29 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Chromebooks &amp; Laptops]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ andrew.myrick@futurenet.com (Andrew Myrick) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gFPejNC9vmezuxHLbeHX2A.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Goldeneye on Acer Chromebook 516 GE 16x9]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Goldeneye on Acer Chromebook 516 GE 16x9]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Black Friday makes it the perfect time to finally buy a VR console ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>I've been a VR gamer for a decade now and I've seen this industry morph significantly in that time. It went from an incredibly complicated mess of expensive PCs, wires everywhere, and hours of configuration to the simplicity of a console in that timespan, and now VR is finally in a place where anyone can pick up and play anytime they want.</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">AC thVRsday</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="LGmZZrc8DWcxmZm6RRUYbC" name="ac-thvrsday-logo.jpg" caption="" alt="AC thVRsday logo" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LGmZZrc8DWcxmZm6RRUYbC.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">In his <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/ac-thvrsday">weekly column</a>, Android Central Senior Content Producer Nick Sutrich delves into all things VR, from new hardware to new games, upcoming technologies, and so much more.</p></div></div>
<p>Of course, I'm talking about a system like the Meta Quest 3S or the Meta Quest 3, both of which offer next-gen mobile computing in an easy-to-use package. If you weren't already aware, these systems are identical to a console like a Nintendo Switch, letting you pick up and play at any time without needing an IT degree.</p><p>Heck, it's even easier and cheaper than a PlayStation 5 since you don't need to hook it up to a TV or PC. Plus, this has been the single greatest year for VR gaming releases in the history of the medium, with big names like Metro, Batman, Alien, Skydance's Behemoth, Assassin's Creed, and plenty more.</p><p>Value-wise, there's simply no better holiday shopping deal than picking up a Meta Quest 3S during Black Friday week. In addition to retailers like Amazon including a $75 gift card — let's face it, an Amazon gift card is basically cash in 2024 — you also get Batman Arkham Shadow and three months of Meta Quest+ for free. As Patrick pointed out, that's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/heads-up-this-black-friday-meta-quest-3s-deal-gives-you-over-usd140-worth-of-free-stuff-im-not-kidding"><strong>over $140 worth of free stuff</strong></a>.</p><p>Good console hardware is only as good as the games that are on it, but,  thankfully, the Quest has most of the all-time best VR games and many of the best games of the generation. Better yet, lots of these are games you probably didn't know existed, and what's more fun than trying something <em>completely</em> new, especially in the land of gaming where so many things are derivative? Nothing, that's what.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="d1bd8486-a710-4b72-b37e-f6778689dc8b" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Meta Quest 3S 128GB: $299.99, plus free copy of Batman: Arkham Shadow, three-month trial of Meta Quest Plus, and FREE $75 digital credit at Amazon" data-dimension48="Meta Quest 3S 128GB: $299.99, plus free copy of Batman: Arkham Shadow, three-month trial of Meta Quest Plus, and FREE $75 digital credit at Amazon" href="https://www.amazon.com/Vega-1-Meta-Quest/dp/B0DDK1WM9K" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2304px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="fCUPHg8DY6xth6JoYMuDGK" name="meta-quest-3s-official-render-with-controllers-square.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fCUPHg8DY6xth6JoYMuDGK.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2304" height="2304" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Meta Quest 3S 128GB: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Vega-1-Meta-Quest/dp/B0DDK1WM9K" data-dimension112="d1bd8486-a710-4b72-b37e-f6778689dc8b" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Meta Quest 3S 128GB: $299.99, plus free copy of Batman: Arkham Shadow, three-month trial of Meta Quest Plus, and FREE $75 digital credit at Amazon" data-dimension48="Meta Quest 3S 128GB: $299.99, plus free copy of Batman: Arkham Shadow, three-month trial of Meta Quest Plus, and FREE $75 digital credit at Amazon" data-dimension25=""><strong>$299.99, plus free copy of Batman: Arkham Shadow, three-month trial of Meta Quest Plus, and FREE $75 digital credit at Amazon</strong></a></p><p><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-quest-3s-review"><strong>Android Central review: ★★★★½</strong></a></p><p>Pick up the Meta Quest 3S from Amazon and you'll get a free $75 gift card, plus all of the free goodies that usually come with new Quest purchases, like a three-month trial of Meta Quest Plus and a free copy of Batman: Arkham Shadow. That makes it cheaper than a Nintendo Switch and it includes 23 free games to boot!<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/Vega-1-Meta-Quest/dp/B0DDK1WM9K" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="d1bd8486-a710-4b72-b37e-f6778689dc8b" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Meta Quest 3S 128GB: $299.99, plus free copy of Batman: Arkham Shadow, three-month trial of Meta Quest Plus, and FREE $75 digital credit at Amazon" data-dimension48="Meta Quest 3S 128GB: $299.99, plus free copy of Batman: Arkham Shadow, three-month trial of Meta Quest Plus, and FREE $75 digital credit at Amazon" data-dimension25="">View Deal</a></p></div>
<h2 id="the-most-fun-games-2">The most fun games</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="oFF95qJpzuUYcNqiUpGBaN" name="walkabout-minigolf-wallace-and-gromit-screesnshot-02.jpg" alt="Screenshots of the Wallace and Gromit course on Walkabout Minigolf taken on a Meta Quest 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oFF95qJpzuUYcNqiUpGBaN.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Some people play games to escape their problems. Some play them to experience a good story or to do things they can't in real life. Others play games just to have fun or to unwind. The Meta Quest offers all of these things and does them in new ways that feel tangibly different from traditional gaming.</p><p>You've probably heard of the immersion factor of VR by now and while it seems like a trope, it really isn't. There's a reason you see those videos on the news of people jumping into TVs when they try Richie's Plank Experience for the first time. VR transports you into the game, and that's something unique you won't get by sitting on a couch.</p><p>But that angle has been overplayed because it's simply not something you can understand unless you experience it, so instead of focusing on that, let's go the best VR games released in the last year.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:960px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="UbzRu9fqJUCAeAcP5cKfbP" name="assassin-creed-nexus-vr-official-screenshot-04.jpg" alt="Screenshots of Assassin's Creed Nexus VR for Quest" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/UbzRu9fqJUCAeAcP5cKfbP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="960" height="540" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ubisoft)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>At the tail-end of 2023, Assasin's Creed Nexus debuted as <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/assassins-creed-nexus-vr-review">the best Assassin's Creed game</a> in over a decade. It channels everything that's great about the series: great stealth mechanics, plenty of scenario variety with three playable characters over three timelines, and an intriguing story that weaves everything together.</p><p>It's a masterpiece, and the series' trademark mechanics work <em>perfectly</em> from a first-person perspective, including a brilliant parkour engine that makes it easy to feel like a master assassin.</p><p>Right afterward, we got <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/asgards-wrath-2-review">Asgard's Wrath 2</a>, a game that channels classic 3D Zelda games in a 100+ hour-long adventure that gets new content every few months. It's the sequel to one of the highest-rated PCVR games of all time and delivers a world that's bigger, better, and bolder than the original in every way. Combat is visceral, the clever puzzles make you feel smart when you solve them, and the world is constantly interesting as you move between playable characters and realms of existence.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="h66QuVNucsaqyXnxEWXB65" name="Batman-Arkham-Shadow-Screenshot-03" alt="A screenshot from Batman Arkham Shadow taken on a Meta Quest 3 headset" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/h66QuVNucsaqyXnxEWXB65.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>This year we've had even more to play, but the most recent titles are among the very best you'll find on any system in 2024. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/batman-arkham-shadow-review">Batman Arkham Shadow</a> is the first true Arkham game in a decade, letting you play through the eyes of Batman in a story that takes place between Arkham Origins and Arkham Asylum.</p><p>After an epically gripping four-chapter prologue filled with emotion, action, and detective work, players are thrust into the Metroidvania-style Blackgate Prison to unravel the mystery of the Rat King and stop the Day of Destruction. You'll switch between Batman himself and a new prisoner of Blackgate, lending plenty of variety in a 12+ hour campaign. New Game+ is coming in January, too, so finding all those secrets will be even better.</p><p>If that wasn't enough, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/metro-awakening-review">Metro Awakening</a> is the first built-for-VR game in the Metro universe by the makers of the excellent Arizona Sunshine series. As with any good Metro game, this one's as much a horror game as it is a first-person shooter. You'll play as a doctor trying to help his wife overcome the pain of losing a child, only to uncover the horrors that lie within the depths of the metro and become something totally unexpected.</p>
<h2 id="multiplayer-like-you-ve-never-played-before-2">Multiplayer like you've never played before</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="o6bVHwmujBipQkokqgdCAV" name="the-last-stand-official-screenshot-01" alt="An official screenshot of The Last Stand on a Meta Quest 3 showing a player attacking another player from across the mall" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/o6bVHwmujBipQkokqgdCAV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Soul Assembly)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Every week, I meet up with a group of friends to hang out and play some games together. Usually, we're facing off in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/breachers-is-the-best-multiplayer-quest-game-ive-ever-played">Breachers</a>, a 5v5 Rainbow Six-like shooter that pits Enforcers against Revolters with traps, destructible walls, rappelling, and plenty of fun. It's a joy to join the crew every week and it feels like we're there in the same room together even though none of us live anywhere near each other.</p><p>It goes back to that whole "immersion" thing I mentioned earlier, and it's part of what makes multiplayer gaming in VR so special.</p><p>I also occasionally jump back into <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.oculus.com/experiences/quest/developer-post/1548271679142026/">Population: One</a>, the free-to-play battle royale that feels amazing in VR thanks to its VR-centric mechanics. You can climb anything, glide anywhere, and generally feel like a superhero because of it. The game just launched a fun seasonal Turkeys vs Pilgrims event and always does something special for the holiday season, so stay tuned for that if you're a player.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="LmZETihvWesXXkaMvvQaH9" name="dungeons-of-eternity-official-screenshot-04.jpg" alt="Official screenshots of Dungeons of Eternity for Meta Quest" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LmZETihvWesXXkaMvvQaH9.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Othergate)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Closer to home, I regularly play games like Dungeons of Eternity <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/you-should-play-more-video-games-with-your-kids">with my son</a> in between bouts of Minecraft on the Switch or Steam Deck. It's fun to delve into new worlds in Minecraft but there's something special about diving into a dungeon with a more physical persona.</p><p>I've written about the joy of Dungeons of Eternity several times and named it my favorite multiplayer game of 2023, and the game has seen some notable updates this year, keeping it fresh and enjoyable. This year's best multiplayer game is, undoutedbly, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/contractors-showdown-meta-quest-3">Contractors: Showdown</a> for me. It's a full-fledged Call of Duty Warzone or PUBG competitor, all with the unique movement and gun handling that's only possible in VR.</p><p>And then there's the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/one-year-later-mixed-reality-games-are-booming">bevy of mixed reality games</a> that have come out this year. Mixed reality is a new concept that only makes sense with a headset like the Quest 3 or Quest 3S because of its color cameras which let you still see the room around you even with the headset on. It's straight up amazing, especially now that developers have figured out new types of games to make with the new medium.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="2DpFoYBAeymaDcqF4FQZUQ" name="contractors-showdown-screenshot-01.jpg" alt="An official screenshot of the island in Contractors Showdown" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2DpFoYBAeymaDcqF4FQZUQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Caveman Studios)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Lots of people flock to titles like Resonite, VR Chat, and even Horizon Worlds as well, which are more social-first hubs with gaming worlds inside. Meta even rebranded the Quest app on phones to the "Meta Horizon" app to further promote its Roblox-like title (Horizon Worlds), but I'm not super keen on these experiences.</p><p>Still, these games are some of the biggest primary traffic drivers of VR content and get people to come back regularly every day. The most successful VR game to date is arguably Gorilla Tag with over $100 million in revenue, and the group that made it is already hard at work on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/gorilla-tag-creator-talks-new-game-orion-drift">next generation of social VR games</a>.</p>
<h2 id="something-new-for-you-2">Something new for you</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1440px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="dGQtREwWCTHpzf5VEEt8Pn" name="just-dance-vr-meta-quest-screenshot" alt="Dancing in Just Dance VR on a Meta Quest 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dGQtREwWCTHpzf5VEEt8Pn.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1440" height="810" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ubisoft)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>If you've been playing games for a few decades like me, you'll probably remember when games went from 2D to 3D and changed everything. The Meta Quest feels exactly like that and delivers both virtual reality AND mixed reality in one headset, opening up two worlds that you probably haven't properly experienced before, even if you've used an older VR headset.</p><p>There's something for everyone here, and the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-oculus-quest-2-games">best Meta Quest games</a> show the depth and variety of the thousands of games that are available on the platform. What are you waiting for? Grab a Quest 3S today and start enjoying some of the best gaming you'll ever play.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/black-friday-makes-it-the-perfect-time-to-finally-buy-a-vr-console</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Playing games no longer means you have to be glued to a TV, and a VR console means you don't even have to see your usual four walls, either. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">fLTVvVfVLhVRJkMXffjhwD</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NZPBjHcV8HUXxtvJKWVeCJ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 21:58:18 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NZPBjHcV8HUXxtvJKWVeCJ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A Meta Quest 3S alongside a Steam Deck, Nintendo Switch, and PlayStation 5 controller]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A Meta Quest 3S alongside a Steam Deck, Nintendo Switch, and PlayStation 5 controller]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>