<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 09:02:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google needs to make a budget Pixel phone ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The Pixel A series is the best way to get Google&apos;s custom software features and terrific cameras for less, and the Pixel 8a takes things to a new level. It has considerable upgrades, including a 120Hz OLED panel, larger battery, Tensor G3, and it will get the same seven years of software updates as the regular <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-review">Pixel 8</a> models.</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Hardwired</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="5u6gVPowTCuSQ8NJeoktj7" name="lloyd-hardwired.png" caption="" alt="Android Central's LLoyd with a bionic eye" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5u6gVPowTCuSQ8NJeoktj7.png" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">In <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/hardwired">Hardwired</a>, AC Senior Editor Harish Jonnalagadda delves into all things hardware, including phones, storage servers, and routers.</p></div></div>
<p>But there&apos;s a problem. All the new features come with an inflated price tag, with the Pixel 8a retailing at $499 — $50 more than the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-7a-review">Pixel 7a</a> and $100 more than the Pixel 3a. The Pixel 8a is still a good bargain considering you get most of the same features as the $699 Pixel 8, and if you need a mid-range phone, it is the best overall choice.</p><p>While Google is doing the right things with the Pixel A series, I think it needs to shift its attention to the budget segment. There aren&apos;t as many choices in this category as previous years; other than the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/moto-g-5g-2024-review">Moto G 5G</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-nord-n30-5g-review">OnePlus Nord N30</a>, and a few TCL options, you don&apos;t get much if you&apos;re interested in a sub-$350 phone. Even the Galaxy A35 starts off at $399.</p><p>This isn&apos;t limited to North America either. I&apos;ve always recommended Xiaomi&apos;s Redmi Note series in the past, but the brand decided to move up a segment with recent launches, and the result is that the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/redmi-note-13-pro-plus-review">Redmi Note 13 Pro+</a> now costs the equivalent of $495, a truly ridiculous state of affairs. The only budget-focused model in the series is the standard Redmi Note 13, and that just doesn&apos;t have the same caliber of hardware.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="nWZPhBUMpYx79ZArta3CNT" name="nothing-phone-2a-9.jpg" alt="Nothing Phone 2a review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nWZPhBUMpYx79ZArta3CNT.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The only budget phone that I&apos;d recommend is the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/nothing-phone-2a-review">Nothing Phone 2a</a>; it has a great design, good internal hardware, and clean software with unique extras. The cameras aren&apos;t as good as the Pixel 7a, but you get two usable lenses — which isn&apos;t the case with most budget options.</p>
<p>Google is seeing a lot of momentum with the Pixel A series, but the only way to truly scale its hardware ambitions is by focusing on the budget segment. That&apos;s the only feasible area where Google can meaningfully grow its business in countries like India. While Google sells its phones in the region, they&apos;re significantly costlier than their rivals — the Pixel 8a starts off at an absurd ₹52,999 ($634), and that effectively kills the phone before it even goes on sale.</p>
<p>Ideally, Google needs to introduce a model in the sub-$350 segment to be able to challenge Samsung and Xiaomi. But it is unlikely the search giant will ever do that; in an interview with Austrian publication <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.derstandard.at/story/3000000189970/warum-google-keine-billig-smartphones-bauen-will-und-wieso-oesterreich-erst-jetzt-drankommt"><em>Der Standard</em></a>, Google&apos;s Pixel division Nanda Ramachandran confirmed that the brand will not release a budget device, stating "we would have to make too many compromises for that."</p><p>A budget Pixel makes sense in a lot of ways. Google&apos;s camera wizardry combined with its unique software features would make a budget Pixel device stand out considerably, but it&apos;s clear that Google has no intention of taking that route. Google says it wants to be a major hardware player, but it doesn&apos;t have a strategy in place that allows the brand to get there. While Pixels are still terrific devices they continue to be out of reach of buyers interested in affordable phones.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-needs-to-make-a-budget-pixel-phone</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google needs to make a sub-$350 Pixel phone to challenge Samsung and Xiaomi. There's only one problem — it doesn't want to do that.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">btzTTmhSXNsXNNqtFKPdfm</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/49AVQgVxLWzNimwEovQZeL.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 07:06:16 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/49AVQgVxLWzNimwEovQZeL.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The back of the Charcoal Google Pixel 7a]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The back of the Charcoal Google Pixel 7a]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Matter 1.3 wants to connect appliances and EV chargers to your smart home ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Matter, the standard that has a goal of making all smart home devices and platforms interoperable, has a new update.</li><li>The Connectivity Standards Alliance (CSA) revealed the new Matter 1.3 update today, which adds support for more kinds of devices.</li><li>New to this release is support for more home appliances, like stovetops and dryers, as well as EV chargers. </li></ul>
<hr>
<p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/matter">Matter</a> has lofty goals, aiming to make all sorts of smart home devices and ecosystems play nice with each other. The rollout of Matter has been slow, but the Connectivity Standards Alliance (CSA) that develops the standard continues expanding its reach. In a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://csa-iot.org/newsroom/matter-1-3-specification-released/" target="_blank">blog post</a> on Wednesday, May 8, the CSA released the next version of Matter, known as Matter 1.3. The update adds support for new kinds of devices, such as home appliances and electric vehicle chargers.</p><p>The biggest part of Matter 1.3 is the inclusion of new energy management features. EV chargers will be the first type of device to benefit from Matter 1.3&apos;s new energy management system, but it will likely come to others in the future. The CSA says that Matter 1.3 enables supported accessories to "report actual and estimated measurements, including instantaneous power, voltage, current, and others, in real-time, as well as its energy consumption or generation over time." </p><p>In practice, this will help users charge more efficiently and cheaply. High-energy products, like electric vehicles, can have a big impact on their owner&apos;s energy bill when they are charged at peak usage times. That&apos;s why scheduling EV charging at times when energy usage is typically low can be an excellent cost-saving measure.</p><p>With Matter 1.3, supported EV chargers can be controlled over the internet for uses like manually starting or stopping a charging session. Other uses include adjusting the rate of EV charging and to "specify how many miles of range to be added by a set departure time." </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.30%;"><img id="4eqXGmkp6RC4gBFBFGaoAk" name="Google-Pixel-7-Pro-smart-home-lock-screen-lifestyle-01.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 7 Pro smart home controls from lock screen" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4eqXGmkp6RC4gBFBFGaoAk.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4000" height="2252" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Chris Wedel/Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Aside from energy management, the CSA says Matter 1.3 also adds support for water management devices. These include "leak and freeze detectors, rain sensors, and controllable water valves." </p><p>Matter 1.3 opens the door for more smart home appliances to be released with Matter support, building upon existing support for washing machines, which was <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/matter-1-2-upgrade-details">added with Matter 1.2</a>. Five new appliances are supported: microwaves, ovens, cooktops, vent hoods, and laundry dryers.  </p><p>Finally, the latest release improves integration between Matter-equipped TVs and other devices. For example, you might someday get a push notification on your TV that your laundry has finished drying.</p><p>This all requires widespread adoption of Matter to make a meaningful difference, and that&apos;s supposedly coming. The issue with Matter thus far is the pace at which it is being added to new products and existing software platforms. That will still apply to Matter 1.3 because the release only covers the new specification. No new products are ready to release with Matter 1.3 just yet, and it&apos;ll take time for manufacturers to ship home appliances and EV chargers with Matter support. </p><p>"Looking ahead to the fall release and beyond, we anticipate support for enhancements benefiting all users and devices, including new categories of devices, and enabling users to start, grow, and maintain their secure smart home with smart home-focused networking infrastructure," the CSA said. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/matter-1-3-upgrade</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Connectivity Standards Alliance (CSA) revealed Matter 1.3, which adds support for new kinds of devices, like more home appliances and EV chargers. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">HF5zPTkYddmZUd73sRCeLh</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9ma8GnK3AJPDvJ5QK2fVcC.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 06:52:49 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Smart Home]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9ma8GnK3AJPDvJ5QK2fVcC.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Matter]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Matter logo]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Matter logo]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google explains how Find My Device can locate Pixel 8 when it's dead or powered off ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Back in April, Google announced that the Pixel 8 and Pixel 8 Pro would support offline finding. </li><li>Now that the Find My Device is rolling out widely, Google is explaining the feature to users enrolled in the network with a push notification.</li><li>Google says that Pixel 8 and Pixel 8 Pro can report their location to the Find My Device network for "several hours" after it is turned off or the battery dies.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google started rolling out the Find My Device network a month ago, and it included a key feature for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-review">Pixel 8</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-pro-review">Pixel 8 Pro</a>. In an April 8 <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.google/products/android/android-find-my-device/" target="_blank">blog post</a>, Google said that these <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">flagship phones</a> would be able to report their location to the Find My Device ecosystem even if their batteries were dead or powered off. Now that the Find My Device network is being widely enabled by Android users, Google is explaining to Pixel 8 and Pixel 8 Pro owners how this new feature works. </p><p>In a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/android/answer/3265955?#zippy=%2Cstep-find-offline-devices-and-devices-without-power" target="_blank">support document</a>, Google elaborates on how long Pixel 8 and Pixel 8 Pro devices can continue providing location data after they&apos;ve been turned off or the battery has been depleted. "For supported devices, like the Pixel 8 series, if the device runs out of battery or is off, the Find My Device network can still locate the phone for several hours after it’s turned off," the company says.</p><p>Google broadly references the Pixel 8 series in its support document, but it doesn&apos;t indicate whether or not the Pixel 8a will support the feature. In other times Google has referenced this functionality, only the Pixel 8 and Pixel 8 Pro were listed as having support. However, it&apos;s possible these documents were published before the Pixel 8a&apos;s announcement, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/pixel-8a-find-my-device-network-3441230/">support could come in the future</a>, as noted by Mishaal Rahman.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/05/08/pixel-8-find-my-device-power/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a> first spotted the push notification Google is sending out to Pixel 8 and Pixel 8 Pro users. The notification seems to be more informative than anything else, letting users know that the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/find-my-device">Find My Device</a> functionality is available. After all, it won&apos;t be helpful when you need it if you don&apos;t know it&apos;s there. Tapping the <strong>Learn more</strong> button on the push notification will provide more details about offline finding, like Google&apos;s guidance that users should make sure Bluetooth and Location are both enabled before their phone shuts down. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="fYbbdUHcevxnfRkZqxndqG" name="Google-Pixel-8-Pro-back-porecelain-10.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 8 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fYbbdUHcevxnfRkZqxndqG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div></figure>
<p>If you&apos;ve opted into the Find My Device network, your Pixel 8 or Pixel 8 Pro should report its location automatically when it is powered down or the battery dies. However, that might change if you tweak the default settings. Google provides users with four offline device location settings to choose from: <strong>Off</strong>, <strong>Without network</strong>, <strong>With network in high-traffic areas only </strong>(default), and <strong>With network in all areas</strong>.</p><p>To adjust your choice, open the <strong>settings app </strong>and navigate to <strong>Google</strong> <strong>></strong> <strong>All services ></strong> <strong>Find My Device</strong>. Then, tap <strong>Find your offline devices</strong> and pick one of the above four options. Be sure to note that only the latter two will make your Pixel 8 or Pixel 8 Pro available for offline finding. </p><p>While this feature will only be useful in the first few hours after your smartphone is shut down or dies, it&apos;ll still come in handy. For example, if you lose your phone or it gets stolen, no one can shut it off and immediately cut location reporting. It&apos;s limited to the Pixel 8 and Pixel 8 Pro for now, but Google&apos;s wording leaves the door open for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/should-you-buy-pixel-8a">Pixel 8a</a> support in the future. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-explains-pixel-8-find-my-device-powered-off</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ With the new Find My Device network, the latest Pixel flagships are gaining support for offline finding, and Google is explaining more about how it works.   ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">r8MupV8buhJrZo6ZNSKokW</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JgPhFosKC6tCDAFCv469z7.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 06:46:09 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JgPhFosKC6tCDAFCv469z7.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Hands on with the Google Pixel 8 and Pixel 8 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Hands on with the Google Pixel 8 and Pixel 8 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Fiio FA19 review: Standout design, stellar sound ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Fiio has exciting products in a range of categories, but IEMs are still its biggest focus. The brand has several dozen IEMs on sale, including traditional dynamic driver designs, hybrid models that use dynamic and balanced armature (BA) drivers, and tribrid models that include electrostatic drivers in addition to dynamic and BA drivers.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-fx15-review">FX15</a> is Fiio&apos;s only tribrid IEM as of writing, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/FIIO-FX15-Six-Driver-Hybrid-Monitors/dp/B0CF2RN8LP">coming in at $749</a>, it is significantly costlier than the brand&apos;s other offerings — until now. Fiio also makes IEMs that solely use BA drivers, and the FA19 is the latest product in this series. With 10 BA drivers in each earbud and as <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/FiiO-FA19-Audiophile-Earphones-Detachable/dp/B0D2RCKGW7/">asking price of $999 on Amazon</a>, it is also the brand&apos;s costliest IEMs to date. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="8VxaFxx5TEnVykNofu8e2X" name="fiio-fa19-4.jpg" alt="Showcasing the design of the Fiio FA19 and bundled cable" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8VxaFxx5TEnVykNofu8e2X.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Fiio says that the FA19 isn&apos;t an upgrade to the FA9; instead, it is a ground-up reimagining of the brand&apos;s BA offerings, and it has unique bass-focused drivers that give it a distinct presence in the low-end that isn&apos;t evident in its siblings. The brand collaborated with Knowles — the largest manufacturer of BA drivers — to create a custom driver with a larger vent, delivering better bass.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="44fJ8EisvyHquCKj9sntkX" name="fiio-fa19-6.jpg" alt="Close view of Fiio FA19 shells with driver units inside" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/44fJ8EisvyHquCKj9sntkX.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="kgq4FGG5YyP6KBCAbGPBVX" name="fiio-fa19-5.jpg" alt="Close view of Fiio FA19's see-through shell with driver units inside" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kgq4FGG5YyP6KBCAbGPBVX.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 3</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="zprubUGejNy9zVGzitSjwX" name="fiio-fa19-7.jpg" alt="Close view of Fiio FA19 shells with driver units inside" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zprubUGejNy9zVGzitSjwX.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>I&apos;ll get to the sound in a little bit, but before that, let&apos;s talk about the design. Fiio uses 3D printed resin shells for a lot of its products, and that&apos;s no different with the FA19. The resin shells allow the FA19 to be lightweight, and the contoured design means you get a comfortable fit. I used the FA19 for the better part of two weeks now, and I didn&apos;t see any issues with comfort even with extended use.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="JeNgyEmtsFQkyLvCEsBjeW" name="fiio-fa19-1.jpg" alt="Fiio FA19 IEMs next to cable against colorful background" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JeNgyEmtsFQkyLvCEsBjeW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The faceplate has a custom design that doesn&apos;t have any similarities to other Fiio IEMs, but I still prefer the frond-style design that&apos;s featured in the FX15. There&apos;s a toggle on the FA19 that lets you switch between mastering and Hi-Fi modes; the mastering mode has a neutral sound and is designed to be used for monitoring, and the latter has an exaggerated bass that sounds terrific.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="4X3nXvPDY8Bc5ieWGtxE9Y" name="fiio-fa19-8.jpg" alt="Design of the Fiio FA19 shells with cable next to it" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4X3nXvPDY8Bc5ieWGtxE9Y.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The shells have a see-through design that lets you view the individual drivers and sound tubes that feed the audio to the nozzle. There&apos;s a vent at the back, and it affects noise isolation to a noticeable extent. The IEMs connect via MMCX connectors, and while these tend to be not as easy to use as standard 2-pin connectors, Fiio did a great job in this area, and the bundled tool lets you easily detach the cable.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="hzMEjqpLoGazvkonPkKWNY" name="fiio-fa19-9.jpg" alt="Fiio FA19 packaging with all the bundled accessories" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hzMEjqpLoGazvkonPkKWNY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>On that subject, the FA19 has one of the best accessory package in this category. You get a total of 18 pairs of ear tips, including silicone balanced, bass-focused, and vocal tips along with memory foam options. The exhaustive selection means you&apos;re guaranteed to get a great fit, and Fiio also bundles the same HB5 case that you get with the FX15. The leather case that&apos;s exquisite; it is just the right size, and it easily holds the IEMs and the cable.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="tpKNTskh3S5Q7LPjigMsFZ" name="fiio-fa19-14.jpg" alt="Fiio FA19 with the cable attached" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tpKNTskh3S5Q7LPjigMsFZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The cable itself is really good; the 8-strand silver cable has a braided design and a sheath that gives it added resilience, and it has a modular connector that lets you switch between 4.4mm and 3.5mm with ease.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="kgVDMWhd4PdsqiiiKpeFhY" name="fiio-fa19-11.jpg" alt="Fiio FA19 with bundled accessories" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kgVDMWhd4PdsqiiiKpeFhY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Coming to the sound, the FA19 houses ten Knowles BA drivers in each earbud; there are four custom bass drivers, two ED mid-range drivers, and four SWFK treble drivers. Fiio uses a negative feedback bass enhancement system that reduces low-frequency sounds to the rear cavity of the earbud, delivering detailed bass. There&apos;s also the brand&apos;s S.Turbo that prevents crossover from the low-frequency to the mids.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="BWk3kunj6KDZzA8PKEaTsY" name="fiio-fa19-12.jpg" alt="Fiio FA19 connected to Fiio M23 music player" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BWk3kunj6KDZzA8PKEaTsY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In addition to the custom bass driver, Fiio says it collaborated closely with Knowles to optimize the sound of the mid- and high-frequency drivers. The result is a sound signature that&apos;s very different to most BA IEMs; the bass in particular is incredible, with a lot of energy and vibrancy. Toggling the IEMs to Hi-Fi mode kicks things up a notch, with the sub-bass and mid-bass frequencies getting even more pronounced.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="UfcaTHg6Erx6RuuaqWXHPZ" name="fiio-fa19-15.jpg" alt="Balanced 4.4mm cable of Fiio FA19 connected to Fiio M23 audio player" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/UfcaTHg6Erx6RuuaqWXHPZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The mid-range is clean and detailed, with a forward presentation for the vocals. There&apos;s good instrument separation, terrific dynamics, and from a technical point of view, the FA19 nails the basics. The treble has good range, and there&apos;s no sibilance whatsoever; it&apos;s not as detailed as the FX15, but it comes close.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="Rsbg63NsNX7WNbgGTmRd4Z" name="fiio-fa19-13.jpg" alt="Fiio FA19 connected to Fiio M23 music player" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Rsbg63NsNX7WNbgGTmRd4Z.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>With a sensitivity of 106dB and 10Ω, it&apos;s effortlessly easy to drive the FA19. I used it with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-k19-review">K19 DAC</a>, M23 audio player, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-ka13-review">KA13 dongle</a>, and ideally, you&apos;ll need something on the same level as the KA13 to get the most out of the IEMs.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="k6uyeo6XQtjvScjeVNUvDX" name="fiio-fa19-3.jpg" alt="Design of Fiio FA19 shells and bundled cable" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/k6uyeo6XQtjvScjeVNUvDX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Overall, Fiio did a stellar job with the FA19. The BA IEM segment isn&apos;t as extensive as hybrid options, and by using a vented design along with custom bass drivers, the FA19 manages to deliver detailed bass that&apos;s closer to large dynamic drivers. The soundstage is wide and inviting, and you get a comfortable fit thanks to the generous options in the box. I still prefer the FX15&apos;s sound — particularly with the music I listen to — but the FA19 is a technical powerhouse, and if you IEMs with all-BA drivers, it is a terrific choice.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="80358b7e-c453-4eee-9f33-f2574432a924">
            <a href="https://www.amazon.com/FiiO-FA19-Audiophile-Earphones-Detachable/dp/B0D2RCKGW7/" data-model-name="Fiio FA19"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:101.57%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/w6DBYdr2n53BaSXKWbr3cU.jpg' alt='Fiio FA19'></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Fiio FA19</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>The FA19 has it all: a great design with durable shells, sublime sound that's customizable, and a comfortable fit. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/fiio-fa19-review</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ With the FA19, Fiio is going all-in on its BA driver offerings, and the IEMs have 10 drivers in each earbud. The result is a magnificent sound that's among the best in this segment.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">nKRMZoKTwXH9sJVDgJz5JS</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dCV68htXbTQhJjqGnsaZpW.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 06:37:25 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dCV68htXbTQhJjqGnsaZpW.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Design of Fiio FA19 shells against colorful background]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Design of Fiio FA19 shells against colorful background]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ TikTok is suing the US government to stop a law that bans the app ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>TikTok and its parent company, ByteDance, have filed a lawsuit challenging a new US law signed by President Biden.</li><li>The law may either force TikTok to separate from ByteDance or ban the app in the US, citing national security concerns.</li><li>TikTok argues that the law targets it unfairly and violates the First Amendment's rules on free speech.</li><li>The company also claims that the requirement for TikTok to be sold is not feasible—commercially, technologically, or legally.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>TikTok has been on thin ice since President Joe Biden signed the <em>Protecting Americans from Foreign Adversary Controlled Applications Act</em> in April, but the company is suing to stay afloat.</p><p>CNN <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/05/07/tech/tiktok-sues-us-app-ban/index.html" target="_blank">reports</a> that the short-form video platform and its parent company, ByteDance, have <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="chrome-extension://efaidnbmnnnibpcajpcglclefindmkaj/https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.cadc.40861/gov.uscourts.cadc.40861.1208620273.1.pdf" target="_blank">filed a petition</a> to the US Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit to challenge the new law that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/tiktok-ban-just-got-the-houses-nod-and-it-might-be-law-real-soon">forces the app to split from ByteDance or otherwise bans it in the country</a>. TikTok claims the law unfairly targets it and is unconstitutional.</p><p>Last month, as part of an aid package for Ukraine and Israel, President Biden <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/us-bill-to-ban-tiktok-signed-into-law">signed a new law that gives ByteDance nine months to either divest TikTok or shut it down in the US</a> due to national security concerns. However, the complaint claims that the government hasn&apos;t provided proof that the Chinese government has misused TikTok.</p><p>“The statements of congressional committees and individual Members of Congress during the hasty, closed-door legislative process preceding the Act’s enactment confirm that there is at most speculation, not ‘evidence,’ as the First Amendment requires,” the filing states.</p><p>The company adds that the law breaks the rules of free speech in the First Amendment and that it&apos;s impossible to follow anyway. TikTok explains that the requirement for the platform to be sold off is impossible in commercial, technological, and legal terms.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="RFefyrc78eYzo2G8MFgNuY" name="TikTok-icon.jpg" alt="TikTok icon" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RFefyrc78eYzo2G8MFgNuY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3000" height="1687" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Jay Bonggolto / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>TikTok has less than a year from when President Biden signed the act to find a US buyer or risk being shut down.</p><p>But even if ByteDance were open to selling TikTok, the Chinese government would likely prevent the sale, as it needs to approve the transfer of TikTok&apos;s algorithms. TikTok also mentions that a sale would be tricky, explaining that "millions of lines of software code" would need to be transferred to a new owner.</p><p>When the U.S. government first tried to ban TikTok during the Trump administration, ByteDance looked into selling its US operations to an American company. However, talks of selling to Oracle, Microsoft, or even Walmart fell through, and apparently, ByteDance isn&apos;t interested in a repeat and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/bytedance-is-willing-to-ditch-tiktok-in-the-us-instead-of-selling-it-off">would rather shut down TikTok in the US</a>.</p><p>This lawsuit is the latest chapter in a years-long drama. The US government keeps saying TikTok&apos;s China ties are a security risk, worried that American user data might be leaked. TikTok denies it all, saying it spent tons of cash to keep the treasure trove of data safe.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/tiktok-is-suing-the-us-government-to-stop-a-law-that-bans-the-app</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ TikTok sues to challenge a new US law that bans the video-sharing app, hoping to reverse it. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">RCwcubXi7kes7Yc4xoqHDj</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/grNeVRDB3Cyt4cKWUcd9QL.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 05:56:41 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/grNeVRDB3Cyt4cKWUcd9QL.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[TikTok app logo on Android]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[TikTok app logo on Android]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Teenage Engineering CM-15 review: The ultimate portable studio mic ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>In the context of phones, Teenage Engineering is best known for its collaboration with Nothing; the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/nothing-phone-1-review">Phone 1</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/nothing-phone-2-review">Phone 2&apos;s unique design</a> identity was created by the Swedish brand. And while it teams up with plenty of other brands to design eye-catching products — such as the Playdate handheld console — its main focus is music production gear.</p><p>I&apos;ve always been a fan of Teenage Engineering&apos;s Pocket Operator series of miniature synths, and a decade after its launch, the OP-1 continues to be a standout synth. The brand rolled out its field system at the start of last year, introducing a range of devices that are designed for portable use. The CM-15 is a part of that range, which includes a field recorder, mixer, and a lighter OP-1 dubbed the OP-1 Field.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="DfEharEJcvgVSdTettfwc5" name="teenage-engineering-cm15-8.jpg" alt="Teenage Engineering CM-15 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DfEharEJcvgVSdTettfwc5.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The idea is to be able to create music on the go, and each of the products is designed to work in conjunction with the rest. The CM-15 is particularly notable because of its sheer versatility; you can use it as a traditional studio mic to record vocals or instruments, and there&apos;s the ability to connect it to your phone and use it to record audio — this is handy during interviews — and so much more.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="mYVpBA722bd7Qt9Ze5B9w4" name="teenage-engineering-cm15-5.jpg" alt="Teenage Engineering CM-15 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mYVpBA722bd7Qt9Ze5B9w4.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Then there&apos;s the design. Obviously, design isn&apos;t a key consideration when it comes to a mic, but the CM-15 has a minimal aesthetic that differentiates it from other studio mics. The diminutive size makes it a great choice for use on the road; it is about half the size of a phone, and weighs just 132g — no small feat considering it has a built-in battery.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="Ly44z6EAg5qpwfuXqrjHo5" name="teenage-engineering-cm15-9.jpg" alt="Teenage Engineering CM-15 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Ly44z6EAg5qpwfuXqrjHo5.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Clearly, a lot of thought went into the design of the CM-15, and the small form factor combined with the anodized aluminum chassis makes it inherently portable and durable. You also get a decent set of accessories in the box; the bundled adapter allows to mount the CM-15 on a tripod with relative ease, and you get a mini-XLR to XLR along with USB-C to USB-C cables and a field pouch with a water-resistant fabric.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="JDRrzgxAfZELLDz6Y5rpW6" name="teenage-engineering-cm15-13.jpg" alt="Teenage Engineering CM-15 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JDRrzgxAfZELLDz6Y5rpW6.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="mYVpBA722bd7Qt9Ze5B9w4" name="teenage-engineering-cm15-5.jpg" alt="Teenage Engineering CM-15 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mYVpBA722bd7Qt9Ze5B9w4.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="Nyb7akrbTZDrfAdQGYddA5" name="teenage-engineering-cm15-6.jpg" alt="Teenage Engineering CM-15 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Nyb7akrbTZDrfAdQGYddA5.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 4 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="eqNbHSnfrAJ5B65wdasRM5" name="teenage-engineering-cm15-7.jpg" alt="Teenage Engineering CM-15 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/eqNbHSnfrAJ5B65wdasRM5.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 5 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="REBDYV2L98quzipEqBsBb4" name="teenage-engineering-cm15-4.jpg" alt="Teenage Engineering CM-15 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/REBDYV2L98quzipEqBsBb4.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>The design feature I like the most is the built-in kickstand at the back; it allows the mic to stay upright on a desk without having to use a mount. Connectivity is via mini-XLR, 3.5mm, and USB-C, and you can power it via 48V phantom power, USB-C, or use the internal battery. It switches between the three automatically, and there&apos;s a tiny LED on the side that serves as a visual indicator for the battery charge level.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="Kh7EeLAmVXWGbGSXd92tf6" name="teenage-engineering-cm15-14.jpg" alt="Teenage Engineering CM-15 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Kh7EeLAmVXWGbGSXd92tf6.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Charging the battery takes just over two hours, and you get nearly nine hours of usage between charges — which is more than adequate in this setting.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="v9nfRgm3QCjyharkRcToS7" name="teenage-engineering-cm15-12.jpg" alt="Teenage Engineering CM-15 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/v9nfRgm3QCjyharkRcToS7.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Other than the power button that&apos;s on the left, the only other toggle on the CM-15 is the gain switch; there are three modes available, with the left-most position at 0dB, the middle setting boosting gain by 14dB, and the right-most position increasing it by 32dB.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="jZADygZruXnchYVnkLhZ66" name="teenage-engineering-cm15-11.jpg" alt="Teenage Engineering CM-15 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jZADygZruXnchYVnkLhZ66.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Coming to the mic itself, the CM-15 includes a 1-inch diaphragm capsule that&apos;s manufactured by Peluso Microphones. The sound quality is fantastic; I normally use a Blue Yeti to record audio and the occasional instrument, and the CM-15 is in another league altogether.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="P2QnhqHnDnTFAepC3u5gx6" name="teenage-engineering-cm15-15.jpg" alt="Teenage Engineering CM-15 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/P2QnhqHnDnTFAepC3u5gx6.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The condenser mic has a unidirectional pattern, so it picks up sounds in front of it, and it does a decent job isolating ambient noise. The best part is the versatility; I used the CM-15 for the better part of four months, and in that time, I recorded interviews on the go, plugged it into my phone to record audio, and while it is vastly overkill for this use case, I attended several dozen briefings and meetings with it.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="8WpfNoycnmQRQXsvkuYe87" name="teenage-engineering-cm15-16.jpg" alt="Teenage Engineering CM-15 review" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8WpfNoycnmQRQXsvkuYe87.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It is outstanding as a studio mic, and the portability gives it a distinct edge. Coming in at $1,199, the CM-15 is several magnitudes costlier than most products in this category, but if you want a high-quality studio mic with a durable design that can be used anywhere, it is a great choice. </p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="7a0bed5b-5e7a-4c67-8c8f-92e1f1835d57">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sXkCzFYZiQLtXkp2zfCci5.jpg' alt='Teenage Engineering CM-15'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Teenage Engineering CM-15</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>With fantastic sound and an elegant design, the CM-15 holds its own against the best studio mics. </p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/teenage-engineering-cm-15-review</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Teenage Engineering's CM-15 is a condenser studio mic like no other; it has a gorgeous design, built-in battery, and is built to last. Oh, and it costs $1,199. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">VvWEyXzjXEjRmPr9ZN4vEb</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NJZyXU6zLw9od8SCoBGpA4.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 03:49:51 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NJZyXU6zLw9od8SCoBGpA4.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Teenage Engineering CM-15 review]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Teenage Engineering CM-15 review]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Prime Video users are in for ad(ded) streaming interruptions ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Amazon Ads will roll out three new interactive ads for Amazon Prime video on TVs and other living room devices.</li><li>The company says this will enable users to seamlessly shop during the 15-30-second ad breaks between their shows/movies.</li><li>These ads are said to pop up even when a video is paused and showcase facts about the brand that will help users shop better.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Streaming on Prime Video will get a bit busier as Amazon <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://advertising.amazon.com/blog/amazon-ads-announces-three-new-streaming-tv-ad-formats">announced</a> on Tuesday (May 7) that it will add three new interactive and shoppable ad formats to its streaming platform on living room devices.</p><p>The company said that Prime Video will now receive an expanded suite of interactive and shoppable ad formats, including remote-enabled capabilities for living room devices that go a step ahead of the usual QR code that pops up in an ad.<br>
<br>
Brands will now be able to showcase shoppable carousel ads to help viewers browse and shop multiple product variations on Amazon during ad breaks in Prime Video shows and movies. Brands can also use interactive pause and brand trivia ads in Prime Video TV shows, movies, and live sports. </p><p>These interactive ads are said to appear in three distinctive formats during ad breaks or when the video is paused.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Shoppable carousel ads: </strong>Brands present a sliding lineup of their products that customers can explore on Amazon and add to their cart using most living-room remotes. Viewers can pause these ads to browse through the products.</li><li><strong>Interactive pause ads:</strong> These pop up when viewers pause the show or movie they're streaming. A translucent ad featuring brand messaging and imagery, along with an "Add to Cart" and "Learn More," will create an overlay on the screen, replacing the usual pause screen containing information about the show/movie — these ads will show up even after the ad breaks and disappear when the video is resumed.</li><li><strong>Interactive brand trivia ads: </strong>These Provide facts about a specific brand, giving users the opportunity to shop on Amazon, learn more about services and products, and even unlock rewards. Customers can use their living-room remote to add a product to their cart, request information via email, and claim rewards like Amazon shopping credits with the purchase of eligible items.</li></ul>
<p>Amazon&apos;s research indicated that interactive ads are more effective in boosting engagement rates and driving product sales, allowing viewers to add items to their cart while binging on a show/movie.</p><p>“We are developing innovative experiences to help brands better engage with customers as we work to transform streaming," said Alan Moss, vice president of global ad sales for Amazon Ads.</p><p>"Ads in Prime Video provide an unparalleled experience for advertisers to deliver on any <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://advertising.amazon.com/blog/what-is-full-funnel-marketing?ref_=a20m_us_blg_nwadfmt_blg_fll_fnnl">full-funnel marketing</a> objective – whether it’s awareness, consideration or conversion,” Moss added.</p><p>Amazon CEO Andy Jassy noted during the company&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/amazon-q1-2024-earnings">Q1 2024 earnings call</a> that the company&apos;s efforts to bring ads to Prime Video were off to a good start and that advertisers were "excited about being able to expand their ability to advertise with us [with] video" beyond the previous offerings.</p>
<h2 id="is-this-a-good-move-for-users-2">Is this a good move for users?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1922px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.30%;"><img id="yYEUxUtZmYKVqzg52Hii7Q" name="Amazon-Prime-video-continue-watching.jpg" alt="Prime Video continue watching" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yYEUxUtZmYKVqzg52Hii7Q.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1922" height="1082" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Amazon)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Many people find ads on streaming platforms frustrating, and paying an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/amazon-prime-video-introduces-ads">additional $2.99 </a>on top of their Prime Video or Amazon Prime subscription isn&apos;t something that everyone willingly does to get rid of ads. Instead, viewers painfully wait for the 15-30 sec ads to get done. Imagine an added layer of interactive ads to steer your attention away.</p><p>However, the downside is that Amazon seems to be looking to boost revenue through these new ads, and how viewers will react remains to be seen. Will they really find these ads engaging, or will they become more frustrated and consider switching to an ad-free streaming platform? </p><p>Amazon isn&apos;t the only platform that has introduced interactive ads. Since 2022, they&apos;ve <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.techradar.com/streaming/hulu-max-and-peacock-are-introducing-a-pause-ads-feature-and-im-not-a-fan">appeared more frequently </a>on Hulu, Max, and Peacock, and customers weren&apos;t keen on these changes.</p><p>Kara Manatt of the media and advertising group Magna <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://variety.com/2023/tv/news/pause-ads-hulu-max-peacock-streaming-1235764850/">told Variety</a> last year that "having a bad experience or having a lot of ad clutter erodes the impact of ads and is really bad for users." Manatt said research found that customers also changed their behavior due to these ads and canceled their streaming service subscriptions. </p><p>Amazon Ads first introduced interactive video ads in 2021 on services like IMDb TV on Fire TV devices and has continued to expand the format across most of its streaming TV portfolio, including shows, movies, and live sports on Prime Video, Twitch, Fire TV Channels, and third-party streaming TV apps.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/amazon-prime-video-interactive-ads</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Amazon Ads unveiled three new interactive and shoppable ad formats for Prime Video with remote-enabled capabilities. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Xxx4UsdpBarPaR3WKqfkPC</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rRVbpLNe8zPGmbefjKhuwG.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:58:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Streaming &amp; TV]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nandika.iyerravi@futurenet.com (Nandika Ravi) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rRVbpLNe8zPGmbefjKhuwG.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A TV show page on Prime Video]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A TV show page on Prime Video]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Another new Mint Mobile deal just dropped —  get some FREE streaming with your dirt-cheap wireless ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Mint Mobile was already home to some of the best wireless deals on the market, but they&apos;ve just made their popular New Customer Offer even better by throwing in a fresh new incentive. Sign up for Mint today with ANY of their three-month data plans and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/"><strong>you&apos;ll get six months of Paramount Plus&apos; Essential Plan</strong></a> for 100% free. That&apos;s a value of over $35, plus Mint is still offering that promo that drops ALL of their data plans to only $15 per month for the first three months. Half a year of streaming and three months of unlimited data for only $45 upfront? Sign me up. </p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="b5255bfa-1959-41dc-93b5-d0ccfc63897f" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Mint Mobile New Customer Offer: Three months of Unlimited for $15/month, now includes six months of Paramount Plus" data-dimension48="Mint Mobile New Customer Offer: Three months of Unlimited for $15/month, now includes six months of Paramount Plus" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:300px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="BPWiQe3vKGWbwqwX3mVeqG" name="mint-mobile-logo.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/BPWiQe3vKGWbwqwX3mVeqG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="300" height="300" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Mint Mobile New Customer Offer: </strong><a href="https://www.mintmobile.com/" data-dimension112="b5255bfa-1959-41dc-93b5-d0ccfc63897f" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Mint Mobile New Customer Offer: Three months of Unlimited for $15/month, now includes six months of Paramount Plus" data-dimension48="Mint Mobile New Customer Offer: Three months of Unlimited for $15/month, now includes six months of Paramount Plus"><strong>Three months of Unlimited for $15/month, now includes six months of Paramount Plus</strong></a></p>
<p>Mint Mobile already won the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/carriers/best-mvno-deals-of-month-year-is-it-time-to-switch">best MVNO deal</a> of the month award when they started dropping the prices on ALL of their three-month plans to only $15 per month for new customers, but now they're sweetening the deal by throwing in six free months of Paramount Plus as well. It's clear that the T-Mobile acquisition hasn't dampened Mint's generous spirit quite yet. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="b5255bfa-1959-41dc-93b5-d0ccfc63897f" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Mint Mobile New Customer Offer: Three months of Unlimited for $15/month, now includes six months of Paramount Plus" data-dimension48="Mint Mobile New Customer Offer: Three months of Unlimited for $15/month, now includes six months of Paramount Plus">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>Now owned by T-Mobile, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/mint-mobile-review">Mint Mobile</a> is a popular MVNO that offers great 5G coverage that you purchase in 3, 6, or 12-month increments of time. This "buy in bulk" approach typically means that you&apos;re saving some serious cash on your phone bill, while the many <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/mint-mobile-deals-promo-codes">Mint Mobile deals</a> that are available could take these savings even further. </p><p>The plan options range from 5GB per month to Unlimited, and all plans come with unlimited talk and text, free calls to Mexico and Canada, a mobile hotspot, and more. New customers who sign up during the promotional period will only pay $15 per month for the first three months ($45 upfront) regardless of the plan they select, and thanks to this new offer, they&apos;ll also get six months of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/paramount-plus-review">Paramount Plus</a> at no cost whatsoever. </p>
<h2 id="need-a-new-phone-too-2">Need a new phone too?</h2>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="dcc677de-4d37-4f14-86f4-db3321fefeba" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 8 Pro 128GB: $999" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 8 Pro 128GB: $999" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-8-pro/4367961/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="ZDGZ5sQDctV2JzkVHKp9Ao" name="google-pixel-8-pro-bg-crop.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZDGZ5sQDctV2JzkVHKp9Ao.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Google Pixel 8 Pro 128GB: </strong><a href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-8-pro/4367961/" data-dimension112="dcc677de-4d37-4f14-86f4-db3321fefeba" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 8 Pro 128GB: $999" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 8 Pro 128GB: $999"><del>$999</del> <strong>$559, plus six months FREE with any six-month data plan at Mint Mobile</strong></a></p>
<p>Not one to rest on their laurels, Mint Mobile is also offering one of the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-and-pixel-8-pro-deals-of-the-month">best Pixel 8 phone deals</a> on the web today. Purchase the Google Pixel 8 Pro on Mint's website alongside any six month plan and the carrier will hook you up with a $440 discount AND six additional months of service for 100% free. </p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-pro-review">Pixel 8 Pro</a> is one of our favorite flagships on the Android sea, pairing the efficiency of Google's proprietary Tensor G3 chip with cutting-edge AI features and some of the best cameras found on any smartphone to date. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-8-pro/4367961/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="dcc677de-4d37-4f14-86f4-db3321fefeba" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 8 Pro 128GB: $999" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 8 Pro 128GB: $999">View Deal</a></p></div>
<ul><li><strong>MVNO deals: </strong><a href="https://www.mintmobile.com/"><u><strong>Mint Mobile</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.visible.com/plans/"><u><strong>Visible</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://deals.boostmobile.com/mypromo/trial-mybm"><u><strong>Boost</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://tello.com/buy/custom_plans"><u><strong>Tello</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.cricketwireless.com/cell-phone-plans"><u><strong>Cricket</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/carriers/another-new-mint-mobile-deal-just-dropped-get-some-free-streaming-with-your-dirt-cheap-wireless</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Join Mint Mobile with ANY of their data plans and only pay $15 per month for three months. They'll also give you six months of Paramount Plus streaming, just for kicks. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">HCSKMA8B5Xa3RrSMM7FETB</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mrx7azXQDRtj7SPZuix24B.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 21:53:18 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Carriers]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mrx7azXQDRtj7SPZuix24B.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A Google Pixel 7a with Mint Mobile&#039;s home page on the screen placed among some house plants]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A Google Pixel 7a with Mint Mobile&#039;s home page on the screen placed among some house plants]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Is the Google Pixel 8a waterproof? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <section class="article__schema-question"><h3>Is the Google Pixel 8a waterproof?</h3><article class="article__schema-answer"><p><strong>Best answer:</strong> Yes, the Google Pixel 8a is waterproof, but there are some limitations. It has an IP67 rating, which means that it's protected against temporary immersion in water and is dust-tight. The Pixel can only be submerged up to a meter for a total of 30 minutes in fresh water.</p></article></section>
<h2 id="wait-this-is-what-you-need-to-know-before-exposing-your-pixel-to-water-2">Wait! This is what you need to know before exposing your Pixel to water</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:958px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.26%;"><img id="VroGKCafXrhWXyoLXZExhW" name="Google-Pixel-8a-water-drops-wet-lifestyle.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 8a in Aloe covered in water droplets" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VroGKCafXrhWXyoLXZExhW.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="958" height="539" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Since the Google Pixel 8a is not waterproof for hours on end, it&apos;s best to use a waterproof <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/best-google-pixel-8a-cases">Pixel 8a case</a> to protect it from water damage if you take it for a swim longer than 30 minutes. But if you don&apos;t have a case yet, be cautious of how much water lands on your Pixel since an IP67 rating (given by the International Electrotechnical Commission) will protect it if caught in light rain or you splash water from the faucet on it. However, the protection rating doesn&apos;t include corrosive liquids such as sugary or soft drinks. If you drop in the snow or the toilet, your phone should be fine.</p><p>Never take your <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/should-you-buy-pixel-8a">Pixel 8a</a> when showering with hot water, and try to avoid highly chlorinated pools or seawater since the IP rating was conducted in a lab and done with fresh water. But if you want to snap a quick picture underwater while swimming, it should be fine. The Pixel 8a has the same protection as its predecessor, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-7a-review">Pixel 7a</a>, but with other apparent upgrades in the specification list.</p><p>The rating always consists of two numbers, the first referring to protection against solids and the second to liquids. The lowest rating for each one is a zero, which indicates no protection, and an X indicates the manufacturer has not provided a rating. But remember that the IP rating can degrade over time as your phone is exposed to impacts, wear and tear, and various temperature changes.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1067px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="vXQfgQcni7RQ8esY58Vk9k" name="google-pixel-8a-colors-lifestyle.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 8a all colors" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vXQfgQcni7RQ8esY58Vk9k.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1067" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Pixel 8a is only a hair short of its bigger sibling in terms of protection, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-pro-review">Pixel 8 Pro</a>, which has an IP68 rating and high protection against dust and water. While the IP68 rating is a high one, it doesn&apos;t make the device waterproof for long periods of submersion, but it allows it to be submerged more than a meter and is more protected against the effects of continuous immersion in water.</p><p>The Pixel 8a&apos;s IP rating doesn&apos;t mean it will perform well in high-moisture environments. There is no similarity between humidity tolerance and IP rating, so if you&apos;re going to be in an area with a high humidity level, it would be best to use a waterproof case to be on the safe side. With an IP rating, there is no confusion as to how much water the device can withstand, and it is more precise than words such as water-resistant and waterproof.</p><p>The Pixel 8a may not have the same rating as the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-review">Pixel 8</a> or 8 Pro, but it has various similar specifications, especially when compared to its smaller flagship sibling. For example, both Pixels have a 120Hz refresh rate and a 2400 x 1080 resolution. Both phones reach 1,400 nits for HDR or 2,000 nits for peak brightness, and they share the same 1-million-to-1 contrast ratio along with 16 million colors. Another great addition to the Pixel 8a is the Tensor G3 chipset and the fact that it gets seven years of system updates up to Android 21.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="373e662a-6ed4-475b-8732-7d04dafd6299">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rkG8MMYwEzPpdaYB6rQ5y9.jpg' alt='Google Pixel 8a in Bay'></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 8a</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Affordable Pixel</strong></em></p>
<p>It might not have the same specs as its big brother, but it gets seven years of system updates and shares the same display specifications. Get a respectable phone at a decent price and enjoy the fun AI feature it comes with.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/is-the-pixel-8a-waterproof</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Is the Google Pixel 8a waterproof? We'll provide easy-to-understand answers so you know how much water your phone can resist. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">5hyLNhKAVar3hS2PonvDJW</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uUonzEjAggGMsaeQsivaN9.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 20:10:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ judysanhz30@gmail.com (Judy Sanhz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uUonzEjAggGMsaeQsivaN9.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Pixel 8a with drops of water on it]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Pixel 8a with drops of water on it]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung allegedly begins Android 15-based One UI 7 testing on Galaxy S24 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A recent discovery suggests that Samsung has started testing its One UI 7 software skin atop Google's Android 15.</li><li>It seems Samsung has started testing the upcoming software on the Galaxy S24 Ultra in Europe.</li><li>Google's latest Android 15 Beta 1.2 continued to solve crushing problems its enrolled testers have faced, though there are more under the hood that need fixing.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>It seems that Samsung is beginning to put together the pieces behind its upcoming One UI 7 software, based on Google&apos;s Android 15.</p><p>According to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.sammobile.com/news/galaxy-s24-ultra-one-ui-7-0-development-started-internally-firmware/">SamMobile</a>, Samsung may have started internally testing One UI 7 as a new firmware build, version S928BXXU2BXE2, was spotted on its servers. The company has allegedly paired this new version with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review">Galaxy S24 Ultra</a> in Europe. It was stated that what&apos;s most important with the build is the apparent swap at the end from "<strong>A</strong>..." to "<strong>B</strong>..."</p><p>Samsung&apos;s past suggests that this single character change typically indicates the beginning of a new major OS. We&apos;ll have to wait and see.</p><p>Other phones, such as the Galaxy S24 and S24 Plus, have yet to begin testing the supposed One UI 7 software. It should start sometime soon, as the publication notes Samsung usually begins development shortly after Google&apos;s first beta for the next Android software.</p><p>Similarly, a beta program for the upcoming Android 15-based software should start at some point as we&apos;re coming up on the summer months.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:654px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:91.74%;"><img id="aPJZTViWXJre6r8LJomVRc" name="samsung-one-ui-7-testing-spotted.jpg" alt="Evidence of a new firmware on Samsung's servers, which could indicate One UI 7." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/aPJZTViWXJre6r8LJomVRc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="654" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: SamMobile)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>One UI 7 murmurings have started ramping up as a Samsung Good Lock developer spilled that the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-phones-may-finally-get-a-long-awaited-app-drawer-revamp">sideways app drawer</a> could disappear. This update could lessen its reliance on the Home Up module which, currently, displays all of a user&apos;s apps on pages that scroll horizontally.</p><p>More specifically, the representative stated the team is looking into implementing a "vertical list function" that the OS can utilize without relying on Good Lock.</p><p>Android 15&apos;s development is continuing as expected with Google recently <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-beta-1-2">rolling out Beta 1.2</a> toward the end of April. This smaller, iterative update was to build on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-beta-1-1">Beta 1.1</a> problems the company aimed to fix. App freezing, odd battery drain issues, crashes, and more were on the docket. While it seems as though Google has made its current test build for Android 15 more stable, there are still problems enrolled users have reported that haven&apos;t been solved.</p><p>We&apos;ve crossed into May, which means we should be moving into Android 15 Beta 2 at any point now. According to Google&apos;s timeline, it plans to reach "Platform Stability" by June before rolling out its stable Android 15 software anywhere from August and beyond.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1184px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:22.80%;"><img id="yLhhiQ75n3jd8vyVtKKiC7" name="Android-15-release-timeline.jpg" alt="The Android 15 preview and beta release timeline" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yLhhiQ75n3jd8vyVtKKiC7.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1184" height="270" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<ul><li> <strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-one-ui-7-early-testing-spotted</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ New firmware on Samsung's servers could point toward its early testing of One UI 7. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">e7eaeX8FiGAquDNeUguT4</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QqEiJpvBnkhzVMDbGydkNi.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 19:28:54 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QqEiJpvBnkhzVMDbGydkNi.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Hands-on with the smaller Samsung Galaxy S24]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Hands-on with the smaller Samsung Galaxy S24]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>