<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 13:33:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ This solid-state micro speaker aims to bring huge sound upgrades to earbuds, XR glasses, and smartwatches ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>There&apos;s no shortage of innovation in the audio industry, and one particular driver of progress is the introduction of solid-state audio tech. Most earbuds use regular audio drivers with a magnetic coil to generate sound, but the idea with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/earbuds-with-solid-state-audio-drivers-are-about-to-go-mainstream">silicon-based alternatives</a> is that they use a piezoelectric drive in conjunction with ultra-thin membranes to make sound, and that&apos;s just inherently cool.</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Hardwired</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="5u6gVPowTCuSQ8NJeoktj7" name="lloyd-hardwired.png" caption="" alt="Android Central's LLoyd with a bionic eye" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5u6gVPowTCuSQ8NJeoktj7.png" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">In <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/hardwired">Hardwired</a>, AC Senior Editor Harish Jonnalagadda delves into all things hardware, including phones, audio products, storage servers, and routers.</p></div></div>
<p>The brand making these drivers is xMEMS, and it just rolled out its latest product: the Sycamore. While its earlier Cypress driver is used in several earbuds — including the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/creative-aurvana-ace-2-review">Creative Aurvana Ace 2</a> — and is designed for in-ear options, the Sycamore is aimed at the open-ear category instead, and is coming to earbuds, XR glasses, and smartwatches.</p><p>The timing of the launch is interesting, because there has been a steady increase in open-ear products, with Nothing and Bose catering to this niche. With the Sycamore, xMEMS is leveraging its “sound from ultrasound” design, and with the module coming in at just 1.13mm and weighing 150mg, it is three times thinner than a regular driver and one-seventh the size.</p><p>Ahead of the launch, I had an email interaction with Mike Housholder, VP Marketing and Business Development at xMEMS Labs, to understand how the Sycamore is different to the Cypress. Housholder noted that the new driver "represents the maturation of our ultrasonic transducer technology," and that changes to the "design and efficiency of the MEMS architecture" has allowed it to go from an in-ear design to open-air.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="rurtAr3WQXdJT5nVnPJTNe" name="xmems-2.jpg" alt="xMEMS Sycamore driver highlighted in renders" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rurtAr3WQXdJT5nVnPJTNe.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: xMEMS)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Sound quality is a key metric in micro speakers, and I was interested in learning about how something as small as the Sycamore is able to produce anywhere close to the same level of sound as a regular dynamic driver. "One of the key characteristics of our ultrasonic, modulated air pulse generation technology is that it exhibits a 1st-order low frequency degradation to provide a robust low frequency response as compared to conventional dynamic drive speakers which typically exhibit a 2nd-order (more steep) low frequency degradation," said Housholder.</p><p>As such, the brand is touting a similar mid-bass performance as regular drivers, with as much as 11dB headroom in the sub-bass extension. The driver comes with IP58 ingress protection, making it a decent choice for use in active earbuds.</p><p>Another issue that&apos;s resolved with the Sycamore is designing the shell of the earbuds. With regular audio drivers, brands focus on the design and materials of the shell, but Housholder noted that as MEMS speakers are not as prone to back volume due to the "stiff and rigid silicon diaphragm," this isn&apos;t as big a consideration. That&apos;s a big deal for an audio manufacturer, and with the driver itself not taking up anywhere as much room, it should free up additional space for a larger battery or result in buds that are smaller.</p><p>So when will we get to see products with the new driver? Housholder noted that xMEMS will showcase prototypes at CES 2025, with mass production starting in Q4 2025 and initial consumer products debuting in 2026. Considering the number of design wins the brand managed with its earlier drivers, it shouldn&apos;t have many problems with the Sycamore, particularly given that it can be used with XR glasses and smartwatches in addition to earbuds.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/this-solid-state-micro-speaker-aims-to-bring-huge-sound-upgrades-to-earbuds-xr-glasses-and-smartwatches</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Sycamore is an all-silicon solid-state audio driver made by xMEMS, and it is designed to be used with open-ear products, including earbuds, XR glasses, and smartwatches.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">GhY9DjqY8prdcu5hSeToo8</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XueFgzteKFeR8yAtwHw2De.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 11:09:11 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XueFgzteKFeR8yAtwHw2De.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[xMEMS]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[xMEMS Sycamore driver highlighted in renders]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[xMEMS Sycamore driver highlighted in renders]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Instagram is giving you a reset button for your feed recommendation ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Instagram is testing a new feature that lets you reset content recommendations on the platform.</li><li>Users can start by hitting the reset button, which gives them a fresh start in watching reels and feeds and exploring tabs on Instagram.</li><li>The feature is primarily aimed at teens, as they are more prone to changing their passions and interests as they mature.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>If you are hooked on content on Instagram, like its reels or interesting posts, that is because of the suggestions the social media platform provides by learning what you've liked or prefer to view the most. While there was no way to erase your recommendations before, Meta is now bringing a new button, which might likely provide a fresh start for your recommendations on Instagram.</p><p>Meta <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://about.fb.com/news/2024/11/introducing-recommendations-reset-instagram">has announced</a> that Instagram is currently testing a new feature that allows users to reset recommendations, allowing them to clear the previous ones and start fresh. These recommendation-based content users generally see on Instagram's Explore, Reels, and Feed sections. Clearing them is seemingly easy with just a couple of taps.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:689px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:87.08%;"><img id="AmitAkvod3BYhngBC6XvU7" name="instagram-reset-recommendations" alt="Instagram Reset Recommendations" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AmitAkvod3BYhngBC6XvU7.webp" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="689" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Instagram)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Instagram notes in the announcement post that the emphasis of incorporating this new feature is primarily aimed at Teens. The platform wants to "give teens new ways to shape their Instagram experience" so that they can find their passions and interests as they evolve. Resetting occasionally might allow the app to learn those parameters and recommend new ones as they move forward.</p><p>Once people hit the new reset recommendations button, the app will start personalizing recommendations again to showcase relevant content based on their reactions and the accounts they often interact with.</p><p>During the resetting process, consumers are also allowed to check who they are following and can unfollow them right away if they are not interested in the respective accounts they're following.</p>
<p>After hitting reset, users can go to the explore tab again and look for content. If they like any new content, they can look for a three-dot menu and hit "Interested." Similarly, if the showcased content doesn't appease them, they can hit "Not Interested."</p><p>Instagram notes both these suggestions and further helps the social media app showcase preferred content in the future. If there are too many to deal with, the new reset button certainly comes in handy.</p><p>Although Instagram indicates that the new feature is currently in the testing phase, it will eventually roll out globally, which sounds promising.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/instagram-bringing-recommendations-reset-button</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Instagram tries to engage you in scrolling through numerous reels or feeds through its recommendations based on your interests, which can now be fully reset. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">LACpppH2j4dwf9ZR33UqkH</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8ZKDJUHPgucMghz5HGKrQZ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 10:20:21 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8ZKDJUHPgucMghz5HGKrQZ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Instagram logo on a smartphone lying flat on a table]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Instagram logo on a smartphone lying flat on a table]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ You have no reason to install the Android 16 preview ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The first of many early versions of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16">Android 16</a> is here, and almost every person reading this should shrug and not care about it. OK, maybe that's harsh, but really, because there is nothing there for you, and even Google will tell you that it's going to be a mess.</p><p>Software like this is important. Some people will need to get ready in any way they can for the coming <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16-developer-preview-1-is-here-with-new-features-and-a-snappier-release-timeline">API changes</a> and any new ones for things like user health data. Other people need to do everything they can to try and break things and then report their findings in minute detail to the Android team at Google. The rest of us should just look and not touch. You already know if you're a person who needs to install this.</p>

<p>You've heard all this before. Every time Google throws out some pre-beta test software that nobody should install, people like me will remind you that it's not worth it. Trust me, I'll have to install it eventually and wish I didn't need to. It's just one of the things I have to do to make a living because <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G44xTr8D_bw">my music career</a> never took off.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4480px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="MLCKfeSHeDZWCUwT9QjhHA" name="Android-16-Pixel9PF" alt="The logo for Android 16 on a Pixel 9 Pro Fold." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MLCKfeSHeDZWCUwT9QjhHA.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4480" height="2520" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Brady Snyder / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Another way to look at it is to ask yourself why you would even want to install this. There are no new features for you to see, and even if there are, they may not work properly. Sure, you might be able to tap things a bunch of times and see a new logo, but you could also just download a screenshot and look at it on your phone for the same result. The announced features are not there, and any underpinnings in place to be ready for them only make the system unstable right now.</p>
<p>Android 16 could turn out to be the best version of Android ever. Thanks to more phones getting supported longer, you'll probably get a chance to use it, too. When it's ready and awesome you should install it the first chance you get.</p><p>Right now, though, Android 16 sucks. It's just like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a>, with more bugs and less stability. Let Google keep it in the kitchen and work on the recipe a little longer, and you'll be happier.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1418px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:23.06%;"><img id="bWFzR6evEiAM759kFoNVT8" name="Android-16-Platform-Stability-Schedule" alt="Android 16 platform stability schedule." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bWFzR6evEiAM759kFoNVT8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1418" height="327" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="bfda14cd-90ba-4973-9c4e-b970ea91cc89">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/B22jKfVHKzg8nbRGgwTHSP.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro official render - Rose Quartz - Front and Back"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 Pro</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Get Android 16 first</strong></em></p><p>The Pixel series is the only way to get your hands on Android 16 before anyone else, whether you're a developer testing apps or a regular Joe waiting for the stable release in 2025.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/you-have-no-reason-to-install-the-android-16-preview</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Developer previews are meant for developers. Let someone else break their phone. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">mdKSVZPxTm58i8ovdyiq8</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ET6VQxPCmiVobyxmeWrkV.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ET6VQxPCmiVobyxmeWrkV.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android 16 developer preview]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android 16 developer preview]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Android 16 has a new trick to put a damper on annoying app pings ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Android 16’s first developer preview introduces "Notification Cooldown," which softens the volume of repetitive app alerts.</li><li>The feature reduces alert volume if an app sends multiple notifications in a short span.</li><li>With it on, alerts will pop up quietly in the notification shade instead of blaring pings, lasting up to two minutes.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Android 16’s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16-developer-preview-1-is-here-with-new-features-and-a-snappier-release-timeline">first developer preview</a> has introduced a new feature that softens the volume of back-to-back alerts from the same app.</p><p>Mishaal Rahman from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/android-16-notification-cooldown-3501276/" target="_blank">Android Authority</a> has spotted a nifty update coming to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16">Android 16</a>’s notifications. Called "notification cooldown," this feature cuts alert volume if an app keeps spamming you with notifications in a short time. The goal is to cut down on distractions while keeping important notifications front and center.</p><p>With notification cooldown on, your device volume will drop and alerts will be toned down for up to two minutes if an app sends a bunch of notifications in quick succession. You’ll still see them, but they’ll pop up quietly in the notification shade instead of blasting through with a loud ping.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:485px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:222.68%;"><img id="9bAqhCQkXx3WgxUsq7Dn7j" name="Android-16-notification-cooldown" alt="notification cooldown toggle in Android 16 DP1" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9bAqhCQkXx3WgxUsq7Dn7j.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="485" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:485px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:222.68%;"><img id="gGq2mpBvMvEagPk2sfHr5j" name="Android-16-notification-cooldown" alt="notification cooldown toggle in Android 16 DP1" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gGq2mpBvMvEagPk2sfHr5j.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="485" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>You can find notification cooldown under <strong>Settings </strong>> <strong>Notifications </strong>> <strong>Notification cooldown</strong>. Keep in mind, though, that this feature won’t silence high-priority alerts, calls, or alarms.</p><p>Of course, notifications are a given, but when they come in nonstop, it can be super annoying. So, this new feature should tame those pesky repeating app alerts.</p><p>Notification cooldown <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-notification-cooldown">first showed up in Android 15 Developer Preview 1</a>, but Google kept it under wraps in the first public beta and didn’t bring it back for the stable release, as Rahman points out.</p><p>Early worries about the feature being scrapped were eased when it resurfaced in Android 15 QPR1 Beta 2. This suggests that Google is likely setting the stage for a wider rollout across <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android devices</a> by Q2 2025 when stable Android 16 rolls out.</p><p>While notification cooldown is a big win for managing alerts, it doesn’t tackle persistent vibrations just yet.</p><p>Nevertheless, this feature is a great addition for Android users. By cutting down on the flood of alerts, it helps users stay focused and put important notifications front and center.</p>
<hr>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="23d64f1b-8d59-4dca-973d-4f10df37e493">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/tnQGJNQVqF2XVQV4KfMbN8.jpg' alt="google pixel 9 square render"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>The Google Pixel 9 packs a ton of value for your money. It's basically the same as the higher-end Pro and Pro XL models, making it one of the best deals out there right now.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16-has-a-new-trick-to-put-a-damper-on-annoying-app-pings</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Android 16's notification timeout will bring some much-needed peace and quiet. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">DFXyeftcYyCdBp6YLbjLQf</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MLCKfeSHeDZWCUwT9QjhHA.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 02:37:01 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MLCKfeSHeDZWCUwT9QjhHA.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Brady Snyder / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The logo for Android 16 on a Pixel 9 Pro Fold. ]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The logo for Android 16 on a Pixel 9 Pro Fold. ]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Android could steal a crucial iOS 18 feature that helps curb motion sickness ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Code snippets discovered in Google Play Services indicates Google could be copying an iOS 18 accessibility feature.</li><li>The feature, called Motion Cues, tries to avert motion sickness by adding visual cues to the screen that show which direction a vehicle is moving.</li><li>Aside from the <strong>Motion Cues </strong>name, we don't know what this tool might entail, or when (and if) it will release.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google may be eying an Android accessibility feature that aims to limit the effect of motion sickness while using a smartphone or tablet in the car. A few code snippets relating to an unannounced <strong>Motion Cues</strong> feature were discovered in an APK teardown by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/google-play-services-motion-cues-apk-teardown-3500830/" target="_blank">Android Authority</a>. While not a lot of information about this rumored feature is available, it's likely similar to <strong>Vehicle Motion Cues</strong>, an accessibility tool in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/everything-ios-18-stole-from-android">iOS 18</a> that adds visual signals to your phone screen.</p><p>Motion sickness is a common problem that can be made worse by using a smartphone or tablet in the car. That's because while looking at your phone screen, your mind and body aren't able to recognize and adjust changes in vehicle movement. As such, Apple's Vehicle Motion Cues add dots to your iPhone's screen that indicate which direction a car is moving. They're clear enough to give your mind an idea of how the car is moving, while being unobtrusive enough to not significantly impede phone use.</p><p>These visual cues, as demonstrated by Apple in the graphic below, are intended to limit the effects of motion sickness. Soon, they could be coming to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a>, too.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:864px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="QsLT2tNNecvp9PzoMEff9" name="Motion-Cues-iOS-18" alt="An example of Motion Cues in iOS 18." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QsLT2tNNecvp9PzoMEff9.gif" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="864" height="864" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apple)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In <strong>version 24.46.30</strong> of the Google Play Services beta, Android Authority spotted multiple code strings related to "motion sickness." Specifically, the code references a feature that is presumably called <strong>Motion Cues</strong>. It's described as being used to "show visual cues to mitigate the motion sickness." In other words, it sounds a lot like Apple's Vehicle Motion Cues in iOS 18.</p>
<pre class="line-numbers language-" language="" ><code><string name="motion_sickness_enabled_key">motion_sickness_enabled</string>
<string name="motion_sickness_settings_activity_label">Motion Cues</string>
<string name="motion_sickness_settings_page_description">Show visual cues to mitigate the motion sickness.</string></code></pre>
<p>The feature isn't active yet, and the code snippets aren't exactly clear on how Google plans to implement these motion cues in Android. However, being that the strings are appearing in the Google Play Services beta and not an Android beta, it's possible that Motion Cues could eventually rollout for multiple Android versions. There's precedent for this, as <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-adds-anti-theft-security-features-like-theft-detection-lock">Android's latest security updates</a> recently rolled out to most devices running Android 10 or higher.</p><p>Still, being that this feature is currently in the development stage, it's impossible to know for sure when (or if) it will release publicly.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-could-steal-a-crucial-ios-18-feature-that-helps-curb-motion-sickness</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ If you get motion sickness while using your phone in the car, this Android leak might be exactly what you need.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">sXseEZuyfBwrtBUzYWqWE9</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YfD6Q5pxGMKDQxCieNMHP6.png" type="image/png" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 22:46:27 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/png" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YfD6Q5pxGMKDQxCieNMHP6.png">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[iOS 18 Lock Screen on iPhone 15 Pro Max and Android 15 logo on Pixel 8 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[iOS 18 Lock Screen on iPhone 15 Pro Max and Android 15 logo on Pixel 8 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ This smart ring is basically an April Fool's joke, but is it ahead of the curve? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Casio announced the CRW-001-1JR, a "smart ring" that's actually a tiny smartwatch for your finger.</li><li>It has a stainless steel design, LCD panel, three buttons, and a functional stopwatch and alarm tech.</li><li>It costs about $128 USD, only ships in Japan in three ring sizes, and has no health functionality.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>To celebrate its 50th anniversary of making big, rugged watches for athletes, Casio is selling an absurd, adorable little smartwatch that fits on your finger but barely qualifies as a "smart ring" <em>or</em> a fitness device.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.casio.com/jp/watches/casio/product.CRW-001-1/">Casio CRW-001-1JR</a>, launching in December 2024 in Japan for ￥19,800 (about $128 USD), isn't like traditional smart rings since it has no health tracking functionality. Instead, the design "combines practicality and playfulness" (via Google Translate) into a 1/10-sized watch with a stainless steel frame, LCD, and three buttons (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.techradar.com/health-fitness/smartwatches/the-new-casio-crw-001-1jr-is-both-a-smart-ring-and-a-smartwatch">Techradar</a>).</p><p>It measures 6.2mm thick and weighs 16g, well above the usual 3mm thickness and 2–5g weight of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/best-smart-rings">best smart rings</a>. Aside from being a conversation starter, the Casio smart ring has programmable alarms to wake you up and a stopwatch function for up to 60 minutes.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1549px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="CpyTqwopjxgVqS3w7vuw9m" name="Casio-smart-ring-press-photo-2" alt="A press photo showing a person wearing the Casio CRW-001-1JR smart ring on their index finger." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CpyTqwopjxgVqS3w7vuw9m.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1549" height="871" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Casio)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Aside from Casio superfans, this quirky novelty tech may not appeal to many people. But the idea of a smart ring that takes after smartwatches is a persistent one, and it's unclear how close smart rings will eventually stray into smartwatch territory with more <em>traditional</em> smarts beyond health.</p>
<h2 id="do-smart-rings-need-to-get-smarter-like-watches-2">Do smart rings need to get "smarter" like watches?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="6rqtLGT5c8GDWFRrfMqvyT" name="Oura-Ring-4-review-05.jpg" alt="The Oura Ring 4 next to the Pixel Watch 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6rqtLGT5c8GDWFRrfMqvyT.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4240" height="2385" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Most smart rings are meant to be invisible; unless you look at the companion app on your phone, you wouldn't even know if it's working. But a few rings specifically take after smartwatches — if not to the extent of the Casio smart ring.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-ring-review">Samsung Galaxy Ring</a> supports gesture control shortcuts for phone connectivity, just as smartwatches have gesture tricks like the double-tap.</p><p>The Circular Ring has a haptic motor for gently waking you up, signaling notifications or medication reminders, and guiding you during meditation. The original Pro had a button to end haptic feedback, while the newer Circular Slim has a reactive touch surface on the logo.</p><p>Early smart ring prototypes like the Smarty Ring and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/motiv-ring-review">Motiv Ring</a> had outer displays or LED indicators, following in line with smartwatches at the time. Motiv, for instance, would let you twist the ring to trigger a gesture and then light up the LED if it was successful. A green light signaled a 100% charge, a blue light meant data syncing, and so on.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1260px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:75.00%;"><img id="z9q2oQRQLcYRCEMqgqRUkU" name="motiv-ring-hero.jpg" alt="The black Motiv Ring worn on a man's ring finger" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/z9q2oQRQLcYRCEMqgqRUkU.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1260" height="945" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="caption-text">The Motiv Ring with its subtle LED indicator </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Russell Holly / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>If you look into the Wild West of smart ring Indiegogo campaigns today, several of them have some kind of touch strip or multi-color LED indicator. Though there's no guarantee any of them will successfully launch, and they have other ambitious promises like blood pressure tracking, people still spend millions on these prototypes, hoping for the best.</p><p>Right now, successful and established smart rings like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oura-ring-4-review">Oura Ring 4</a> have designs centered on their lightness and traditional style. Almost no one wants an LED strip or bulky design that calls attention to the ring's techy nature; they want subtlety.</p><p>But I wonder — as smart rings continue to flood the market offering the same health data — if  we'll see more phone-ring integration to make rings more of a watch replacement for people who wear basic luxury watches instead of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch">Android smartwatches</a> or Apple Watches.</p><p>Basically, I'm curious if future smart rings will take the same approach as hybrid watches, with a tiny strip that looks "normal" but can occasionally light up with a tiny notification, letting you know whether or not to take your phone out of your pocket.</p><p>But until smart rings can pull that off more subtly than Casio's unintentionally hilarious design, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/smart-rings-vs-smartwatches-key-differences">smart rings and smartwatches</a> should probably stay in their own lanes.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="c94cea16-5a1a-4bc3-b396-66dceb0b456e">
            <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/oura-ring-4-smart-ring-size-before-you-buy-with-oura-ring-4-sizing-kit-size-13-silver/6595520.p?skuId=6595520" data-model-name="Oura Ring 4"><div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nG8MVq445oJMCacip4R7FR.jpg' alt="The Oura RIng 4 in silver"></p></div></a>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Oura Ring 4</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>No gimmicks required</strong></em></p><p>The Oura Ring 4 doesn't have an eye-catching design like the Casio Smart Ring, and that's for the best. Instead, it has a lightweight and slim design, with all the smarts like heart rate, SpO2, stress, sleep, and daily readiness clustered along the <em>inside</em> of the smart ring. This attractive titanium ring ships in most ring sizes and a variety of finishes, from Brushed Silver and Gold to Stealth and Rose Gold.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/casio-smart-ring-gimmicky-design-may-show-future-smart-rings-sort-of</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ This tiny smartwatch/ smart ring hybrid isn't going to appeal to most people, but there is a definite niche market for smart rings with working displays. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">XvejDEViMMVzvPqKVqRDbY</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WpFQxZzWZ4sPi8pmBrniRm.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 21:16:31 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WpFQxZzWZ4sPi8pmBrniRm.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Casio]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A press photo showing a person wearing the Casio CRW-001-1JR smart ring on their index finger.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A press photo showing a person wearing the Casio CRW-001-1JR smart ring on their index finger.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google TV is asking users if homescreen ads are a vibe or a buzzkill ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google TV may be aware users might be getting tired of ads, so it's running a survey asking users if the home screen ads are too much.</li><li>The survey, popping up on Onn 4K Boxes, gets users to rate if they "strongly agree" or "strongly disagree" with the ads.</li><li>While the survey could cut back on ads, it might also justify adding more, especially with Google's ad-driven revenue.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google TV recently sent out a survey to some users, stirring up concerns by asking how they feel about the number of ads popping up on the homescreen.</p><p>9to5Google spotted a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AndroidTV/comments/1gtzc27/got_this_survey_on_my_onn_4k_google_is_asking_if/" target="_blank">Reddit post</a> showing Google asking some <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/google-tv">Google TV</a> users in the U.S. what they think about the home screen ads—but just those, nothing else.</p><p>The survey shows up in the bottom-right of an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/walmart-onn-google-tv-4k-pro-review">Onn 4K Box</a>, asking if the home screen ads on Google TV are a deal or a drag. The options range from “Strongly Agree” to “Strongly Disagree.”</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3653px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:63.37%;"><img id="vtPchCcEVo4WRuHWic8iV6" name="Google-TV-survey" alt="a survey on Google TV asking users about their thoughts on the frequency of homescreen ads" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vtPchCcEVo4WRuHWic8iV6.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="3653" height="2315" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: lament / Reddit)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The survey indicates that Google knows people might be getting fed up with all the ads on Google TV. It’s just a sign that ads are pretty much a permanent part of the digital scene now.</p><p>Google’s push for more ads on Google TV is ruffling some feathers. While the survey might lead to fewer ads, it could just as easily be a way to back up adding even more. And with Google’s ad money machine running strong, don’t count on ads disappearing anytime soon.</p><p>It’s a bummer to watch the once ad-free digital world fill up with ads. Many of our <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-services-free-trial-deals">favorite streaming services</a> were once all about ditching traditional TV, but have now jumped on the ad-revenue bandwagon too.</p><p>Google TV, once all about personal recommendations, has turned into an ad-heavy platform, now bombarded with autoplay video ads. This shift from chill suggestions to in-your-face commercialization is part of a bigger trend where entertainment and ads are blending together more than ever.</p><p>Google is not the only one leaning into on-device ads for cash. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/amazon-prime-video-interactive-ads">Amazon has been rolling out new features</a> with the same idea, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/roku-ceo-video-ads-home-screen-confirmed">Roku has found ways to make money by running ads</a> during gameplay breaks.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/google-tv-is-asking-users-if-homescreen-ads-are-a-vibe-or-a-buzzkill</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google TV is running a survey asking users if its homescreen ads are over the top. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">H7FBidJZU73cF66DZykX76</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oXcrZwfzk2M2rzeMv2kqtQ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 20:41:12 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Streaming &amp; TV]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oXcrZwfzk2M2rzeMv2kqtQ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google TV Streamer Free Live TV]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google TV Streamer Free Live TV]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ ASUS ROG Phone 9 is a speedster with AI gaming features and the 8 Elite ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>ASUS launched its ROG Phone 9 series today and the duo features Qualcomm's Snapdragon 8 Elite SoC.</li><li>Its design remains close to the Phone 8 series, with the unique dot matrix rear panel and a new cooling accessory, the Chill Case.</li><li>The ROG Phone 9 Pro will be available for $1,199 while the base model starts at $999.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>The next generation of gaming phones is here from ASUS as its latest flagship duo debuts.</p><p>As ASUS launches the ROG Phone 9 series, it kicks things off by highlighting the Pro model. Appearance-wise, the device remains similar to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/asus-rog-phone-8-pro-review">Phone 8 Pro</a>. Users will find a 6.7-inch FHD+ panel with up to 165Hz refresh rate. However, ASUS says users can push its fresh rate even further, up to 185Hz, through the "Game Genie." Protecting the Phone 9 Pro's display is Corning's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/corning-gorilla-glass-victus-2">Gorilla Glass Victus 2</a>.</p><p>The back of the device sees more of the same as ASUS continues to feature AniMe Vision. The company revealed the change from its LED lighting with the 8 Pro. For a second time, users are treated to a dot matrix on its rear panel, which acts like a secondary screen. ASUS states this matrix offers 648 programmable mini-LEDs for animations and interactions.</p><p>ASUS detailed the continuation of the phone's squarish triple camera array. The company states the Phone 9 Pro features a 50MP Lytia 700 Sony sensor with lossless 2x zoom and OIS (optical image stabilization). The main camera is joined by a 13MP ultrawide lens and a 32MP telephoto sensor.</p><p>The front selfie camera enters at 32MP.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:861px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:61.56%;"><img id="pEjb9FKcHkUtjFecj8SPxZ" name="asus-rog-phone-9-model-example" alt="The ASUS ROG Phone 9." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pEjb9FKcHkUtjFecj8SPxZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="861" height="530" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: ASUS)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>At the heart of the ROG Phone 9 Pro are those AI veins alongside Qualcomm's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-announces-snapdragon-8-elite-chip">Snapdragon 8 Elite</a> and Android 15. The SoC provides the device with a 4.30GHz, Octa-core processor alongside the Adreno 830 GPU. For AI, ASUS states the Phone 9 Pro features its X Sense, X Capture, and AI Grabber. These three tools combined can assist gamers with recording highlights while gaming, finding tips, and "tracking enemy spawns."</p><p>The device features even more on-device AI for daily tasks, such as AI Call Translator, Transcript, Wallpaper, Noise Cancellation, and "Sematic Search."</p><p>With such power, ASUS highlights the Phone 9 Pro's cooling systems in place. The device reportedly uses a graphite sheet to increase heat dissipation by roughly 57%. This is said to have improved the phone's cooling abilities by ~12%. However, users can opt to purchase additional cooling accessories like the AeroActive Cooler X Pro or the new ROG Chill Case.</p><p>Those interested can check out Android Central's full review of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/asus-rog-phone-9-pro-review">ROG Phone 9 Pro</a>, including how it fairs performance and battery-wise.</p><p>The ROG Phone 9 Pro will be available soon for $1,199 in white and Phantom Black.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1220px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:49.18%;"><img id="HQqCxsaYpCYrvqingXqp8X" name="asus-rog-phone-9-cooling-accessories" alt="The ASUS ROG Phone 9 features two accessories to help keep the device cool when gaming." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HQqCxsaYpCYrvqingXqp8X.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1220" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: ASUS)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The duo of this new gaming phone series is the base ASUS Phone 9. Most of the base model remains close to the Pro variant; however, a major difference is with its cameras. The base Phone 9 features the same 50MP primary lens and a 13MP ultrawide lens. The telephoto sensor is replaced with a 5MP macro camera.</p><p>Users will be able to purchase the ROG Phone 9 in white and Phantom Black for $999 in the U.S.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/asus-rog-phone-9-series-launch</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ ASUS announced the launch of its ROG Phone 9 series. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">5w7TBACmQgxLUWRQuzuwYS</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PWeGaFDqtnY8yzRLfbujNc.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 20:23:26 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PWeGaFDqtnY8yzRLfbujNc.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[ASUS]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The ASUS ROG Phone 9 Pro in Phantom Black.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The ASUS ROG Phone 9 Pro in Phantom Black.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Android 16 Developer Preview 1 supports the Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro — here's why it matters ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-32">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google released the first developer preview of Android 16 today, and surprisingly, the Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro are supported.</li><li>The two phones were guaranteed Android version updates through 2024, so the update to Android 16 wasn't a given.</li><li>While this still doesn't guarantee Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro users will get the stable Android 16 release, it bodes well for the phones' future.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16-developer-preview-1-is-here-with-new-features-and-a-snappier-release-timeline">dropped its first preview of Android 16 today</a>, with a release aimed at developers. If you're a developer and have a Google Pixel phone, you can flash an Android 16 Developer Preview 1 system image to try out the new features now. Surprisingly, the list of supported Pixel phones includes the Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro, as first spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/11/19/pixel-6-android-16-dp1/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a>. Being that the Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro weren't guaranteed the update to Android 16, this is a positive sign that those two phones could get it after all.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-pixel-6">Pixel 6</a> and 6 Pro, released in 2021, are the oldest Pixel phones supporting Android 16 Developer Beta 1. They were officially guaranteed full OS updates through October 2024, plus security updates for an additional two years. That would mean <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a> is the last guaranteed Android version update for the Pixel 6 and 6 Pro. Regardless, it's possible that Google goes above and beyond, shipping Android 16 to those smartphones.</p><p>For now, Pixel 6 users can download the system image for Android 16 Developer Preview 1 <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://dl.google.com/developers/android/baklava/images/ota/oriole_beta-ota-bp21.241018.009-b1a9d5fc.zip" target="_blank">here</a>, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-pixel-6-pro">Pixel 6 Pro</a> users can get their system image <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://dl.google.com/developers/android/baklava/images/ota/raven_beta-ota-bp21.241018.009-1075add0.zip" target="_blank">here</a>. However, since this is still a developer preview, it's not recommended that users install the preview on their main device.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4480px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="MLCKfeSHeDZWCUwT9QjhHA" name="Android-16-Pixel9PF" alt="The logo for Android 16 on a Pixel 9 Pro Fold." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MLCKfeSHeDZWCUwT9QjhHA.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4480" height="2520" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Brady Snyder / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>There's still a long way to go before <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16">Android 16</a> nears platform stability. The support for Android 16 Developer Preview 1 doesn't guarantee that the Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro receive the final release in mid-2025. Google could be testing the waters to see how these older devices perform running the new OS, and make the call of whether they're up to the task later on.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1418px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:23.06%;"><img id="bWFzR6evEiAM759kFoNVT8" name="Android-16-Platform-Stability-Schedule" alt="Android 16 platform stability schedule." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bWFzR6evEiAM759kFoNVT8.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1418" height="327" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>If the Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro continue to receive Android 16 previews and beta releases, especially as they near platform stability, there's a good chance these phones will get the full Android 16 release. However, we're a long way out from that, and Pixel 6 and 6 Pro users should watch for the compatibility future previews and beta releases. For those holding onto a Pixel 6 or Pixel 6 Pro in 2024, this early support is certainly a step in the right direction.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16-developer-preview-1-supports-the-pixel-6-and-pixel-6-pro-heres-why-it-matters</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Despite receiving all its guaranteed OS updates, the Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro are getting Android 16 Developer Preview 1. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">82K2peua9CiM76CWwsZwaY</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/W3SqfhAz5sXRfHd5LoTKtj.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 20:09:01 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/W3SqfhAz5sXRfHd5LoTKtj.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nick Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Pixel 6 Pro lying on the forest ground with its back shown off]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Pixel 6 Pro lying on the forest ground with its back shown off]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Mint Mobile REALLY wants to give you 50% off your phone bill this Black Friday — here are three deals that make it happen ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Your phone bill may not be top of mind when shopping for Black Friday deals, but Mint Mobile is attempting to change all of that with its new lineup of holiday offers. For a limited time, the T-Mobile-owned MVNO carrier is dropping ALL of its data plans to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/deals/"><strong>a mere $15 per month</strong></a> during your first three months of service ($45 upfront). Sign up for the Unlimited plan and you&apos;re looking at a straight 50% discount. </p><p>And that&apos;s not the only Mint Mobile deal launching this holiday season. You can also bundle your purchase of wireless with a great Android phone and get 50% off an entire YEAR of Unlimited. Oh, <em>and </em>the carrier is carving up to 50% off the phones in question, just for kicks. Why is Mint Mobile offering so many half off deals right now? Who knows, but it&apos;s certainly making <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/black-friday-2024">Black Friday 2024</a> more interesting. </p>
<h2 id="mint-is-apparently-dropping-50-off-everything-this-black-friday-2">Mint is apparently dropping 50% OFF everything this Black Friday</h2>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="f2c7bb14-b849-4753-bbf0-b86445ecf45a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="New customers get 50% off the Unlimited plan for three months at Mint Mobile" data-dimension48="New customers get 50% off the Unlimited plan for three months at Mint Mobile" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/plans/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="cNfSyKCaNDAiPxukdZBSfG" name="mnt mobile square render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/cNfSyKCaNDAiPxukdZBSfG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="500" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><em><strong>Option #1</strong></em><strong><br>
</strong><a href="https://www.mintmobile.com/plans/" data-dimension112="f2c7bb14-b849-4753-bbf0-b86445ecf45a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="New customers get 50% off the Unlimited plan for three months at Mint Mobile" data-dimension48="New customers get 50% off the Unlimited plan for three months at Mint Mobile"><strong>New customers get 50% off the Unlimited plan for three months at Mint Mobile</strong></a></p>
<p>Join <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/mint-mobile-review">Mint Mobile</a> on ANY three-month data plan, including the Unlimited plan, and the carrier will drop the price down to a single upfront payment of $45 (which shakes out to $15 per month). All of Mint's plans come with high-speed data on T-Mobile's vast 5G network, plus unlimited talk and text, a free mobile hotspot, and free calls to Mexico and Canada. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/plans/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="f2c7bb14-b849-4753-bbf0-b86445ecf45a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="New customers get 50% off the Unlimited plan for three months at Mint Mobile" data-dimension48="New customers get 50% off the Unlimited plan for three months at Mint Mobile">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="4b7670dc-2f2a-479f-8570-db8bcb786ec9" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9/6810275/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:204px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:121.08%;"><img id="Y8nScb7AAtxK4j2d2EnxjV" name="google-pixel-9-render-obsidian.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Y8nScb7AAtxK4j2d2EnxjV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="204" height="247" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><em><strong>Option #2<br>
</strong></em><strong>Google Pixel 9 128GB: </strong><a href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9/6810275/" data-dimension112="4b7670dc-2f2a-479f-8570-db8bcb786ec9" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799"><del>$799</del> <strong>$399, plus one year of Unlimited for $15 per month</strong></a></p>
<p>If you'd like a new smartphone to go with your new wireless carrier, check out this deal that gives you 50% OFF both the Google Pixel 9 and one year of the Unlimited plan at Mint Mobile. In other words, you could be getting one of our favorite phones AND a full year of service from one of our favorite <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-mvno-carrier">MVNO carriers</a> for a single payment of $579 (or $25 per month using affirm). <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9/6810275/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="4b7670dc-2f2a-479f-8570-db8bcb786ec9" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 128GB: $799">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="2cecb799-17b8-45bf-97ed-6cd101442927" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Switch from AT&amp;T or Verizon and get a second line FREE at Mint Mobile" data-dimension48="Switch from AT&amp;T or Verizon and get a second line FREE at Mint Mobile" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/best-value-wireless/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="cNfSyKCaNDAiPxukdZBSfG" name="mnt mobile square render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/cNfSyKCaNDAiPxukdZBSfG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="500" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><em><strong>Option #3</strong></em><strong><br>
</strong><a href="https://www.mintmobile.com/best-value-wireless/" data-dimension112="2cecb799-17b8-45bf-97ed-6cd101442927" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Switch from AT&amp;T or Verizon and get a second line FREE at Mint Mobile" data-dimension48="Switch from AT&amp;T or Verizon and get a second line FREE at Mint Mobile"><strong>Switch from AT&T or Verizon and get a second line FREE at Mint Mobile</strong></a></p>
<p>Sick of your AT&T or Verizon service? Bring your number to Mint Mobile with the purchase of any three-month data plan and the carrier will give you a second identical line at no added cost. </p>
<p>This deal works in conjunction with the new customer offer detailed above, so you could potentially get two lines of the Unlimited plan and only pay $45 ($15 per month) for three months. It's like BOGO, but better.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/best-value-wireless/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="2cecb799-17b8-45bf-97ed-6cd101442927" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Switch from AT&amp;T or Verizon and get a second line FREE at Mint Mobile" data-dimension48="Switch from AT&amp;T or Verizon and get a second line FREE at Mint Mobile">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Black Friday deals</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Black Friday Google Pixel deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Black Friday Motorola deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024">Black Friday Samsung deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Black Friday OnePlus deals</a></p></div></div>
<p>Mint Mobile is an interesting carrier. Unlike other phone companies that bog you down with confusing contracts and hidden fees, Mint keeps it simple by selling T-Mobile-powered wireless in three, six, and 12-month increments of time. All of Mint&apos;s plans come with high-speed data on T-Mobile&apos;s legendary 5G network, plus you get a free mobile hotspot, calls to Mexico and Canada, and no confusing fine print. The carrier also supports most of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a>, and there are typically loads of great <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/mint-mobile-deals-promo-codes">Mint Mobile deals</a> that can get you into the service for dirt cheap. </p><p>Sure, there are some drawbacks with Mint Mobile, but they are mostly due to the carrier&apos;s simple business structure. Mint has no retail locations, for instance, and you must purchase a minimum of three months of service to join. The Unlimited plan also only gives you 10GB of mobile hotspot data each month, and you lose out on some of the premium international perks and entertainment benefits offered by certain larger carriers. </p><p>With Mint, what you see is what you get, and right now I&apos;m seeing some pretty outstanding Black Friday offers. If you&apos;re on the hunt for a new wireless carrier, that might be enough. </p>
<ul><li><strong>MVNO deals: </strong><a href="https://www.mintmobile.com/"><u><strong>Mint Mobile</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.visible.com/plans/"><u><strong>Visible</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://deals.boostmobile.com/mypromo/trial-mybm"><u><strong>Boost</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://tello.com/buy/custom_plans"><u><strong>Tello</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.cricketwireless.com/cell-phone-plans"><u><strong>Cricket</strong></u></a> </li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/carriers/mint-mobile-really-wants-to-give-you-50-percent-off-your-phone-bill-this-black-friday-here-are-three-deals-that-make-it-happen</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The T-Mobile-owned MVNO Mint Mobile has dropped its lineup of Black Friday deals, and they're no joke if you're looking to switch carriers.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">QH3zMRdnhWWEbt4jL7yHbH</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mrx7azXQDRtj7SPZuix24B.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 19:54:37 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Carriers]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mrx7azXQDRtj7SPZuix24B.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A Google Pixel 7a with Mint Mobile&#039;s home page on the screen placed among some house plants]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A Google Pixel 7a with Mint Mobile&#039;s home page on the screen placed among some house plants]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>