<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 13:05:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Exclusive: Honor is using AI to try to reverse your nearsightedness ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Until last year, I was a person who never needed to wear glasses. But life eventually caught up to me, and a combination of age and the unique strains of modern life caused me to finally visit an optometrist last Spring. While I&apos;m wearing glasses throughout the day now, a new solution from Honor could help reduce that glasses usage over time using, you guessed it, AI.</p><p>AI has been a bit of an annoying buzzword this year, but every so often a new feature breaks through all the noise and presents a solution that&apos;s <em>actually</em> a solution, not just some minor new form of convenience. Honor <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/honors-latest-ai-features-want-to-fight-deep-fake-videos-and-eye-strain">previously announced</a> its new AI defocus tech for the upcoming Honor Magic V3 foldable phone, but I can confirm it&apos;s also on the new Honor MagicPad 2 tablet.</p><p>Myopia is quickly becoming a global issue, as experts predict that it will affect 50% of the world&apos;s population by 2050. Honor is only one brand, and while wider adoption of this kind of technology could slow down or even reverse this negative trend entirely, optometrists I spoke with said this kind of therapy only works best for certain age groups.</p><p>I&apos;ve been testing out Honor&apos;s AI defocus tech on both the MagicPad 2 and Magic V3 for the past few weeks and it&apos;s impressive just how transparently it works. Few companies are taking eye care as seriously as Honor—something that&apos;s particularly personal to me as I&apos;ve been dealing with display-induced headaches due to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-is-pwm-display-flicker-tips-and-tricks">PWM dimming</a>—and the company&apos;s latest devices are a bastion of relief in a world where displays are meant to bedazzle but ultimately hurt us.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="70d86b8c-50dd-4cee-828c-9277ea43625b">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:65.90%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KP86qoLWLE32d99RnrY85.jpg' alt="An official render of the front of the Honor MagicPad 2"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Honor MagicPad 2</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>Packed with a powerful processor, incredible speakers, and a display that's eye-friendly and gorgeous at the same time, the Honor MagicPad 2 is the new tablet you should be looking at.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<h2 id="solutions-to-a-real-problem-2">Solutions to a real problem</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="53o3bRqLo3j6APUDF6cdSh" name="honor-magicpad-2-magic-v3-defocus-01.jpg" alt="Configuring eye care settings on both the Honor MagicPad 2 and the Honor Magic V3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/53o3bRqLo3j6APUDF6cdSh.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Myopia, or nearsightedness, is a problem created when eyes grow longer in order to better focus on objects that are arm&apos;s length or closer to them. In a world where we&apos;re constantly looking at monitors or smartphones for long periods of time throughout the day, it&apos;s not hard to understand why this is a (literal) growing problem.</p><p>But smartphone or monitor usage isn&apos;t going away in the modern age, but instead of just relying on glasses usage to fix the problem, Honor is taking a two-pronged approach. The company just introduced the first nearwork-induced transient myopia-reducing display on both the Honor Magic V3 folding phone and the Honor MagicPad 2 tablet.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>An estimated 50% of the world's population will have myopia (nearsightedness) by 2050 if something isn't done to reverse the trend.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>These special displays use a combination of advanced OLED display technology and AI scene understanding to recreate the effects of Defocus Incorporated Multiple Segments (DIMS) lenses, which have been <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://bjo.bmj.com/content/104/3/363">scientifically proven</a> to slow down the elongation of the eye.</p><p>In a document provided to Android Central, Honor links to several pieces of related research that show how simulated defocus solutions can help improve the eyes of anything from tree shrews to human adults when used regularly over a period of anywhere from 45 minutes to 2 weeks.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2022px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:30.71%;"><img id="3fFqsd49vEtjBzppD6Ebc9" name="bjophthalmol-2020-March-104-3-363-F3.large.jpg" alt="A chart showing the effectiveness of DIMS lenses in slowing progression of childhood myopia" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3fFqsd49vEtjBzppD6Ebc9.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="2022" height="621" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="caption-text">A chart showing the effectiveness of DIMS lenses in slowing progression of childhood myopia </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: British Journal of Ophthalmology)</span></figcaption></figure>
<figure><blockquote><p>Special glasses can help reverse myopia, and Honor's solution aims to replicate these types of lenses as closely as possible via clever display technology.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>The technology works by separating colors and keeping some in focus while "defocusing" others. There are also times when colors are changed or objects receive faint outlines that place them more or less in focus, depending on the color used. It&apos;s similar to chromatic aberration, a lens effect that separates colors via a prism, which can also be seen in 3D movies that provide artificial depth.</p><p>In essence, it simulates the act of looking away from your device at a distant object, helping to automate a process that most of us forget to do.</p><p>It&apos;s difficult to describe and even more difficult to understand unless you see it in action. Surprisingly, I didn&apos;t find that this affected image quality negatively. While I had a hard time capturing the effect on camera, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0c5VtgEP43Y">YouTuber PhoneBuff</a> did an excellent job of tearing the technology apart in an easy-to-understand way in the video below.</p><p>He even corroborates the notion that the effect is normally nearly invisible to the naked eye in most circumstances, which I found particularly interesting. The big downside is that Honor&apos;s AI Defocus tech currently only works on the YouTube and Amazon Kindle apps, but Honor says it&apos;s working to expand support for more apps in the near future.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0c5VtgEP43Y" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>But not everyone is convinced that this could be a one-stop-shop solution. According to Bhavin Shah, Behavioural Optometrist at Central Vision Opticians, DIMS therapy—remember, those are the physical defocus lenses that people can wear—is generally only used in people up to age 21 and sees only a 1% success rate beyond that age.</p><p>Shah says "I don&apos;t believe that stimulating the same defocus on a screen will be detected by the peripheral retinal in the same way that the actual light hits the retina through glasses or contact lenses. I&apos;ve worn these contact lenses and glasses myself as an adult and it did not make any difference to comfort or eyestrain, the vision is much better with regular glasses or contacts compared to wearing defocus lenses."</p><p>Honor has been very careful to pen this as one additional arrow in the quiver for better eye health rather than a one-size-fits-all solution. But while it&apos;s not going to work for everyone, it may help quite a few people, and Honor&apos;s own research—plus Shah&apos;s experience—seems to corroborate the possibility.</p><p>Shah seemed hopeful about the tech so long as the study included a proper control mechanism for testers, meaning one group has the defocus AI mode enabled while one has it disabled. "If this change was better than those not using the defocus mode, then it shows some minor benefit. However, a long-term independent study would be the next step before I would start recommending it. I would have to try it myself."</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>Honor has been very careful to pen this as one additional arrow in the quiver for better eye health rather than a one-size-fits-all solution, but some experts say we need more testing to make sure it's effective.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>Shah notes that "our eyes do have a system where only the central vision is clear and the peripheral part is blurred and the eyes keep moving and pointing the central part of the vision to build up a clear picture by joining the clear parts and ignoring the blur, so in theory, if the peripheral defocus were to move based on where a person is viewing the screen at any one time, there may be some effect but I would highly doubt that it would make a significant difference."</p><p>I&apos;ve seen similar mixed results in the PWM-sensitive communities on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://ledstrain.org/">LEDStrain forum</a> and in Telegram groups I&apos;m a part of, where one "flicker-free" solution works wonders for some people while it does absolutely nothing to help another person.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.30%;"><img id="5S4HdrkVU9qB8aimhFhg5" name="honor-magicpad-2-reading-01.jpg" alt="Reading books on an Honor MagicPad 2" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5S4HdrkVU9qB8aimhFhg5.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1153" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Honor MagicPad 2 utilizes DC-like dimming at high brightness and an impressive 4320Hz PWM dimming at low brightness. For reference, that&apos;s 20x better than the latest iPad Pro models. Even this solution won&apos;t work perfectly for everyone, but it can help quite a lot of people who are sensitive to light flicker, like myself.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>This won't help everyone but, combined with higher PWM rates and other eye care solutions, mean that Honor is pushing the envelope for eye care more than any other brand.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>Shah offered one particular ray of hope based on Honor&apos;s research results, though. "Central Choroidal thickness has been shown to increase with near work and then return to normal but there is only a little research on this subject and the impact it has on adults and eyestrain."</p><p>AI Defocus solutions like the one in the Honor MagicPad 2 and Honor Magic V3 are designed to keep Central Choroidal thickness from changing as little as possible, meaning our eyes likely won&apos;t be as negatively affected by long-term screen use if more people are able to use this kind of technology.</p>
<h2 id="the-road-to-better-eye-health-2">The road to better (eye) health</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="MwTw3oahEAVMqGJPqoJpFo" name="honor-magicpad-2-reading-close.jpg" alt="Reading books on an Honor MagicPad 2" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MwTw3oahEAVMqGJPqoJpFo.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>For this article, I spoke with three different eye care professionals and all agreed that less screen time is the best solution. Dr. James R. Kelly from Kelly Vision Center recommends a simple 20/20/20 vision break rule along with frequent blinking when working on screens or using your tablet or phone for a long time. The 20/20/20 rule "means taking a visual break every 20 minutes where the individual looks at something 20 feet away for 20 seconds."</p><p>Frequent blinking might sound funny, but it&apos;s been shown that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://hub.salford.ac.uk/appliedcognition/2021/08/27/2068/">blinking decreases by 66%</a> when focusing on something. Additional research has shown that the blink rate for displays versus books <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24413278/">isn&apos;t any different</a>, but few people—in the past or otherwise—would spend as much time reading a book as often as most people look at a computer monitor or smartphone, meaning most of us don&apos;t blink as often as we should.</p><p>Shah builds upon this specifically for children, saying "it would be better to give them better habits like cutting screen time, taking breaks, and holding the device further away." In fact, new smartwatches like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fitbit-ace-lte-review">Fitbit Ace LTE</a> encourage not only fun outdoor play but also reduced screen time, setting hard limits on games to only a few minutes of screen time per session.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="QPiwKDd47VagREzJKrkYv7" name="honor-magicpad-2-watching-youtube.jpg" alt="Watching a YouTube video on the Honor MagicPad 2" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QPiwKDd47VagREzJKrkYv7.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>But while kids can get away with reduced screen time, it&apos;s not a reality for most working adults in the modern age. Dr. Kelly recommends "proper distancing and angling of screens, along with blue light blocking filters and anti-glare filters, and making sure screens are clean and smudge-free to reduce glare and reflections."</p><p>Samsung actually took a fascinating step toward this last part with the display on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review">Galaxy S24 Ultra</a>, giving it anti-glare properties but the company didn&apos;t go far enough to reduce the amount of flicker coming from its relatively slow 480Hz PWM rate. Remember, Honor is pushing 10x that number on its phones and tablets.</p><p>Additionally, Dr. Kelly recommends proper room lighting to avoid eye fatigue and strain. I&apos;ve personally had to remove all smart lights and LED strips from my home office because nearly <em>all</em> of them use PWM dimming and flicker at all brightness levels. I&apos;ve since switched them out for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B019KKEXOE/">these Sylvania LED bulbs</a> from Amazon that are not only inexpensive but are also non-dimmable, which is usually the code word in the LED world for "doesn&apos;t use PWM."</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="xSqe5EujsH5kjRGvWBRM78" name="honor-magicpad-2-back-01.jpg" alt="The back of the white Honor MagicPad 2" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xSqe5EujsH5kjRGvWBRM78.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>My verdict on the Honor MagicPad 2 and Honor Magic V3 displays? Superb. Sublime, even. The MagicPad 2 has the better display because it&apos;s a more consistent PWM rate at low brightness. It uses true 4320Hz PWM at low brightness whereas only the inner display in the Magic V3 has true 4320Hz—the outer display is identical to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-6-pro-review">Honor Magic 6 Pro</a>&apos;s 3840Hz panel, which uses an accelerated 360Hz DC-like cycle to achieve a higher overall PWM frequency.</p><p>Either way, I&apos;ve had no discomfort from either device after weeks of use, which is a lot more than I can say about the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-fold-review">Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold</a>. If all else fails, the only other real solution is just to spend more time outdoors and less time in front of screens.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magicpad-2-honor-magic-v3-ai-defocus-display</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Myopia is a huge problem and only getting worse. Honor's AI defocus tech aims to fix the problem by starting at the root of the problem: our eyes. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">52qszzejshs7S2Lf92zhuP</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ruCgppDYs3B85jEttfgkfh.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 13:01:07 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ruCgppDYs3B85jEttfgkfh.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Honor MagicPad 2 with the Honor Smart Keyboard attachment and the Honor Magic V3 alongside a pair of glasses]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Honor MagicPad 2 with the Honor Smart Keyboard attachment and the Honor Magic V3 alongside a pair of glasses]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Honor Magic V3 is trying to redefine what a foldable can be ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Honor introduces its latest foldable, which measures 9.2mm in thickness when folded.</li><li>In comparison, the rival Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 measures 12.1mm in thickness.</li><li>The Magic V3 sports a 6.43-inch external screen and a 7.92-inch foldable screen.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Honor finally introduced its much-anticipated foldable smartphone, the Magic V3, at the IFA 2024 event in Berlin. In addition to its thinnest inward-folding phone, the company has announced several other products, including the Honor Magic Pad 2, Watch 5, and MagicBook Art 14.</p><p>The Magic V3 is aiming for the title of the world&apos;s thinnest book-style <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">foldable phone</a>. When folded, it’s just 9.2mm thick and weighs about 226 grams. For comparison, the rival <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6</a> comes in at 12.1mm and 239 grams. Honor credits this impressive slim-down to 19 new materials and 114 microstructures packed into the design.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="zWQrAfrCCZ5JFt7ZRJgqVc" name="Honor-Magic-V3-06.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zWQrAfrCCZ5JFt7ZRJgqVc.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Honor)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="YgpSHf8bTfWzn9XbyDV2Sc" name="Honor-Magic-V3-04.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YgpSHf8bTfWzn9XbyDV2Sc.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Honor)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="wnPPkpLMjSiAKhc4DGcTNc" name="Honor-Magic-V3-02.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wnPPkpLMjSiAKhc4DGcTNc.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Honor)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 4 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="j7a66xBeNMUhtcBuqoj6Zc" name="Honor-Magic-V3-07.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/j7a66xBeNMUhtcBuqoj6Zc.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Honor)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>In a press release, Honor further notes that the handset&apos;s back cover is also shrunk using Special Fiber, which notably enhances impact resistance 40 times over the other foldable phones on the market. The hinge is promised with up to 500,000 folding cycles. </p><p>The Magic V3 features a 7.92-inch foldable screen inside and a 6.43-inch cover screen outside. Both displays come with 4320Hz ultra-high-frequency PWM dimming tech for smoother visuals. Under the hood, it&apos;s powered by the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3, stepping up from the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-v2-review">Magic V2</a>.</p><p>Keeping the lights on both displays is a 5150mAh battery capacity that supports Honor&apos;s 66W fast charging alongside 50W wireless charging as well. The foldable uses a giant circular module on the rear featuring a 50MP primary camera, a 50MP periscope telephoto lens, and a 40MP ultra-wide sensor for optics. The device also hosts AI-enabled photography features like "HONOR AI Motion Sensing for Lightning-fast shots, and the HONOR AI Portrait Engine for portrait enhancement."</p><p>The Honor Magic V3 comes in Reddish Brown, Green, and Black colorways.</p>
<h2 id="honor-magic-pad-2-2">Honor Magic Pad 2</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="vzNXK3aouNbPQpnMenqpii" name="Honor-Magic-Pad-2-02.jpg" alt="Honor Magic Pad 2" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vzNXK3aouNbPQpnMenqpii.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Honor)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Honor Magic Pad 2 is yet another slim-form-factor device that falls under the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-tablets">Android tablets</a> segment. It weighs 555 grams and measures only 5.8mm in thickness. It has a 12.3-inch giant display with a 144Hz refresh rate and supports high-frequency PWM dimming, just like the foldable phone. The tablet comes in Emerald Green, Starry Grey, and White color options.</p><p>Underneath, the device runs on a Snapdragon 8s Gen 3, paired with a hefty 10,050mAh battery that supports 66W fast charging. It ships with MagicOS 8.0 and comes with cool AI tricks, like the Magic Portal feature, which predicts what you need and lets you create schedules or manage tasks with just a long press and drag.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="JjCBKSyTKDwbMWLgGmwxbi" name="Honor-Magic-Pad-2-01.jpg" alt="Honor Magic Pad 2" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JjCBKSyTKDwbMWLgGmwxbi.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Honor)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="FHK6FaX66MKGkh3HSYvMfi" name="Honor-Magic-Pad-2.jpg" alt="Honor Magic Pad 2" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FHK6FaX66MKGkh3HSYvMfi.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Honor)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<h2 id="honor-watch-5-2">Honor Watch 5</h2>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="KtRuFWkB4dNenmiYwovQN" name="Honor-Watch-5-01.jpg" alt="Honor Watch 5" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KtRuFWkB4dNenmiYwovQN.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Honor)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="zDfNb5BzYc9BkotYHCRxH" name="Honor-Watch-5-02.jpg" alt="Honor Watch 5" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zDfNb5BzYc9BkotYHCRxH.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Honor)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>At IFA this year, Honor also introduced the Watch 5. It has a 1.85-inch AMOLED square display, a resolution of 450 x 390 pixels, and 322ppi. It measures 11mm in thickness and weighs around 35 grams. There is also a rotatable button on the right through which users can navigate across the interface. The Watch 5 is available in Black, Gold, and Green color variants.</p><p>The smartwatch&apos;s 480mAh battery capacity promises a 15-day battery life on a single charge. It also features health features like heart rate monitoring, SpO2 monitoring, and an AccuTrack positioning system for GPS accuracy.</p><p>Honor has yet to share the pricing and availability of these devices.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-v3-foldable-announced</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The slim foldable craze is heating up, and Honor's Magic V3 just jumped on the bandwagon. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">cYnqvyzfYoWoVEkSL5RtSY</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/e2PG7BGXHJJFpeRhETgmJc.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 13:00:53 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/e2PG7BGXHJJFpeRhETgmJc.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Honor]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Honor Magic V3]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Honor Magic V3]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Honor Magic V3 hands-on: Effortlessly upstaging the Galaxy Z Fold 6 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Honor clearly knows what it&apos;s doing with foldables, and although the Magic V2 launched a year ago, it continues to be among the thinnest and lightest devices around. The ultra-thin design is a major differentiator, and it is the main reason why I used the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-v2-review">Magic V2</a> more than just about any other foldable in 2024 — it doesn&apos;t feel cumbersome in the least.</p><p>Honor is putting all the learnings from the Magic V2 toward its latest foldable, the Magic V3. The foldable retains the best features of its predecessor, but it is thinner and lighter, and that makes it even better to hold and use. Coming in at just 9.3mm folded and an incredible 4.4mm unfolded, the Magic V3 is unbelievably thin.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="yBYucR97mbCFcL9SNGnACa" name="honor-magic-v3-hands-on-3.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3 hands-on" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yBYucR97mbCFcL9SNGnACa.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The overall design is largely the same as last year, but the Magic V3 switches to a new camera module that&apos;s similar to that of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-6-pro-review">Magic 6 Pro</a>, and it looks much more elegant. What I like the most about the camera island is that it is centered, and there&apos;s no wobble whatsoever when using the Magic V3 on a table; this was a bugbear on the V2.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="FvbUB2VtqfyVddKzS5wpnb" name="honor-magic-v3-hands-on-7.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3 hands-on" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FvbUB2VtqfyVddKzS5wpnb.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>At 226g, it is 5g lighter than the V2 while offering a bigger 5150mAh battery. By contrast, Samsung&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Galaxy Z Fold 6</a> weighs 13g more, and you get a much smaller 4400mAh battery. To give you additional context, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-review">Pixel 9 Pro XL</a> weighs 221g, and it doesn&apos;t fold in half. Honor once again is proving that it is the brand to beat when it comes to foldable designs, and the Magic V3 looks and feels like a device that&apos;s a few generations ahead of what Samsung is offering.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="YsyVqDER8pFFHVA7DpsqMa" name="honor-magic-v3-hands-on-4.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3 hands-on" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YsyVqDER8pFFHVA7DpsqMa.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The hinge has a smooth articulation, and it doesn&apos;t take much effort to unfold the device. Honor says the hinge has better durability this time around, and that it can withstand 500,000 unlocks. It is a little stiffer than the hinge on the V2, but that&apos;s a good thing — it allows the V3 to stay locked at various angles between 40 to 150 degrees. What continues to be great is that the hinge doesn&apos;t lead to a noticeable crease — it definitely isn&apos;t as evident as Samsung&apos;s offering.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="gVAp9vpszAaHbmXdVF4Aaa" name="honor-magic-v3-hands-on-5.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3 hands-on" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gVAp9vpszAaHbmXdVF4Aaa.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While Honor didn&apos;t change the dimensions of the inner and outer screens, both panels have better brightness levels, and class-leading PWM dimming. Honor is also rolling out a defocus mode that&apos;s meant to relieve eye strain, and the brand continues to lead the way when it comes to eye comfort.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="rwQjFCwoofBps63k4YBRCc" name="honor-magic-v3-hands-on-9.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3 hands-on" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rwQjFCwoofBps63k4YBRCc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Ingress protection was an area where Honor lagged behind its rivals last year, and thankfully, the Magic V3 gets IPX8 water resistance as standard, allowing it to weather the elements much better. Honor is also rolling out bold new colors, and the green variant does a great job accentuating the design of the camera housing.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="CwTrtCHzAtSDEQmbrRJVQc" name="honor-magic-v3-hands-on-10.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3 hands-on" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CwTrtCHzAtSDEQmbrRJVQc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Honor is positioning the Magic V3 against the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">best foldables</a>, so it isn&apos;t astonishing that the device gets the latest tech. It is powered by Qualcomm&apos;s Snapdragon 8 Gen 3, and comes with 12GB of RAM and 256GB of storage with the base model. It has the latest connectivity modem, NFC, USB 3.1 with DisplayPort 1.2, and in the little I used the device, I didn&apos;t see any issues with lag or jitter while gaming.</p>
<p>Obviously, battery life is a key area of consideration on a foldable, and the Magic V3 has a 5150mAh battery that uses a silicon-carbon substrate to increase longevity. While I haven&apos;t used the device enough to gauge battery life, I got a day&apos;s worth of use between charges, and I don&apos;t see any problems in this area.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="ZmBFVD86cYL6dEVHaRUNyb" name="honor-magic-v3-hands-on-8.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3 hands-on" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZmBFVD86cYL6dEVHaRUNyb.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Honor is upgrading the cameras as well, with the Magic V3 offering a new 50MP camera alongside a 40MP wide-angle lens and 50MP zoom lens with 3.5x optical zoom. The foldable gets a lot of the same features as the Magic 6 Pro, including AI-based scene recognition and motion-tracking.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="vV3r6TtYccFbzJuqxHVvxZ" name="honor-magic-v3-hands-on-2.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3 hands-on" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vV3r6TtYccFbzJuqxHVvxZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Honor doubled down on AI-assisted software features in Magic OS 8.0, and the Magic V3 runs the 8.0.3 build out of the box that comes with a few extras. Honor is teaming up with Google to bring the search giant&apos;s best AI features to its devices, and this is absolutely the right move; Google has class-leading translation and image editing AI features, and you can now use these on the Magic V3.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="ZwMjC3c9eJ6QfwBvFAfzcc" name="honor-magic-v3-hands-on-11.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3 hands-on" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZwMjC3c9eJ6QfwBvFAfzcc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While Honor got a lot right with the Magic V2 last year, the brand messed up availability; the foldable went on sale in the U.K. at the end of Q1 2024 — six months after its global debut — and that was undoubtedly detrimental to its sales figures. Honor isn&apos;t making that mistake this time around; the Magic V3 will be available in the U.K. starting September 5, and it has mainstream carrier backing.</p>
<p>Coming in at £1,699 ($2,233), the Magic V3 is positioned against the Galaxy Z Fold 6. I&apos;ll reserve judgement for the review, but if you&apos;re ready to switch to a foldable and want something that&apos;s just as easy to use as a regular phone, the Magic V3 needs to be on your radar — it is one of the best phones I used in 2024.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-v3-hands-on</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Magic V3 just made its global debut, and it may just be one of the best foldables of 2024.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">oejejGyTNAVwU3ibF2EU49</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zaTupidC4WUGNt2uNDZ7qc.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 13:00:13 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zaTupidC4WUGNt2uNDZ7qc.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Honor Magic V3 hands-on]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Honor Magic V3 hands-on]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ OnePlus reportedly eager to challenge Honor with a thinner Open 2 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Rumors suggest OnePlus is interested in making the Open 2 even thinner than the first model, which could bring it contention with Honor's Magic V3.</li><li>The device is "expected" to feature a 9.Xmm thinness when folded with a circular triple camera array, and a 2K Plus high-definition display.</li><li>Honor's Magic V3 is incredibly thin and durable as the company stated it measures 9.2mm when folded and 4.3mm unfolded.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>New rumors claim consumers could have an interesting competition brewing between OnePlus and Honor following its thin Magic V3 foldable.</p><p>Known Weibo tipster <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://weibo.com/6048569942/Ovgu56gT8?pagetype=profilefeed">Digital Chat Station</a> (DCS) posted some rumors about the OnePlus Open 2, which purported its new thinner mentality. The information was recently edited away; however, the folks at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/oneplus-open-2-thin-leak-3478093/">Android Authority</a> snapped a screenshot of it. According to the original rumor, DCS states a key aspect of OnePlus&apos; design for the Open 2 is to make it "even thinner and lighter."</p><p>Supposedly, the Chinese OEM is interested in producing a foldable with a thickness of 9.Xmm. This is rumored to be "expected" as development of the device continues. The tipster didn&apos;t give a specific number, though it should be relatively thinner than Honor&apos;s recent book-style foldable if it wants to beat it.</p><p>Other rumors claim the phone could feature a Sony 50MP primary sensor within its triple camera array. It&apos;s suggested that a periscope camera will join this. Additionally, it seems OnePlus is sticking with the large, circular array that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-open-review">its previous iteration</a> offered.</p><p>Lastly, a "2K Plus full high-definition" foldable screen is rumored for the Open 2 alongside the Snapdragon 8 Gen 4.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:713px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:84.15%;"><img id="ewxMBAzqfSfFVbRwWm76Ug" name="oneplus-open-2-thinness-rumors.jpg" alt="A set of rumors about the upcoming OnePlus Open 2, which claim its thinness could rival Honor's Magic V3." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ewxMBAzqfSfFVbRwWm76Ug.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="713" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The idea of a thinner foldable, especially one within the 9mm range, gets us thinking about the Honor Magic V3. The company detailed <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-v3-ultra-thin-durable-creation-details">how it made its ultra-thin foldable</a>, which measures 9.2mm when folded and 4.3mm unfolded. Honor stated that it invested heavily in the R&D side of its battery technology, implementing a 5,150mAh silicon carbon battery.</p><p>The company honed in on durability, an aspect of the previous model that consumers complained about. With the Magic V3, Honor added an additional set of "swing arms" for its hinge to boost its durability and longevity.</p><p>It remains to be seen just how much of a challenger OnePlus will be with the Open 2 against Honor. Rumors so far suggest it will be thinner than the Pixel 9 Pro Fold at 10.5mm and the Galaxy Z Fold 6 at 12.1mm.</p><p>Other OnePlus Open 2 <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-open-tipped-to-have-a-6000mah-battery">rumors claim</a> the device could feature a beefed-up 6,000mAh battery. The current claims double down on the theory of Qualcomm&apos;s upcoming flagship SoC being featured within the device. Elsewhere, the Open 2 <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-oneplus-open-might-not-see-a-successor-this-year">may not arrive this year</a> as originally speculated. A tipster&apos;s post on X suggested that the next OnePlus foldable could arrive during Q1 2025.</p><p>The reason is supposedly due to OPPO, a OnePlus sister company, delaying the launch of its Find N5 until next year. Both foldables are likely to mirror one another like last year.</p>
<ul><li><strong> Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><strong>Best Buy</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><strong>Walmart</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><strong>Samsung</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><strong>Amazon</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><strong>Verizon</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><strong>AT&T</strong></a></li></ul>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="98f2791a-0756-4f09-9f89-7e7b391130c7">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oP8j6zYak7fmALcFEDr9Da.jpg' alt="An official render of the OnePlus Open in Emerald Dusk color"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">OnePlus Open</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Immersive and smooth</strong></em></p>
<p>The OnePlus Open is an all-around superb foldable phone that truly stands a part from the competition. With a striking design and performance that is typical for OnePlus, the Open is a worthy book-style foldable for new users and tech lovers alike.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-open-2-thinner-design-rumors</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ OnePlus is rumored to create a thinner Open 2 foldable to compete with the likes of Honor. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">kTgt8SLE2CMnWqEUaLBvm9</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/eGyLKviAK3wq4uCoqV8HdX.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 19:00:40 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/eGyLKviAK3wq4uCoqV8HdX.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus Open Apex Edition review]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus Open Apex Edition review]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Mint Mobile will now give you $400 OFF the Pixel 9 Pro XL and 50% off a year of wireless, just for kicks ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Do a quick Google search and you&apos;ll find no shortage of great Google Pixel 9 Pro XL deals right now, but once again, Mint Mobile&apos;s offer is probably the best out there, and once again, it&apos;s flying well under the radar.</p><p>I&apos;m not being hyperbolic: if you buy the Pixel 9 Pro XL alongside any six-month data plan at Mint Mobile, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9-pro-xl/6810506/"><strong>the T-Mobile-powered MVNO will hook you up with $400 off the phone AND six months of additional wireless for free</strong></a>. That means you can get an awesome AI-powered device and a <em>full year</em> of wireless service for as little as<em> </em>$789, or $33 per month if you pay using affirm. </p><p>I&apos;ve seen <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/mint-mobile-deals-promo-codes">Mint Mobile deals</a> like this before, but it&apos;s pretty unusual to see the promo drop so soon after the phone&apos;s release date. </p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="8a573d31-591b-455a-bdcb-d1b17d267471" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL 128GB: $1,099" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL 128GB: $1,099" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9-pro-xl/6810506/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="qxxHFzMsUCW6peiznjeMek" name="google-pixel-9-pro-xl-official-render-obsidian-front-back.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qxxHFzMsUCW6peiznjeMek.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="500" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Google Pixel 9 Pro XL 128GB: </strong><a href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9-pro-xl/6810506/" data-dimension112="8a573d31-591b-455a-bdcb-d1b17d267471" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL 128GB: $1,099" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL 128GB: $1,099"><del>$1,099</del> <strong>$699, plus six months free with any six-month plan at Mint Mobile</strong></a></p>
<p>Big, bold, and beautiful, the new Google Pixel 9 Pro XL features the power of the new Tensor G4 chipset, plus you're getting cutting-edge AI-features and loads of software support straight out of the box. Pick up an XL from Mint Mobile with any six-month data plan and the carrier will carve a straight $400 off the price of the phone. You'll also get an additional six months of service for free! <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9-pro-xl/6810506/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="8a573d31-591b-455a-bdcb-d1b17d267471" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL 128GB: $1,099" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL 128GB: $1,099">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>The Pixel 9 Pro XL is likely to rank among the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a> released this year, and for good reason: you&apos;re essentially getting the power, efficiency, and lengthy software support of the regular Pixel 9 Pro in a larger, more glorious-looking package.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-xl-comparison-video">Early tests</a> show that the Pixel 9 Pro XL performs handily next to the super-powered Galaxy S24 Ultra from Samsung, but you&apos;re paying significantly less. Pair the XL with this Mint Mobile deal and you&apos;re getting a premium, AI-powered device for the price of a flagship, and that&apos;s not even considering the value of saving 50% on a year of wireless provided by T-Mobile.</p><p>Of course, this kind of deal isn&apos;t for everyone. If you&apos;re happy with your current phone service or you&apos;re looking to do a trade-in, there are plenty of other great <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/best-google-pixel-9-deals-pixel-9-pro-discounts">Google Pixel 9 deals</a> to consider. But if you&apos;re ready to switch to an MVNO and you&apos;re looking to get a great phone out of the deal, this is an outstanding opportunity.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/mint-mobile-will-now-give-you-dollar400-off-the-pixel-9-pro-xl-and-50-off-a-year-of-wireless-just-for-kicks</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Mint Mobile is now including the Pixel 9 Pro XL in its free wireless bundle deal, resulting in savings as immense as the phone itself.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">KsJr9s3W8uaWcR2DhajuYG</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vVYYjY4JW9uei4MkoGAW8S.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 19:00:12 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vVYYjY4JW9uei4MkoGAW8S.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The back of the Hazel Google Pixel 9 Pro XL]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The back of the Hazel Google Pixel 9 Pro XL]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google's latest security patch fixes a couple of key problems for Pixel owners ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google has started rolling out its September 2024 security patch to Pixel devices ranging from the Pixel 6 series to the latest Pixel 9.</li><li>The light patch solves the extreme Pixel vulnerability caused by a Verizon demo app and a Wi-Fi issue for the Pixel 9 series.</li><li>The vulnerability could've exposed Pixel devices to malware and spyware viruses.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>September is off to a fast start for Google as the company has started rolling out its monthly security update.</p><p>Despite a light September 2024 security update, Google is fixing two crucial problems with its Pixel lineup. According to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/pixelphone/thread/294694412/google-pixel-update-september-2024?hl=en&sjid=792810088250019396-NA">patch notes</a>, the patch is rolling out for the Pixel 6 series as version <strong>AP2A.240905.003.F1</strong>. The Pixel 7, Pixel 8, the O.G. Fold, and the Pixel Tablet will see version <strong>AP2A.240905.003 </strong>while the 8a sees an <strong>A1</strong> tacked onto the end.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9">Pixel 9</a> users will find firmware version <strong>AD1A.240905.004</strong>.</p><p>While this patch brings the usual security improvements, one major fix involves the removal of a "third-party APK to address security vulnerability." This is a major issue, as Google states the security flaw affected its entire past-gen line of devices. The devices this fix is for involve the Pixel 6 series up to the Pixel 8.</p><p>The Pixel Fold and the Pixel Tablet were also affected and rectified.</p><p>Google&apos;s final fix involves an odd Wi-Fi problem. The changelog details that the fix should correct Wi-Fi "stability and performance." These were issues that Pixel 9 series users may have noticed as their devices arrived.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="YUK5ipDMWC2ke7WPN2XqVc" name="google-pixel-9-pro-fold-review-11.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold with Pixel 9 Pro screen comparison" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YUK5ipDMWC2ke7WPN2XqVc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2500" height="1406" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The post states the update is for all Android 14 devices and will roll out "in phases." Everyone won&apos;t see the patch simultaneously as Google delivers it per device and carrier.</p><p>Regarding the Pixel vulnerability, it was discovered in mid-August that a pre-loaded <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-pixel-verizon-demo-app-vulnerability-details">Verizon demo app contained a file</a> that could expose a user&apos;s device to MITM (man-in-the-middle) attacks. The only saving grace is that the app (and the file by extension) remained dormant on Pixel phones unless they were specifically enabled and granted permissions.</p><p>The Showcase.apk file was the culprit, which could&apos;ve given outside threats a way to "virtually inject" malware and spyware onto your Pixel phone.</p><p>With the Pixel 9&apos;s Wi-Fi problem seemingly squared away, there&apos;s still nothing further about the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/pixel-9-rooting-unlocked-bootloader-problems-reported">unlocked bootloader issues</a>. Pixel 9 users quickly discovered that unlocking the bootloader breaks many of the new AI-powered features. Rooting the device caused similar problems. Pixel Screenshots, Pixel Studio, and the Pixel Weather app stopped working and displayed error messages.</p><p>The only way to get things working again would be to lock and unroot the device in question. It&apos;s an unfortunate development as unlocking the bootloader can <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-8-pro-display-upgrade">bring a lot of good to users who desire it</a>.</p>
<ul><li><strong> Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><strong>Best Buy</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><strong>Walmart</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><strong>Samsung</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><strong>Amazon</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><strong>Verizon</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><strong>AT&T</strong></a></li></ul>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="91ffdfcc-9538-4786-ab3d-2807cf305ee5">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Epz84yteXYHhCgKXftnMDm.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL official render - Rose Quartz - front and back"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 Pro XL</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>One Vision</strong></em></p>
<p>Google's Pixel 9 Pro XL is the largest of the smartphone trio with a 6.8-inch display and a slightly bigger battery. The larger variant offers the same great "Pro" experience, with the Gemini AI features to match. The device has also received the latest wave of Android features in September, taking the device to a new level of enjoyment.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-pixel-september-2024-security-patch</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google detailed its September 2024 security patch, which included a fix for a problematic vulnerability. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">hjWLPmGm52eEpRWES57sv</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vVYYjY4JW9uei4MkoGAW8S.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 18:32:30 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vVYYjY4JW9uei4MkoGAW8S.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The back of the Hazel Google Pixel 9 Pro XL]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The back of the Hazel Google Pixel 9 Pro XL]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Pixel 9a could grab a year-old modem and a curious Tensor G4 change ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Rumors claim Google plans to pack the older Exynos Modem 5300 in the Pixel 9a instead of the upgraded 5400 like the flagship Pixel 9.</li><li>Speculation adds the device could also feature a "slightly different" Tensor G4 as the packaging method for it in the Pixel 9a could result in higher temperatures.</li><li>A few alleged real-life images of the Pixel 9a leaked, showing off a surprisingly small camera visor.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Consumers are just getting their hands on the flagship Pixel 9 series, but some interesting rumors have surfaced about its budget variant.</p><p>Kamila Wojciechowska writing for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/exclusive-google-pixel-9a-modem-3477459/">Android Authority</a> claims the upcoming Pixel 9a will not use the same modem as its flagship friends. The tipster claims Google&apos;s next budget phone will continue to use the Exynos Modem 5300 SoC that its Pixel 8 and Pixel 7 series featured last year.</p><p>The post notes how the Pixel 9a may miss out on the efficiency increases and cooling capabilities the Exynos Modem 5400 provides the flagship line.</p><p>The other side of these rumors involves Google&apos;s SoC, which will supposedly be a "slightly different" version. The publication states that the Tensor G4 packed in the Pixel 9 will hit the Pixel 9a; however, the "plastic package" will reportedly differ. The packaging method of an SoC can affect the performance of a chip.</p><p>More importantly, the difference in method can notably affect its heating/cooling capabilities. Kamila states the Pixel 9a&apos;s Tensor G4 could feature the IPoP packaging method instead of the flagship&apos;s FOPLP, which delivers a cooler experience.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="N9Tp2Zhx5PPyKgEuw6AEVH" name="google-pixel-9-pro-obsidian-and-pixel-9-pro-xl-hazel-in-cases-02.jpg" alt="A Google Pixel 9 Pro in a Thinborne aramid fiber case and a Google Pixel 9 Pro XL in an official Google case" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/N9Tp2Zhx5PPyKgEuw6AEVH.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>What&apos;s interesting about this potential packaging change for the Pixel 9a is that we&apos;ve seen <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/pixel-7a-tensor-g2-alleged-packaging">similar behavior with the Pixel 7a</a>. It was stated in 2023 that Google opted for a "slightly worse" method for its budget device: IPOP. The other option was Samsung&apos;s FOPLP-PoP proprietary technology. Switching to IPOP could cause the device to heat up quicker than the other, negatively impacting the phone&apos;s performance.</p><p>IPOP is also "thicker and larger," according to Kamila&apos;s initial revelation about Google&apos;s packaging change last year. Whether Google decides to do the same for the Pixel 9a remains to be seen.</p><p>Elsewhere, Pixel 9a rumors continue as a few <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9a-alleged-real-life-photos-leak">alleged real-life images</a> leaked about it late last month. The device will seemingly sport Google&apos;s new boxy design like the flagship models, but a slight change could hit its rear panel. While the Pixel 9 series boasts a pretty large (<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/pixel-design-lead-discusses-large-camera-visor">and not-so-sorry</a>) camera bump, the 9a could take a minimalistic approach.</p><p>The photos show the bump could be incredibly small with two camera lenses and an LED flash on the outside of the array. There&apos;s no telling how this could affect the sensors (and megapixels) of the Pixel 9a. The design change is also quite different from Pixel A-series past as those phones typically remain close to the flagship line.</p><p>The Pixel 9a is expected to launch in Q2 2025.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/pixel-9a-modem-tensor-g4-rumored-changes</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ New Pixel 9a rumors suggested Google could change up the inner workings of the next budget phone. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">VQzp3vXWo8qAirpWyW3Nde</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3fBjYdhmrr5uPkU5Lt25mb.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 18:25:06 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3fBjYdhmrr5uPkU5Lt25mb.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Pixel 9 next to a bush]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Pixel 9 next to a bush]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Later Exynos — Samsung rumored to drop its SoC for Qualcomm for the Galaxy S25 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A new report claims that Samsung is moving toward packing Qualcomm's next Snapdragon 8 Gen 4 in the Galaxy S25 instead of its Exynos SoC.</li><li>This is reportedly done due to Qualcomm's "high performance" and to help Samsung keep in contention with AI advancements from Apple and Chinese OEMs.</li><li>Samsung's Exynos is reportedly taking a backseat for now and will arrive for next year's foldable duo.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>We&apos;re a few months away from Samsung&apos;s next flagship series, but the latest rumors claim the market is in for a chip switch.</p><p>A <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.hankyung.com/article/2024090197421">Hankyung</a> (Korean) report purports Samsung is moving to drop its Exynos chip from the Galaxy S25 series for Qualcomm&apos;s Snapdragon (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.sammobile.com/news/galaxy-s25-snapdragon-8-gen-4-exclusive-ditch-exynos-report/">SamMobile</a>). This move will reportedly encompass the next flagship line&apos;s global release as the company <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-hands-on">has previously put forth</a> a dual-chip mentality.</p><p>While that typically left areas like Europe with its latest Exynos launch, the publication states this change concerns Samsung&apos;s competition.</p><p>The post adds that Samsung is teetering toward Qualcomm and its work toward bettering on-device AI to stay in contention with Apple and other Chinese OEMs. AI features <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/honor-magicpad-2-ai-math-equation-digitizer">in development by Honor</a> for its big IFA 2024 showcase could be an object of discussion.</p><p>Rumors continue, stating Samsung isn&apos;t ditching its next chip, the Exynos 2500, entirely. The publication states the company is moving to "use it in a foldable phone to be released in the second half of next year." Supposedly, this claim involves both the "tentatively" named Galaxy Z Flip 7 and Fold 7 slated for next summer.</p><p>An <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-exynos-2500-soc-specs-leak">early specification leak</a> teased noteworthy performance and speed increases for Samsung&apos;s Exynos 2500. What followed were rumors stating this Exynos chip could make <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-galaxy-s25s-exynos-chipset-could-outpace-the-snapdragon-8-gen-4-in-efficiency">for a closer rival</a> for Qualcomm&apos;s Snapdragon 8 Gen 4. The chip will likely be built off a 3nm process with a single Cortex X-5 CPU ranging from 3.2 to 3.3GHz.</p><p>AMD&apos;s RDNA-based Xclipse 950 GPU may enter to boost its graphical capabilities.</p><p>What concerns a large breadth of flagship phones is Qualcomm&apos;s upcoming Snapdragon 8 Gen 4, which <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/snapdragon-8-gen-4-power-hungry-rumor">might demand more</a> from your phone&apos;s battery. This hunger for power is reportedly caused by the chip&apos;s usage of a 2+6 core setup. Devices may need to jump to 6,000mAh, though some have been (supposedly) tested with a 5,500mAh capacity.</p><p>A Qualcomm executive confirmed the next chip will <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-4-launch-details">arrive in October</a> with Oryon CPU. This new CPU hardware is estimated to provide 2x more power and 4.5x faster AI processing.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-bye-exynos-qualcomm-galaxy-s25-rumor</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A report claimed Samsung is dropping its Exynos chip from the Galaxy S25 series in favor of Qualcomm's next Snapdragon. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">xgYBzgJzTzha59isbr69MA</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7P2ErZCEHSc73umEzHChMN.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 18:18:08 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7P2ErZCEHSc73umEzHChMN.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The back of the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra in the Titanium Grey colorway]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The back of the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra in the Titanium Grey colorway]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Pixel Watch 3 vs. OnePlus Watch 2: Which one is better? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[         <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="d83ca201-ce27-4f35-b1dd-8309f9f1b32d">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MmSNt98mDWNb9A22APSDCb.jpg' alt="Google Pixel Watch 3"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel Watch 3</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>More size options</strong></em></p>
<p>The Google Pixel Watch 3 aims to impress with its 41mm or 45mm Actua AMOLED LTPO display and 5ATM/IP68 rating. The good-looking watch is available in black, champagne gold, or matte hazel. All colors look great and you also get some great features to go along with it.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Fancy design</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Two sizes to choose from</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Smaller bezels</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>You can reuse the older watch straps (41mm)</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>LTE variants are expensive</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Inferior battery</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_versus" data-id="be4fbc40-0752-42c7-b81c-1c533d6b6e35">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JkM9AXnzS7ciSb2yqxfsrU.jpg' alt="OnePlus Watch 2"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">OnePlus Watch 2</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The fancy model</strong></em></p>
<p>The OnePlus Watch 2 significantly improved upon its predecessor and impresses with its dual processor and two operating systems under the stainless steel case. You can use it with a standard 22mm quick-release strap if you have one lying around.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"><div class="list-pros-wrapper"><h4 class="list-pros-label">For</h4><ul class="list-pros"><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Great battery</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Premium stainless steel design</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Dual-band GPS</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Large 1.43-inch AMOLED display</li><li class='list-item list-item-pros'>Features lightweight RTOS and Wear OS</li></ul></div><div class="list-cons-wrapper"><h4 class="list-cons-label">Against</h4><ul class="list-cons"><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No LTE option</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Only one size option</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Useless crown</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>Heavy</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No ECG</li><li class='list-item list-item-cons'>No fall detection</li></ul></div></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<p>The information you&apos;ll get from the Google Pixel Watch 3 vs. OnePlus Watch 2 comparison will hopefully help you choose your next smartwatch. Each wearable has its strengths and weaknesses, but it all comes down to what features are more important to you.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oneplus-watch-2-review">OnePlus Watch 2</a> has been out for a while now, while the Google Pixel Watch 3 is pretty new. Time will tell if the latest Pixel watch is the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wear-os-watch">best Android wearable</a>, but regardless of that, it still has a lot to offer. Here is what each smartwatch has to offer.</p>
<h2 id="google-pixel-watch-3-vs-oneplus-watch-2-design-and-display-2">Google Pixel Watch 3 vs. OnePlus Watch 2: Design and display</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="bRPN7tsgYe3KVTmMaVBWWf" name="google-pixel-watch-3-45mm-on-wrist-morning-brief-exercise.jpg" alt="Morning Brief Exercise Overview on Pixel Watch 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bRPN7tsgYe3KVTmMaVBWWf.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2500" height="1406" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>

<p>Companies try to make their smartwatches as tempting as possible with features that entice you to buy them. For example, Google gives users more options with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-3-hands-on">Pixel Watch 3</a> by offering 41mm or 45 mm models. The 41mm model measures 41 x 12.3mm and weighs 31 grams without the band. However, if bigger is better for you, the 45mm model measures 45 x 12.3mm and weighs 37 grams without the band.</p><p>Google has made the Pixel Watch band available in different colors, such as Porcelain Active, Polished Silver, Rose Quartz, Champagne Gold with a Hazel band, or Matte Black with an Obsidian band. The 45mm model is available in Polished Silver/Porcelain, Matte Black/Obsidian, or Matte Hazel/Hazel Active. </p><p>Google made the Pixel Watch 3 out of 100% recycled aluminum. The latest Pixel Watch also has a haptic crown with a side button, and you can&apos;t forget about the built-in mic and speaker. Thanks to the 5ATM and IP68 water and dust-resistant rating, you can shower with it without worrying about damaging it.</p><p>You&apos;ll enjoy the wearable&apos;s 1.27-inch (41mm or 1.46-inch (45mm) AMOLED display, which offers a 320ppi pixel density on both models. The display tops off at 2,000 nits of brightness alongside a custom 3D Corning Gorilla Glass 5.</p><p>The OnePlus Watch 2, on the other hand, is available in only one 46mm size and two colors, Radiant Steel and Black Steel. You don&apos;t get as many color options with OnePlus, but it still has a very elegant design. OnePlus made the watch out of stainless steel with a fluoro rubber band and stainless steel buckle.</p><p>The Watch 2 measures 47 x 46.6 x 12.1mm (including the 13.65 mm PPG sensor) and weighs 49 grams, excluding the wristband. You can easily change the band and choose from the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-oneplus-watch-2-bands">best OnePlus Watch 2 bands</a>. Its brightness doesn&apos;t match that of its Pixel competitor since it only reaches 600 nits. Thanks to the 5ATM/IP68 rating, you can shower with your watch without worrying about water damage.</p><p>This fancy wearable has a 1.43-inch display with a 466 x 466 resolution, 326 ppi pixel density, 60Hz refresh rate,  and 2.5D Sapphire Crystal cover plate. These specifications give you excellent brightness levels under direct sunlight. </p>
<h2 id="google-pixel-watch-3-vs-oneplus-watch-2-hardware-and-battery-2">Google Pixel Watch 3 vs. OnePlus Watch 2: Hardware and battery</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:42.87%;"><img id="TB2uojYkSL4UFW3itGUpdd" name="oneplus-watch-2-hero2.jpg" alt="OnePlus Watch 2 against red background" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TB2uojYkSL4UFW3itGUpdd.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="878" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The 45mm Google Pixel 3 option features a bigger 420mAh battery than the 41mm option, which has a smaller 307mAh capacity. Google claims that both models should last up to 24 hours. However, Battery Saver mode can allow you to use the wearable for as long as 36 hours. The 41mm model charges fully in an hour, while the bigger option will need about 80 minutes.</p><p>The Pixel Watch 3 has the Snapdragon W5 Gen 1 SoC and a Cortex M33 co-processor on both models to help with everyday tasks. Both sizes include 2GB of RAM and 32GB of onboard storage. GPS, Galileo, and Glonass are featured in both sizes. Google also added sensors such as gyroscopes, barometers, magnetometers, etcetera.</p><p>The OnePlus Watch 2 is powered by the Snapdragon W5 Gen 1 and the BES 2700 chip. It has a bigger 500mAh battery that aims to provide 100 hours of uptime with power-saving features. This watch also packs in many sensors such as a barometer, accelerometer, gyroscope, optical heart rate sensor, and more. The OnePlus Watch 2 matches the Pixel&apos;s 2GB RAM and 32GB storage.</p>
<h2 id="google-pixel-watch-3-vs-oneplus-watch-2-connectivity-and-software-2">Google Pixel Watch 3 vs. OnePlus Watch 2: Connectivity and software</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="ytjYPWvwW9e5xpqWH9c7rZ" name="google-pixel-watch-3-41mm-45mm-with-pixel-buds-pro-2-2.jpg" alt="Pixel Watch 3 41mm and 45mm with Buds Pro 2" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ytjYPWvwW9e5xpqWH9c7rZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2500" height="1406" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Google Pixel Watch 3 features WearOS 5.0 and can track vitals such as SpO2, ECG, heart rate, EDA, sleep, skin temperature, activity, and more. You can use the Pixel Watch to track more than 40 distinct exercises and get readiness insights, such as whether you should rest instead of going on that run.</p><p>This <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-running-watches">excellent running watch</a> includes custom runs with cues like cooldown, pacing, warmup, and real-time guidance with audio and haptic cues. You also get informative performance insights. Google AI analyzes your goals, but you need a Fitbit Premium subscription for that. The good news is that Google throws in a six-month free trial with your Pixel Watch 3 purchase.</p><p>If you&apos;re using a Pixel phone, such as the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-review" target="_blank">Pixel 9 Pro XL</a> or the Pixel 8 Pro, you can use the Pixel Watch 3 to control its camera. You can even use the watch as a viewfinder and switch between different camera modes. You can also view the feed of a compatible Nest Cam and access Google TV.</p><p>The Pixel Watch also has diverse connectivity specs such as Bluetooth 5.3, Wi-Fi 2.4/5GHz, NFC, UWB, LTE (upgrade), GPS, Galileo, Glonass, (ROW) Beidou, QZSS, Navic, and NFC contactless payments. Google also bundles in two years of free cellular data using Google Fi, but you only get a paltry 500MB of data before you see the download speed capped.</p><p>The OnePlus Watch 2 has WearOS 4, and you can use its dual-band GPS (L5 + L1), which is fantastic for pinpointing your location outdoors. Other useful features include Bluetooth 5.0, QZSS support, and RTOS, which optimizes battery life for small tasks.</p><p>Using the OHealth app, you can collect all the health data you need to monitor your health. For example, if you play badminton, you can see how strong and fast your swing is. You can also get detailed data with the sleep-tracking analysis, such as your deep sleep, REM, and wake times. </p><p>Unfortunately, there is no LTE model of the OnePlus Watch 2, but it does offer connectivity options such as Bluetooth 5.3, Wi-Fi, GPS (Dual-frequency L1 + L5), GLONASS, GALILEO, and BeiDou.</p>
<h2 id="google-pixel-watch-3-vs-oneplus-watch-2-which-one-is-the-one-2">Google Pixel Watch 3 vs. OnePlus Watch 2: Which one is THE one?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:5111px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="7CYB4VkaSFhmKx45pLQhJ3" name="google-pixel-watch-3-41mm-45mm-fitbit-quick-start.jpg" alt="Fitbit Quick Start buttons on Pixel Watch 3 41mm and 45mm" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7CYB4VkaSFhmKx45pLQhJ3.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="5111" height="2875" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The watch you go with will depend on the specs you need it to have. For example, if LTE is necessary, your choice might be the Google Pixel 3 since it has an LTE version, unlike the OnePlus Watch, which does not. You also get two size options with the Pixel Watch, while you only get on with the Watch 2. You get one more year of OS updates with the Pixel Watch and have more colors to choose from.</p><p>The OnePlus Watch 2 has a bigger battery than the Pixel Watch 3, so if it&apos;s important not to have to charge your watch as often, you might want to go with the Watch 2. Which one are you more inclined to get?</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="1302e944-d3c7-47b2-939f-18427ead40e2">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sW9CTBf4mfXe5VckiKx9G4.jpg' alt="Render of the Obsidian Google Pixel Watch 3 smartwatch."></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel Watch 3</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The latest Pixel watch</strong></em></p>
<p>You can't go wrong with the Google Pixel Watch 3 since you get the latest Tensor G4 processor and various colors to choose from. There are a lot of AI goodies to have fun with and they can even help you control your Pixel phone.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="52852b4d-ce4f-46ac-bfad-44c650ea672e">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JkM9AXnzS7ciSb2yqxfsrU.jpg' alt="OnePlus Watch 2"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">OnePlus Watch 2</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The fancy watch</strong></em></p>
<p>The OnePlus Watch 2 gives you two processors and two operating systems. You also get a great battery life and robust ingress protection for active users.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-3-vs-oneplus-watch-2</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ After reading the Google Pixel Watch 3 vs. OnePlus Watch 2 comparison and comparing what each watch offers, you can see which watch is best for you. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">MjPYeHQLWGxk4NN8Zq4fvc</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fs5f8mn65hUPZJwc2DbzHS.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 17:57:41 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ yorknectar@gmail.com (Judy Sanhz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fs5f8mn65hUPZJwc2DbzHS.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Two Google Pixel Watch 3s on display at the Made by Google 2024 event.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Two Google Pixel Watch 3s on display at the Made by Google 2024 event.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ How to take a screenshot on the Google Pixel  ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>When you take a screenshot of the Google Pixel, you can quickly save what&apos;s on your display. You can choose from different methods to take a screenshot, whether it involves buttons or not. There is the button combination method or the one where you tell Google to take it for you.</p><p>If you have one of the latest <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-review">Google Pixel 9 series</a> models or older and this is your first time using a Pixel, the following tutorial will show you all the options you can choose from when taking screenshots on your Pixel. Google makes some of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="http://androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a> out there, especially thanks to its Pixel UI, which offers plenty of ways to take screenshots other than buttons.</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-take-a-screenshot-using-buttons"><span>Take a screenshot using buttons</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="Z5KNrcCMbUhFPuPjzcTQde" name="google-pixel-6-side-view-buttons.jpg" alt="Side view of the Google Pixel 6 and its buttons" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Z5KNrcCMbUhFPuPjzcTQde.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The first method you can try to take screenshots is straightforward and is usually the first method many turn to on various <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phones</a>. The button combination is quick and easy, so you can try it by doing the following.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-take-a-screenshot-on-the-google-pixel-using-buttons-2">How to take a screenshot on the Google Pixel using buttons</h2>
<p>1. Hold down the <strong>power </strong>and <strong>volume down buttons</strong> on the phone&apos;s right side.</p><p>2. <strong>Release</strong> both buttons at the <strong>same time</strong>.</p><p>3. Your Pixel will make a snapping sound, and a miniature version of your screen will appear on the bottom left-hand side of the screen.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="DrERM72e8fTjt8gM3BQRna" name="google-pixel-6-screenshot.jpg" alt="Taking a screenshot on a Google Pixel 6" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DrERM72e8fTjt8gM3BQRna.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>If you performed the combination correctly, you should see a smaller version of the screen you took and a notification. Tap the share or edit buttons to access your screenshot.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-take-a-scrolling-screenshot-2">How to take a scrolling screenshot</h2>
<p>Taking a screenshot of what&apos;s on your screen isn&apos;t always enough, but that&apos;s when you can try a scrolling screenshot. You can easily take one by </p><p>1. Using the button combination (<strong>Power + volume down</strong>).</p><p>2. Besides the <strong>thumbnail preview</strong>, you&apos;ll see an option called <strong>Capture more</strong>.</p><p>3.<strong> Drag the screenshot window</strong> until you crop what you need. A magnifying glass on the side will show you what information the screenshot will include.</p><p>4. Tap the <strong>Save button</strong>. You&apos;ll also see an option to share or edit your screenshot.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3024px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:74.21%;"><img id="oqBwEsucCYfahyANfgtgKb" name="scrolling-screenshot-pixel.jpg" alt="The capture more button to get a scrolling screenshot and the preview window" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oqBwEsucCYfahyANfgtgKb.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="3024" height="2244" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nick Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-take-a-screenshot-without-buttons"><span>Take a screenshot without buttons</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="caKocMqdZz3Gex36g8Cz9L" name="google-pixel-7-pro-review-29.jpg" alt="Google Pixel 7 Pro home screen full view against green background" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/caKocMqdZz3Gex36g8Cz9L.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>There are several methods to take screenshots without using the hardware buttons. These depend on the type of navigation you are using on the Google Pixel. For reference, here are the different navigation methods available on Google Pixel:</p><p>1. Gesture navigation</p><p>2. Three-button navigation</p><p>3. Back tap gestures</p><p>4. Google Assistant</p>
<h2 id="how-to-take-a-screenshot-on-the-google-pixel-with-gesture-navigation-2">How to take a screenshot on the Google Pixel with gesture navigation</h2>
<p>1. <strong>Swipe up and hold</strong> from the bottom of the screen.</p><p>2. Tap the <strong>Screenshot</strong> button at the bottom when the App Switcher is revealed.</p><p>3. A preview will appear in the bottom left corner once successful.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2416px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:71.77%;"><img id="4kcPLWrAWCocPnJ8oDpaUG" name="How to take a screenshot on the Google Pixel with gesture navigation.jpg" alt="How to take a screenshot on the Google Pixel with gesture navigation" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4kcPLWrAWCocPnJ8oDpaUG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="2416" height="1734" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<h2 id="how-to-take-a-screenshot-on-the-google-pixel-with-three-button-navigation-2">How to take a screenshot on the Google Pixel with three-button navigation</h2>
<p>1. Tap the <strong>square Overview button</strong> in your navigation bar.</p><p>2. <strong>Swipe over to the app</strong> that you wish to screenshot.</p><p>3. Tap the <strong>Screenshot</strong> button.</p><p>4. A preview will appear in the bottom left corner once successful.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:72.17%;"><img id="icbSbFzvvWKPV8NWD8b8LX" name="How to take a screenshot on the Google Pixel with 3-button navigation.jpg" alt="How to take a screenshot on the Google Pixel with 3-button navigation" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/icbSbFzvvWKPV8NWD8b8LX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="2400" height="1732" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<h2 id="how-to-take-a-screenshot-on-the-google-pixel-with-back-tap-gestures-2">How to take a screenshot on the Google Pixel with back tap gestures</h2>
<p>You can <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-customize-back-tap-gestures-google-pixel-phone">customize the back tap gestures on your Google Pixel</a> phone so that they take screenshots. Once you have assigned the screenshot function to the back tap gesture, you must tap the back twice. Here&apos;s how to customize your Pixel&apos;s back tap gesture to take screenshots when you tap the rear twice.</p>
<p>1. Open <strong>Settings</strong> on your Pixel.</p><p>2. Tap <strong>System</strong>.</p><p>3. Select <strong>Gestures</strong> to locate the relevant options.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3228px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:74.35%;"><img id="3ecd5GVNpFteYZVpScdAW3" name="pixel-back-tap-gesture-1.jpg" alt="How to customize the Google Pixel's back tap gestures" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3ecd5GVNpFteYZVpScdAW3.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="3228" height="2400" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>4. Once you&apos;re in the gestures settings, tap <strong>Quick Tap</strong>.</p><p>5. Make sure the <strong>Use Quick Tap</strong> toggle is switched on.</p><p>6. Select <strong>Take screenshot</strong>.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3224px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:74.44%;"><img id="j8Xc6g2KENvHFrbRaHukgA" name="pixel-back-tap-gesture-screenshot-1.jpg" alt="How to customize the Google Pixel's back tap gestures" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/j8Xc6g2KENvHFrbRaHukgA.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="3224" height="2400" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<h2 id="how-to-take-a-screenshot-on-the-google-pixel-with-google-assistant-2">How to take a screenshot on the Google Pixel with Google Assistant</h2>
<p>In 2017, Google introduced the ability to use Google Assistant to snap screenshots with nothing but your voice, a feature that had been long anticipated. Here&apos;s how to take a screenshot with Google Assistant.</p>
<p>1. Say <strong>Hey Google</strong>.</p><p>2. When ready, say <strong>Take a screenshot</strong>.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2240px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:77.32%;"><img id="TTZCct86cXA9Ghr7ofKdtC" name="How to take a screenshot on the Google Pixel with Google Assistant.jpg" alt="How to take a screenshot on the Google Pixel with Google Assistant" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TTZCct86cXA9Ghr7ofKdtC.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="2240" height="1732" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>To activate Google Assistant, you can press the Power button for a second or swipe inward from the bottom corners of the display.</p><p>If you try to activate Google Assistant in every possible way but don&apos;t get an answer, here is how to check if you have it enabled.</p><p>1. Go to Settings </p><p>2. Select Google</p><p>3. Tap the All services tab</p><p>4. Choose Settings for Google apps </p><p>5. Select the Search, Assistant & Voice option</p><p>6. Google Assistant</p><p>7. Hey Google & Voice Match</p><p>8. Toggle on Hey Google</p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-how-to-access-your-screenshots"><span>How to access your screenshots</span></h3>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="VYUdxSNnMbs6wPzZqhwon3" name="google-photos-pxel-6-pro-lifestyle.jpg" alt="Google Photos app on a Pixel 6 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VYUdxSNnMbs6wPzZqhwon3.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nick Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<h2 id="how-to-access-the-screenshot-you-took-on-the-google-pixel-2">How to access the screenshot you took on the Google Pixel</h2>
<p>Right after taking a screenshot, you&apos;ll see a tiny thumbnail in the left-hand corner of your Pixel&apos;s display that shows a miniature version of the image. You can access the screengrab you just took by tapping the preview.</p>
<p>1. In the bottom right corner, <strong>tap the preview</strong> of the screenshot you just took.</p><p>2. If you want to <strong>edit</strong> the image, tap the <strong>pencil icon</strong>.</p><p>3. Alternatively, tap the <strong>Share</strong> button to send the screenshot to someone or share it via an app.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1238px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:69.95%;"><img id="TgHrji9YEaaD7KZifRkyv4" name="How to access the screenshot you took on your Pixel.jpg" alt="How to access the screenshot you took on your Pixel" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TgHrji9YEaaD7KZifRkyv4.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1238" height="866" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<h2 id="how-to-access-all-of-your-screenshots-on-the-google-pixel-2">How to access all of your screenshots on the Google Pixel</h2>
<p>If you were too late and the thumbnail disappeared, don&apos;t worry. It isn&apos;t gone forever! Screenshots are stored in a designated Google Pixel folder and accessible through the Photos app.</p>
<p>1. Open <strong>Google Photos</strong> from the home screen, folder, or app drawer.</p><p>2. Tap the <strong>Collections</strong> button in the bottom toolbar.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:713px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:112.20%;"><img id="og3nLZ33icfF6MvwZdbvm9" name="Pixel-Screenshot.jpg" alt="New layout of Google Photos and the Collections tab." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/og3nLZ33icfF6MvwZdbvm9.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="713" height="800" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Myrick / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>3. Under the <strong>Photos on device</strong> section, tap <strong>Screenshots</strong>. You can also tap the Screenshots option directly.</p><p>4. Open or share the screenshot or screenshots you want.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="keep-capturing-2">Keep capturing</h2>
<p>Screenshots are possible on all phones. Once you have all the necessary screenshots, you can <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-quickly-find-screenshots-google-photos">access them in Google Photos</a>. It&apos;s good that you have different methods, just in case you&apos;re having issues with one. You might be using Google Photos more often since you might not resist taking many pictures of the latest Pixel 9 series phones, including the Pixel 9, 9 Pro, and 9 Pro XL. Older-gen Pixels are spectacular at photography too, so this applies to Google phones universally.</p><p>If you want the Pixel with the best camera out of the series, you can choose the 9 Pro or 9 Pro XL. They have the same specs and share a 50MP wide camera, a 48MP ultrawide camera with autofocus, and a 48MP telephoto camera. The Pixel 9 Pro lacks a 48MP telephoto camera.</p><p>To access your screenshots, you can take the long or short way by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-photos-new-screenshot-folder-shortcut" target="_blank">long-pressing on the Google Photos app icon</a>. Remember to double-check which screenshots you&apos;re erasing before they are permanently removed. You may also need instructions on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://forums.androidcentral.com/threads/how-to-recover-delete-photos-from-android.1006910/">how to recover deleted photos from Android</a>.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="30177545-b383-4018-9d50-64c76d78fd81">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Epz84yteXYHhCgKXftnMDm.jpg' alt="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL official render - Rose Quartz - front and back"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Google Pixel 9 Pro XL</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>The Google-iest Google phone ever</strong></em></p>
<p>With the Pixel 9 Pro and 9 Pro XL, Google has achieved next-level finesse and elegance. Equipped with state-of-the-art cameras, a large display, and Google's improved custom silicone, the Pixel 9 Pro XL checks all of the boxes and then some.</p></p>
                </div>
                
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/how-take-screenshot-google-pixel</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ It's easy to take a screenshot on the Google Pixel, but finding them can sometimes be challenging. Here's how to do both! ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">vRQJvjQMQAB1CNEs7mkUaA</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bCYgC5mMBiLLuJeH6hW4ck.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 17:15:22 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ andrew.myrick@futurenet.com (Andrew Myrick) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bCYgC5mMBiLLuJeH6hW4ck.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Pixel Screenshot]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Pixel Screenshot]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>