<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 17:06:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Android 15 has tools to fix washed-out SDR content on HDR displays. What does that even mean? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/ultra-hdr-explained">HDR</a> is a tech buzzword. Much like "AI" and "X% faster," it&apos;s one of those things we hear about every product, and none of the companies making them ever bother to tell us why it matters.</p><p>What&apos;s different about it is that you probably do care about having it, even if you have no idea what it means beyond "content looks better." <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a> has a set of tools for developers that will make that content look even better as long as an app developer cares enough to use them.</p>
<p>Specifically, I&apos;m talking about this cryptic bit from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2024/09/android-15-is-released-to-aosp.html">the release notes</a>:</p><p>"For screens that contain both HDR and SDR content, Android 15 allows you to control the HDR headroom with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://developer.android.com/reference/kotlin/android/view/Window?hl=en#setdesiredhdrheadroom" target="_blank">setDesiredHdrHeadroom</a> to prevent SDR content from appearing too washed-out."</p><p>I&apos;m sure Google&apos;s explanation tells you everything you need to know, and you&apos;re excited to see this great new feature in your phone and favorite apps. If you&apos;re developing apps that show this type of content, that&apos;s true, but for the rest of us, it takes a bit more explaining.</p>
<h2 id="hdr-vs-sdr-2">HDR vs. SDR</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:137.41%;"><img id="ikifqSmfoXz7UDMH2FguuA" name="Android-HDR-screen-example.jpg" alt="Side by side comparison of HDR10 video on Google Camera app." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ikifqSmfoXz7UDMH2FguuA.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1080" height="1484" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The "DR" in HDR and SDR stands for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dynamic_range">dynamic range</a>; HDR has <em>high</em> dynamic range, and SDR has <em>standard</em> dynamic range. The dynamic range of a display has an upper end of brightness and a lower end of brightness. Any content falling outside this range will not be displayed using the correct color and contrast.</p><p>You have seen this in action, and it&apos;s easy to demonstrate. This evening go outside and take a picture of the sunset. Look at the photo and compare it to what your eyes actually see and you&apos;ll find a lot of detail and colors just aren&apos;t quite right. those bits have fallen outside the dynamic range of the camera, the display, or both.</p>
<p>To use numbers, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.viewsonic.com/library/photography/what-is-hdr-hdr-vs-sdr/#:~:text=High%20Dynamic%20Range%20(HDR)%20is,Standard%20Dynamic%20Range%20(SDR).">ViewSonic gave me a quick answer</a> when I went looking for them. An SDR ViewSonic display has a dynamic range of about <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://exposuretherapy.ca/what-is-the-stop-in-photography/#:~:text=In%20photography%2C%20a%20stop%20is,same%20as%20dividing%20by%20two.)">6 stops</a>, and an HDR ViewSonic display has a dynamic range of about 17.6 stops. The display on your phone may not use the same numbers, but they will be comparable. You&apos;ll notice HDR can display a lot more colors than SDR.</p><p>Yes, all this translates into colors. Inside the dynamic range of the display, you can <em>mostly</em> see individual colors. With an HDR display, you can see more bright colors and darker colors. Viewing the same content on an SDR display means those colors are going to mix — grey looks like black, ivory looks like white, you see fewer shades of yellow, etc.</p><p>In short, you want a good HDR display on your phone, TV, or computer because you want the colors and brightness to look "right."</p>
<h2 id="when-you-cross-the-streams-2">When you cross the streams</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:62.50%;"><img id="kpA5necQNWRh7MS8kcrVHR" name="HDR-SDR-Crystal-Red-Shrimp.jpg" alt="HDR vs. SDR" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kpA5necQNWRh7MS8kcrVHR.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="600" height="375" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="caption-text"> Photo showing content saved with an SDR profile then displayed as an HDR image versus doing it the right way. </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Jerry Hildenbrand)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The real problems arise when you try to set a display using HDR data but then display SDR content on it. </p><p>SDR content has already lost all the color and contrast information outside of its dynamic range. It&apos;s simply not there. That&apos;s fine when it&apos;s being displayed as SDR content, but as soon as your screen expects HDR content with a broader range of information about what it should show, it&apos;s left with a big chunk of missing data.</p><p>If AI has taught us anything, it&apos;s what happens when a computer doesn&apos;t have the right data but has to give a result anyway — <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-search-ai-overview-problems">it makes stuff up</a>.</p>
<p>Your phone is usually smart enough to know what kind of content is being displayed and will correctly display both SDR and HDR imagery without any input from you. Sometimes, though, an app will need to display both types of content at the same time. Apps like social media, photo storage and galleries, or even a web browser showing an image picker can often have both types of images on the same page.</p><p>Inevitably, the SDR content gets washed out. That can mean the darker parts of the image turn all muddy and mix into a single color, or the lighter parts do the opposite. Everything above or below the range threshold is either white or black, or the whole image looks like it has a dull filter over it. Generally, it just looks bad.</p>
<p>Most of the time, this is just a minor inconvenience and really doesn&apos;t matter. Sure, we want everything to look great, but if a photo or two on a page of thumbnails looks goofy, it&apos;s not a big deal, especially if once you open one, the image is displayed correctly.</p><p>For other folks who might earn a living through their content, it has to be displayed correctly. A photographer needs the photo gallery on their phone to give an accurate rendition of how that content looks. A videographer might need to know if they should change their settings by looking at the thumbnails of the clips. Or maybe it just bugs you, and you want it to look correct.</p>
<p>With Android 15, developers writing apps that display content can set the app to try and not wash out those SDR images but still allow HDR images to "pop" because they show a better, brighter image. However, that&apos;s only if developers bother to implement it; you can lead a horse to water.</p><p>By default, your phone knows the right amount of brightness and contrast increase that should happen when showing HDR content but developers <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://developer.android.com/reference/kotlin/android/view/Window?hl=en#setColorMode(kotlin.Int)">can have some control</a> inside their apps. Now, they have even more control to try and keep all content looking the best it can.</p><p>These are the kinds of little things we&apos;ll see more and more of with each new Android version. The hard part—building an operating system that works well and has the features we all want—is mostly done, so it&apos;s time to fine-tune everything to make it even better.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-has-tools-to-fix-washed-out-sdr-content-on-hdr-displays-what-does-that-even-mean</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ You've seen washed-out images in your apps even if you didn't realize it. Android 15 tries to fix it but developers have to do the work. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">2xSXwoV7fdDgq7nF6LKzzk</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xPtVdNFY49NWAQihjdSeNa.gif" type="image/gif" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 15:46:59 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/gif" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xPtVdNFY49NWAQihjdSeNa.gif">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Photos video HDR]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Photos video HDR]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Looking for the perfect back-to-school kids' watch? You don't need an Apple Watch SE. ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Most public schools are starting back up this week, and many parents want to find a kids&apos; smartwatch that (A) lets them keep in touch, (B) can track their location if they leave school unexpectedly, and (C) prevents having to buy their kid a smartphone for another few years.</p><p>Many people buy an affordable Apple Watch SE for this purpose since they can set it up via their own iPhone, set Schooltime activity blocks, and create makeshift geofencing with the Find My app. The problem is that this is a fully functional smartwatch for adults; you have to be more purposeful about setting it up and supervising its use so it&apos;s not too unrestricted or complicated for your kid.</p><p>Thankfully, we can point you to an alternative that&apos;s explicitly designed for kids: the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fitbit-ace-lte-review">Fitbit Ace LTE</a>. It launched this summer and immediately became the favorite of Android Central&apos;s resident Dad-tech expert Nick Sutrich. It&apos;s a watch that keeps things simple and enjoyable for your young&apos;un while giving you peace of mind.</p>
<h2 id="why-we-recommend-this-fitbit-watch-for-your-kid-2">Why we recommend this Fitbit watch for your kid</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="XaVTvPAySzLpDikR82eH8f" name="fitbit-ace-lte-wearing-02.jpg" alt="A child wearing the Fitbit Ace LTE" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XaVTvPAySzLpDikR82eH8f.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Fitbit Ace LTE is essentially a squircle <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-2-review">Pixel Watch 2</a> running a stripped-down Wear OS interface that (unlike the Pixel Watch) can still connect with parents&apos; iPhones, as well as <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phones</a>. It&apos;s fast, comfortable on small kids&apos; wrists, has cute games that encourage activity, and keeps track of their location.</p><p>As Nick explains in his <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-bounce-best-watch-for-kids-in-school">Fitbit Ace LTE review</a>, most <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/best-kids-smartwatch">kids watches</a> are designed like plastic toys, or something you&apos;d see in a 50s sci-fi show. They&apos;re "thick and chonky," and the unoptimized software is just as unsightly. They fulfill their purpose and let kids stay in touch, but they&apos;re not going to enjoy wearing them once the novelty wears off.</p><p>But Fitbit has been making slim squircles and coding its popular Fitbit OS for over a decade — well before Google acquired it — and that expertise comes across in the Ace LTE. While it comes with a thick bumper case if your kid gets too rough with their toys, it&apos;s "so darn sleek looking" by itself, so kids will <em>feel</em> like they&apos;re wearing an "adult" smartwatch.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:540px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.30%;"><img id="n3P8pEbJcFSCJoyqU2dojR" name="fitbit-ace-lte-fishing.gif" alt="Playing the fishing game on a Fitbit Ace LTE" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/n3P8pEbJcFSCJoyqU2dojR.gif" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="540" height="304" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="caption-text">A fishing game on the Fitbit Ace LTE </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Under the surface, the Ace LTE software is tailor-made for kids to hit their 60 minutes of activity a day; finishing quests like step goals or just moving around instead of sitting will net them "movement points" that they can cash in to play games. Nick&apos;s kid loves the space strategy game that has him point his wrist to fire attacks at ships, but he knows he can&apos;t start the next level unless he gets active first.</p><p>You can also use those points on your Eejie, which Nick calls "a sort of Tamagotchi-meets-Animal Crossing-type virtual pet." Gaining points lets you customize your Eejie in fun ways so kids have a visual incentive to stay fit. </p><p>Unlike more adult-focused fitness watches that track complicated metrics, the Fitbit Ace LTE keeps things simple: steps, floors, light activity, and moderate-to-vigorous activity. It doesn&apos;t have tools like sleep tracking or manual workouts that any other Fitbit can manage, which feels like an intentional decision to avoid overcomplicating things, distracting kids with a screen at night, or stressing parents out about kids&apos; sleep habits.</p><p>In a similar vein, the Fitbit Ace LTE deliberately limits the amount of screen time kids can get, with five minutes or so of earned gaming time after 20+ minutes of activity. My colleague argued that parents should be allowed to tweak this ratio to make the screen incentive a bit more fun, but at least you won&apos;t have to worry about the Ace becoming a time-suck distraction for your kid.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="Y3vRauNmyR9PjzVTSwt67b" name="fitbit ace lte calls messages.jpg" alt="Fitbit Ace LTE" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Y3vRauNmyR9PjzVTSwt67b.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="450" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Really, all of this is just window dressing, meant to make your kid feel good about staying active at a young age instead of sitting around watching YouTube. The main reason to buy any kids smartwatch is to give them a way to call or text you (and other family members) without giving them a phone.</p><p>Unlike with a smartphone, you don&apos;t need to worry about your kid getting messaged by strangers. The Fitbit Ace LTE calls dedicated contacts set up via the Android/iOS Fitbit Ace app; if you want your kid to be able to call or message, say, a grandparent or sibling, they&apos;ll also need a smartphone with the Fitbit Ace app and a Google account, which is only a downside if your family members aren&apos;t tech-savvy.</p><p>You&apos;ll need the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fitbit/whats-included-with-the-fitbit-ace-pass-subscription">Fitbit Ace Pass subscription</a> for LTE calling; it can still call over wi-fi, but you&apos;ll want cellular connectivity for things like broadcasting your kid&apos;s real-time location through the Fitbit Ace app. It&apos;s a relief for parents to be able to check, though unfortunately, Fitbit hasn&apos;t implemented a geofencing tool that auto-notifies you if the kid leaves a designated area, like the school grounds. </p><p>Geofencing is the <em>one</em> feature found on other kids watches like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/t-mobile-syncup-kids-watch-review">T-Mobile SyncUp</a> or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-bounce-kids-watch-review-the-fun-smartwatch-for-kids#section-how-it-works">Garmin Bounce</a> that we wish the Fitbit Ace LTE offered, too. But hopefully, you&apos;ll be satisfied with the ability to check your kid&apos;s location at any time, such as if you lose track of them in a store or at the park.</p>
<hr>
<p>Last year, we <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-bounce-best-watch-for-kids-in-school">recommended the Garmin Bounce</a> as the back-to-school watch to beat, and it&apos;s still a great option. It&apos;s cheaper (with the same monthly fee for LTE calling), better for battery life, and fitness-focused. But if you can afford the Fitbit Ace LTE, it&apos;s arguably better for both hardware and software.</p><p>Google is continuing to update the Ace LTE, adding an NFC tap-to-pay feature — with approval from parents, of course — new games, and a promised feature to let kids message other kids with Ace LTE watches later this year. This gives us hope that it may receive updates like geofencing down the line; even without it, this is a great kids watch that should last you through multiple school years.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="c35672ce-5826-4e01-ae95-dcaff8a59783">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Xonqwbik4gYFi7koY23K8k.jpg' alt="Fitbit Ace LTE with Courtside Band render"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Fitbit Ace LTE</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Keep your kid safe, healthy, and happy.</strong></em></p>
<p>Continuous step and activity tracking will ensure your kid is staying healthy and reward them with interactive games and virtual pet perks. Beyond that, you'll get wi-fi or LTE calling, messaging, and location tracking, all packed into a stylish watch with hardware that's built to last.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/why-fitbit-ace-lte-is-best-back-to-school-kids-watch</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Plenty of parents buy their kids an Apple Watch SE in lieu of a smartphone, but we'll point those parents towards the Fitbit Ace LTE (or Garmin Bounce, if you need geofencing) instead. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">jsHErNHmPYQbucr9mCbZJ7</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8mqw4BjCbnGBBYPNxhYHHA.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 15:46:03 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/8mqw4BjCbnGBBYPNxhYHHA.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Customizing the Eejie on a Fitbit Ace LTE]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Customizing the Eejie on a Fitbit Ace LTE]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Qualcomm is chasing Google when it comes to AI and your battery will be the victim ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-tensor-g4-is-a-key-piece-of-googles-smartphone-vision">Google&apos;s Tensor G4 chip</a> is mediocre in every way but one. It&apos;s not as powerful as competing products from Qualcomm, MediaTek, or Apple. It doesn&apos;t have the same GPU that spits out numbers faster than software can use them. It&apos;s not even very efficient. It&apos;s not <em>bad,</em> and it certainly does its job in ways almost everyone can appreciate, but it&apos;s not some over-the-top super chip.</p><p>Except when it comes to AI. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/pixel-9-new-google-ai-features-claims">Google&apos;s AI</a> in particular. Google has complete iron-fist-level control over its entire AI stack. It writes the software, designs the algorithms, controls what parts are off-loaded to a cloud-based server and it designed the NPU inside its in-house processor to best take advantage of it all. </p><p>The only company that might do something comparable would be Apple, once it weans itself off its dependence on OpenAI. Samsung could do it, but it is in the business of selling electronics and not building out AI tech on such a scale or working on its own mobile operating system.</p>
<p>Other companies are certainly capable of making advanced AI-capable chips. Qualcomm can do it and is doing it. They do a good job at it, too, by all accounts. Certainly, a good enough job to include much of Google&apos;s AI features alongside other features from companies like Samsung on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24">Galaxy S24</a>. </p><p>I&apos;m concerned, though, about the news that Qualcomm is going even harder into AI with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-4-launch-details">Snapdragon 8 Gen 4</a> and that Samsung <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-bye-exynos-qualcomm-galaxy-s25-rumor">reportedly seems determined to use it</a> in every <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25">Galaxy S25</a> around the world. Not because it won&apos;t be capable or because I think Samsung should use a different chip.</p><p>The power for all this has to come from somewhere.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="cJgunLzMZSirHU5Rxjmk7N" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-Ultra-back-titanium-03.jpg" alt="The back of the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra in the Titanium Grey colorway" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/cJgunLzMZSirHU5Rxjmk7N.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Supposedly, insiders know that devices using the Gen 4 will need <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/snapdragon-8-gen-4-power-hungry-rumor">6,000mAh batteries</a> because the chip is very power-hungry. High-density batteries using unnamed materials are close to reaching those numbers but who knows when this tech will be ready for release.</p><p>Samsung will want to make the S25 as thin as possible because phone makers are convinced we want even thinner phones. Other manufacturers will follow the same playbook, even if it means using too-small batteries.</p>
<p>Often, we&apos;re told how easy and fast it is to top your phone off during the day because it <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/ask-jerry-does-fast-charging-hurt-my-phone-battery">charges so quickly</a> whenever battery life is brought into question. That&apos;s a poor substitute for a bigger battery, especially for anyone who isn&apos;t around an outlet all day long. As a crutch, we need to buy <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/best-high-capacity-power-banks">portable batteries</a> or deal with a phone that doesn&apos;t last long enough.</p><p>The answer is obvious, even if it will never happen. Make the phone thicker and include a bigger battery. If you insist on incorporating so much AI you need a chip capable of running it fast enough, you need to provide it. Or simply forgo some of the AI and realize that Google simply has an advantage in that space. Samsung doesn&apos;t need to match Google with AI to build a great product or even one that&apos;s better.</p>
<p>Google is never going to license its tensor SoC design nor will it try to write Android in a way that doesn&apos;t leverage its AI capabilities. That&apos;s Google&apos;s advantage and it knows it.</p><p>Forcing a phone that won&apos;t run all day without charging on your customers is not the solution and nobody is asking for AI features that might make it happen.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/qualcomm-is-chasing-google-when-it-comes-to-ai-and-your-battery-will-be-the-victim</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ When phone makers want everything to be thin and chipmakers want even more power you're left buying a battery pack. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">MRFUsEgyGh4w3423Dkk4T4</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/n2uCyiNeV2pEi36AmQyTXc.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 15:45:45 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/n2uCyiNeV2pEi36AmQyTXc.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[null]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Aukey 26800 Battery Pack Box]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Aukey 26800 Battery Pack Box]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Govee’s Curtain Lights 2 are here to turn your home decor dreams into reality ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Govee has launched its new Curtain Lights 2, which takes its "refined lighting display" further with 520 light beads, stronger computing power, and 10 canvas layers.</li><li>The device features "AI Lighting Bot" and the ability for users to upload a custom image or GIF to display on the Curtain Lights 2.</li><li>The Govee Curtain Lights 2 can be purchased as a single pack for $149, a double pack for $259, or a triple pack for $399.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Govee today unveiled a new set of smart curtains that promise to elevate your home to a whole new level of fancy.</p><p>In a press release, Govee boasts that the second-gen Curtain Lights come with a "refined lighting display" thanks to enhanced computing power and storage. The big win here is improved GIF performance, with "richer" and more detailed patterns plus an expanded 10 canvas layers.</p><p>The device features a new chip and 520 light beads. Govee also offers two-pack and three-pack options so you can really amp up your colorful displays.</p><p>Taking the Curtain Lights 2&apos;s enriched experience even further is its improved DIY effects.</p><p>The company promises an easier setup with a streamlined customization section. There’s a DIY material library with Govee’s own elements to jazz up your Curtain Lights 2, or you can upload your own photos or GIFs and see them come to life.</p><p>Another new addition for the Curtain Lights 2 is Govee&apos;s first steps into AI via the "AI Lighting Bot." The company states this lets consumers utilize its voice commands alongside a text-based option to control the device. Not only can users control the Curtain Lights 2, but they can also "create" new designs and patterns using this AI tool.</p><p>The AI can aid in creating "static lighting effects." However, Govee informs that the "gif/dynamic lighting effect is coming soon." The company adds that the Curtain Lights 2 is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://us.govee.com/pages/govee-dreamview-release">fully compatible with DreamView</a> for a "fully immersive experience."</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1361px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:44.09%;"><img id="Tww2nmErwDsuBZiB2M4HkG" name="govee-curtain-lights-2-palm-tree-cover.jpg" alt="The Govee Curtain Lights 2 box with palm tree cover art." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Tww2nmErwDsuBZiB2M4HkG.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1361" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Govee)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Installation is a breeze with the Curtain Lights 2, which can be used indoors or outdoors. Both the lights and control box have an IP65 waterproof rating. Govee has also thrown in hooks, adhesives, tape, and installation strips to help you set it up anywhere around the house.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/matter">Matter support</a> is another aspect of the Curtain Lights 2 that separates it from the original model. Now, users can pair the device with other ecosystems like Google Home, Amazon Alexa, and Apple HomeKit. To make pairing seamless, users can scan the provided QR code to get started on their network.</p><p>Those interested in the Govee Curtain Lights 2 can pick it up in a single pack for $149. Its double pack starts at $259 while the triple pack sits at $399.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/smart-home/govee-curtain-lights-2-ai-diy-launch</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Govee highlighted the launch of its Curtain Lights 2 smart home product with improved computing power for an immersive display. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">GREUynYya5tQsdwdHN7DaW</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NfvsUURYVJwt29PD5qHqKU.png" type="image/png" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 14:00:46 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Smart Home]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/png" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NfvsUURYVJwt29PD5qHqKU.png">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Govee]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Govee Curtain Lights 2.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Govee Curtain Lights 2.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Samsung's new Galaxy Book 5 Pro brings together AI smarts and premium hardware ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung’s Galaxy Book 5 Pro 360 packs a serious 47 TOPS of NPU power and runs on the Intel Core Ultra Series 2, which is four times more powerful than the last model.</li><li>The 16.0-inch Dynamic AMOLED 2X screen is stunning with its 2880×1800 resolution, 500 nits HDR brightness, and 120Hz refresh rate.</li><li>It includes over 300 AI-driven features across 100+ apps for everything from work to play.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Samsung has launched the Galaxy Book 5 Pro 360, kicking off the new Galaxy Book series with Copilot+ tech and blending AI right into the user experience.</p><p>The Galaxy Book 5 Pro 360 is the first in Samsung’s new Galaxy Book 5 series. With its Copilot+ features, it packs a hefty 47 TOPS of NPU power, letting it handle all kinds of AI-driven apps, not just those from Microsoft.</p><p>It gets its impressive power from the Intel Core Ultra Series 2 processor, which has four times the NPU capacity of the previous model, as per Samsung&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://news.samsung.com/global/embrace-ai-with-galaxy-book5-pro-360-the-first-in-samsungs-lineup-of-new-powerhouse-ai-pcs" target="_blank">press release</a>. Plus, it’s ready for Wi-Fi 7, so it’s set to keep up with the latest networking tech and stay ahead of the curve.</p><p>The Pro 360 sports a 16.0-inch Dynamic AMOLED 2X display that’s basically showing off with its 2880×1800 WQXGA+ resolution. It’s a visual treat with 500 nits of HDR brightness, 120% DCI-P3 color coverage, and a slick 120Hz adaptive refresh rate, all enhanced by Vision Booster tech.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:66.67%;"><img id="4KdivJcVstBJEQC52oJmiK" name="Samsung-Mobile-Galaxy-Book5-Pro-360-screen.jpg" alt="Galaxy Book5 360 Pro screen" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4KdivJcVstBJEQC52oJmiK.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4500" height="3000" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Samsung)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Furthermore, the device is loaded with over 300 AI-enhanced features spread across more than 100 apps, covering everything from productivity to playtime.</p><p>Built for on-the-go ease, the device is just 355.4 x 252.2 x 12.8mm and tips the scales at only 1.69 kg. You can choose between 16GB or 32GB of memory and go for either 512GB or 1TB of storage to fit all your digital demands.</p><p>It also packs a 2MP camera for HD video, dual mics, and quad speakers with Dolby Atmos for a rich sound experience. Running on Windows 11 Home, it’s secured with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/what-samsung-knox">Samsung Knox</a> and all the built-in Windows protections.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:66.67%;"><img id="W4UDuEWgM8XcvfPSPWJrvH" name="Samsung-Mobile-Galaxy-Book5-Pro-360-back.jpg" alt="Galaxy Book5 360 Pro back" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/W4UDuEWgM8XcvfPSPWJrvH.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4500" height="3000" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Samsung)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Additional features include a 2MP camera for high-definition video, dual microphones, and quad speakers with Dolby Atmos for an immersive audio experience. It runs on Windows 11 Home and comes with Samsung Knox plus all the standard Windows security features.</p><p>Connectivity-wise, the laptop has Bluetooth v5.4 and Wi-Fi 7, plus a bunch of ports: USB-A (3.2), HDMI 2.1, two Thunderbolt 4s, a Micro SD slot, and a headphone/mic combo. It’s got a big 76Wh battery that&apos;s promised to last up to 25 hours of video and charges super-fast with a 65W USB Type-C adapter.</p><p>As part of its ecosystem, the laptop connects effortlessly with Microsoft Phone Link, so you can mirror your <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-samsung-phones">Galaxy phone</a>’s screen and tap into <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-galaxy-ai">Galaxy AI</a> features like Circle to Search and Live Translate, among others.</p><p>Samsung hasn’t revealed the price yet, but the Galaxy Book 5 Pro 360 is landing in Canada, France, Germany, the UK, and the U.S. this month.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/chromebooks-laptops/samsungs-new-galaxy-book-5-pro-brings-together-ai-smarts-and-premium-hardware</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung's Galaxy Book 5 Pro 360 is a beast with an Intel Core Ultra processor and 47 TOPS of NPU power. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">eXCojTpnj6jUu9tcyaxBkF</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/B8Vdg97rK84ZtM35FZdqJ5.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 13:42:56 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Chromebooks &amp; Laptops]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/B8Vdg97rK84ZtM35FZdqJ5.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Samsung]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Galaxy Book5 Pro 360 screen]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Galaxy Book5 Pro 360 screen]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Exclusive: Honor is using AI to try to reverse your nearsightedness ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Until last year, I was a person who never needed to wear glasses. But life eventually caught up to me, and a combination of age and the unique strains of modern life caused me to finally visit an optometrist last Spring. While I&apos;m wearing glasses throughout the day now, a new solution from Honor could help reduce that glasses usage over time using, you guessed it, AI.</p><p>AI has been a bit of an annoying buzzword this year, but every so often a new feature breaks through all the noise and presents a solution that&apos;s <em>actually</em> a solution, not just some minor new form of convenience. Honor <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/honors-latest-ai-features-want-to-fight-deep-fake-videos-and-eye-strain">previously announced</a> its new AI defocus tech for the upcoming Honor Magic V3 foldable phone, but I can confirm it&apos;s also on the new Honor MagicPad 2 tablet.</p><p>Myopia is quickly becoming a global issue, as experts predict that it will affect 50% of the world&apos;s population by 2050. Honor is only one brand, and while wider adoption of this kind of technology could slow down or even reverse this negative trend entirely, optometrists I spoke with said this kind of therapy only works best for certain age groups.</p><p>I&apos;ve been testing out Honor&apos;s AI defocus tech on both the MagicPad 2 and Magic V3 for the past few weeks and it&apos;s impressive just how transparently it works. Few companies are taking eye care as seriously as Honor—something that&apos;s particularly personal to me as I&apos;ve been dealing with display-induced headaches due to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-is-pwm-display-flicker-tips-and-tricks">PWM dimming</a>—and the company&apos;s latest devices are a bastion of relief in a world where displays are meant to bedazzle but ultimately hurt us.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="70d86b8c-50dd-4cee-828c-9277ea43625b">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:65.90%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KP86qoLWLE32d99RnrY85.jpg' alt="An official render of the front of the Honor MagicPad 2"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Honor MagicPad 2</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>Packed with a powerful processor, incredible speakers, and a display that's eye-friendly and gorgeous at the same time, the Honor MagicPad 2 is the new tablet you should be looking at.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<h2 id="solutions-to-a-real-problem-2">Solutions to a real problem</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="53o3bRqLo3j6APUDF6cdSh" name="honor-magicpad-2-magic-v3-defocus-01.jpg" alt="Configuring eye care settings on both the Honor MagicPad 2 and the Honor Magic V3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/53o3bRqLo3j6APUDF6cdSh.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Myopia, or nearsightedness, is a problem created when eyes grow longer in order to better focus on objects that are arm&apos;s length or closer to them. In a world where we&apos;re constantly looking at monitors or smartphones for long periods of time throughout the day, it&apos;s not hard to understand why this is a (literal) growing problem.</p><p>But smartphone or monitor usage isn&apos;t going away in the modern age, but instead of just relying on glasses usage to fix the problem, Honor is taking a two-pronged approach. The company just introduced the first nearwork-induced transient myopia-reducing display on both the Honor Magic V3 folding phone and the Honor MagicPad 2 tablet.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>An estimated 50% of the world's population will have myopia (nearsightedness) by 2050 if something isn't done to reverse the trend.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>These special displays use a combination of advanced OLED display technology and AI scene understanding to recreate the effects of Defocus Incorporated Multiple Segments (DIMS) lenses, which have been <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://bjo.bmj.com/content/104/3/363">scientifically proven</a> to slow down the elongation of the eye.</p><p>In a document provided to Android Central, Honor links to several pieces of related research that show how simulated defocus solutions can help improve the eyes of anything from tree shrews to human adults when used regularly over a period of anywhere from 45 minutes to 2 weeks.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2022px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:30.71%;"><img id="3fFqsd49vEtjBzppD6Ebc9" name="bjophthalmol-2020-March-104-3-363-F3.large.jpg" alt="A chart showing the effectiveness of DIMS lenses in slowing progression of childhood myopia" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/3fFqsd49vEtjBzppD6Ebc9.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="2022" height="621" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="caption-text">A chart showing the effectiveness of DIMS lenses in slowing progression of childhood myopia </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: British Journal of Ophthalmology)</span></figcaption></figure>
<figure><blockquote><p>Special glasses can help reverse myopia, and Honor's solution aims to replicate these types of lenses as closely as possible via clever display technology.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>The technology works by separating colors and keeping some in focus while "defocusing" others. There are also times when colors are changed or objects receive faint outlines that place them more or less in focus, depending on the color used. It&apos;s similar to chromatic aberration, a lens effect that separates colors via a prism, which can also be seen in 3D movies that provide artificial depth.</p><p>In essence, it simulates the act of looking away from your device at a distant object, helping to automate a process that most of us forget to do.</p><p>It&apos;s difficult to describe and even more difficult to understand unless you see it in action. Surprisingly, I didn&apos;t find that this affected image quality negatively. While I had a hard time capturing the effect on camera, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0c5VtgEP43Y">YouTuber PhoneBuff</a> did an excellent job of tearing the technology apart in an easy-to-understand way in the video below.</p><p>He even corroborates the notion that the effect is normally nearly invisible to the naked eye in most circumstances, which I found particularly interesting. The big downside is that Honor&apos;s AI Defocus tech currently only works on the YouTube and Amazon Kindle apps, but Honor says it&apos;s working to expand support for more apps in the near future.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0c5VtgEP43Y" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>But not everyone is convinced that this could be a one-stop-shop solution. According to Bhavin Shah, Behavioural Optometrist at Central Vision Opticians, DIMS therapy—remember, those are the physical defocus lenses that people can wear—is generally only used in people up to age 21 and sees only a 1% success rate beyond that age.</p><p>Shah says "I don&apos;t believe that stimulating the same defocus on a screen will be detected by the peripheral retinal in the same way that the actual light hits the retina through glasses or contact lenses. I&apos;ve worn these contact lenses and glasses myself as an adult and it did not make any difference to comfort or eyestrain, the vision is much better with regular glasses or contacts compared to wearing defocus lenses."</p><p>Honor has been very careful to pen this as one additional arrow in the quiver for better eye health rather than a one-size-fits-all solution. But while it&apos;s not going to work for everyone, it may help quite a few people, and Honor&apos;s own research—plus Shah&apos;s experience—seems to corroborate the possibility.</p><p>Shah seemed hopeful about the tech so long as the study included a proper control mechanism for testers, meaning one group has the defocus AI mode enabled while one has it disabled. "If this change was better than those not using the defocus mode, then it shows some minor benefit. However, a long-term independent study would be the next step before I would start recommending it. I would have to try it myself."</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>Honor has been very careful to pen this as one additional arrow in the quiver for better eye health rather than a one-size-fits-all solution, but some experts say we need more testing to make sure it's effective.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>Shah notes that "our eyes do have a system where only the central vision is clear and the peripheral part is blurred and the eyes keep moving and pointing the central part of the vision to build up a clear picture by joining the clear parts and ignoring the blur, so in theory, if the peripheral defocus were to move based on where a person is viewing the screen at any one time, there may be some effect but I would highly doubt that it would make a significant difference."</p><p>I&apos;ve seen similar mixed results in the PWM-sensitive communities on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://ledstrain.org/">LEDStrain forum</a> and in Telegram groups I&apos;m a part of, where one "flicker-free" solution works wonders for some people while it does absolutely nothing to help another person.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.30%;"><img id="5S4HdrkVU9qB8aimhFhg5" name="honor-magicpad-2-reading-01.jpg" alt="Reading books on an Honor MagicPad 2" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5S4HdrkVU9qB8aimhFhg5.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1153" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Honor MagicPad 2 utilizes DC-like dimming at high brightness and an impressive 4320Hz PWM dimming at low brightness. For reference, that&apos;s 20x better than the latest iPad Pro models. Even this solution won&apos;t work perfectly for everyone, but it can help quite a lot of people who are sensitive to light flicker, like myself.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>This won't help everyone but, combined with higher PWM rates and other eye care solutions, mean that Honor is pushing the envelope for eye care more than any other brand.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>Shah offered one particular ray of hope based on Honor&apos;s research results, though. "Central Choroidal thickness has been shown to increase with near work and then return to normal but there is only a little research on this subject and the impact it has on adults and eyestrain."</p><p>AI Defocus solutions like the one in the Honor MagicPad 2 and Honor Magic V3 are designed to keep Central Choroidal thickness from changing as little as possible, meaning our eyes likely won&apos;t be as negatively affected by long-term screen use if more people are able to use this kind of technology.</p>
<h2 id="the-road-to-better-eye-health-2">The road to better (eye) health</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="MwTw3oahEAVMqGJPqoJpFo" name="honor-magicpad-2-reading-close.jpg" alt="Reading books on an Honor MagicPad 2" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MwTw3oahEAVMqGJPqoJpFo.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>For this article, I spoke with three different eye care professionals and all agreed that less screen time is the best solution. Dr. James R. Kelly from Kelly Vision Center recommends a simple 20/20/20 vision break rule along with frequent blinking when working on screens or using your tablet or phone for a long time. The 20/20/20 rule "means taking a visual break every 20 minutes where the individual looks at something 20 feet away for 20 seconds."</p><p>Frequent blinking might sound funny, but it&apos;s been shown that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://hub.salford.ac.uk/appliedcognition/2021/08/27/2068/">blinking decreases by 66%</a> when focusing on something. Additional research has shown that the blink rate for displays versus books <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24413278/">isn&apos;t any different</a>, but few people—in the past or otherwise—would spend as much time reading a book as often as most people look at a computer monitor or smartphone, meaning most of us don&apos;t blink as often as we should.</p><p>Shah builds upon this specifically for children, saying "it would be better to give them better habits like cutting screen time, taking breaks, and holding the device further away." In fact, new smartwatches like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fitbit-ace-lte-review">Fitbit Ace LTE</a> encourage not only fun outdoor play but also reduced screen time, setting hard limits on games to only a few minutes of screen time per session.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="QPiwKDd47VagREzJKrkYv7" name="honor-magicpad-2-watching-youtube.jpg" alt="Watching a YouTube video on the Honor MagicPad 2" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QPiwKDd47VagREzJKrkYv7.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>But while kids can get away with reduced screen time, it&apos;s not a reality for most working adults in the modern age. Dr. Kelly recommends "proper distancing and angling of screens, along with blue light blocking filters and anti-glare filters, and making sure screens are clean and smudge-free to reduce glare and reflections."</p><p>Samsung actually took a fascinating step toward this last part with the display on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review">Galaxy S24 Ultra</a>, giving it anti-glare properties but the company didn&apos;t go far enough to reduce the amount of flicker coming from its relatively slow 480Hz PWM rate. Remember, Honor is pushing 10x that number on its phones and tablets.</p><p>Additionally, Dr. Kelly recommends proper room lighting to avoid eye fatigue and strain. I&apos;ve personally had to remove all smart lights and LED strips from my home office because nearly <em>all</em> of them use PWM dimming and flicker at all brightness levels. I&apos;ve since switched them out for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B019KKEXOE/">these Sylvania LED bulbs</a> from Amazon that are not only inexpensive but are also non-dimmable, which is usually the code word in the LED world for "doesn&apos;t use PWM."</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="xSqe5EujsH5kjRGvWBRM78" name="honor-magicpad-2-back-01.jpg" alt="The back of the white Honor MagicPad 2" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xSqe5EujsH5kjRGvWBRM78.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>My verdict on the Honor MagicPad 2 and Honor Magic V3 displays? Superb. Sublime, even. The MagicPad 2 has the better display because it&apos;s a more consistent PWM rate at low brightness. It uses true 4320Hz PWM at low brightness whereas only the inner display in the Magic V3 has true 4320Hz—the outer display is identical to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-6-pro-review">Honor Magic 6 Pro</a>&apos;s 3840Hz panel, which uses an accelerated 360Hz DC-like cycle to achieve a higher overall PWM frequency.</p><p>Either way, I&apos;ve had no discomfort from either device after weeks of use, which is a lot more than I can say about the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-fold-review">Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold</a>. If all else fails, the only other real solution is just to spend more time outdoors and less time in front of screens.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magicpad-2-honor-magic-v3-ai-defocus-display</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Myopia is a huge problem and only getting worse. Honor's AI defocus tech aims to fix the problem by starting at the root of the problem: our eyes. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">52qszzejshs7S2Lf92zhuP</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ruCgppDYs3B85jEttfgkfh.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 13:01:07 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ruCgppDYs3B85jEttfgkfh.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Honor MagicPad 2 with the Honor Smart Keyboard attachment and the Honor Magic V3 alongside a pair of glasses]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Honor MagicPad 2 with the Honor Smart Keyboard attachment and the Honor Magic V3 alongside a pair of glasses]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Honor Magic V3 is trying to redefine what a foldable can be ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Honor introduces its latest foldable, which measures 9.2mm in thickness when folded.</li><li>In comparison, the rival Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 measures 12.1mm in thickness.</li><li>The Magic V3 sports a 6.43-inch external screen and a 7.92-inch foldable screen.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Honor finally introduced its much-anticipated foldable smartphone, the Magic V3, at the IFA 2024 event in Berlin. In addition to its thinnest inward-folding phone, the company has announced several other products, including the Honor Magic Pad 2, Watch 5, and MagicBook Art 14.</p><p>The Magic V3 is aiming for the title of the world&apos;s thinnest book-style <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">foldable phone</a>. When folded, it’s just 9.2mm thick and weighs about 226 grams. For comparison, the rival <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6</a> comes in at 12.1mm and 239 grams. Honor credits this impressive slim-down to 19 new materials and 114 microstructures packed into the design.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="zWQrAfrCCZ5JFt7ZRJgqVc" name="Honor-Magic-V3-06.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zWQrAfrCCZ5JFt7ZRJgqVc.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Honor)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="YgpSHf8bTfWzn9XbyDV2Sc" name="Honor-Magic-V3-04.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YgpSHf8bTfWzn9XbyDV2Sc.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Honor)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="wnPPkpLMjSiAKhc4DGcTNc" name="Honor-Magic-V3-02.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wnPPkpLMjSiAKhc4DGcTNc.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Honor)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 4 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="j7a66xBeNMUhtcBuqoj6Zc" name="Honor-Magic-V3-07.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/j7a66xBeNMUhtcBuqoj6Zc.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Honor)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>In a press release, Honor further notes that the handset&apos;s back cover is also shrunk using Special Fiber, which notably enhances impact resistance 40 times over the other foldable phones on the market. The hinge is promised with up to 500,000 folding cycles. </p><p>The Magic V3 features a 7.92-inch foldable screen inside and a 6.43-inch cover screen outside. Both displays come with 4320Hz ultra-high-frequency PWM dimming tech for smoother visuals. Under the hood, it&apos;s powered by the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3, stepping up from the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-v2-review">Magic V2</a>.</p><p>Keeping the lights on both displays is a 5150mAh battery capacity that supports Honor&apos;s 66W fast charging alongside 50W wireless charging as well. The foldable uses a giant circular module on the rear featuring a 50MP primary camera, a 50MP periscope telephoto lens, and a 40MP ultra-wide sensor for optics. The device also hosts AI-enabled photography features like "HONOR AI Motion Sensing for Lightning-fast shots, and the HONOR AI Portrait Engine for portrait enhancement."</p><p>The Honor Magic V3 comes in Reddish Brown, Green, and Black colorways.</p>
<h2 id="honor-magic-pad-2-2">Honor Magic Pad 2</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="vzNXK3aouNbPQpnMenqpii" name="Honor-Magic-Pad-2-02.jpg" alt="Honor Magic Pad 2" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vzNXK3aouNbPQpnMenqpii.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Honor)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Honor Magic Pad 2 is yet another slim-form-factor device that falls under the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-tablets">Android tablets</a> segment. It weighs 555 grams and measures only 5.8mm in thickness. It has a 12.3-inch giant display with a 144Hz refresh rate and supports high-frequency PWM dimming, just like the foldable phone. The tablet comes in Emerald Green, Starry Grey, and White color options.</p><p>Underneath, the device runs on a Snapdragon 8s Gen 3, paired with a hefty 10,050mAh battery that supports 66W fast charging. It ships with MagicOS 8.0 and comes with cool AI tricks, like the Magic Portal feature, which predicts what you need and lets you create schedules or manage tasks with just a long press and drag.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="JjCBKSyTKDwbMWLgGmwxbi" name="Honor-Magic-Pad-2-01.jpg" alt="Honor Magic Pad 2" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JjCBKSyTKDwbMWLgGmwxbi.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Honor)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="FHK6FaX66MKGkh3HSYvMfi" name="Honor-Magic-Pad-2.jpg" alt="Honor Magic Pad 2" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FHK6FaX66MKGkh3HSYvMfi.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Honor)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<h2 id="honor-watch-5-2">Honor Watch 5</h2>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="KtRuFWkB4dNenmiYwovQN" name="Honor-Watch-5-01.jpg" alt="Honor Watch 5" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KtRuFWkB4dNenmiYwovQN.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Honor)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="zDfNb5BzYc9BkotYHCRxH" name="Honor-Watch-5-02.jpg" alt="Honor Watch 5" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zDfNb5BzYc9BkotYHCRxH.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Honor)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>At IFA this year, Honor also introduced the Watch 5. It has a 1.85-inch AMOLED square display, a resolution of 450 x 390 pixels, and 322ppi. It measures 11mm in thickness and weighs around 35 grams. There is also a rotatable button on the right through which users can navigate across the interface. The Watch 5 is available in Black, Gold, and Green color variants.</p><p>The smartwatch&apos;s 480mAh battery capacity promises a 15-day battery life on a single charge. It also features health features like heart rate monitoring, SpO2 monitoring, and an AccuTrack positioning system for GPS accuracy.</p><p>Honor has yet to share the pricing and availability of these devices.</p>
<h2 id="pricing-and-availability-2">Pricing and availability</h2>
<p>In the UK, the Honor Magic V3 starts at £1,699, with the 12GB+512GB model going for €1,999. You can grab it from Honor UK’s website starting September 5. Meanwhile, the Magic Pad 2 will set you back £499 and is also available from September 5. Pricing for the Honor Watch 5 and other regional details will be announced soon.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-v3-foldable-announced</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The slim foldable craze is heating up, and Honor's Magic V3 just jumped on the bandwagon. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">cYnqvyzfYoWoVEkSL5RtSY</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/e2PG7BGXHJJFpeRhETgmJc.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 13:00:53 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/e2PG7BGXHJJFpeRhETgmJc.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Honor]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Honor Magic V3]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Honor Magic V3]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Honor Magic V3 hands-on: Effortlessly upstaging the Galaxy Z Fold 6 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Honor clearly knows what it&apos;s doing with foldables, and although the Magic V2 launched a year ago, it continues to be among the thinnest and lightest devices around. The ultra-thin design is a major differentiator, and it is the main reason why I used the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-v2-review">Magic V2</a> more than just about any other foldable in 2024 — it doesn&apos;t feel cumbersome in the least.</p><p>Honor is putting all the learnings from the Magic V2 toward its latest foldable, the Magic V3. The foldable retains the best features of its predecessor, but it is thinner and lighter, and that makes it even better to hold and use. Coming in at just 9.3mm folded and an incredible 4.4mm unfolded, the Magic V3 is unbelievably thin.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="yBYucR97mbCFcL9SNGnACa" name="honor-magic-v3-hands-on-3.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3 hands-on" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yBYucR97mbCFcL9SNGnACa.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The overall design is largely the same as last year, but the Magic V3 switches to a new camera module that&apos;s similar to that of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-6-pro-review">Magic 6 Pro</a>, and it looks much more elegant. What I like the most about the camera island is that it is centered, and there&apos;s no wobble whatsoever when using the Magic V3 on a table; this was a bugbear on the V2.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="FvbUB2VtqfyVddKzS5wpnb" name="honor-magic-v3-hands-on-7.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3 hands-on" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FvbUB2VtqfyVddKzS5wpnb.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>At 226g, it is 5g lighter than the V2 while offering a bigger 5150mAh battery. By contrast, Samsung&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Galaxy Z Fold 6</a> weighs 13g more, and you get a much smaller 4400mAh battery. To give you additional context, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-review">Pixel 9 Pro XL</a> weighs 221g, and it doesn&apos;t fold in half. Honor once again is proving that it is the brand to beat when it comes to foldable designs, and the Magic V3 looks and feels like a device that&apos;s a few generations ahead of what Samsung is offering.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="YsyVqDER8pFFHVA7DpsqMa" name="honor-magic-v3-hands-on-4.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3 hands-on" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/YsyVqDER8pFFHVA7DpsqMa.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The hinge has a smooth articulation, and it doesn&apos;t take much effort to unfold the device. Honor says the hinge has better durability this time around, and that it can withstand 500,000 unlocks. It is a little stiffer than the hinge on the V2, but that&apos;s a good thing — it allows the V3 to stay locked at various angles between 40 to 150 degrees. What continues to be great is that the hinge doesn&apos;t lead to a noticeable crease — it definitely isn&apos;t as evident as Samsung&apos;s offering.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="gVAp9vpszAaHbmXdVF4Aaa" name="honor-magic-v3-hands-on-5.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3 hands-on" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gVAp9vpszAaHbmXdVF4Aaa.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While Honor didn&apos;t change the dimensions of the inner and outer screens, both panels have better brightness levels, and class-leading PWM dimming. Honor is also rolling out a defocus mode that&apos;s meant to relieve eye strain, and the brand continues to lead the way when it comes to eye comfort.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="rwQjFCwoofBps63k4YBRCc" name="honor-magic-v3-hands-on-9.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3 hands-on" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rwQjFCwoofBps63k4YBRCc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Ingress protection was an area where Honor lagged behind its rivals last year, and thankfully, the Magic V3 gets IPX8 water resistance as standard, allowing it to weather the elements much better. Honor is also rolling out bold new colors, and the green variant does a great job accentuating the design of the camera housing.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="CwTrtCHzAtSDEQmbrRJVQc" name="honor-magic-v3-hands-on-10.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3 hands-on" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CwTrtCHzAtSDEQmbrRJVQc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Honor is positioning the Magic V3 against the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">best foldables</a>, so it isn&apos;t astonishing that the device gets the latest tech. It is powered by Qualcomm&apos;s Snapdragon 8 Gen 3, and comes with 12GB of RAM and 256GB of storage with the base model. It has the latest connectivity modem, NFC, USB 3.1 with DisplayPort 1.2, and in the little I used the device, I didn&apos;t see any issues with lag or jitter while gaming.</p>
<p>Obviously, battery life is a key area of consideration on a foldable, and the Magic V3 has a 5150mAh battery that uses a silicon-carbon substrate to increase longevity. While I haven&apos;t used the device enough to gauge battery life, I got a day&apos;s worth of use between charges, and I don&apos;t see any problems in this area.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="ZmBFVD86cYL6dEVHaRUNyb" name="honor-magic-v3-hands-on-8.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3 hands-on" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZmBFVD86cYL6dEVHaRUNyb.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Honor is upgrading the cameras as well, with the Magic V3 offering a new 50MP camera alongside a 40MP wide-angle lens and 50MP zoom lens with 3.5x optical zoom. The foldable gets a lot of the same features as the Magic 6 Pro, including AI-based scene recognition and motion-tracking.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="vV3r6TtYccFbzJuqxHVvxZ" name="honor-magic-v3-hands-on-2.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3 hands-on" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vV3r6TtYccFbzJuqxHVvxZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Honor doubled down on AI-assisted software features in Magic OS 8.0, and the Magic V3 runs the 8.0.3 build out of the box that comes with a few extras. Honor is teaming up with Google to bring the search giant&apos;s best AI features to its devices, and this is absolutely the right move; Google has class-leading translation and image editing AI features, and you can now use these on the Magic V3.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="ZwMjC3c9eJ6QfwBvFAfzcc" name="honor-magic-v3-hands-on-11.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3 hands-on" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZwMjC3c9eJ6QfwBvFAfzcc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While Honor got a lot right with the Magic V2 last year, the brand messed up availability; the foldable went on sale in the U.K. at the end of Q1 2024 — six months after its global debut — and that was undoubtedly detrimental to its sales figures. Honor isn&apos;t making that mistake this time around; the Magic V3 will be available in the U.K. starting September 5, and it has mainstream carrier backing.</p>
<p>Coming in at £1,699 ($2,233), the Magic V3 is positioned against the Galaxy Z Fold 6. I&apos;ll reserve judgement for the review, but if you&apos;re ready to switch to a foldable and want something that&apos;s just as easy to use as a regular phone, the Magic V3 needs to be on your radar — it is one of the best phones I used in 2024.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-v3-hands-on</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Magic V3 just made its global debut, and it may just be one of the best foldables of 2024.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">oejejGyTNAVwU3ibF2EU49</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zaTupidC4WUGNt2uNDZ7qc.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 13:00:13 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/zaTupidC4WUGNt2uNDZ7qc.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Honor Magic V3 hands-on]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Honor Magic V3 hands-on]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ OnePlus reportedly eager to challenge Honor with a thinner Open 2 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Rumors suggest OnePlus is interested in making the Open 2 even thinner than the first model, which could bring it contention with Honor's Magic V3.</li><li>The device is "expected" to feature a 9.Xmm thinness when folded with a circular triple camera array, and a 2K Plus high-definition display.</li><li>Honor's Magic V3 is incredibly thin and durable as the company stated it measures 9.2mm when folded and 4.3mm unfolded.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>New rumors claim consumers could have an interesting competition brewing between OnePlus and Honor following its thin Magic V3 foldable.</p><p>Known Weibo tipster <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://weibo.com/6048569942/Ovgu56gT8?pagetype=profilefeed">Digital Chat Station</a> (DCS) posted some rumors about the OnePlus Open 2, which purported its new thinner mentality. The information was recently edited away; however, the folks at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/oneplus-open-2-thin-leak-3478093/">Android Authority</a> snapped a screenshot of it. According to the original rumor, DCS states a key aspect of OnePlus&apos; design for the Open 2 is to make it "even thinner and lighter."</p><p>Supposedly, the Chinese OEM is interested in producing a foldable with a thickness of 9.Xmm. This is rumored to be "expected" as development of the device continues. The tipster didn&apos;t give a specific number, though it should be relatively thinner than Honor&apos;s recent book-style foldable if it wants to beat it.</p><p>Other rumors claim the phone could feature a Sony 50MP primary sensor within its triple camera array. It&apos;s suggested that a periscope camera will join this. Additionally, it seems OnePlus is sticking with the large, circular array that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-open-review">its previous iteration</a> offered.</p><p>Lastly, a "2K Plus full high-definition" foldable screen is rumored for the Open 2 alongside the Snapdragon 8 Gen 4.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:713px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:84.15%;"><img id="ewxMBAzqfSfFVbRwWm76Ug" name="oneplus-open-2-thinness-rumors.jpg" alt="A set of rumors about the upcoming OnePlus Open 2, which claim its thinness could rival Honor's Magic V3." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ewxMBAzqfSfFVbRwWm76Ug.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="713" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The idea of a thinner foldable, especially one within the 9mm range, gets us thinking about the Honor Magic V3. The company detailed <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magic-v3-ultra-thin-durable-creation-details">how it made its ultra-thin foldable</a>, which measures 9.2mm when folded and 4.3mm unfolded. Honor stated that it invested heavily in the R&D side of its battery technology, implementing a 5,150mAh silicon carbon battery.</p><p>The company honed in on durability, an aspect of the previous model that consumers complained about. With the Magic V3, Honor added an additional set of "swing arms" for its hinge to boost its durability and longevity.</p><p>It remains to be seen just how much of a challenger OnePlus will be with the Open 2 against Honor. Rumors so far suggest it will be thinner than the Pixel 9 Pro Fold at 10.5mm and the Galaxy Z Fold 6 at 12.1mm.</p><p>Other OnePlus Open 2 <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-open-tipped-to-have-a-6000mah-battery">rumors claim</a> the device could feature a beefed-up 6,000mAh battery. The current claims double down on the theory of Qualcomm&apos;s upcoming flagship SoC being featured within the device. Elsewhere, the Open 2 <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-oneplus-open-might-not-see-a-successor-this-year">may not arrive this year</a> as originally speculated. A tipster&apos;s post on X suggested that the next OnePlus foldable could arrive during Q1 2025.</p><p>The reason is supposedly due to OPPO, a OnePlus sister company, delaying the launch of its Find N5 until next year. Both foldables are likely to mirror one another like last year.</p>
<ul><li><strong> Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><strong>Best Buy</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><strong>Walmart</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><strong>Samsung</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><strong>Amazon</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><strong>Verizon</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><strong>AT&T</strong></a></li></ul>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="98f2791a-0756-4f09-9f89-7e7b391130c7">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oP8j6zYak7fmALcFEDr9Da.jpg' alt="An official render of the OnePlus Open in Emerald Dusk color"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">OnePlus Open</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Immersive and smooth</strong></em></p>
<p>The OnePlus Open is an all-around superb foldable phone that truly stands a part from the competition. With a striking design and performance that is typical for OnePlus, the Open is a worthy book-style foldable for new users and tech lovers alike.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-open-2-thinner-design-rumors</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ OnePlus is rumored to create a thinner Open 2 foldable to compete with the likes of Honor. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">kTgt8SLE2CMnWqEUaLBvm9</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/eGyLKviAK3wq4uCoqV8HdX.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 19:00:40 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ tips@androidcentral.com (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/eGyLKviAK3wq4uCoqV8HdX.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus Open Apex Edition review]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus Open Apex Edition review]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Mint Mobile will now give you $400 OFF the Pixel 9 Pro XL and 50% off a year of wireless, just for kicks ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Do a quick Google search and you&apos;ll find no shortage of great Google Pixel 9 Pro XL deals right now, but once again, Mint Mobile&apos;s offer is probably the best out there, and once again, it&apos;s flying well under the radar.</p><p>I&apos;m not being hyperbolic: if you buy the Pixel 9 Pro XL alongside any six-month data plan at Mint Mobile, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9-pro-xl/6810506/"><strong>the T-Mobile-powered MVNO will hook you up with $400 off the phone AND six months of additional wireless for free</strong></a>. That means you can get an awesome AI-powered device and a <em>full year</em> of wireless service for as little as<em> </em>$789, or $33 per month if you pay using affirm. </p><p>I&apos;ve seen <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/mint-mobile-deals-promo-codes">Mint Mobile deals</a> like this before, but it&apos;s pretty unusual to see the promo drop so soon after the phone&apos;s release date. </p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="8a573d31-591b-455a-bdcb-d1b17d267471" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL 128GB: $1,099" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL 128GB: $1,099" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9-pro-xl/6810506/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="qxxHFzMsUCW6peiznjeMek" name="google-pixel-9-pro-xl-official-render-obsidian-front-back.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qxxHFzMsUCW6peiznjeMek.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="500" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Google Pixel 9 Pro XL 128GB: </strong><a href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9-pro-xl/6810506/" data-dimension112="8a573d31-591b-455a-bdcb-d1b17d267471" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL 128GB: $1,099" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL 128GB: $1,099"><del>$1,099</del> <strong>$699, plus six months free with any six-month plan at Mint Mobile</strong></a></p>
<p>Big, bold, and beautiful, the new Google Pixel 9 Pro XL features the power of the new Tensor G4 chipset, plus you're getting cutting-edge AI-features and loads of software support straight out of the box. Pick up an XL from Mint Mobile with any six-month data plan and the carrier will carve a straight $400 off the price of the phone. You'll also get an additional six months of service for free! <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.mintmobile.com/devices/google-pixel-9-pro-xl/6810506/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="8a573d31-591b-455a-bdcb-d1b17d267471" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL 128GB: $1,099" data-dimension48="Google Pixel 9 Pro XL 128GB: $1,099">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>The Pixel 9 Pro XL is likely to rank among the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a> released this year, and for good reason: you&apos;re essentially getting the power, efficiency, and lengthy software support of the regular Pixel 9 Pro in a larger, more glorious-looking package.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-xl-comparison-video">Early tests</a> show that the Pixel 9 Pro XL performs handily next to the super-powered Galaxy S24 Ultra from Samsung, but you&apos;re paying significantly less. Pair the XL with this Mint Mobile deal and you&apos;re getting a premium, AI-powered device for the price of a flagship, and that&apos;s not even considering the value of saving 50% on a year of wireless provided by T-Mobile.</p><p>Of course, this kind of deal isn&apos;t for everyone. If you&apos;re happy with your current phone service or you&apos;re looking to do a trade-in, there are plenty of other great <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/best-google-pixel-9-deals-pixel-9-pro-discounts">Google Pixel 9 deals</a> to consider. But if you&apos;re ready to switch to an MVNO and you&apos;re looking to get a great phone out of the deal, this is an outstanding opportunity.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/mint-mobile-will-now-give-you-dollar400-off-the-pixel-9-pro-xl-and-50-off-a-year-of-wireless-just-for-kicks</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Mint Mobile is now including the Pixel 9 Pro XL in its free wireless bundle deal, resulting in savings as immense as the phone itself.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">KsJr9s3W8uaWcR2DhajuYG</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vVYYjY4JW9uei4MkoGAW8S.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 19:00:12 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vVYYjY4JW9uei4MkoGAW8S.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The back of the Hazel Google Pixel 9 Pro XL]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The back of the Hazel Google Pixel 9 Pro XL]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>