<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 17:09:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Our 'Pepsi Challenge' reveals what people really think about hi-res audio ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Have you listened to your favorite song through a pair of high-end headphones or $300 Hi-Res Audio certified Bluetooth earbuds? Do you subscribe to Spotify’s free plan, or are you more of a premium-tier Tidal listener? Apple has a massive lossless quality music library right now but you probably don’t have the right equipment to fully take advantage of it. Same thing with Tidal, which is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.billboard.com/business/streaming/tidal-new-pricing-1235622516/">lowering its prices</a> starting April 10th, making its high-resolution music more accessible. Meanwhile, Spotify still doesn’t offer lossless after announcing “Spotify HiFi” back in 2021.</p><p>But even though the most popular <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-streaming-music-apps-android">music streaming service</a> still doesn’t offer hi-res audio, is it something you actually care about? Could you tell the difference between the free lower-resolution offerings on Spotify and the lossless quality streams from Tidal, Apple Music, or Amazon Music Unlimited?</p><p>To truly discern the difference between them, you need the right wired equipment or the right combination of smartphone, Bluetooth codec, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/these-9-earbuds-support-high-res-codecs">quality Bluetooth earbuds</a>/headphones/mobile DAC, which support what’s being played from the phone.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="N3etMayJdAu5CH9XMwn9tX" name="sennheiser-660S2-momentum-4-iFi-DACs-group-shot-close-up.jpg" alt="Sennheiser headphones and iFi DACs" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/N3etMayJdAu5CH9XMwn9tX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>That seems like a lot to go through, but that’s what I did, and I brought it right to your doorstep! My “Pepsi Challenge” was presenting a blind “taste” test to the average smartphone user to find out if all of this progress, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-to-stream-hi-res-music-from-phone">these advances in audio technology</a>, really matter.</p>
<h2 id="lg-made-hi-res-audio-easy-rip-to-easy-2">LG made hi-res audio easy. RIP to easy.</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="iaNWkBwKiRDG4hTwZucbVM" name="lg-v60-blue-back-1-wide.jpg" alt="The back of the LG V60" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/iaNWkBwKiRDG4hTwZucbVM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Martonik / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Let me take a brief moment to say RIP to my beloved <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/lg-v60-thinq-5g-review">LG V60 ThinQ</a> from 2020, which featured a Quad DAC built-in and a 3.5mm audio port. That was one of the easiest ways to get CD-quality audio out of a phone. </p><p>Some over-ear or on-ear headphones can be connected to modern-day 3.5mm port-less phones via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/everything-you-need-know-about-usb-c">USB-C</a> or 3.5/4.4/6.3mm connectors and adapters when you use a USB-C mobile DAC/Amp. That said, how many of you reading this consider yourself an “audiophile” and would spring for both Bluetooth earbuds <em>and</em> over-ear headphones <em>and</em> a DAC (do you even know what that is)?</p><p>Did your eyes just glaze over reading that? So, I ask again, does the average consumer care enough to figure all of this out to leverage all of that high bit rate goodness? To figure that out, I devised a test to get some definitive answers.</p>
<h2 id="testing-to-find-what-matters-2">Testing to find what matters</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="MRERJwDopQEuKL5MRaLVwY" name="sennheiser-660S2-momentum-4-iFi-DACs-group-shot.jpg" alt="Group shot of Sennheiser headphones and iFi DACs" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MRERJwDopQEuKL5MRaLVwY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>For this test, I chose 10 people of varying ages, ethnicities, and genders and played low-resolution audio streams, followed by either lossless FLAC files or high-resolution Tidal streams. Some of the responses I received expanded my understanding of what influences people’s choices profoundly. I was taken aback by some of the answers because I hadn&apos;t considered the context in which some people enjoy music. </p><p>I set up the methodology for testing my sample group like so:</p><p>Some participants had more time than others, so the number of songs varied, but each song they sampled was played twice. I used a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-7-pro-review">Pixel 7 Pro</a> to play each song once from Spotify, with the audio stream quality set to “Medium,” and then a second time directly from my Pixel using the USB Audio Player Pro app or Tidal. I had to use that app because Android downsamples the audio coming out of that USB-C port to 16bit, 44.1kHz, and the files I was playing were higher resolution than that. </p><p>HummingBird Media, who was as excited about this test as I was, outfitted me with the gear for this experiment. For round one, I used the excellent <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/earbuds/sennheiser-momentum-true-wireless-4-review">Sennheiser Momentum True Wireless 4</a> over-ear headphones via Bluetooth. In round two, the same songs were played via those same headphones but wired now, using <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://ifi-audio.com/products/go-link/">iFi’s Audio GO link USB-C dongle DAC/headphone amp</a>. I had one instance where I employed some higher-end equipment that Hummingbird sent, but I’ll get to that in a moment.</p>
<h2 id="who-cares-about-hi-res-audio-and-why-2">Who cares about hi-res audio, and why?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="d3j6LezfNWEoVr2T3ykCdf" name="pixel-7-pro-streaming-spotify-and-playing-FLAC.jpg" alt="Pixel 7 Pro displaying bluetooth codecs" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/d3j6LezfNWEoVr2T3ykCdf.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="caption-text">A screenshot the codecs my Pixel 7 Pro used for Spotify and FLAC files </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>So, what were the results after my participants&apos; listening tests and then subsequent Q&A sessions? Most people said they could hear a clear difference. Literally. The most common feedback was that the locally played FLAC files or streamed Tidal tracks had more clarity. There was more separation with the instruments, meaning they could discern individual sounds better in the higher-resolution files and streams. Sounds like an easy “W” for hi-res audio, right? Wrong.</p><p>One tester, JT, a broadcast engineer by trade, remarked that despite the perceived difference, it wasn’t enough for him to pay for anything special to have higher-quality content. He likened it to 1080P vs. 4K TVs. He told me that he knows 4K is better, but 1080P is good enough for his needs. So, no Tidal and no hunting down and purchasing FLAC files; he’s fine with lower-quality music, technically speaking. </p><p>Some other testers had similarly nuanced responses. Two testers, whom I&apos;ll call CA and CF, said they would both pay, but in different contexts. CA could hear the difference in clarity but was only willing to pay the one-time cost for the $59.99 iFi GO link dongle DAC. He wasn’t willing to fork over the extra dough monthly for a premium music service.</p><p>CF already pays for Spotify because she doesn’t like ads, so she is also willing to pay for the difference she hears between the two streams. But she would expand on that and say that it wasn’t worth it in her car, and she’d only want to take advantage of paying for premium streaming or upgrading to more premium equipment like the Sennheiser Momentum 4 and iFi GO link for active, recreational listening at home.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>Some people may be able to tell the difference between low-resolution and hi-res audio, but that still might not be enough to justify the extra cost often associated with it.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>Hearing, or “audition,” as it may also be called in neuroscience circles, is highly subjective. It’s as much about perception as it is about the technical aspects of the sound source, and as such, it shouldn’t be a surprise that two of my testers didn’t hear any difference in quality. This also means that they had no incentive to pay for anything more than what they had already used. Hi-res doesn’t matter to either of them.</p><p>One of those testers is also an avid music listener. She cooks with music on and does chores with it on. When we get in the car, the first thing she does is turn on the radio and hit her favorite Spotify playlists on her phone. It’s my wife, so I know these things.</p><p>Since I had more time to test my wife, I had her listen to one of the test tracks a third time, “Diamonds on the Souls of Her Shoes,” by Paul Simon. Only this time, I employed iFi’s impressive <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://ifi-audio.com/products/go-blu/">GO blu HD Bluetooth DAC</a> and streamed in the Hi-Res LDAC codec at 96kHz, 32bits through that DAC into a pair of audiophile-grade <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.sennheiser-hearing.com/en-US/p/hd-660s2/">Sennheiser HD 660S2</a> open-back over-ear headphones. If you don’t know, these are like seeing a movie in IMAX, where the Momentum 4 would be viewing that same movie on one of the standard large screens. Both are enjoyable, but the 660S2 is more dynamic.</p><p>With the 660S2, my wife was able to hear a slightly discernable difference from the lower-resolution music, but it still wasn’t significant enough to influence any action on her part toward the higher-resolution experience.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="DK7d9iQaSvPk4bfmSqFfaX" name="sennheiser-660S2-momentum-4-group-shot.jpg" alt="Group shot of the Sennheiser HD 660S2 and Momentum 4 Wireless" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/DK7d9iQaSvPk4bfmSqFfaX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The two most profound Q&As touched on perception and brought up questions of neurodiversity, which I hadn’t considered before. One of my testers preferred the lower-resolution music because of a phenomenon I actually enjoy. High-resolution music files paired with high-end headphones make me feel like I’m truly immersed in the music. At its best, it feels like the music is not playing at me but that it is actually in my head. It feels like it’s all around me, or more precisely, I’m in it. I’m on stage, sitting in the middle of the band.</p><p>She didn’t like that feeling, initially saying it was too loud even though I checked to be sure that the tracks were playing at the same perceived loudness. This made me think of people who have processing sensitivities, those for whom certain stimuli could lead to sensory overload. I realized that in that context, hi-res audio played through earbuds or high-end headphones could be “bad,” and the lower resolution, less dynamic streams, “good.”</p><p>Then there was SK. He heard and articulated the difference in clarity, but to him, an avid Spotify user, the difference in the higher-resolution tracks sounded too “digital.” He said the Spotify streams were “familiar, comfortable.” For him, the enjoyment was in the familiar, and the perceived difference took him out of that place of comfort and made it less enjoyable.</p>
<h2 id="final-conclusions-what-really-matters-2">Final conclusions: What really matters</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1920px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="q5jEcBFb9uzzhWiFLcTtfZ" name="various-dacs-dongles-aux-cables-group-shot.jpg" alt="Various DACs and dongles needed to listen to Hi-Res audio" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/q5jEcBFb9uzzhWiFLcTtfZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1920" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Tshaka Armstrong)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>At the end of my experiment, I’ve come to two conclusions:</p>
<ul><li>Almost all of my testers hadn’t listened to music playing in something they’d consider “high-end” headphones. They all remarked on how amazing the Sennheiser Momentum 4 sounded. So, part of answering my initial question requires first asking, “Has the average user even <em>heard</em> high-quality audio played through high-quality audio gear to know if Hi-Res audio matters?”</li><li>There is no “average” user. There are numerous contexts and reasons for smartphone users to care or not care about Hi-Res audio despite it being “better” on paper, and all of them are right.</li></ul>
<p>At the end of the day, technology will keep moving forward, and as things progress and wireless technologies are better able to handle lossless files, people will just have access to them, which will become the norm, much like how Apple made its entire library available in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apple-music-hi-fi-lossless-dolby-atmos-spatial-audio-announcement">its lossless ALAC format</a>.</p><p>Those with reasons and contexts for not liking it will find the services that work for them if there&apos;s no option to retain the lower-resolution versions of the songs they listen to. The rest likely won’t even recognize that they’ve been “upgraded” because they don’t have the more expensive, higher-end listening gear, which would make that upgrade really pop like the Sennheiser and iFi gear I used here. They’ll continue to buy the earbuds whose focus is on cost and feature set first, and Hi-Res dynamic range audio second.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/do-listeners-really-care-about-hi-res-audio</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Does hi-res audio matter to the average smartphone user? We performed our version of the "Pepsi Challenge" to get some answers. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">bwyKTYTrJfhFN5DKtvXxzc</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pizXizjzne4RV5GtQnWJYY.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 17:00:08 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ klpmediallc@gmail.com (Tshaka Armstrong) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pizXizjzne4RV5GtQnWJYY.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Tshaka Armstrong]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Tshaka wearing Sennheiser 660S2 with hi-res audio]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Tshaka wearing Sennheiser 660S2 with hi-res audio]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Alphabet, Apple, and Meta are under investigation in Europe for non-compliance with the Digital Markets Act ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>The European Commission is investigating Alphabet, Apple and Meta for potential non-compliance with the Digital Markets Act.</li><li>The DMA requires gatekeepers to allow developers to alert consumers to offers outside their app stores, for free.</li><li>Meta is being investigated over its “pay or consent” model, which may breach rules on personal data gathering.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>The European Commission has confirmed that it has placed Alphabet (Google’s parent company), Apple, and Meta under investigation for concerns over their potential failure to comply with rules established under the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/what-is-digital-markets-act">Digital Markets Act</a>. Those rules were introduced in 2022 and came into full effect on March 7, 2024.</p><p>In the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/IP_24_1689">announcement</a> (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/apple-google-meta-eu-dma-investigation-3428386/">Android Authority</a>), the European Commission confirmed that several investigations are running alongside one another, each of which focuses on a specific aspect of non-compliance.</p><p>Alphabet and Apple are being investigated for a potential breach of steering rules on their app stores. According to the DMA, so-called “gatekeepers” are required to allow app developers to “steer” consumers away from the app store if there are cheaper offers available elsewhere.</p>
<p>Additionally, Alphabet is under scrutiny over concerns around “self-preferencing”, where Google search results may be highlighting Google’s own products and services through its search engine. </p><p>Apple is being checked over whether it makes it easy enough for consumers to use non-Apple software on their devices, such as search engines or web browsers. This is separate from the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-doj-apple-antitrust-case-means-google-android">Apple antitrust case</a> recently announced by the US Department of Justice. </p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Today, we've opened five non-compliance investigations under the Digital Markets Act.It concerns:🔹Alphabet’s rules on steering in Google Play 🔹Alphabet’s self-preferencing on Google Search🔹Apple’s rules on steering in the App Store 🔹Apple's choice screen for Safari… pic.twitter.com/kiZ7sLQa8B<a href="https://twitter.com/EU_Commission/status/1772207590212063397">March 25, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>The proceedings against Meta concern its “pay or consent” model, which offers a paid membership tier for Facebook and Instagram. Users who pay can use the service without their data being used for adverts. However, users who don’t pay may be inadvertently giving Meta permission to harvest their personal data. The commission is “concerned that the binary choice imposed by Meta&apos;s “pay or consent” model may not provide a real alternative in case users do not consent.” </p><p>In summary of the various investigations, the EC said: “The Commission suspects that the measures put in place by these gatekeepers fall short of effective compliance of their obligations under the DMA.” </p>
<p>Thierry Breton, the commissioner for the internal market, added that “the Digital Markets Act became applicable on 7 March. We have been in discussions with gatekeepers for months to help them adapt, and we can already see changes happening in the market. But we are not convinced that the solutions by Alphabet, Apple, and Meta respect their obligations for a fairer and more open digital space for European citizens and businesses.”</p><p>The investigations are expected to be concluded within 12 months, at which point the three companies will be informed of the preliminary findings of the investigation and what measures the commission expects them to take to ensure compliance. If any of the companies are found to have broken the rules, they can be fined up to 10 percent of their total worldwide turnover, with further sanctions for repeated infringements. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/alphabet-apple-and-meta-are-under-investigation-in-europe-for-non-compliance-with-the-digital-markets-act</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The three tech giants are being investigated for potentially failing to comply with new rules. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">n3cB6k5ZBAU6Qd7vAD2ZzP</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9ee4iMVZtEdSkpgKEFbmkA.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 16:33:38 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ stevenshaw444@gmail.com (Steven Shaw) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9ee4iMVZtEdSkpgKEFbmkA.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Big Tech logo with EU flag in the background]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Big Tech logo with EU flag in the background]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Google Pixel Tablet drops to its lowest price EVER during Amazon's Big Spring Sale — $150 off! ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The Amazon Big Spring Sale is set to end this evening (March 25th), so it may be your last chance to take advantage of the many historic tablet deals that are available on the site. Case in point: <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C1SKS79W/"><strong>you can score a whopping 25% discount</strong></a> on the Google Pixel Tablet (256GB version) if you pick one up today. That&apos;s the cheapest that the versatile device has <em>ever been</em>, plus it comes with that free charging speaker dock that lets you easily convert the tablet into a smart home hub. </p>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/amazon-spring-sale-2024-early-deals-predictions-and-what-to-expect"><strong>Amazon Big Spring Sale ends March 25th </strong>— check out our top 30 deals</a></li></ul>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="258901c3-fce0-44a7-be8b-0a2b7aa8af68" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$599.99" data-dimension48="$599.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C1SKS79W" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:611px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:88.38%;"><img id="fRfBFHZEuH5V2eSGkFN2aA" name="pixel-tablet-render-w-space.JPG" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fRfBFHZEuH5V2eSGkFN2aA.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="611" height="540" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Google Pixel Tablet 256GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C1SKS79W" data-dimension112="258901c3-fce0-44a7-be8b-0a2b7aa8af68" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$599.99" data-dimension48="$599.99"><del>$599.99</del> <strong>$449.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>Last chance! For the first time ever, Amazon is slashing $150 off the 256GB Pixel Tablet as part of its Spring Sale. Thanks to the included charging speaker dock, this versatile device could easily double as a smart home hub, plus you get outstanding battery life and the fluid interface that Pixel fans love. The only problem is the tablet's abnormally large bezels, but if you can get over that design choice, it's an excellent device.</p>
<p>This historic discount is for 256GB version, but if you need less storage, you can also get a sweet <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C1SLD1PK"><strong>$100 discount</strong></a> on the 128GB tablet. Keep in mind that the Amazon Spring Sale ends this evening, March 25th, so don't wait too long to make your move. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C1SKS79W" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="258901c3-fce0-44a7-be8b-0a2b7aa8af68" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$599.99" data-dimension48="$599.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>Knowing Amazon, I wouldn&apos;t be terribly surprised if Amazon extended this discount beyond the confines of the Spring Sale, but I wouldn&apos;t risk it if you&apos;re interested. </p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/google-pixel-tablet-review">Google Pixel Tablet</a> packs the recognizably sleek Pixel platform into the body of a tablet, but you get some surprises as well, such as a vibrant 11-inch LCD display, 8GB of RAM, and enough battery life to rival some of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-tablets">best Android tablets</a> on the market. You&apos;ll also enjoy the efficiency of the Tensor G2 chipset and, of course, all of the lengthy software support that Google is known for.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/the-google-pixel-tablet-drops-to-its-lowest-price-ever-during-amazons-big-spring-sale-dollar150-off</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Grab the 256GB Pixel Tablet before the sale ends and you're guaranteed to score a stellar 25% discount at Amazon.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">NxiZ4ZX5warYCpj29bGLfL</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uJDp3PYcTYEc2ruefbfFLJ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 15:49:58 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uJDp3PYcTYEc2ruefbfFLJ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Pixel Tablet in vertical mode]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Pixel Tablet in vertical mode]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Motorola Edge 50 Pro with Snapdragon 7 Gen 3 is launching early next month ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Motorola Edge 50 Pro is launching in India on April 3.</li><li>The device is listed on the country's Flipkart e-commerce site.</li><li>The listing reveals most of the device's specs, including SoC and cameras.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Motorola is gearing up to release its next premium mid-range smartphone in India on April 3, dubbed the Edge 50 Pro. </p><p>While the company had started teasing the device and its features, its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.flipkart.com/moto-edge-50-pro-coming-soon-27dsh-store?param=4789&otracker=clp_bannerads_1_8.bannerAdCard.BANNERADS_Moto-edge50Pro-tsr-EB%2B-%2B22nd%2B12PM_mobile-phones-store_3QOG6ND0M7G8">e-commerce listing</a> revealed all the details of this next <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-android-phones">mid-range phone</a>.</p><p>The device will be one of the fewer handsets powered by Qualcomm&apos;s latest Snapdragon 7 Gen 3 chipset. The same chipset is also venturing with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-nord-ce-4-to-launch-on-april-1-2024">OnePlus Nord CE 4</a>, which is also scheduled to launch in India on April 1.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Experience Mridupawan's fusion of intelligence & art with the stunning #MotorolaEdge50Pro!✨Let the magic unfold in your hands.Join the #AIArtMagic challenge for a chance to win yours using the Edge50 Pro AR Filter. Launching April 3rd#Ai #Art #Magic #Cinematic pic.twitter.com/WlKKoPE2c8<a href="https://twitter.com/motorolaindia/status/1771762987843391634">March 24, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>The upcoming Motorola Edge 50 Pro is already listed on India&apos;s Walmart-owned Flipkart e-commerce and will go on sale starting April 3. The listing confirms that the device features at least three colorways: a purple colorway with a vegan leather finish and a textured silver finish, which the company calls "a beautiful pearl finish," and the traditional black colorway.</p><p>The Edge 50 Pro&apos;s design will include a redesigned camera module that appears slightly raised from the back panel and consists of a three-camera setup. Per the listing, it will have a 50MP primary camera aided by a 13MP macro camera that simultaneously acts as the ultra-wide camera.</p><p>The rear cameras are believed to have AI-powered features like AI adaptive stabilization and AI photo enhancement engine, to name a few. On the front, the punch hole display beholds a 50MP selfie camera.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="7esqVprQeVc7wuRZAn9BuE" name="motorola-edge-50-pro-01.jpg" alt="Motorola Edge 50 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7esqVprQeVc7wuRZAn9BuE.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Motorola)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Speaking of, the device will sport a 6.7-inch pOLED 1.5K display accompanied by a 144Hz higher refresh rate, which very few phones in the segment feature. Additionally, it will have HDR10+ certification next to 2000 nits of peak brightness. </p><p>Other highlights of the device include an IP68 for underwater protection. The Edge 50 Pro will be shipped with <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review">Android 14</a> out of the box, and the company promises a three-year assured Android OS upgrade. </p><p>While the device&apos;s battery capacity is yet to be determined, it will support 125W fast charging; additionally, the interesting aspect appears to be the 50W wireless charging support, further accompanied by 10W wireless power-sharing that can be helpful to charge your compatible tiny TWS earbuds.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-edge-50-pro-launching-on-april-3-2024</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Motorola is gearing up to launch its next mid-range phone in India on April 3. It packs a host of impressive specs for its segment. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">8yqzrjPCnxLzrVa8VzgqCG</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rHBUZmjMQT4SL5jd7oxRpE.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 15:45:15 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rHBUZmjMQT4SL5jd7oxRpE.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Motorola]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Motorola Edge 50 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Motorola Edge 50 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Ask Jerry: How do I remove malware? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Welcome to Ask Jerry, where we talk about any and all the questions you might have about the smart things in your life. I&apos;m Jerry, and I have spent the better part of my life working with tech. I have a background in engineering and R&D and have been covering Android and Google for the past 15 years. </p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Ask Jerry</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="rbW6k4ZmBUAZL7mR2bMnV6" name="jerrydude-avatar.gif" caption="" alt="Android Avatar of Jerry" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rbW6k4ZmBUAZL7mR2bMnV6.gif" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Future)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">Ask Jerry is a column where we answer your burning Android/tech questions with the help of long-time Android Central editor Jerry Hildenbrand.</p></div></div>
<p>I&apos;m also really good at researching data about everything — that&apos;s a big part of our job here at Android Central — and I love to help people (another big part of our job!). If you have questions about your tech, I&apos;d love to talk about them. </p><p>Email me at <strong>askjerryac@gmail.com</strong>, and I&apos;ll try to get things sorted out. You can remain anonymous if you like, and we promise we&apos;re not sharing anything we don&apos;t cover here.</p><p>I look forward to hearing from you!</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="what-can-i-do-about-malware-2">What can I do about malware?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4535px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="A4qzwGwLWnqmoYpoYPnxyC" name="Google-Play-Manage-Apps-Devices.jpg" alt="The manage apps and devices tab of the Google Play Store." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/A4qzwGwLWnqmoYpoYPnxyC.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4535" height="2551" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Brady Snyder / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Anonymous writes:</p><p><em><strong>I know this is a longshot, but by chance do you know how to remove malware from my Android phone that came from the Google Play Store?</strong></em></p><p><em><strong>Thanks.</strong></em></p>
<p>Howdy anon! I love this one because it&apos;s a question about a very confusing topic. I&apos;m sure a lot of folks are wondering something similar because of the way the word malware gets used.</p><p>I&apos;m guilty of doing it too, so I&apos;m not being judgmental or anything. I&apos;m just saying malware doesn&apos;t necessarily mean what you think it means.</p>
<p>First things first — removing it. You say it came from the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-play">Play Store</a>, so you can probably do nothing and it will get removed by itself. Google uses what it calls <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/what-is-google-play-protect">Play Protect</a>, which is a sort of malware scanner that is good at detecting malware and can alert you or even uninstall it for you.</p><p>If you&apos;d rather not wait, or it&apos;s something Play Protect hasn&apos;t caught, you can uninstall it like any other app from Google Play:</p>
<ul><li>Open your phone's settings.</li><li>Find the section for Apps. Open it and find a link for "All apps" and tap it.</li><li>You'll find the app in the list, and tapping it will open a page where you can uninstall it.</li></ul>
<p>With the offending app out of the picture, let&apos;s talk more about malware. </p>
<h2 id="what-is-malware-2">What is malware?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1974px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:65.75%;"><img id="SW7Xj2Utm6syCa5478m9ff" name="android-malware.jpg" alt="Android malware on a Sony smartphone" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SW7Xj2Utm6syCa5478m9ff.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1974" height="1298" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Oxford Dictionary defines malware as "software specifically designed to disrupt, damage, or gain unauthorized access to a computer system." But everyone seems to have a different opinion. Malware can affect even the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a>.</p><p>To me, malware is a name for a computer program (your phone is a computer) that does more than it is supposed to do — usually things we don&apos;t <em>want</em> it to do. Many people writing about tech for a living have a similar definition. Others think of malware more like Oxford does.</p><p>This overly broad interpretation means the word gets thrown around a lot, and everyone who uses it has a different idea of what it is. This is fine but confusing because you might read someone like me calling an app malware, but Google doesn&apos;t consider it malware. </p>
<p>Google has <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/what-gms-and-why-does-my-phone-need-it">specific rules</a> about apps and their <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/android-app-permissions">permissions</a>, and as long as an app follows those rules, it can stay in the Play Store.</p><p>An example would be an app that collects and shares data, but only after we agreed that it could collect and share it. As long as we give permission — by clicking yes and not reading the terms and conditions — the app isn&apos;t doing anything wrong as far as Google is concerned.</p><p>Other people might call an app that harvests data it doesn&apos;t need to work "malware." I would call it malware. Google would not in this case because the app is doing what it promised it would do.</p>
<p>What really matters is what you think. Uninstalling apps is easy unless the company that made your phone put them into the OS, but taking time to read what you&apos;re installing isn&apos;t. Some developers know you&apos;re not going to read through 10 pages of text when you install an app and count on you to click Agree, so they can act a little bit shady.</p><p>The best way to fight malware? Keep your phone&apos;s software up to date, don&apos;t <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/unknown-sources">install apps from places you don&apos;t trust</a>, and read both the app&apos;s reviews and the terms and conditions. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/ask-jerry-how-remove-malware-from-phone</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Have a question about the tech in your life? If so, maybe we can get them answered! ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">JeTw4LHvCnDSyfx6GxJ9f8</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HrmCzNcQDgwjg2sArrBf7S.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 15:13:15 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HrmCzNcQDgwjg2sArrBf7S.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android statues]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android statues]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Maps is far and away the most popular navigation app, study finds ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A MarketWatch study analyzing speed traps in the U.S. found that an overwhelming majority of people use Google Maps as their navigation app.</li><li>After surveying 1,000 drivers in the U.S., the results were that 70% of people used Google Maps for navigation. </li><li>Waze and Apple Maps were runner-ups in the study, with each app being used by about a quarter of the population surveyed. </li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Apple Maps and Google Maps are two of the most popular navigation apps available, and each app has passionate fans who claim one is better than the other. In some ways, it&apos;s representative of the iPhone vs. Android debate. However, according to the numbers, there&apos;s one navigation app that stands out from the rest. In a recent <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.marketwatch.com/guides/insurance-services/u-s-speeding-trends-penalties-and-avoiding-traps/" target="_blank">MarketWatch</a> study, 70% of respondents said they use Google Maps to avoid speed traps. </p><p>Navigation apps help people find their destination, but they provide other functionality as well thanks to crowd-sourcing efforts. Apps can let drivers know about hazards, road closures, accidents, and speed traps. This MarketWatch study focused on the latter and how navigation apps help drivers avoid tickets. Researchers studied 1,000 people in the U.S., who gave insight into their driving habits with regard to speed traps and how navigation apps play a role. </p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-maps">Google Maps</a> blew every other navigation app out of the water when it came down to usage. The study found that 70% of people use Google Maps, in part to help detect and avoid speed traps. Waze, which is also owned by Google, came in second with a 27% usage rate. Apple Maps came in third, just behind Waze, with 25% of respondents saying they use Apple&apos;s navigation app. </p><p>In total, MarketWatch says 34% of people have been warned by one of the navigation apps about a speed trap at least once. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:912px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:99.34%;"><img id="gHhrQXQ9svrpTppo5TTTUf" name="Screenshot 2024-03-23 233615.png" alt="The results of a MarketWatch study about navigation app usage." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gHhrQXQ9svrpTppo5TTTUf.png" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="912" height="906" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: MarketWatch)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The results are interesting because the iPhone is extremely popular in the U.S. Annual reports have found that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/report-android-users-switching-to-ios-2023">Android users are consistently switching to iOS</a> each year. While fewer Android users purchased iPhones in 2023, 13% of all iPhone purchasers came from an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android device</a>. Plus, iPhones make up over half of all smartphone shipments in the U.S. With all that said, it figures that iPhone users are foregoing the inbuilt Apple Maps app in favor of Google Maps, based on the results of the MarketWatch report. </p><p>Combining the users of Waze and Google Maps, an overwhelming majority of people in the U.S. turn to Google for navigation. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-maps-popularity-united-states-study</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ There are plenty of high-quality navigations apps, including Google Maps, Apple Maps, and Waze, but a new study found Google's option is nearly ubiquitous. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">jAT6BKJPj3y43mhpPm2v7m</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qUjfN5VNqqQvdfJehALEH6.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 07:38:32 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qUjfN5VNqqQvdfJehALEH6.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Maps driving mode black bar]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Maps driving mode black bar]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ WhatsApp will soon let you hide link previews in messages ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Currently, sending a hyperlink in WhatsApp will generate a link preview, revealing information about the website or page shared. </li><li>WhatsApp is planning a new option in settings that will allow users to disable link previews in messages. </li><li>The privacy feature was spotted in the latest version of the WhatsApp beta for Android, but it's not ready for end users yet.  </li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Most of us can probably recall a time when something popped up on our <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">smartphones</a> that we weren&apos;t expecting. Whether it&apos;s an embarrassing link sent by a friend or family member or just something stumbled upon on social media, some things are just better kept private. That&apos;s why WhatsApp is preparing to introduce a new feature for Android users that will let them disable link previews in messages. That way, WhatsApp users won&apos;t ever have to worry about a link preview unexpectedly showing up. </p><p>The new option for WhatsApp was spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://wabetainfo.com/whatsapp-beta-for-android-2-24-7-12-whats-new/" target="_blank">WABetaInfo</a>, which found the toggle in the app&apos;s advanced settings menu. Specifically, this option only appeared in version <strong>2.24.7.12</strong> of WhatsApp via the Google Play Beta Program. That means you won&apos;t be able to find it in your public release of the WhatsApp for Android app, and it might not even show up for everyone running the beta software. </p><p>The option is fairly self-explanatory. <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/whatsapp">WhatsApp</a> currently generates a link preview for URLs sent in messages in the Android app. This makes links appear larger than typical messages, and they include more information. When all the information is available, WhatsApp will show the webpage title, excerpt, and thumbnail image. Depending on the link, this might not be an issue. However, link previews in WhatsApp messages could reveal things you might want to keep private for a variety of reasons. </p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">📝 WhatsApp beta for Android 2.24.7.12: what's new?WhatsApp is working on a new privacy feature to disable link previews, and it will be available in a future update!https://t.co/nFi2dfDc18 pic.twitter.com/MmsAA95LG0<a href="https://twitter.com/WABetaInfo/status/1770964879375020041">March 22, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>In the public version of the app, link previews are not optional. But in the latest WhatsApp beta, there&apos;s a toggle called <strong>Disable link previews</strong> in the <strong>Advanced </strong>section of WhatsApp settings. By default, link previews will still be generated in WhatsApp messages. However, the upcoming feature will give privacy-conscious users the option of turning them off as they see fit. </p><p>As of now, the ability to disable link previews is not rolling out publicly, but it&apos;s likely to appear in a subsequent WhatsApp update. We don&apos;t know the timing of a public rollout for the toggle, though. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/whatsapp-beta-prepares-optional-link-preview</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Currently, links sent in WhatsApp messages will automatically generate previews. Users will soon get an option to disable this feature if they prefer.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">zPAjgKmkojZr4HKyWPH8Za</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/v7Wn9fCXXtv8f2AvinErWA.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 07:35:07 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/v7Wn9fCXXtv8f2AvinErWA.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[WhatsApp chat window with an edited message highlighted]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[WhatsApp chat window with an edited message highlighted]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ This is the ONLY Samsung phone deal I'm buying during Amazon's Big Spring Sale ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The Amazon Big Spring Sale ends March 25th, so I&apos;m using the remaining hours of the shopping event to grab one last smartphone deal before it&apos;s gone for good (or at least until Prime Day, I guess). For the duration of the sale, the Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus is getting a straight $150 discount, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Smartphone-Unlocked-Android-Processor/dp/B0CMDRLL66"><strong>knocking the price down to $849.99</strong></a>. That&apos;s the cheapest that the unlocked device has <em>ever been</em>, and it means I can finally ditch my Pixel 7a with its middling battery life. </p>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/amazon-spring-sale-2024-early-deals-predictions-and-what-to-expect"><strong>Amazon Big Spring Sale 2024 </strong>— see the 30+ deals we're buying</a></li></ul>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="0224dc0f-6ff4-4f88-8598-a3914b38c9dd" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$999.99" data-dimension48="$999.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CMDRLL66" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="VisKfptUSa9PzxXytLJU94" name="galaxy-s24-plus-official.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/VisKfptUSa9PzxXytLJU94.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus 256GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CMDRLL66" data-dimension112="0224dc0f-6ff4-4f88-8598-a3914b38c9dd" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$999.99" data-dimension48="$999.99"><del>$999.99</del><strong> $849.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>For the first time since the flagship lineup was revealed back in January, Amazon is carving a sweet $150 off the unlocked Galaxy S24 Plus. Any color, any configuration. Despite being considered the "middle child", the S24 Plus has no shortage of standout specs, including the powerful new Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 chipset, fantastic battery life, and enough software support to keep the phone relevant for many years to come. </p>
<p><strong>Price comparison: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-s24-512gb-unlocked-onyx-black/6569852.p">Best Buy - $849.99</a> | <a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/smartphones/galaxy-s24/buy/galaxy-s24-plus-256gb-unlocked-sm-s926uzkaxaa/">Samsung - $999.99</a> | <a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/SAMSUNG-Galaxy-S24-Plus-Cell-Phone-256GB-AI-Smartphone-Unlocked-Android-50MP-Camera-Fastest-Processor-Long-Battery-Life-US-Version-2024-Onyx-Black/5262667714">Walmart - $895</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CMDRLL66" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="0224dc0f-6ff4-4f88-8598-a3914b38c9dd" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$999.99" data-dimension48="$999.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>Sure, you can probably find better <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/best-samsung-galaxy-s24-deals-of-the-month">Samsung Galaxy S24 deals</a> if you do a trade-in or upgrade your wireless service, but if you prefer the simplicity of an unlocked phone, this offer is for you. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-plus-review">Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus</a> sits right in between the other two phones of the flagship lineup, with a stunning QHD+ 6.7-inch display, Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 processor, and seven years of software updates guaranteed. You also get to enjoy all of those <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-galaxy-ai">AI-powered software features</a> that everyone&apos;s been talking about. </p><p>It&apos;s quite likely that the Galaxy S24 Plus will rank among the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a> released in 2024, but in the meantime, this is a great way to get your hands on an excellent phone for way under the retail price.</p><p><em>It&apos;s not a phone, but if you were hoping to find a new smart TV to pair with your new phone before the sale ends, it&apos;s worth mentioning that Amazon and Samsung alike are </em><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/uh-what-amazon-is-now-giving-away-free-samsung-smart-tvs-during-the-big-spring-sale"><em><strong>currently running a BOGO TV deal</strong></em></a><em> when you preorder one of the new 2024 Samsung TVs. Grab an eligible set and you can score a second 65-inch smart TV for 100% free. </em></p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/this-is-the-only-samsung-phone-deal-im-buying-during-amazons-big-spring-sale</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ During Amazon's sale event, the unlocked Galaxy S24 Plus is getting a $150 discount for the first time ever. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">HhEhVQBjDB9r4ESs4qgm6k</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NAgWD6zM6wmGVrUqUWknrm.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 18:00:09 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NAgWD6zM6wmGVrUqUWknrm.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Galaxy S24 Plus lying face down on rocks]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Galaxy S24 Plus lying face down on rocks]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Max Mustard is the blissful VR rebirth of a popular 32-bit genre ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>I can&apos;t begin to describe my elation when Max Mustard first popped onto my Meta Quest 3 screens. The vibrant colors, quirky enemies, lovable animations, plunger gun, and jet boots all scream 90s platformer, and yet it&apos;s debuting for the first time in 2024, and in VR, no less.</p><p>A VR platformer sounds a bit strange until you think of the evolution of the platformer genre. All of the earliest examples from the genre were side-scrolling 2D games like Pitfall and Super Mario Bros. A few decades later, 3D platformers like Super Mario 64, Crash Bandicoot, and Sonic Adventure would take the concept into 3D space and revolutionize it completely.</p><p>Since there&apos;s no 4D, taking the genre into VR makes the most sense when you think about it. Now, instead of just moving your character, you yourself can look around the world, better approximate 3D depth, and even interact with the virtual world with your own two hands.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-meta-quest-games">best Meta Quest games</a>, like the Moss series, Ghost Giant, and Lucky&apos;s Tale, have already proven this formula to be successful, but it&apos;s the original PSVR&apos;s AstroBot Rescue Mission is the gold standard in VR platformers.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nECSEOy1zwM" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<p>Thankfully, Max Mustard is here to try and wrestle the title away from Astro, delivering similar precision mechanics, hidden secrets throughout each level, jump boots, and even in-game controller upgrades to the now-classic title. Adding a plunger gun to my controller was a brilliant way to enhance interaction with the world, particularly in places tough for your joystick-controller character to reach.</p><p>I had my doubts going in, but they were assuaged almost instantly with the game&apos;s Saturday morning cartoon-like intro. After all, the indie developer has only made one other game before — the ever-popular but highly gimmicky Richie&apos;s Plank Experience — yet the enthusiasm for this new title can&apos;t help but be felt in every second spent in its vibrant world.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>Platformers are always a collectathon, but Max Mustard rewards you with upgrades from an item shop in exchange for collectables.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>As you&apos;d expect from a platformer game, the most basic goal in Max Mustard is to get to the end of each level successfully, all while collecting as many items as possible along the way. You&apos;ll pick up different colored coins, jump on the heads of baddies, spin kick open crates to free trapped creatures, and collect power-ups that give you an edge in specific scenarios.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3840px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="uwNyRoUpoQTAAvhfqzGu5H" name="max-mustard-plunger-gun.jpg" alt="A Max Mustard screenshot from the Meta Quest 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uwNyRoUpoQTAAvhfqzGu5H.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="3840" height="2160" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3840px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="K3fEB3tbQMtEL9JEm8p9gG" name="max-mustard-spikes.jpg" alt="A Max Mustard screenshot from the Meta Quest 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/K3fEB3tbQMtEL9JEm8p9gG.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="3840" height="2160" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3840px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="RKjKXHgEPmqzbFYHHCxziF" name="max-mustard-green-space.jpg" alt="A Max Mustard screenshot from the Meta Quest 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RKjKXHgEPmqzbFYHHCxziF.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="3840" height="2160" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 4 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3840px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="AXQPfoCF6kRCgsVKHL59FF" name="max-mustard-desert.jpg" alt="A Max Mustard screenshot from the Meta Quest 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AXQPfoCF6kRCgsVKHL59FF.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="3840" height="2160" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 5 of 5</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:3840px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="xgHUnjPkTR3abssYBEBUpE" name="max-mustard-city-boss.jpg" alt="A Max Mustard screenshot from the Meta Quest 3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xgHUnjPkTR3abssYBEBUpE.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="3840" height="2160" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>What&apos;s nice is that collecting coins isn&apos;t just for one-ups or bragging rights. Coins allow you to purchase upgrades from the item shop. One of the initial cheap upgrades includes a camera rotation option, letting you easily rotate around each level without needing to stand up or physically turn around in your seat.</p><p>The game is also perfectly playable in a seated position. I found this game to be most enjoyable when playing seated, which isn&apos;t something I&apos;d say about most VR games.</p><p>The music is whimsical, and the environments remind me quite a bit of the original Ratchet & Clank. Each world offers a good bit of variety, and you&apos;ll navigate to each level via an overworld map similar to many Super Mario games.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>Max Mustard challenges AstroBot Rescue Mission, delivering similar precision mechanics, hidden secrets throughout each level, jump boots, and even in-game controller upgrades.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>The sound design is mostly good, but I felt like there were a few times when additional sound effects would have added extra depth. I also had to repeat some of the light story sequences because I was impatient and walked off a cliff, so I&apos;d love a "skip" button in these sorts of scenarios.</p><p>All in all, this is the VR platformer I&apos;ve been waiting for and is wholly worth the $29.99 price on Meta Quest. The game is also coming to PSVR 2 and Steam VR sometime this Summer.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/max-mustard-vr-platformer-debut</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Max Mustard is the reboot of the 3D platformer, adding a Saturday morning cartoon vibe and VR interactivity to revitalize an aging genre. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">i388tuSsduk5m6Q6tvod9K</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/G8b824u93tM6boBdQRw9EG.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 17:00:41 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nicholas.sutrich@futurenet.com (Nicholas Sutrich) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/G8b824u93tM6boBdQRw9EG.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A Max Mustard screenshot from the Meta Quest 3]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A Max Mustard screenshot from the Meta Quest 3]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Amazon's Big Spring Sale SLASHES over 40% off the Fire HD 10 tablet (but not for long) ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The tablet deals are plentiful this Spring, in no small part due to Amazon&apos;s limited-time Big Spring Sale! For those who don&apos;t mind lockscreen advertisements, Amazon has <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CD1C2WB1"><strong>slashed $75 off the price of the 64GB Fire HD 10 tablet</strong></a>. At just $104.99, this deal offers an impressive 42% in savings, making it a strong pick for anyone on a budget.</p><p>This 2023 version of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/amazon-fire-hd-10-2021-review">Amazon Fire HD 10</a> includes a 10-inch full HD display, up to 13 hours of battery life per charge, and expandable storage of up to 512GB with the use of a MicroSD card. Though slightly lacking in resolution, it also includes rear- and front-facing cameras, as well as dual speakers sporting Dolby Atmos.</p>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/amazon-spring-sale-2024-early-deals-predictions-and-what-to-expect"><strong>Amazon Big Spring Sale 2024</strong> — check out our top 30 deals</a></li></ul>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="29721d07-d0cd-4568-91a3-93f561450887" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Amazon Fire HD 10 (2023): $179.99" data-dimension48="Amazon Fire HD 10 (2023): $179.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BL5PYD69" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="269AR967vuZMNvSBiELmAM" name="amazon fire hd 10 reco 600x600.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/269AR967vuZMNvSBiELmAM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Amazon Fire HD 10 (2023): </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BL5PYD69" data-dimension112="29721d07-d0cd-4568-91a3-93f561450887" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Amazon Fire HD 10 (2023): $179.99" data-dimension48="Amazon Fire HD 10 (2023): $179.99"><del>$179.99</del> <strong>$104.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>The Fire HD 10 tablet is a great affordable pick, and at this price, it's going to be hard to beat. The Amazon Spring Sale has dropped the Fire HD 10 price by 42% for the 64GB configuration with lockscreen ads. This brings the device back down to the lowest price its ever been, making it a solid choice for those trying to save on a tablet.</p>
<p>This tablet features a 10-inch full HD display, along with up to 13 hours of battery life. If you aren't a fan of lockscreen ads, you can get this tablet without—though it won't include any special Spring savings.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BL5PYD69" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="29721d07-d0cd-4568-91a3-93f561450887" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Amazon Fire HD 10 (2023): $179.99" data-dimension48="Amazon Fire HD 10 (2023): $179.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>you&apos;re looking for a tablet that can consistently deliver over 10 hours of battery life; you want something that includes expandable storage with MicroSD; you plan to use your tablet for gaming.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>you prefer a tablet that&apos;s especially lightweight; you need a camera that can deliver high-quality pictures; lockscreen ads bother you.</p><p>We consider the Fire HD 10 the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-kindle-fire-tablet">Best Fire Tablet for Sharing</a>, along with it being our third favorite Amazon Fire tablet overall. Beyond having a fairly nice full HD display, it also comes with up to 13 hours of battery life, expandable storage of up to 512GB, and dual stereo speakers with Dolby Atmos.</p><p>As for downsides, this particular deal is for the Fire HD 10 with lockscreen ads, and the discount isn&apos;t available for either the 64GB or 32GB versions without advertisements. Some have also said this tablet is heavy amongst peers, and it doesn&apos;t have great cameras.</p><p>With that being said, it still may be a great pick for those who are on a serious budget and don&apos;t mind the few negatives.</p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/amazons-big-spring-sale-slashes-over-40-off-the-fire-hd-10-tablet-but-not-for-long</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Amazon has slashed the price of the 64GB Fire HD 10 tablet by a whopping 42% for its Spring Sale, making it the cheapest this model has ever been. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Dg6L3z56Wem7cgjNH8Nvvj</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yU89jUKTKvGRBpD8ZNSxmc.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 15:58:05 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yU89jUKTKvGRBpD8ZNSxmc.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Amazon]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Amazon Fire HD 10 2023 video call with coffee]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Amazon Fire HD 10 2023 video call with coffee]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>