<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 01:45:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ What happens if Google has to sell Chrome? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>The worst person you know finally made a great point. Former Google CEO Eric Schmidt was <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.cnbc.com/video/2024/11/19/watch-cnbcs-full-interview-with-the-former-google-ceo-eric-schmidt.html">on CNBC</a> and said the quiet part out loud:</p><p><em>“Breaking up these companies is not going to fundamentally address the annoyance you have with them.”</em></p><p>He was talking about the news that the Justice Department may ask a judge to force<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-could-be-forced-to-sell-off-chrome-to-level-the-search-playing-field"> Google to sell off its Chrome browser</a> and he's absolutely right. Breaking up Google may benefit other tech companies, but nothing will change for you and me.</p>
<p>The reason why isn't hard to figure out; simply look at which companies would be both willing and able to buy Chrome from Google. Do you think Jeff Bezos or Elon Musk is going to treat you and your data any better than Google does? Will either somehow make the web a better place if they suddenly own the world's most popular browser?</p>
<p>I don't think it's going to happen, and after <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/the-pulse-google-is-now-a-monopoly-but-nothing-will-really-change">Google has exhausted every appeal</a> and tried every trick it can think of, it will have plenty of things on its plate that it hates. But selling Chrome (<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-will-die-if-split-from-google">or Android</a>, or its cloud platform, or any other of its "big" products) won't be one of them. Even if selling Chrome would help consumers, it hinges on finding a buyer who can face the regulatory scrutiny that Google is now facing. None of them can, or at least none of them should be able to. Big Tech is equally evil, and Meta is no better than Apple, which is no better than Microsoft.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1389px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="uCyqjgRgv6aNdMgFBZcHE3" name="google-my-ads-center-lifestyle.jpg" alt="Google My Ad Center on a Chromebook" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uCyqjgRgv6aNdMgFBZcHE3.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1389" height="781" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Namerah Saud Fatmi / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>With no buyer, the only other option would be to force Google to shut down Chrome, and that's downright un-American. Nope. Can't do it, won't do it. Remember, you think tech CEOs are fighting the good fight against Washington, but in reality, they're <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/musk-joined-call-between-trump-google-ceo">calling president-elect Trump to congratulate him</a>. The posturing and feel-good social media posts are to draw your attention away from the donations and camaraderie.</p>
<p>In a perfect world, getting rid of Chrome <em>could</em> be great. It would open the way for a company with no ties to ads or operating systems to lead the charge, and we all could use <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/">Firefox</a> and be treated a little better. In the real world, Firefox is still going to die a slow death without Google's money, while Chrome will still be around, sucking in everything it can in order to manipulate and monetize you regardless of what name is on the company letterhead.</p><p>It's my opinion that forcing Google to stop investing in Chrome actually does plenty of harm to consumers. Google spends so much money and time on Chrome's open codebase — which powers almost every WebKit browser — because <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/does-google-sell-your-data">it makes so much in return</a>. Chrome is an avenue to data, and data is an avenue to effective advertisements. It's just like Android, and to Google, spending money on a free product is an investment in its ad business. No other company will do this, and names like Opera, Brave, Samsung Internet Browser, and even Microsoft Edge will pay the price for it.</p>
<p>People use Chrome for one reason — its integration with Google's other products. You don't (well, shouldn't) use Chrome if you want a fast and resource-friendly web browser that doesn't spy on you like a dirty old man with a pair of binoculars. You use it because it works seamlessly with all the other stuff you use, like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gmail-android-how-to">Gmail</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-docs-new-feature-is-your-go-to-tool-for-wrangling-those-giant-documents">Google Docs</a>, or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/i-used-new-google-pay-over-two-years-heres-why-amazing">Google Pay</a>. This cohesion is something every other tech company dreams about, and only Apple can come close for people who only use an iPhone. For better or worse, the web belongs to Google.</p><p>Selling Chrome or making Google syndicate search results won't change any of that. It will allow other companies to make more money, but for consumers, nothing is going to change no matter how Alphabet gets carved up because all tech companies have the same goals.</p>
<p>For me, it's nice to see Google on the hot seat because the company does so many terrible things. I just think the people who run companies like Google are smarter than the people going after them and will always win in the end.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/what-happens-if-google-has-to-sell-chrome</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A win for Microsoft and Apple, selling Chrome isn't going to make the web better.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">SQeYjWP5gHm9CeuqNvjVbH</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZogmMvXgwJrn6aMHtVxdd5.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZogmMvXgwJrn6aMHtVxdd5.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Myrick / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Chrome logo at 2024 Fall Chromebook Event]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Chrome logo at 2024 Fall Chromebook Event]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Skip Black Friday, the Galaxy S24 Ultra just scored a stunning $350 discount at Best Buy — no trade-in required! ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>If steep price tags have prevented you from buying this year&apos;s greatest Android phones, you&apos;re in luck: Best Buy just dropped <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-256gb-unlocked-titanium-black/6569855.p"><strong>an early Black Friday deal that slashes $350 off</strong></a> the Galaxy S24 Ultra — no strings attached, no trade-in required!</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Black Friday deals</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Black Friday Google Pixel deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Black Friday Motorola deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Black Friday OnePlus deals</a><br>
<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/early-black-friday-garmin-deals-2024-ditch-your-old-smartwatch-and-save-big-on-forerunner-venu-and-more">-Black Friday Garmin deals</a></p></div></div>
<p>For $949.99, you&apos;re getting what is arguably the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-samsung-phones">best Samsung phone</a> ever built, a super-powered device with a stunning 6.8-inch AMOLED display, built-in S Pen stylus, and a powerful 200MP main camera. You also get a reliable two-day battery, a ton of useful Galaxy AI features, and the unrivalled efficiency of the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 chipset. And like all of the phones in the Galaxy S24 lineup, the S24 Ultra comes with seven years of guaranteed OS and security updates. We&apos;ve already seen a ton of outstanding <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024">Black Friday Samsung deals</a> this year, but this offer takes the cake as one of the best. </p>
<h2 id="the-premium-galaxy-s24-ultra-just-got-a-little-less-premium-for-black-friday-2">The premium Galaxy S24 Ultra just got a little less premium for Black Friday</h2>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="a0c2601e-c57c-4fa1-8f44-b1f4e483064d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,299.99" data-dimension48="$1,299.99" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-256gb-unlocked-titanium-black/6569855.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:800px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="GgWobTBkWru648FmweBtcg" name="samsung galaxy s24 ultra square render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GgWobTBkWru648FmweBtcg.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="800" height="800" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra 256GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-256gb-unlocked-titanium-black/6569855.p" data-dimension112="a0c2601e-c57c-4fa1-8f44-b1f4e483064d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,299.99" data-dimension48="$1,299.99"><del>$1,299.99</del> <strong>$949.99 unlocked | $849.99 with activation at Best Buy</strong></a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review"><strong>Android Central review: </strong>★★★★<strong>½</strong></a></p>
<p>If you value power in your devices, look no further than the Galaxy S24 Ultra. This beast of performance features a powerful Snapdragon processor with 12GB of RAM, a glorious QHD+ AMOLED display, and all of the innovative Galaxy AI features you could ever need. </p>
<p>Thanks to Best Buy's Black Friday sale, you can currently grab this super-powered smartphone with a $350 discount, no strings attached. Activate the device through your carrier and Best Buy will throw in an additional $100 off, just for kicks. </p>
<p>👀<strong>Alternate Black Friday deal: </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/smartphones/galaxy-s24-ultra/buy/galaxy-s24-ultra-256gb-unlocked-sm-s928ulbexaa/"><strong>Up to $800 off with trade-in, free storage upgrade at Samsung</strong></a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-256gb-unlocked-titanium-black/6569855.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="a0c2601e-c57c-4fa1-8f44-b1f4e483064d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$1,299.99" data-dimension48="$1,299.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>you want one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best Android phones</a> ever produced; you prefer to buy your phones unlocked; you want years of software support. </p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>you can wait for the Galaxy S25 to come out next year; you&apos;re looking for a trade-in opportunity. </p><p>Of course, even with this deal, 950 bucks isn&apos;t nothing. If you&apos;re cool with doing a trade-in (or you own something like the Galaxy S23 Ultra), I&apos;d consider skipping this Best Buy offer altogether and heading straight to Samsung.com, where you can <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.samsung.com/us/smartphones/galaxy-s24-ultra/buy/galaxy-s24-ultra-256gb-unlocked-sm-s928ulbexaa/"><strong>score up to $800 off the S24 Ultra</strong></a> when you send in an old or broken device. </p><p>No matter how you choose to save money this holiday season, you can rest easy knowing that there&apos;s never been a better time to buy the Galaxy S24 Ultra than <em>right now. </em></p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/skip-black-friday-the-galaxy-s24-ultra-just-scored-a-stunning-usd350-discount-at-best-buy-no-trade-in-required</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Days before Black Friday officially kicks off, Best Buy is carving a straight $350 off the super-powered Galaxy S24 Ultra. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">gBaejHPHY8vNgnFTZdwh8N</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7P2ErZCEHSc73umEzHChMN.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 22:57:52 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7P2ErZCEHSc73umEzHChMN.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The back of the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra in the Titanium Grey colorway]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The back of the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra in the Titanium Grey colorway]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Early Black Friday Garmin deals 2024 — ditch your old smartwatch and save big on Forerunner, Venu, and more ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>If you&apos;re planning to buy a new smartwatch this holiday season, you&apos;ll be pleased to learn that many of the best Black Friday Garmin deals have already gone live. Retailers like Best Buy and Amazon are carving up to $250 off Garmin wearables, and I&apos;ve dropped a selection of my favorite offers below. Whether you want something sleek and versatile or rugged enough to withstand ALL the elements, the best Garmin watch deals of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/black-friday-2024">Black Friday 2024</a> can be found in this guide. </p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">More Black Friday deals</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Black Friday Google Pixel deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Black Friday Motorola deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024">Black Friday Samsung deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Black Friday OnePlus deals</a></p></div></div>
<p>Here at Android Central, it&apos;s no secret that we&apos;re big fans of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-garmin-smartwatch">Garmin smartwatches</a>. These wearables are expertly crafted for athletes of all ages and skill levels, whether you&apos;re a marathon runner, long-distance hiker, or simply counting your steps throughout the day. Garmin devices can range from budget models to premium beasts of performance, but whatever you&apos;re searching for today, there&apos;s probably a Black Friday deal just waiting to be uncovered. </p>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-quick-links"><span>Quick links</span></h3>
<ul><li><strong>Black Friday Garmin sales: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/Garmin/page/675B188D-FBE3-4FF4-9DD0-E48E4A2C888D"><strong>Amazon</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/searchpage.jsp?st=garmin"><strong>Best Buy</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/browse/0?facet=brand:Garmin"><strong>Walmart</strong></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.garmin.com/en-US/"><strong>Garmin Store</strong></a></li><li><strong>Garmin Venu 3:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/garmin-venu-3-gps-smartwatch-45-mm-fiber-reinforced-polymer-stainless-steel-and-black/6551498.p"><del>was $449.99</del><strong> now $349.99 at Best Buy</strong></a></li><li><strong>Garmin Forerunner 165:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Garmin-Forerunner-Smartwatch-Colorful-Training/dp/B0CT3SGHXL"><del>was $249.99</del> <strong>now $199.99 at Amazon</strong></a></li><li><strong>Garmin Fenix 7 Pro Solar: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/garmin-fenix-7-pro-solar-gps-smartwatch-47-mm-fiber-reinforced-polymer-slate-gray/6545135.p"><del>was $799.99</del> <strong>now $549.99 at Best Buy</strong></a></li><li><strong>Garmin Vivoactive 5: </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Garmin-v-voactive-5-Slate-Aluminim-Bezel-with-Black-Case-and-Silicone-Band/5022920052"><del>was $299.99</del><strong> now $199.99 at Walmart</strong></a></li><li><strong>Garmin Venu Sq 2: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Garmin-Smartwatch-All-Day-Monitoring-Long-Lasting/dp/B0B5VVNJBF/"><del>was $249.99</del><strong> now $149.99 at Amazon</strong></a></li><li><strong>Garmin Forerunner 965: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/garmin-forerunner-965-gps-smartwatch-47-mm-fiber-reinforced-polymer-carbon-gray-tlc-titanium/6544443.p"><del>was $599.99</del><strong> now $499.99 at Best Buy</strong></a></li><li><strong>Garmin Bounce:</strong> <a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Garmin-Bounce-Green-Burst/6659973310"><del>was $149.99</del> <strong>now $129.99 at Walmart</strong></a></li></ul>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-early-black-friday-garmin-deals"><span>Early Black Friday Garmin deals</span></h3>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="7037602c-b3dc-4dfe-9452-ab9e83a5c811" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$449.99" data-dimension48="$449.99" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/garmin-venu-3-gps-smartwatch-45-mm-fiber-reinforced-polymer-stainless-steel-and-black/6551498.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="2WiJoGHqwkgsQeNTwMwDwL" name="garmin venu 3 400x500.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2WiJoGHqwkgsQeNTwMwDwL.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Garmin Venu 3:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/garmin-venu-3-gps-smartwatch-45-mm-fiber-reinforced-polymer-stainless-steel-and-black/6551498.p" data-dimension112="7037602c-b3dc-4dfe-9452-ab9e83a5c811" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$449.99" data-dimension48="$449.99"><del>$449.99</del><strong> $349.99 at Best Buy</strong></a></p>
<p>The watch we'd recommend to most folks is the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-venu-3-review">Garmin Venu 3</a>. This super-balanced wearable boasts a spacious AMOLED display with up to 14 days of battery life and all of the health and fitness tracking features you could ever need. Grab the Venu 3 during Best Buy's Black Friday sale and you'll score a straight $100 off your purchase!   <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/garmin-venu-3-gps-smartwatch-45-mm-fiber-reinforced-polymer-stainless-steel-and-black/6551498.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="7037602c-b3dc-4dfe-9452-ab9e83a5c811" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$449.99" data-dimension48="$449.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="639ee3dc-3ccc-425b-8e20-9dfa0cab752d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$249.99" data-dimension48="$249.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/Garmin-Forerunner-Smartwatch-Colorful-Training/dp/B0CT3SGHXL" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="kes35gCrRe7qtT24rDFeoP" name="garmin-forerunner-165-whitestone-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/kes35gCrRe7qtT24rDFeoP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1080" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Garmin Forerunner 165:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Garmin-Forerunner-Smartwatch-Colorful-Training/dp/B0CT3SGHXL" data-dimension112="639ee3dc-3ccc-425b-8e20-9dfa0cab752d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$249.99" data-dimension48="$249.99"><del>$249.99</del> <strong>$199.99 at Amazon</strong></a> </p>
<p>Currently 20% off at Amazon, the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-forerunner-165-review">Forerunner 165</a> is a great starter fitness watch with a lightweight design, up to 11 days of battery life, and some accurate heart rate and sleep tracking capabilities. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/Garmin-Forerunner-Smartwatch-Colorful-Training/dp/B0CT3SGHXL" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="639ee3dc-3ccc-425b-8e20-9dfa0cab752d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$249.99" data-dimension48="$249.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="8f7fbdb8-df87-48b8-bd7b-d4e1c70bac1e" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799.99" data-dimension48="$799.99" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/garmin-fenix-7-pro-solar-gps-smartwatch-47-mm-fiber-reinforced-polymer-slate-gray/6545135.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:967px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:88.52%;"><img id="voY6FBpVwNB4bARsXDbkrn" name="garmin-fenix-7-pro-solar-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/voY6FBpVwNB4bARsXDbkrn.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="967" height="856" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Garmin Fenix 7 Pro Solar:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/garmin-fenix-7-pro-solar-gps-smartwatch-47-mm-fiber-reinforced-polymer-slate-gray/6545135.p" data-dimension112="8f7fbdb8-df87-48b8-bd7b-d4e1c70bac1e" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799.99" data-dimension48="$799.99"><del>$799.99</del> <strong>$549.99 at Best Buy</strong></a></p>
<p>If you're looking for a fitness watch that's built to last, consider the Fenix 7 Pro Solar. This rugged watch harnesses the power of the sun to bring you up to 22 days of battery life, plus you get military-grade durability, a built-in LED flashlight, and 24/7 health and sleep monitoring. Place your order while the Black Friday sale is active and Best Buy will hook you up with a $250 discount. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/garmin-fenix-7-pro-solar-gps-smartwatch-47-mm-fiber-reinforced-polymer-slate-gray/6545135.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="8f7fbdb8-df87-48b8-bd7b-d4e1c70bac1e" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$799.99" data-dimension48="$799.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="4dac547e-e8fc-408b-be41-facfd037dbd2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$299.99" data-dimension48="$299.99" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Garmin-v-voactive-5-Slate-Aluminim-Bezel-with-Black-Case-and-Silicone-Band/5022920052" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1125px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:133.33%;"><img id="b7JGFY7Rt6zJq2RBZfSLMA" name="garmin-vivoactive-5-render-black.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/b7JGFY7Rt6zJq2RBZfSLMA.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1125" height="1500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Garmin Vivoactive 5:</strong> <a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Garmin-v-voactive-5-Slate-Aluminim-Bezel-with-Black-Case-and-Silicone-Band/5022920052" data-dimension112="4dac547e-e8fc-408b-be41-facfd037dbd2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$299.99" data-dimension48="$299.99"><del>$299.99</del> <strong>$199.99 at Walmart</strong></a></p>
<p>The Vivoactive 5 is a popular choice for folks who want the Garmin experience without sacrificing sleek smartwatch style. Currently sitting with a $100 discount during Walmart's Black Friday sale, the watch features a 1.2-inch AMOLED display, up to 11 days of battery life, and all of the same health and fitness tracking features that made Garmin famous. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Garmin-v-voactive-5-Slate-Aluminim-Bezel-with-Black-Case-and-Silicone-Band/5022920052" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="4dac547e-e8fc-408b-be41-facfd037dbd2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$299.99" data-dimension48="$299.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="7219b63f-1d43-451d-a7ac-cf2364eb5b82" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$249.99" data-dimension48="$249.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/Garmin-Smartwatch-All-Day-Monitoring-Long-Lasting/dp/B0B5VVNJBF/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1045px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:143.54%;"><img id="JigHsWJiLs4qWEQXnLoRQH" name="garmin-venu-sq-2-gray-render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JigHsWJiLs4qWEQXnLoRQH.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1045" height="1500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Garmin Venu Sq 2:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Garmin-Smartwatch-All-Day-Monitoring-Long-Lasting/dp/B0B5VVNJBF/" data-dimension112="7219b63f-1d43-451d-a7ac-cf2364eb5b82" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$249.99" data-dimension48="$249.99"><del>$249.99</del> <strong>$149.99 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>We called the Garmin Venu Sq 2 the "goldilocks smartwatch" in <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-venu-sq-2-review">our 4/5-star review</a>, and it isn't hard to see why. The balanced smartwatch comes with a bright AMOLED display that would look great next to an Apple Watch or Galaxy wearable, plus you get a long-lasting battery, a ton of health and fitness sensors, and NFC support. Grab the Venu Sq 2 before the Black Friday sales end and you'll receive a whopping 40% discount. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/Garmin-Smartwatch-All-Day-Monitoring-Long-Lasting/dp/B0B5VVNJBF/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="7219b63f-1d43-451d-a7ac-cf2364eb5b82" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$249.99" data-dimension48="$249.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="94b1df88-49ec-4afd-a2f4-33fa104062dd" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$599.99" data-dimension48="$599.99" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/garmin-forerunner-965-gps-smartwatch-47-mm-fiber-reinforced-polymer-carbon-gray-tlc-titanium/6544443.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="x3XC9L6qCL8KL6HswwFq78" name="Garmin Forerunner 965.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/x3XC9L6qCL8KL6HswwFq78.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Garmin Forerunner 965:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/garmin-forerunner-965-gps-smartwatch-47-mm-fiber-reinforced-polymer-carbon-gray-tlc-titanium/6544443.p" data-dimension112="94b1df88-49ec-4afd-a2f4-33fa104062dd" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$599.99" data-dimension48="$599.99"><del>$599.99</del><strong> $499.99 at Best Buy</strong></a></p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-forerunner-965-review">Garmin Forerunner 965</a> might just be the best runner's watch ever built, with impressively-accurate mapping software, multiple days of battery life on a single charge, and a vibrant AMOLED display. As part of its Black Friday sale, Best Buy is dropping a straight $100 off the watch. <a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/garmin-forerunner-965-gps-smartwatch-47-mm-fiber-reinforced-polymer-carbon-gray-tlc-titanium/6544443.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="94b1df88-49ec-4afd-a2f4-33fa104062dd" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$599.99" data-dimension48="$599.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="fb67f081-9bc0-4d5b-b7c9-47dc61ffef8d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Garmin Bounce: $149.99" data-dimension48="Garmin Bounce: $149.99" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Garmin-Bounce-Green-Burst/6659973310" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="KyVVivBZwsdKbY64XtEDaY" name="Garmin Bounce render bg.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KyVVivBZwsdKbY64XtEDaY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Garmin Bounce: </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Garmin-Bounce-Green-Burst/6659973310" data-dimension112="fb67f081-9bc0-4d5b-b7c9-47dc61ffef8d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Garmin Bounce: $149.99" data-dimension48="Garmin Bounce: $149.99"><del>$149.99</del> <strong>$129.99 at Walmart</strong></a></p>
<p>Is your kid ready for their first-ever smartwatch? The <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/garmin-bounce-kids-watch-review-the-fun-smartwatch-for-kids">Garmin Bounce</a> might be the answer. Currently $20 off at Walmart, this kid-friendly wearable comes with activity and sleep tracking, a durable construction, voice  and text support, and a bunch of intuitive, easy-to-use software features.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Garmin-Bounce-Green-Burst/6659973310" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="fb67f081-9bc0-4d5b-b7c9-47dc61ffef8d" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Garmin Bounce: $149.99" data-dimension48="Garmin Bounce: $149.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<h3 class="article-body__section" id="section-faq"><span>FAQ</span></h3>
<h2 id="when-is-black-friday-2">When is Black Friday?</h2>
<p>Black Friday is November 29th, the day after Thanksgiving in the United States. Although that&apos;s when sale events have gone live historically, Black Friday sales have been starting earlier and earlier every year, which means you can find excellent Black Friday deals throughout the entire month of November. </p>
<h2 id="which-retailer-has-the-best-garmin-deals-during-black-friday-2">Which retailer has the best Garmin deals during Black Friday?</h2>
<p>Retailers such as Best Buy, Amazon, Walmart, and Garmin itself have all released their Black Friday deals on Garmin watches early, and there are few differences between them. If you&apos;re trying to settle on a particular retailer, look beyond the price tags to see if there are any additional perks in the fine print. Is Amazon Prime going to give you free shipping? Does the Garmin store offer an extended warranty? These are important details to check before choosing an offer. </p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/early-black-friday-garmin-deals-2024-ditch-your-old-smartwatch-and-save-big-on-forerunner-venu-and-more</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Garmin's holiday sale is LIVE, and retailers all over the web are dropping major discounts on some of our favorite smartwatches.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">r2FBm43e4suTnh3KnjtbjR</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/L32utu6sJRhWEgUGUmhh8B.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 20:58:44 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/L32utu6sJRhWEgUGUmhh8B.jpeg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Garmin Forerunner 165 and 965 sitting atop one another on a plant.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Garmin Forerunner 165 and 965 sitting atop one another on a plant.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google's Android 16 release schedule shakeup is all about helping its competitors ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Google is in an interesting position. It's the developer of Android, but it's also the hardware manufacturer of a growing Android phone brand. In years past, being the developer of Android has given it an edge in making hardware and software for Google Pixel phones.</p><p>However, with Android 16, Google is shaking things up. The company is completely changing the Android development and release schedule in a way that'll benefit Google's partner OEMs — and by extension, Pixel competitors.</p><p>Google is such a large tech conglomerate that it naturally has a few competing interests. However, with the release of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16-developer-preview-1-is-here-with-new-features-and-a-snappier-release-timeline">Android 16 Developer Preview 1</a> this week, the company has rightfully and decisively put the Android platform above the Pixel brand. To compete with the iPhone, Google needs all of its Android partner OEMs at their best, shipping thorough and timely version updates each year.</p>

<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="xiQzkBM5cbAGgGccwEM6CB" name="iphone-16-pro-max-30.jpg" alt="Apple iPhone 16 Pro Max next to Pixel 9 Pro XL" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/xiQzkBM5cbAGgGccwEM6CB.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>That's something that even the best Android phone manufacturers have struggled with of late. Samsung can't seem to ship its Android 15-based One UI 7 update quickly, as it was delayed until next year. Smaller brands have horrible reputations for delivering fast and reliable Android updates, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/android-14-is-finally-coming-to-the-motorola-razr-and-razr-plus-and-it-only-took-a-year">like Motorola</a>, which brought <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review">Android 14</a> to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2023-how-it-started-how-its-going">Motorola Razr Plus 2023</a> a full year after it was released.</p><p>OnePlus is one of the few companies with a presence in North America, not named Google, that managed to roll out Android 15 to the OnePlus 12 and OnePlus Pad 2 in a timely manner.</p><p>Google appears to have recognized this issue with Android, and it's actively correcting it. Android 16 is set for release in the second quarter of 2025, and it'll reach platform stability in March. That's months ahead of schedule, and the extra time will give partner OEMs — like Samsung, OnePlus, Motorola, and others — the time they need to deliver Android version updates alongside the release of their <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">best phones</a>.</p>
<h2 id="what-s-changing-about-the-android-yearly-release-schedule-2">What's changing about the Android yearly release schedule</h2>
<p>The first developer preview for Android 16 is here early, and that's not by accident. Google says that the move is "the start of Android having more frequent API releases as part of our effort to drive faster innovation in apps and devices" in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2024/11/first-developer-preview-android16.html" target="_blank">blog post</a> announcing the launch. What exactly does that look like? For one, there will now be two SDK releases each year, with the major one arriving in Q2 2025.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1357px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:21.00%;"><img id="rHUVhYifwwHNUKQpmEHXUj" name="Android-Release-Timeline" alt="The new release timeline for Android." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rHUVhYifwwHNUKQpmEHXUj.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1357" height="285" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The major SDK release will be the Android version update we're used to, which is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16">Android 16</a> in 2025. However, instead of reaching a final release in the third quarter, it'll come an entire quarter early. This is the update that'll include significant Android behavior changes, APIs, and new features.</p><p>Google says it's pushing the release up a quarter "to better align with the schedule of device launches across our ecosystem, so more devices can get the major release of Android sooner."</p><p>There's more — the company will now issue a <em>second</em> SDK release in the final quarter of 2025. This will be a "minor" SDK release, according to Google, that's bigger an a quarterly feature drop but smaller than an annual version update. The minor SDK release in Q4 2025 will come with new APIs and features but won't bring behavior changes.</p><p>This is intended to "ensure continuous quality" for the Android platform while not adding an extra burden for developers. That final SDK release will have feature updates, optimizations, bug fixes, and new developer APIs but won't include the behavioral changes that could cause compatibility issues for apps. "The Q2 major release [Android 16] will be the only release in 2025 to include planned behavior changes that could affect apps," Google emphasizes.</p><p>There are still quarterly Android updates, too. They'll now come in Q1 and Q3, splitting up the major and minor SDK releases with features only. Put them all together, and Google's changes to Android releases extend far beyond just shipping Android 16 a few months earlier. These are strategic changes that'll help the platform overall but will <em>really</em> help partner OEMs.</p>
<h2 id="the-shifted-schedule-will-make-new-android-phones-better-2">The shifted schedule will make new Android phones better</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="pvCDAx8DLCz47TvnBWuBfP" name="pixel-9-9-pro-xl-4.jpg" alt="Pixel 9 and Pixel 9 Pro XL next to Vivo X100 Ultra and Pixel 8 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pvCDAx8DLCz47TvnBWuBfP.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Right now, buying an Android phone is tricky, and the timing of software releases is the reason why. For example, Samsung launched the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-6-review">Galaxy Z Fold 6</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-6-review">Z Flip 6</a> in July, and the former is the most expensive phone it sells. However, it shipped with Android 14, it's still running Android 14, and it'll <em>keep</em> running Android 14 until at least the new year, when <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/delayed-one-ui-7-update-has-me-worried">Samsung is expected to release One UI 7</a>.</p><p>That's a problem. The best Android phones should be running the best Android version, but that's rarely the case. Even Google's own <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9">Pixel 9 series</a> launched without a new version Android for the first time ever.</p><p>Hopefully, it will soon be a problem of the past. By releasing developer previews, beta releases, and final versions of Android updates sooner, partner OEMs will get plenty of time to tune up their Android skins before device releases. "We're actively working with our device partners to bring the Q2 release [Android 16] to as many devices as possible," Google says.</p><p>Could that mean more devices, not just Pixel, launch with fresh Android updates? Or, might it mean that Android releases become less about being synced up with hardware releases and more about getting installed on as many devices as possible?</p><p>Those are questions we're still waiting for answers to. However, it's hard not to get excited about the future of Android. Google's announcements this week reaffirm a few key things. It's committed to working with partner OEMs to help them update their phones to the latest Android version as soon as possible. It's also going to keep the flow of Android updates continuous with security drops, quarterly updates, and a second major SDK release.</p><p>I'm hoping that Android's leaders — Samsung, Google, and others — use these changes to deliver consistent, high-quality, and rapid Android version releases, dispelling the notion that the platform isn't as reliable as Apple's.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-new-android-16-release-schedule-and-why-it-matters</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ It'll be easier for Android's partner OEMs to ship timely updates and line up releases with new products.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">TNYL9VsmpVnrkc3XZUos2B</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MSK4MbWwUCFo87qBSFcWfa.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 20:44:41 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MSK4MbWwUCFo87qBSFcWfa.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Pixel 8 Pro next to 2024 phones]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Pixel 8 Pro next to 2024 phones]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Messages could have a native backup tool in its future on Android ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google is reportedly working on a native backup/restore tool for its Messages app that leans on its cloud serves and your account.</li><li>Details from its code suggests users can choose to enable the backup/sync feature, sign in, and safely store their contents in case of a new device.</li><li>A backup/restore tool is something Meta's WhatsApp has had for a while; however, users can use that in tandem with Google Drive.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>A recent wave of discoveries points toward Google's development of a critical tool to save your texts when switching to a new device.</p><p>Initially discovered by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/11/19/google-messages-backup-restore/">9to5Google</a>, the company is reportedly creating the necessary systems behind a backup and restoration tool for the Messages app. This was noticed in v20241118_02_RC00 of the app's beta; however, AssembleDebug (<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/google-messages-backup-restore-feature-how-works-3501363/">Android Authority</a>) was able to get a more detailed look at Google's progress.</p><p>The tipster was able to produce the introductory splash screen that will likely greet users once this rolls out. Google description states "backup is better with Messages. Restore your conversations, media, and more anytime in app."</p><p>Once it arrives (if all goes well), it seems users can find a new "Backup & Sync" option within the app's settings. Tapping this will throw you to a page consisting of a backup toggle, what account the sync is tied to, and more. If you're signed in and the feature is toggled on, Messages will begin backing up your app contents to its cloud servers.</p><p>Moreover, Google informs users that their contents are E2EE (end-to-end encrypted).</p><p>If a user has switched devices, Google's early in-app description states signing in will download and restore your conversations "automatically."</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:269px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:223.05%;"><img id="Wprp8dz8GuhjMa6krqLDHM" name="google-messages-backup-settings-option-spotted" alt="Google Messages is seemingly developing a native backup/restoration tool." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Wprp8dz8GuhjMa6krqLDHM.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="269" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:268px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:223.88%;"><img id="7g84ES3LfPgxMqeCMin3GR" name="google-messages-backup-settings-options-discovered" alt="Google Messages will reportedly let users toggle its backup feature on or off alongside additional account/sync options." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7g84ES3LfPgxMqeCMin3GR.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="268" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Of course, the choice to use this feature, should it debut, is up to the user. More importantly, both publications highlight the potential option for users to delete and re-do their Google Messages backup. The folks at 9to5 state that turning off the backup/sync option <em>after </em>backing up texts will see them "permanently deleted from your Google Account."</p><p>Most of the feature seems proper and ready for debut, but there's no indication as to when we might see this.</p><p>A backup/restore option for the Messages app is yet another way Google is playing catch-up. Meta's WhatsApp notably features <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-backup-and-move-your-whatsapp-messages-and-media">a backup and restore tool</a> that users can leverage to save their precious conversations. It's one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-messaging-apps">best messaging apps</a> out there and this convenient feature only strengthens that. WhatsApp also lets users utilize Google Drive to safely store their content. Those on iOS are restricted to Apple's iCloud for such restoration services.</p><p>While users await native backup support, Google rolled out <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-messages-now-has-smarter-detection-to-tackle-tricky-scam-messages">stronger spam detection capabilities</a> for the app. The company states its app now piggybacks off its AI software to better fight off potential spam messages. Elsewhere, some users in the U.S. noticed Google's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-messages-dual-sim-rcs-support-us-rollout">dual SIM support</a> arriving for Messages.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://shop-links.co/link?id=pcmcat1563302848653&publisher_slug=future&exclusive=1&u1=ac-us-8320517100837906307&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Ftop-deals%2Fcell-phone-deals%2Fpcmcat1563302848653.c%3Fid%3Dpcmcat1563302848653&article_name=Google%20Messages%20is%20preparing%20to%20handle%20dual%20SIM%20for%20RCS%20%7C%20Android%20Central&article_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.androidcentral.com%2Fapps-software%2Fgoogle-messages-support-for-dual-sim-rcs" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1943169/565706/9383?subId1=ac-us-1021522894658110806&sharedId=ac-us&u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fcp%2Fcell-phones%2F1105910%3Fpovid%3Dweb_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://shop-links.co/link?publisher_slug=future&exclusive=1&u1=ac-us-5529311218434419633&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.samsung.com%2Fus%2Fshop%2Fall-deals%2Fcell-phone-deals%2F&article_name=Google%20Messages%20is%20preparing%20to%20handle%20dual%20SIM%20for%20RCS%20%7C%20Android%20Central&article_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.androidcentral.com%2Fapps-software%2Fgoogle-messages-support-for-dual-sim-rcs" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://target.georiot.com/Proxy.ashx?tsid=169923&GR_URL=https%3A%2F%2Famazon.com%2Fs%3Fk%3Dcell%2Bphone%26crid%3D19CKV7OMEPEMF%26sprefix%3Dcell%2Bphone%252Caps%252C222%26ref%3Dnb_sb_noss_1%26tag%3Dhawk-future-20%26ascsubtag%3Dac-us-3335110674762739320-20" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-100048248-15733793?sid=ac-us-1414899968902852761&url=https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-100048248-15735111?sid=ac-us-5959603424644066160&url=https://www.att.com/" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-messages-native-backup-sync-tool-spotted</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google is tipped to have a backup/restore function in development for Messages. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">D8M8nkBHxoWA4zs64RGGhE</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qEBpNmWm4DdEDy7sbyynw4.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 19:53:33 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qEBpNmWm4DdEDy7sbyynw4.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Messages left-panel menu]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Messages left-panel menu]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ A rumored OnePlus 'Flip' could be the Ace up its sleeve next year ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>OnePlus is rumored to have a clamshell (Flip-style) foldable in the works.</li><li>The device's specifications are still unknown; however, it could arrive in Q2 2025 under the company's Ace series.</li><li>Early Flip rumors claimed OnePlus could pack a telephoto and macro camera into the device.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Rumors are surfacing once again about the potential for a new foldable form factor from OnePlus.</p><p>The latest rumors stem from known Weibo leaker <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://weibo.com/6048569942/P10F1p9Bt">Digital Chat Station</a> (DCS) who states OnePlus could produce a "Flip" of its own (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/11/20/oneplus-allegedly-prepares-flip-style-foldable-for-2025/">9to5Google</a>). The supposed specifications of this clamshell device are still unknown. Curiously, DCS claims OnePlus could launch this new foldable under its "Ace" series.</p><p>Additionally, the tipster states the Chinese OEM could see a "tentative"<em> </em>launch of this device in Q2 2025.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="r2wyyL8TDtc7ZUyULGwjWY" name="oppo-find-n3-flip-42.jpg" alt="OPPO Find N3 Flip" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/r2wyyL8TDtc7ZUyULGwjWY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Rumors of a potential "OnePlus Flip" are nothing new and the most recent one surfaced <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-next-foldable-could-bring-the-heat-to-the-galaxy-z-flip-in-a-whole-new-way">earlier this year</a>, stating one was on the way. A leaker claimed OnePlus was "gearing up" to debut a clamshell foldable to take on Samsung's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-6-review">Galaxy Z Flip 6</a>. Similar to what users hope for in DCS' recent rumor thread on Weibo, the "OnePlus Flip" may debut with a telephoto lens and a macro camera.</p><p>Moreover, there was speculation that OPPO's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oppo-find-n3-flip-review">Find N3 Flip</a> could influence the design and caliber of a OnePlus variant. That wouldn't be surprising as these two companies lean heavily on one another when designing phones.</p><p>However, one thing to consider is the leaker's recent suggestion that a OnePlus Flip <em>could </em>fall under its Ace series. Devices under that moniker are typically mid-range devices with slightly toned-down specs, like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-ace-3-unveiled-in-china">the Ace 3</a> from January. This, of course, encourages a more cost-conscious appeal for the devices, which makes us think OnePlus could have Samsung and its (alleged) <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-z-flip-fe-s24-internal-chip-rumors">Galaxy Z Flip FE</a> in its sights.</p><p>OnePlus was also wrapped up in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oppo-and-oneplus-are-crucial-to-foldable-market">a curious rumor</a> that claimed it, alongside OPPO, could exit the foldable game. Let's not forget that OnePlus didn't release a second-generation version of its Open foldable in 2024. The company reportedly delayed its launch with rumors claiming it will <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-open-2-camera-charging-leaks">seek a Q1 2025 launch</a> for an "Open 2" with wireless charging capabilities.</p><p>Nothing is confirmed for sure, meaning we're going to have to wait and see what happens next year.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-flip-development-next-year-rumors</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ New rumors claimed OnePlus could have a "Flip" in the works. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">EgFb6iAhHYNpxakq2eMNoe</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Z9cnrbNGZ9SNiCxB6sjXZU.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 19:00:32 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Z9cnrbNGZ9SNiCxB6sjXZU.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Apoorva Bhardwaj / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OPPO Find N3 Flip]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OPPO Find N3 Flip]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ OPPO's ColorOS 15 preps several AI features via Gemini 1.5 Pro and more ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>OPPO detailed a major AI update for its ColorOS 15 (Android 15) software thanks to Google's software.</li><li>ColorOS 15 will provide Circle to Search, Gemini Live, and more of OPPO's own AI help thanks to Gemini 1.5 Pro and 1.5 Flash models.</li><li>OPPO is preparing to debut its Find X8 series on November 21.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>OPPO is preparing to rollout some AI additions for its Android 15 software that should aid users in multiple ways.</p><p>The company detailed the upcoming AI features that leverage Google's systems in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.oppo.com/en/newsroom/press/find-x8-series-coloros-15-google-gemini-ai/">press release</a>. OPPO's general manager, Nicole Zhang, stated a goal with its OS was to "create an easy-to-use, harmonious, powerful experience through intelligence and collaboration." With that, the Chinese OEM announced the upcoming arrival of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-circle-to-search">Circle to Search</a>.</p><p>The post reiterates that users can produce the feature by long-pressing the "home button or navigation bar." Users can quickly circle or highlight anything on their display to run a search through Google.</p><p>Elsewhere, the company states it's bringing in more AI features as ColorOS 15 will feature the dedicated Gemini app. OPPO mentions features like "help me write," AI planning assistance, and more. Additionally, OPPO's partnership with Google brings <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/gemini-live-is-available-for-free-on-android-phones">Gemini Live</a> to its "smart devices."</p><p>OPPO is working on a few AI-backed features of its own, but they will reportedly leverage Google's software. According to the post, the upcoming OS upgrade will pick up OPPO Notes, Documents, and AI Recording Summary. These features are said to leverage "Gemini models" like 1.5 Pro and 1.5 Flash. It's likely these models will lend a hand for other on-device AI features, too.</p><p>OPPO states its ColorOS 15 software and Google's AI assistance will debut first on the Find X8 series.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="73yMdYyMsT9vqgfUfLFYFY" name="Oppo-Find-X8-leaked-render.jpg" alt="Oppo Find X8 leaked render" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/73yMdYyMsT9vqgfUfLFYFY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Evan Blass)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>We're on the cusp of OPPO's next flagship series as the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oppos-answer-to-the-galaxy-s25-is-launching-globally-on-november-21">Find X8 is set to debut</a> on November 21. The company confirmed as much earlier this month, stating an event in Bali will hold all the details. Alongside its launch with ColorOS 15 (Android 15), the Find X8 series will feature the MediaTek Dimensity 9400 SoC. The devices will seemingly sport a new, flatter design and larger batteries.</p><p>Additionally, the company confirmed that the Find X8 will arrive in a few global regions like the U.K. and India.</p><p>Google first dropped Gemini Live as an <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-pixel-9-android-gemini-updates-detailed">update for Pixels</a> in August. The AI lets users engage in a more "conversational" way when asking for ideas, tips, and assistance with tasks. Google states Gemini Live can understand "complex questions," meaning users won't have to break up their sentences. The feature was then rolled out <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/gemini-live-is-available-for-free-on-android-phones">to all Android users</a> in October with increased language support.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/oppo-coloros-15-advances-device-ai-google</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ OPPO detailed a major AI update for its ColorOS 15 via Google's Gemini models. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">L3GceX5ufvoPtHGEiJvAFL</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gbE7NDe2Rut6zCprCEjsVE.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 18:04:21 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gbE7NDe2Rut6zCprCEjsVE.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Gemini Live UI on the Pixel 9]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Gemini Live UI on the Pixel 9]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google improving the tools app developers use is just as important as any Android update ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Most of us are glad we have a smartphone. We enjoy the things we can do with one, depend on one for many of our day-to-day tasks, and carry one around with us all of the time. With the right phone, your life is better in a lot of ways.</p><p>Did you ever stop to think about why? Buying <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">the right phone</a> can be hard because there are so many to choose from, but once that's done we usually just start using it without a thought about the things that make a phone useful.</p>
<p>None of those things would be possible without people developing software that gets added on top of Android. You might not know, but <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/aosp">Android is really basic</a>; it's mostly just software that can boot up a phone, support the hardware inside of it, and provide a platform for other software to run. It's that other software that you love to use or depend on every day.</p><p>That's why I think the most important updates to come out of Google are the ones for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini-in-android-studio-debut">"official" developer tools</a>. Improvements to the Android Studio development environment and the other tools developers need are why you want to use your phone.</p>

<p>I'm not an app developer. I have written a handful of apps for both Android and iOS to learn how the process works, but I've never even tried to write an app you would want to use. That experience did teach me a few things, though; the tools are more important than anything else Google can do to further Android as a platform.</p><p>A recent <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2024/11/android-emulator-stability-performance-updates.html">update to the Android emulator</a> (software that "runs" Android so apps can be tested in a live setting) is a great example. Almost every developer depends on the emulator, and there are some issues with it. It would get sluggish or lock up after a while on even the strongest computer hardware. Google decided to focus on improving it, and the most recent update is great. It's still not perfect, but Google hasn't said it is done working on it.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="ZMFgD8diq9sFmCHf975Zkm" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-purple-01.jpg" alt="Looking at the different colorways of the Samsung Galaxy S24" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZMFgD8diq9sFmCHf975Zkm.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google hasn't always done a good job here. It's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://developer.android.com/codelabs/basic-android-kotlin-compose-first-app#0" target="_blank">easy to become an Android app developer,</a> and if you're familiar with any sort of software development, you could have an app ready for the Play Store in a few hours. Throw all of that out the window when you're talking about a <strong>good</strong> app, though. In the beginning, terrible developer tools meant a million terrible apps in the Play Store for every good one. People don't want to write terrible apps, and thankfully, Google realized how important it was to support anyone — including you — who wants to make the next great Android app.</p><p>Writing an application that people will want to use is hard. First, you need to come up with the right idea, work through the issues that you know will arise as you get started, find ways to make your software work with thousands of different devices, and <em>then</em> write the good code that makes an app great. Without the right tools, most of this is going to be very difficult.</p>
<p>You're probably not an app developer, and improvements to these tools and new features in Android Studio probably don't seem very exciting to you. You only need to understand that these updates are important — sometimes more important than an update you'll get on your phone.</p><p>These are the things that make your phone, and Android as a whole, better.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-improving-the-tools-app-developers-use-is-just-as-important-as-any-android-update</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ If you want Android to improve, you must give developers the right tools. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">LZqLtfWJ76qq4uPnwFE7TY</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gp6NufNyDaQcj5KpEofLim.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gp6NufNyDaQcj5KpEofLim.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android Studio emulator view]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android Studio emulator view]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Galaxy S25 Ultra dummy unit gives us a better view of its fresh design ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Leaked dummy units of the Galaxy S25 Ultra give us a clearer look at its design ahead of launch.</li><li>The design features rounded corners, concentric camera rings, and a flatter frame, moving away from the sharp angles of the Galaxy S24 Ultra.</li><li>The rear camera setup stays similar but now includes concentric rings, reminiscent of the Galaxy Z Fold 6.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>A couple of leaked dummy models of Samsung’s upcoming Galaxy S25 Ultra give us a clearer look at what the new design might bring to the table.</p><p>As the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="">Galaxy S25</a> series launch gets closer, leaks are spilling everywhere. Leaker <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://x.com/jukanlosreve/status/1859187280264695898" target="_blank">Jukanlosreve</a>’s recent X post shows dummy unit images revealing some design tweaks, like rounded corners and concentric camera rings (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-dummy-leaks-2025-flagship-3501477/" target="_blank">Android Authority</a>).</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1107px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:97.56%;"><img id="twgna4ETQY8LdNA8zMqfYY" name="Galaxy-S25-Ultra-dummy-leak" alt="dummy unit of the Galaxy S25 Ultra" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/twgna4ETQY8LdNA8zMqfYY.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1107" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: <a href="https://x.com/Jukanlosreve">@Jukanlosreve / X</a>)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>We’re still waiting on official (or real-life) Galaxy S25 Ultra photos, but this new leak gives us a better glimpse so far. This comes <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-leaked-renders-reveal-flat-design">just a couple of months after renders dropped</a>, teasing some design changes for the phone.</p><p>Breaking away from the sharp angles of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="">Galaxy S24 Ultra</a>, the S25 Ultra seems to adopt softer curves. These tweaks could make it feel better in your hand.</p><p>More to the point, these dummy units suggest that the S25 Ultra is ditching the line's old design for a flatter frame and rounder corners, making it look more like the squarer <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="">Galaxy S24</a> base and Plus models.</p><p>Earlier <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://online-solitaire.com/blog/exclusive-samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-leaked-as-aluminium-dummy-phone-2/" target="_blank">rumors</a> pegged the high-end device at 162.82 x 77.65 x 8.25mm. Taking a closer look, this new model is a bit taller, slimmer, and thinner than the Galaxy S24 Ultra, which comes in at 6.40 x 3.11 x 0.34 inches.</p><p>The leaked dummy images show the S25 Ultra in black and white. The rear camera setup is mostly the same, but now the individual cameras sport concentric rings, giving off a vibe similar to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="">Galaxy Z Fold 6</a>.</p><p>Unfortunately, the new leak doesn't dive into the Galaxy S25 Ultra’s camera specs, but it gives us a clear look at the design of the rear camera module.</p><p>In the past few weeks, a wave of leaks has given us plenty of details about the Galaxy S25 Ultra. We've seen how it stacks up in performance against the iPhone 16 Pro Max and got a look at how their bezel designs compare.</p><p>The Galaxy S25 Ultra, along with the S25 and S24 Plus, is rumored to arrive in January or February, so we can probably expect more leaks and rumors to surface before the official reveal.</p>
<hr>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="9a966e05-3469-47c3-b0b3-ea0aa87aa13d">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/PBHvpjpX26yLAmUkjL5o3W.jpg' alt="Galaxy S24 Ultra in Titanium Yellow"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>The S24 Ultra is still a top-tier Android phone, even after all this time. Its killer display, amazing cameras, and smart AI features keep it ahead of the pack. Plus, it's the only flagship with a built-in S Pen.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/galaxy-s25-ultra-dummy-unit-gives-us-a-better-view-of-its-fresh-design</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung's next top-tier flagship model not be changing much. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">afNdUMraV7Zu6zKZHECsYA</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/X65GexZdyC98NmHwvCEFNJ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 16:58:13 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/X65GexZdyC98NmHwvCEFNJ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[OnLeaks/ Android Headlines]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Galaxy S25 Ultra renders leak]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Galaxy S25 Ultra renders leak]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google is giving Windows on Arm some more love with a native Drive app ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google Drive for Desktop now supports Windows on Arm, marking a big win for the platform.</li><li>The app’s in beta, so expect a few rough spots, but if you're used to setting it up on regular Windows, it’ll be an easy switch.</li><li>Outlook Meet plugin is missing, which could be a letdown for heavy Outlook users.</li><li>To use it, you need a Windows 11 PC with an Arm processor and the WebView2 runtime.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Windows on Arm just scored another win with support from Google's Drive for Desktop app.</p><p>Google recently <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/drive/thread/308624582/drive-for-desktop-arm64-support?hl=en" target="_blank">announced</a> a native Drive for Desktop app built for Windows on Arm devices (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.windowscentral.com/software-apps/this-one-google-app-is-finally-here-for-qualcomm-snapdragon-arm-based-windows-11-pcs" target="_blank">Windows Central</a>). It’s in beta right now, so expect some features to feel a bit rough around the edges.</p><p>If you’re used to setting up <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-drive">Google Drive</a> on regular Windows PCs, switching to the Arm64 version for Arm-based systems should be a breeze. The app feels the same, with the main difference being what’s under the hood (a native Arm64 support).</p><p>The native Drive for Desktop on Arm offers solid features but skips the Outlook Meet plugin. This might be a bummer for Outlook power users who depend on it for scheduling and teamwork. There's no word yet on whether Google plans to add it in future updates.</p><p>Since the native Drive for Desktop on Arm is still in beta, Google recommends using it with non-essential data or keeping backups just in case.</p><p>Even with its limitations, the native Arm version of Drive for Desktop is a big step forward. It’s a smoother, more efficient way to access and manage your files on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cloud-storage-service">cloud storage service</a> compared to the web version.</p><p>The app is now the second Google app optimized for Windows on Arm, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/chrome-chrome-windows-arm-optimization-rollout">following Chrome</a>. While Google also says <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-quick-share-upgraded-arm-windows-rollout">the Quick Share app works on Windows on Arm</a>, it’s important to note that it runs through emulation.</p><p>To use the native Drive for Desktop, you'll need a Windows 11 PC with an Arm processor and the Microsoft WebView2 runtime. The setup is straightforward—just download and install the app directly from Google.</p><p>With the launch of Qualcomm’s Snapdragon X platform and the rise of powerful, energy-efficient laptops, app compatibility became a big issue. While most major apps have been optimized for this new architecture, Google Drive was a key holdout, leaving users to rely on emulation.</p><p>The recent beta release of the native Drive for Desktop app eases those concerns and possibly boosts the adoption of Arm64 devices.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-is-giving-windows-on-arm-some-more-love-with-a-native-drive-app</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ One of the leading cloud storage services is now on Windows on Arm. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">hcYHtg6DwLSe5kNFXJBgDJ</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2QiuuNUyS4KYbeiDi5mTJJ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 14:20:45 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/2QiuuNUyS4KYbeiDi5mTJJ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Drive web gets dark mode]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Drive web gets dark mode]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>