<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 05:28:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Amazon Freevee's days are numbered as Prime Video's ad-supported tier picks up steam ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Amazon is shutting down Freevee to simplify its streaming services, making Prime Video the central hub for entertainment.</li><li>Freevee’s content will be moved to Prime Video, giving non-Prime members access to original series that were previously exclusive to Freevee.</li><li>The shutdown will happen over the next few weeks, affecting users in the U.S., UK, Germany, and Austria.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Amazon is set to shut down Freevee as part of efforts to streamline its streaming lineup and make Prime Video the go-to entertainment hub.</p><p>Deadline <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://deadline.com/2024/11/freevee-shut-down-amazon-prime-video-1236172644/" target="_blank">reports</a> that Amazon is moving Freevee’s content straight over to Prime Video. Consequently, non-Prime members will be able to watch new episodes of original series that were once only available on Freevee.</p><p>Freevee’s gradual shutdown is set to wrap up in the next few weeks, impacting viewers in the U.S., UK, Germany, and Austria. After the transition, Freevee’s content will be available on Prime Video’s "Watch for Free" section.</p><p>Although Freevee has been a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-services-free-trial-deals">popular free streaming option</a>, rumors of its shutdown started swirling after Prime Video launched its ad-supported tier in January. The move left many wondering what Amazon’s game plan really was.</p><p>Regular Freevee users might be bummed by this change, as the platform offers a clean, easy-to-use interface just for free content. It saved you from having to sift through the vast Prime Video library to find what you wanted.</p><p>You’ll still be able to access the content, but logging in will be required. It seems Amazon’s plan is to get more people hooked on Prime Video, with free content now mixed in with the paid shows and movies. The entry-level ad-supported tier is priced at $9 a month.</p><p>Bringing Freevee into Prime Video might make things a bit trickier for non-subscribers. Having to navigate paid options or deal with subscription prompts could take away from the simple, focused experience that Freevee used to offer on its own.</p><p>Launched as IMDb Freedive in 2019 under Amazon's IMDb brand, the platform quickly rebranded to IMDb TV and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/amazons-imdb-tv-streaming-service-is-getting-a-ridiculous-rebrand">then became Freevee in 2022</a>.</p><p>This news follows months of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.adweek.com/convergent-tv/amazon-sunset-freevee/" target="_blank">rumors</a> about Amazon planning to shut down Freevee and roll its content into Prime Video. Amazon had <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://deadline.com/2024/02/amazon-insists-no-changes-to-freevee-despite-reports-of-shutdown-streaming-1235832878/" target="_blank">brushed off</a> these claims before, insisting no changes were coming.</p><p>Amazon’s choice to shut down Freevee and move its content to Prime Video is probably due to the growing similarities between the two platforms. With the ad-supported tier now in place, Prime Video and Freevee have become much more alike, making the latter’s unique appeal less necessary.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/amazon-freevees-days-are-numbered-as-prime-videos-ad-supported-tier-picks-up-steam</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Amazon pulls the plug on Freevee and moves the content over to Prime Video. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">DBPAihkEES5GL7EJLK54rN</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RgRFzs8pbmEMkzUFPjxty5.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 22:59:26 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Streaming &amp; TV]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RgRFzs8pbmEMkzUFPjxty5.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Amazon]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Amazon Freevee logo]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Amazon Freevee logo]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ 1More SonoFlow Pro HQ51 review: Budget headphones worth every penny ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Great quality doesn’t have to come at a high price; a mantra 1More continues to perpetuate each time it releases new headphones or wireless earbuds. What makes this all the more compelling is that the company doesn’t skimp out along the way.</p><p>The SonoFlow Pro HQ51 are a prime example of that. It's a pair of over-ear headphones following up on the previous SonoFlow, which proved themselves as serious upstarts in their own right as one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-noise-canceling-headphones-under-100">best headphones under $100</a>. You do make sacrifices when paying less than $100 but you stretch out every dollar here toward some real value each time you use them.</p><p>The company already had a strong foundation to work with from the previous SonoFlow, which explains why the Pro HQ51 bears such a strong resemblance. Aside from color variances, everything else is in the same place, from the hinges to button placement. They fold up exactly the same way, though these prove easier to lay into the included case because there are no indents inside. There’s more room for cables, too.</p>

<h2 id="keeping-it-familiar-2">Keeping it familiar</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="pShfeoEwbe4CZM5a3ZXrSC" name="1More-SonoFlow-HQ51-open-case" alt="1More SonoFlow Pro HQ51 folded up in their carrying case." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pShfeoEwbe4CZM5a3ZXrSC.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ted Kritsonis / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>On the headphones themselves, 1More uses what feels like the same leather for the ear cushions and headband. This is a good idea, given how soft and comfortable it was the first time around. The memory foam inside also feels plush without constraining your head over longer listening sessions. It also helps that the headphones are lightweight, with good hinges for the ear cups. Fit is so subjective, but these should feel great.</p><p>Granted, they may not come off as all that exciting just looking at them. The company chose not to make any aesthetic changes apart from the black and blue color variants. The SonoFlow Pro HQ51 aren't flashy, though that hardly makes them ugly. They just don't have a particular design trademark, unless you count the Louboutin-style red inner ear fabric a nice touch.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="wQuDi56MbUyJGth3AZP7SX" name="1More-SonoFlow-HQ51-ear-cups" alt="1More SonoFlow Pro HQ51 ear cups inside." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wQuDi56MbUyJGth3AZP7SX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ted Kritsonis / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I will say, off the bat, that I would be careful about using these headphones for runs or workouts. They don't have an IP rating, so without any official water resistance, you're taking a chance every time you sweat while wearing them.</p><p>If you're willing to do that, you may like that there are physical buttons for all controls here. The NC button cycles between active noise cancelation (ANC), transparency, and turning both off. Volume buttons do the obvious, but you can also hold Vol+ to go back a track or Vol– to skip one. Press the power button once to play/pause or answer/hang up a call. Double-press it, and your phone's voice assistant will wake up.</p>
<h2 id="sounding-above-their-weight-2">Sounding above their weight</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="oDa3Rp6mah7Csg5kSBe2Vh" name="1More-SonoFlow-HQ51-wearing" alt="Wearing the 1More SonoFlow Pro HQ51 over-ear headphones." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/oDa3Rp6mah7Csg5kSBe2Vh.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ted Kritsonis / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I found it interesting that 1More went into launching these headphones with some boastful claims. Merely suggesting that a pair of sub-$100 cans could deliver lower total harmonic distortion than <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/headphones/sony-wh-1000xm5-review">Sony's WH-1000XM5</a> is a reach. The general idea for any pair of headphones is higher THD means more distortion in the audio signal, which affects sound quality.</p><p>Slight variances are hard to measure for most ears, so don't look into that too much here. I have no real way of verifying 1More's claim other than testing both headphones and coming to the conclusion that I can't detect any audible difference when it comes to distortion levels, specifically.</p><p>This claim comes mainly from the new 40mm diamond-like carbon drivers 1More put in the SonoFlow Pro HQ51. It also has something to do with the fact they support the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-to-stream-hi-res-music-from-phone">LDAC hi-res Bluetooth codec</a>.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:68.46%;"><img id="uSCuXf2UgsZdPJVrnZSy8F" name="1More-SonoFlow-HQ51-screenshots-1" alt="1More app screenshots showing ways to control and customize SonoFlow Pro HQ51 headphones." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uSCuXf2UgsZdPJVrnZSy8F.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1402" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Overall, sound quality is superb—better than the previous SonoFlow. The biggest difference to my ears is the mids, reflecting a balance that does right by the solid bass and treble you get from the Pro HQ51. You'll hear this just a little more with hi-res tracks from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-streaming-music-apps-android" target="_blank">streaming services</a> like Tidal, Amazon Music, and Qobuz, though you'll also catch the improvement with more compressed audio from Spotify and other sources.</p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/bluetooth-audio-terms-codecs-explained">LDAC</a> support isn't there by default since you need to turn it on in the app under the Shortcuts menu. Note that doing so means you can't have spatial audio on, so you're forced to choose between them each time.</p><p>Despite throwing some shade at Sony, 1More's best move is delivering the kind of sound many will probably agree with. Resonant, with good bass and crisp highs, their performance out of the box still doesn't tell the full story.</p><p>As before, the 1More app gives you an EQ with 12 presets plus the option to create your own. The Studio preset is a flat curve, which represents 1More's default tuning for these headphones. You can get pretty creative here because it's a 10-band EQ for more precise tuning adjustments — something not typical for cheaper headphones. Testing both the presets and your own custom ones is worth your time because they can really change what kind of sound you get.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>As before, the 1More app gives you an EQ with 12 presets plus the option to create your own.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>ANC and transparency have a role to play here as well. You may find that turning both off (in a quiet place) allows a little more of the mids and highs to come out. I didn't notice right away but my ears sensed a difference. Not that using noise-cancelation is bad. Audio sounds great with it engaged.</p><p>As for the act of actually canceling background noise, don't expect Sony or Bose-level silence here. That wouldn't be a fair expectation anyway but I can tell you these do a solid job dealing with low-frequency sounds. Nothing groundbreaking, mind you, just better than you might expect for headphones in this price range.</p><p>It's actually the passive isolation you get from the snug fit that helps a lot. ANC augments that and makes for a nice combination when you're trying not to hear what's going on around you. Transparency is fine when you do, even if there's nothing all that surprising about it compared to the previous SonoFlow headphones.</p>
<h2 id="calls-and-other-features-2">Calls and other features</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="bKM2dPSovay6ys24Rt5iHF" name="1More-SonoFlow-HQ51-wearing-side-view" alt="Side profile view wearing the 1More SonoFlow Pro HQ51 headphones." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bKM2dPSovay6ys24Rt5iHF.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ted Kritsonis / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Wired playback is an option if you need it. 1More includes a 2.5mm-to-3.5mm cable for such a purpose. You lose out on the ancillary features when you do, and you may have to raise the volume more often while listening that way. It feels like a miss given that other budget-friendly headphones have managed to at least leave some access.</p><p>For phone calls, you can use the headphones either way because the cable has an inline microphone. Again, you'll need to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-pair-bluetooth-headphones-your-android-phone">stick to Bluetooth</a> if you want extras while talking, like the onboard mics drowning out some of the background noise to hear callers better. In my tests, callers didn't point out any major issues, though they also didn't lavish praise on call quality, for what that's worth.</p><p>The SonoFlow Pro HQ51 support multipoint connections to stay paired with two devices simultaneously. Here, too, you'll need to enable the feature first under the "Experimental Features" menu under Settings. Toggling it on reboots the headphones, so keep that in mind when you need it.</p>
<h2 id="unbelievable-battery-life-2">Unbelievable battery life</h2>
<p>The SonoFlow Pro HQ51 are rated at up to 100 hours with ANC off. Leave ANC on, and you can go up to 65 hours. Both figures are just ridiculous in a good way. While they are based on default volume levels and without some other notable elements thrown in, like LDAC or spatial audio, you can rest assured these cans will play for a long time before you hear a low battery warning.</p><p>I had them for weeks before writing this review and only had to charge them once. I could listen for hours and barely see the battery percentage drop. Regardless of what features you use or volume you prefer, power consumption isn't something you need to worry about here.</p><p>And if you do, a five-minute quick charge can give you up to 10 hours of playback (ANC off), which feels kind of mind-boggling.</p>
<h2 id="headphones-worth-every-dollar-2">Headphones worth every dollar</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="q7EdoaWdCB4bfTESroHkwZ" name="1More-SonoFlow-HQ51-front-view" alt="1More SonoFlow HQ51 headphones resting upright against the wall." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/q7EdoaWdCB4bfTESroHkwZ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Ted Kritsonis / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The 1More SonoFlow Pro HQ51 feel like a bargain, plain and simple. For $100 (or less, given 1More's routine discounts), you get over-ear headphones that not only outperform their price but also serve notice against some that cost double the price. You're not getting over-ears capable of unseating the flagships among the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones">best wireless headphones</a>, but that's not the point.</p><p>These headphones are a big value proposition in that they deliver more than you might otherwise expect. Great sound complements the solid feature set and seemingly endless battery life. When you're simply looking to get the basics right, the SonoFlow Pro HQ51 will give you all those and more.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="56875c96-039e-4c28-820d-e0125f479c9c">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Przx4XFsdV3XyS5RFC7rNE.jpg' alt="1More SonoFlow Pro HQ51 headphones in black on white background."></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">1More SonoFlow Pro HQ51</div>
                                <div class="stars__reviews"><span itemprop="reviewRating" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/Rating" class="chunk rating"><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star"> </span><span class="icon icon-star half"></span><meta itemprop="bestRating" content="100.0" /><meta itemprop="worstRating" content="0.0" /><meta itemprop="ratingValue" content="90" /></span></div>
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Incredible value</strong></em></p><p>The 1More SonoFlow Pro HQ51 headphones can play for up to 65 hours with noise cancelation on, only adding to the excellent value add you get with them. Their great sound will keep you listening to all the content you love.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/headphones/1more-sonoflow-pro-hq51-review</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ For $100, the 1More SonoFlow Pro HQ51 deliver a superb combination of sound quality, noise cancelation, and battery life that's hard to pass up once you put them on.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Hha2pBcEWTcLTsXZv5Td3Q</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/q7EdoaWdCB4bfTESroHkwZ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 22:47:02 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Headphones]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ ted@byteddyk.com (Ted Kritsonis) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/q7EdoaWdCB4bfTESroHkwZ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Ted Kritsonis / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[1More SonoFlow HQ51 headphones resting upright against the wall.]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[1More SonoFlow HQ51 headphones resting upright against the wall.]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Prime Video might roll out a very YouTube TV-style multiview experience ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A discovery within Prime Video's recent build may indicate Amazon's development of a multiview mode like YouTube TV.</li><li>The code suggests users can "set up" their multiview alongside various inabilities regarding rewinding and pausing.</li><li>YouTube TV recently rolled out "build a multiview" for users just before the 2024 NFL season, as well as a basic version for mobile.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Amazon could upgrade its Prime Video streaming service with a feature YouTube TV subscribers will recognize.</p><p>Per an APK dive by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/amazon-prime-video-multiview-apk-teardown-3499139/">Android Authority</a>, the Prime Video app's latest build holds signs pointing toward a "multiview." Diving into version 3.0.389 showcased strings in the code like "exit_multiview_text." From the discovered code, it seems Amazon plans for a multiview experience that lets users "set up" their ideal content.</p><p>Another piece of code seemingly ties the multiview button to mobile — specifically, Android. Moreover, the code highlights multiview's warnings to users about the inability to rewind, pause, or skip ahead.</p><p>Other strings reference the "Android_Player" on its own, potentially indicating that Amazon may roll this out for TVs <em>alongside </em>mobile devices. Unfortunately, the publication discovery was cut short as more detailed information was reportedly unavailable. We're still left wondering how many screens or "views" Amazon's version of multiview will contain.</p><p>In mid-2023, YouTube TV started a test for a limited number of users that enabled multiview mode for <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-tv-multiview-streams-additional-content">more than sports games</a>. However, using the mode to watch games from the NFL, WNBA, and College Basketball games was what users typically activated multiview for. Earlier this year, YouTube TV pushed a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-tv-multiview-mobile-rollout">basic version of multiview to mobile devices</a>, beginning with Apple's iPhone. The mode made a few "pre-determined" options available for users to watch on the go.</p><p>Users were unable to choose which pieces of content they wanted to view, which was a function TV sets picked up in January. YouTube TV rolled the feature out as "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/youtube-tv-build-a-multiview-spotted">build a multiview</a>." The customization option debuted right in time for March Madness, letting users pick and choose which games they wanted. This custom multiview <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/youtube-tv-fantasy-custom-multiview-nfl-sunday-ticket">arrived for NFL Sunday Ticket holders</a> just before the 2024 season kicked off.</p><p>YouTube TV lets users design a multiview with up to four screens (four streams) on game day. It remains to be seen if Amazon's version for Prime Video remains similar or more limited. Additionally, the publication highlighted the company's recent <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/entertainment/prime-video-nba-wnba-streaming-deal">11-year partnership</a> with the NBA and WNBA for games, which might be a strong catalyst behind this multiview venture.</p>
<ul><li> <strong>Streaming deals: </strong><a href="https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/c/221109/564546/9358?subId1=ac-us-6669505491978814929&sharedId=ac-us&u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.disneyplus.com%2F" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Disney+</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.prf.hn/click/camref:1011lqSFc/pubref:ac-us-2055877114246584959/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.max.com%2F" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Max</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://sling-tv.pxf.io/c/221109/1132376/14334?subId1=ac-us-1441612201299102233&sharedId=ac-us&u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.sling.com%2F" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Sling</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://geni.us/YkQAuWd" target="_blank"><u><strong>Fubo</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://imp.i305175.net/c/221109/828265/11640?subId1=ac-us-1125905906988253476&sharedId=ac-us&u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.peacocktv.com%2Fblackfriday" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Peacock</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://paramountplus.qflm.net/c/221109/175360/3065?subId1=ac-us-6764559719159734286&sharedId=ac-us&u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.paramountplus.com%2F" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Paramount+</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/streaming-tv/amazon-prime-video-multiview-code-spotted</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Code in Prime Video's latest build might've teased a "multiview" experience. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">psdpiCjk9iPCDZxr7wSa5</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rRVbpLNe8zPGmbefjKhuwG.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 20:34:53 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Streaming &amp; TV]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rRVbpLNe8zPGmbefjKhuwG.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A TV show page on Prime Video]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A TV show page on Prime Video]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Hurry! The Motorola Razr Plus crashes to its lowest price EVER (again) during Best Buy's Black Friday sale  ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>There has been no shortage of great Black Friday Best Buy deals this year, but one Motorola phone in particular just keeps getting cheaper and cheaper. Head to the retailer&apos;s site now and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/motorola-razr-2024-256gb-unlocked-hot-pink/6583831.p"><strong>order an unlocked Motorola Razr Plus (2024) and you&apos;ll score a straight $250 off</strong></a> your purchase, no strings attached. That&apos;s the cheapest that the beloved flip phone has<em> ever been</em>, and we&apos;re still a few weeks away from Black Friday weekend.</p>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/electronics/black-friday/pcmcat225600050002.c"><em><strong>See Best Buy's full list of Black Friday deals</strong></em></a></li></ul>
<p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/motorola-razr-plus-2024-review">Motorola Razr Plus (2024)</a> impressed us this year with its sophisticated design, upgraded camera tech, and a Snapdragon chip that easily holds its own against Samsung&apos;s popular Galaxy Z Flip 6. The phone also boasts two gorgeous pOLED displays with a vegan leather finish so it&apos;s nice and grippy to hold, plus you get a durable folding hinge that feels much more flexible than the rather-stiff Z Flip 6. As senior editor Derrek Lee put it, "Samsung should really be taking notes". </p>
<h2 id="our-favorite-flip-phone-drops-to-a-record-low-price-2">Our favorite flip phone drops to a record low price</h2>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="b3e85daa-418a-4360-b76b-2ce2c948f2b4" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$999.99" data-dimension48="$999.99" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/motorola-razr-2024-256gb-unlocked-hot-pink/6583831.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="QYuTf5Mv7cbvGoVpNDwkAC" name="motorola razr plus 2024 render 400x500.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QYuTf5Mv7cbvGoVpNDwkAC.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Motorola Razr Plus (2024) 256GB:</strong> <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/motorola-razr-2024-256gb-unlocked-hot-pink/6583831.p" data-dimension112="b3e85daa-418a-4360-b76b-2ce2c948f2b4" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$999.99" data-dimension48="$999.99"><del>$999.99</del> <strong>$749.99 unlocked / $649.99 with activation at Best Buy</strong></a></p>
<p>As part of its early <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/best-buy-black-friday-sale-top-android-deals-2024">Black Friday sale</a>, Best Buy is slashing a whopping $250 off the unlocked Motorola Razr Plus (2024). Activate the phone today and you'll score an additional $100 in savings.  </p>
<p>One of our favorite <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">foldable phones</a> released this year, the Razr Plus (2024) features two glorious pOLED screens with a Snapdragon 8s Gen 3 processor, Moto AI software features, and one of the best folding hinges that we've ever used. </p>
<p><strong>Price comparison: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D23P28XX">Amazon - $799.99</a> | <a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Motorola-razr-2024-Unlocked-Made-for-US-12-256-50MP-Camera-Midnight-Blue-Smartphone-Cell-Phone/11887007525">Walmart - $979.99</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/motorola-razr-2024-256gb-unlocked-hot-pink/6583831.p" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="b3e85daa-418a-4360-b76b-2ce2c948f2b4" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$999.99" data-dimension48="$999.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>I&apos;ve been waiting for the right time to try the clamshell device myself, and thanks to this Black Friday deal, I&apos;m about ready to place the order. Of course, the big question is this: will the Razr Plus get even cheaper as we approach November 29th? It&apos;s hard to know for sure, but if you use a price tracker like CamelCamelCamel, you&apos;ll see that the current discount totally smashes Amazon&apos;s record low price from last month. It&apos;s one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">best Black Friday Motorola deals</a> we&apos;ve seen so far this year, and that&apos;s saying a lot. </p><p>Best Buy will also give you an additional $100 off if you activate the phone with a carrier, and you might even be eligible to receive some trade-in credit if you send in an old or broken device. Will the deal improve in a few weeks? Only time will tell, but this early Black Friday discount is good enough for me. </p>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/hurry-the-motorola-razr-plus-crashes-to-its-lowest-price-ever-again-during-best-buys-black-friday-sale</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Best Buy's Black Friday sale is carving a straight $250 off the Razr Plus (2024), one of our favorite foldable phones released this year.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">BfhfTSyRMUXy7QxRSDmoy8</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SQTpR4gGeasGGCRUBPHsqc.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 19:58:10 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/SQTpR4gGeasGGCRUBPHsqc.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 cover screen with the phone open at an angle]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Motorola Razr Plus 2024 cover screen with the phone open at an angle]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ YouTube tests song remixes made by AI that 'restyle' its mood ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>YouTube detailed a new experiment for content creators with Dream Track access that lets them "restyle" a piece of music.</li><li>Restyling a song leverages the platform's AI tool for a 30-second clip with a completely new genre and mood based on your description.</li><li>YouTube debuted Dream Track late last year as a feature that can create music in the same style as their favorite artist and recreate their voice.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>YouTube is reportedly kickstarting a new test that advances its AI-based generation features for music.</p><p>The platform's <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://support.google.com/youtube/thread/18138167?hl=en&msgid=307521359">latest test</a> involves an expansion of its Dream Track AI experiment that a "limited" number of content creators can try (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/12/24294891/youtube-ai-restyle-music-creators">The Verge</a>). According to YouTube, this test will let creators "restyle" a song using descriptors via a prompt given to its AI software. The company states it has made a few "official songs" available to creators, courtesy of "select" music partners.</p><p>Creators with access can select an eligible song and "describe how you want to restyle it." YouTube states the AI will generate a remix based on a user's description to create a 30-second clip usable in a Short.</p><p>Since these clips are only usable in Shorts, YouTube states the quick video will credit the original song. More importantly, the platform will note that the music users are listening to is generated/remixed by AI. This will most likely be displayed in the bottom right corner of the Short which, when clicked, will take users to more videos created using the <em>original </em>soundtrack.</p><p>The experimental post highlights that creators can alter the "genre or mood" of the song from the provided list. YouTube claims the "customized" soundtrack will retain the "essence of the original song’s vocals and lyrics."</p><p>Unfortunately, as the publication noted, YouTube has not provided a list of the eligible songs for creators to experiment with.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="Fm9BFBYs92bPuYnziBKnnk" name="Google-Pixel-8-Pro-youtube-app.jpg" alt="The YouTube app listing on the Google Play Store, running on a Google Pixel 8 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Fm9BFBYs92bPuYnziBKnnk.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>YouTube detailed its new experiment, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-watermarks-for-ai-generated-music">Dream Track</a>, late last year. The Shorts-only feature leverages Google's DeepMind "Lyria" model to create instrumentals and vocals. Through Dream Track, the company stated that users could create 30-second snippets of music in the "style of their favorite artists." The AI could sample a popular artist's voice and turn it into something completely new. The idea was to help content creators create soundtracks that help bypass the hassle of paying royalties.</p><p>While it seems useful, a tool such as Dream Track has raised a few eyebrows about protecting a music artist's IP (intellectual property).</p><p>AI has continued to rise on YouTube as the company highlighted <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/made-by-youtube-2024-ai-hype-updates">AI generation through Veo</a>. This is another piece of software from Google's DeepMind kitchen that lets users create AI-based backgrounds or "concepts that were once impossible to visualize." Using Veo limits users to a six-second clip for a Short. However, it seems the platform intends users to utilize this software to "fill in any gaps" they may have with a Short.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-song-restyle-ai-remix-test-spotted</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ YouTube detailed a new experiment for its Dream Track AI test. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">NfhR5JnCCboRcjgKvNCo9V</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/53Hee9M7ttmhbNwJuiddgP.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 19:23:34 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/53Hee9M7ttmhbNwJuiddgP.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Chris Wedel/Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[YouTube on Pixel 7 Pro]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[YouTube on Pixel 7 Pro]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ I tested three different 'eye-friendly' displays so you don't have to ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Android Central Labs</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="7WCXSEZSk3FX9EmxxzaGE9" name="android-central-labs-lloyd-logo.jpg" caption="" alt="Android Central's Lloyd mascot wearing a lab coat for the Android Central Labs column" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7WCXSEZSk3FX9EmxxzaGE9.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text"><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/android-central-labs">Android Central Labs</a> is a weekly column devoted to deep dives, experiments, and a focused look into tech you didn't know you needed. It covers phones, tablets, and everything in between.</p></div></div>
<p>Eye health has become increasingly more important as our world becomes filled with screens. Most people look at a screen now more than at any other time in their lives, so it makes sense to find a type of display that isn't going to cause you harm.</p><p>However, not every screen type is created equal, making some devices better for specific tasks than others. For this particular project, I’ve been using the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-e-ink-tablet">best E Ink tablet</a>, the Boox Tab Ultra, as well as the LCD-based <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/tcl-is-bringing-its-innovative-nxtpaper-tech-to-more-phones-and-tablets">TCL Tab 10 NXTPAPER 5G</a> tablet, and the OLED-based Honor MagicPad 2. Each tablet’s display works very differently, but all have the same goal: to be better on your eyes for the long haul.</p><p>That's good because the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/14771535241288783">latest research</a> on light and display flicker shows that some kinds of displays can cause health problems over time, including migraines and eye problems. Thankfully, this same research is pushing companies to make displays that are far more eye-friendly, and three technologies are leading the charge: E Ink, NXTPAPER LCD, and, surprisingly, OLED. Which one is right for you? Let's take a look.</p>

<h2 id="e-ink-2">E-ink</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="5a2fSwqFFRf4g7y7pUtYMc" name="oled-vs-e-ink-pixel-structure" alt="Comparing the pixel structure of an Onyx Boox Tab Ultra E-Ink panel with an Honor MagicPad 2 OLED panel" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5a2fSwqFFRf4g7y7pUtYMc.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="2048" height="1152" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Each of these three display technologies “draws” the image very differently and even displays light completely differently.</p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">E-ink displays</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">Best for reading. Made up of physical spheres that are magnetically charged and don't move between frames. Extremely energy efficient since it doesn't need constant voltage to operate and can stay on indefinitely without power. Watching videos and playing games isn't possible on older E Ink models, but some newer devices, like the Onyx Boox Palma, are more feasible.</p></div></div>
<p>E Ink promises to be the most eye-friendly display of all because it doesn’t flicker the way other types of display tech are prone to. E Ink uses positively and negatively charged white or black pigments, which are situated between a clear fluid. You can see this in the image above which shows what the Boox Tab Ultra's display looks like under a microscope compared to the OLED display on the Honor MagicPad 2.</p><p>When an e-reader like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/onyx-boox-palma-review">Boox Palma</a> draws an image — like the text in a book or a picture in a manga — the pigments are energized to create a specific level of gray and then stay in place until moved again.</p><p>This means that E Ink displays are extremely battery efficient since they <em>only</em> require power when drawing. LCDs and OLEDs require constant voltage to operate and maintain an image on the screen. Additionally, E Ink “accepts” light similarly to paper, so it’s more viewable as ambient light increases. Reading on the beach with an e-reader is a joy, while it’s nearly impossible with an LCD or OLED.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:5184px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.33%;"><img id="MdCcDEqeQBjR6D7JnP4s8J" name="e-ink-vs-lcd-vs-oled-reading-in-sunlight-1" alt="Comparing outdoor reading capabilities of LCD, OLED, and E-Ink tablets" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MdCcDEqeQBjR6D7JnP4s8J.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="1" width="5184" height="2920" attribution="" endorsement="" class="expandable"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<figure><blockquote><p>E Ink “accepts” light similarly to paper, so it’s more viewable as ambient light increases. Reading on the beach with an e-reader is a joy, while it’s nearly impossible with an LCD or OLED.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>All modern e-readers use an optional frontlight, which means they are lit differently from an LCD or OLED if you choose to turn the light on. A frontlight is typically situated around the edges of the display and points at a downward angle.</p><p>Because of E Ink's unique light-accepting properties, light is then carried across the panel and evenly lit. All <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/onyx-boox-tab-ultra-c-review" target="_blank">Onyx Boox</a> e-readers that I’ve tested do not use PWM flickering to dim the light but actual DC dimming to reduce voltage to the light, making it very comfortable on the eyes.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.20%;"><img id="6qyPtuXkUn9gCJwja96cum" name="onyx-boox-palma-warcraft-rumble.gif" alt="Warcraft Rumble's intro video running on an Onyx Boox Palma" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6qyPtuXkUn9gCJwja96cum.gif" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="500" height="281" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The downside of E Ink is that it’s not inherently designed for color or video content. You can find fast-refreshing E Ink displays like the one on the Boox Palma that allow you to play games and watch videos, but the experience is a little weird since the framerate is low.</p><p>It's not impossible to watch videos or play games on certain e-readers — the Boox Tab Ultra I've used for this article is a great example of one that doesn't refresh fast enough for these use cases — but it's not as nice to view this kind of content an on E Ink display as it is an LCD or OLED.</p><p>Likewise, color e-readers often have a reduced color palette compared to LCD or OLED, meaning they are only ideal for reading.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="89251e3d-1a46-4ece-ac2c-2be4c31843b3">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/EAykvtMrbqFYADsmE5YXcX.jpg' alt="Onyx Boox Palma 2 render with extra space"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Onyx Boox Palma 2</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>The Boox Palma 2 is the perfect e-reader for on-the-go use. It's the size of a phone but features an E Ink Carta 1200 display that's easier on the eyes than your phone, plus a refresh rate fast enough to do more than just read books.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<h2 id="nxtpaper-lcd-2">NXTPAPER LCD</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="b3CWgqxhdh4CUbocMuo8SM" name="tcl-tab10-nxtpaper-with-oneplus-nord-n30-lcd.jpg" alt="Holding up a TCL Tab 10 NXTPAPER 5G tablet and a OnePlus Nord N30 5G phone to examine the LCD panels" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/b3CWgqxhdh4CUbocMuo8SM.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">NXTPAPER LCD</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">TCL's spin on LCD tech includes a diffusion layer to soften the image and a matte layer to reduce glare. It looks more like paper but is not as "authentic" as E Ink. The backlight uses proper DC dimming, ensuring zero light flicker, but TCL's use of color dithering means pixels flicker to artificially deepen the colors. NXTPAPER features three different color modes, including full color and a high refresh rate that's great for videos and games. It's not as energy-efficient as the other two display types because the backlight doesn't have zone control.</p></div></div>
<p>TCL’s NXTPAPER technology is a fairly new riff on older LCD technology. Like traditional LCDs, NXTPAPER uses a grid of tiny red, green, and blue pixels illuminated by a separate backlight to display what you see. The biggest difference is in the various layers that separate the pixels and the light itself.</p><p>TCL has packed a light diffusion layer and an anti-glare filter onboard. This diffusion layer makes it difficult to see individual pixels, even under a microscope, giving the light a lovely “soft” quality that no other display tech has.</p><p>Additionally, TCL NXTPAPER backlights are completely DC dimmed, so there’s no flickering at all. All in all, this is the closest thing you’ll find to the eye-friendly light provided by an incandescent light.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-juedlZHdbo" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<figure><blockquote><p>TCL has packed a light diffusion layer and an anti-glare filter onboard, giving the light a lovely “soft” quality that no other display tech has.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>TCL says this is the Goldilocks display tech as it’s got a wider color range than E Ink but doesn't sport the harsh look of an OLED. The TCL NXTPAPER Tab 10 also offers three different color models that can alter colors on the screen to be a reduced palette or make everything completely black and white.</p><p>The idea here is that one of these three modes is optimal for different types of content, but this tablet has one big downside: dithering. In a nutshell, TCL is using the same color tech on its tablet as it does on its popular TVs, which achieves deeper colors by flickering pixels between two colors. This makes each pixel appear as a color that “doesn’t exist,” similar to how your eyes will perceive a non-existent color when spinning a color wheel.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>TCL NXTPAPER tech is wonderful for all kinds of content but users sensitive to dithering should avoid it until TCL offers the ability to disable color dithering.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>In my testing, I've found that this display works very well for any kind of task. Reading on TCL NXTPAPER technology, specifically, is very pleasant thanks to the characteristic soft diffused light. Changing color palettes can help ease eye strain for certain types of content, although I find I use the "color paper" mode less often than the full-color "regular mode" or the black & white-only "ink paper mode."</p><p>The panel is bright enough for indoor use but is very difficult to see outdoors, especially in direct sunlight. It also has rather poor viewing angles and is only perceivably brightest when looking at it straight on.</p><p>This particular generation of NXTPAPER LCD doesn't refresh quite as quickly as an OLED can, though, introducing some motion blur. This is particularly noticeable when scrolling through the OS or web pages but I don't notice it as much when playing games and never notice it while watching videos. This would be the single friendliest overall tech if TCL could provide users the option of disabling color dithering.</p>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="70810d81-fbe7-4e57-bbcb-a3e8894485b6">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:100.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jK9u7uJSfgiDrAubNaKdT7.jpg' alt="TCL Tab 10 NXTPAPER 5G square render"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">TCL Tab 10 NXTPAPER 5G</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p>TCL has gone out of its way to make LCD relevant again with a beautiful matte finish and a diffusion layer that creates a soft glow from the backlight. Different color modes mean it's great for any kind of content and feels good when reading on for a long time. Just don't take it outside because it's not very easy to see in the sun.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

<h2 id="oled-2">OLED</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="bfSY57HkiqTNAFdTbmeXZk" name="honor-magicpad-2-and-honor-magic-v3.jpg" alt="The Honor MagicPad 2 and Honor Magic V3" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/bfSY57HkiqTNAFdTbmeXZk.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">OLED</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">OLED produces the deepest colors, highest contrast, and highest brightness of any modern display technology. While that means it's got the best image quality, it's also the harshest to look at for long periods of time, and the use of PWM dimming by many companies means the risk of eye damage is highest with this tech. It's not as energy efficient as E Ink since it has to have a constant current to power, but it's more energy efficient than LCD since individual LEDs provide the light.</p></div></div>
<p>For the better part of the last decade, OLED displays have been slowly replacing LCDs because they look better and are more energy efficient. But the way some companies make their OLED displays — and even LED lights — are causing health problems for lots of people because they flicker like fluorescent lights.</p><p>I've <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/what-is-pwm-display-flicker-tips-and-tricks">written about this topic many times</a>, so it's a subject very near and dear to my heart.  While Samsung OLED panels often feature harsh flickering that makes me dizzy, gives me eye and headaches, and sometimes makes me nauseous, OLED panels from other companies like LG, BOE, Visionox, and Sony (among others) only flicker at low brightness and, even then, flicker at a far higher frequency than Samsung’s OLEDs.</p><p>The Honor MagicPad 2 I used for this experiment uses <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/how-to-enable-dc-dimming-on-the-oneplus-12-and-oneplus-12r">DC dimming</a> technology above 30% brightness and 4320Hz PWM dimming at lower brightness levels. Meanwhile, Samsung’s best tablets use a paltry 240Hz PWM rate at <em>all</em> brightness levels, meaning there’s no escape from the flickering no matter how bright it gets.</p>
<div class="youtube-video" data-nosnippet ><div class="video-aspect-box"><iframe data-lazy-priority="low" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NqA-Na_l4sk" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>
<figure><blockquote><p>OLED produces the best contrast ratio and deepest colors of the three different display technologies here, as well as the brightest overall output, but it's also the harshest type of light.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>OLED produces the best contrast ratio and deepest colors of the three different display technologies here, as well as the brightest overall output. Despite this, viewability in sunlight is rather poor since the panel itself is super shiny.</p><p>Honor uses true 10-bit display panels, so there’s no need for color dithering as the TCL NXTPAPER Tab 10 has, but the direct light from LED photons may still trigger headaches for the most sensitive users.</p><p>Interestingly enough, Honor has a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/honor-magicpad-2-honor-magic-v3-ai-defocus-display">brilliant new technology</a> on this tablet that works under the hood to help prevent and even reverse myopia, according to research. It's limited to only a few apps but promises some interesting potential if it gets rolled out more widely.</p><p>I’ve been using this tablet for everything from watching movies to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/these-gadgets-got-me-through-the-worst-hurricane-of-my-life">working during Hurricane Helene</a> and find it to be extremely comfortable, but I don’t like using OLEDs for reading. Concentrating on the harsher, direct light of an OLED while reading just doesn’t feel good after long periods of time no matter what’s done behind the scenes.</p>
<h2 id="two-winners-2">Two winners</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="taU6TEkHiSYKaykyDie3CQ" name="honor-magicpad-2-vs-onyx-boox-tab-ultra" alt="Comparing the OLED-powered Honor MagicPad 2 with the E Ink powered Onyx Boox Tab Ultra" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/taU6TEkHiSYKaykyDie3CQ.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While there’s no direct answer to which display type is “best” overall, one characteristic affects more sensitive users than others: flicker. Many modern displays and lights flicker to achieve different goals, from color accuracy to display brightness; flickering has a purpose.</p><p>However, companies that use flicker this way often seem to forget that human eyes and brains don’t always play nice when strobing lights are involved. Lack of flicker is the main reason these three <em>devices</em>, in particular, are better for your eyes.</p><p>Onyx’s E Ink technology doesn’t flicker at all, yet the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://ledstrain.org/d/698-eye-strain-with-e-readers">occasional user</a> will still feel eye strain from certain e-readers. This can be attributed to several potential factors, but the fact is that e-ink is the most comfortable type of display for reading for the largest percentage of users.</p><p>TCL’s NXTPAPER technology has the potential to be the single best overall technology, but TCL needs to offer sensitive users the option to disable dithering completely. If that can be done, the soft, friendly DC-dimmed light from any TCL NXTPAPER device will be an easy recommendation for anyone who wants a great tablet to read on, watch movies on, or even work from.</p>
<figure><blockquote><p>OLED has the biggest potential to inflict harm because of its harsher direct light, so use e-readers when possible for daily reading. TCL NXTPAPER has great potential but it's typically found on underpowered devices.</p></blockquote></figure>
<p>OLED has the biggest potential to inflict harm because of its harsher direct light. Since the individual pixels on an OLED panel emit light, you’re looking directly at an LED when you view content on an OLED instead of at a diffused light as with other display types.</p><p>There are many ways that companies can use diffusion layers or provide better dimming options to help negate the negative effects of OLEDs. Samsung put a wonderful anti-glare layer on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review#section-samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-display-and-design">Galaxy S24 Ultra</a>, for instance. But the technology feels a bit like the old Icarus story: fly too close to the sun and you’ll probably get burned.</p><p>I've found that e-readers like the Onyx Boox Tab Ultra are best for reading books or manga. When I want to watch a video or play a game, the Honor MagicPad 2 is my go-to solution thanks to Honor's use of DC dimming, an unbelievably good set of virtual surround sound speakers, and a powerful processor.</p><p>I'd love to use TCL's NXTPAPER tech more in the future but the company's use of low-power processors and color dithering put it in an awkward middle ground that means it collects dust more than it sees use.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/testing-three-eye-friendly-display-technologies</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ OLED, LCD, and E Ink are all vying to be the best types of display, but are they any good for your eyes? We put them to the test. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">q3N8adtqpEMuLoqo2y97XR</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/S9jW9KXn2YtENKAtnjQAVm.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 19:23:24 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
                                                                                                                                                                                                <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/S9jW9KXn2YtENKAtnjQAVm.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android Central&#039;s Lloyd mascot dressed up in a lab coat displayed on a TCL Tab 10 NXTPAPER 5G, Onyx Boox Tab Ultra, and an Honor MagicPad 2]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android Central&#039;s Lloyd mascot dressed up in a lab coat displayed on a TCL Tab 10 NXTPAPER 5G, Onyx Boox Tab Ultra, and an Honor MagicPad 2]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google to remove content from EU news publishers from News, Search, and Discover in small test ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>In the European Union, the European Copyright Directive (EUCD) regulates how search engines and news aggregators can use, license, and preview news content.</li><li>To measure the impact of news stories from EU publishers on Google services, the company will remove those stories from results in a limited test.</li><li>Google says the test will affect 1% of users in Belgium, Croatia, Denmark, France, Greece, Italy, the Netherlands, Poland, and Spain.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>To find out how much news stories appearing in Google News, Search, and Discover encourage readers to use Google products and services, the company will remove them altogether in an extremely limited test. One percent of users in Belgium, Croatia, Denmark, France, Greece, Italy, the Netherlands, Poland, and Spain won't see news content from EU-based publishers as Google collects data, the company <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.google/around-the-globe/google-europe/more-data-about-news-results-eu/" target="_blank">announced</a> today.</p><p>The changes come in response to a request from regulators and publishers, and is related to Article 15 of the European Copyright Directive (EUCD). This law dictates how search engines and news aggregators can use news content from publishers in the EU. As part of Google's compliance with the EUCD, it started an Extended News Previews (ENP) program. Essentially, the company pays publishers to show previews or snippets of news content under license.</p><p>Google says it has agreements with over 4,000 publications in 20 countries, and the deals are rooted in how much news content affects search and advertising. "These agreements are based on consistent criteria which respect the law and existing copyright guidance, including how often a news website is displayed and how much ad revenue is generated on pages that also display previews of news content," the company explains.</p><p>However, the EU's regulators and publishers now want "additional data about the effect of news content in Search on peoples’ use of our products." To get the data, Google is removing the news content from EU publishers in Google News, Google Search, and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-personalize-google-discover-feed">Google Discover</a> for 1% of users in the previously-listed EU countries. Presumably, it will compare the usage of Google products and services with and without news content present.</p><p>This is a very minor test that only affects a small portion of EU users for a limited time. Results will still appear from publishers outside of the EU, and the removal of EU-based news is temporary. Google says that when the test ends, everything will go back to normal.</p><p>"We intend to use this test to assess how results from EU news publishers impact the search experience for our users and traffic to publishers," Google said in the blog post.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google/google-to-remove-content-from-eu-news-publishers-from-news-search-and-discover-in-small-test</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ As part of Google's efforts to comply with the European Copyright Directive (EUCD), news from EU publishers will disappear in a limited test. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Lfq3JDhkyXNuLmpLmDgoFT</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fYGT9UPqiDFkuJgLgn2wke.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 19:20:43 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fYGT9UPqiDFkuJgLgn2wke.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Discover feed]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Discover feed]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Fitbit Ace LTE gets new features to keep families walking and talking ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google highlighted several new features arriving for the Fitbit Ace LTE, like "Family Chat," which lets parents send their kids quick notes or texts.</li><li>The Ace LTE is also picking up sibling chat, new Daily Quests, and a series of "Family Quests" to keep families engaged in healthier living habits.</li><li>This past summer, Google rolled out several features for kids ahead of the school year, such as "School Time" and tools for better spending.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google details a few updates kids and families can expect to arrive on devices this week.</p><p>The company highlighted features in a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.google/products/fitbit/fitbit-ace-lte-holiday-updates-2024/">Keyword post</a> that help keep families connected and engaged with healthy habits. Rolling out today (Nov 13), Google states the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fitbit-ace-lte-review">Fitbit Ace LTE</a> and the Ace app are picking up "Family Chat." According to the post, families can send each other quick notes and texts via the watch or the app.</p><p>This new "Family Chat" is tied to every member registered in a user's Google family. Additionally, the post states siblings within the family can have their own space to communicate. Private chats between siblings are also rolling out, allowing them to text or call one another from the Ace LTE.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1200px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:41.67%;"><img id="RV2SijrkfnpwWHbGinB8Ff" name="fibit-ace-lte-family-chat-example" alt="Google is rolling out "Family Chat" to keep families engaged on the Fitbit Ace LTE." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/RV2SijrkfnpwWHbGinB8Ff.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1200" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 2</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.20%;"><img id="Rc7wbijqA2ucmUQ3QPUKei" name="fitbit-ace-lte-family-quests" alt="The Ace LTE picks up "Family Quests" to keep families exercising and living healthier." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Rc7wbijqA2ucmUQ3QPUKei.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="1000" height="562" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Google)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>For health, Google states a new wave of exercise engagement features are rolling out via "Family Quests." These colorful (and at times holiday-themed) quests encourage families to get walking to hit their goals and complete tasks. The post highlights an upcoming game for Thanksgiving dubbed "Turkey Berserky." Every completed quest goes toward unlocking rewards and more advanced challenges for the family.</p><p>Joining these Family Quests are "50 extra Daily Quests" alongside "Trivial Tasks" that give kids a fun way to learn about geography and more.</p><p>Seeing progress is always encouraging, which is why Google states the Fitbit Ace LTE receives additional Noodle watch faces.</p><p>Kids don't always have to run around — and that's where the Ace LTE's newest game, Solar Sword, comes in. This new game is available through the Fitbit Arcade. Gamers are tasked with slashing through hordes of monsters invading a village like any (powerful) sword-wielding hero. The company highlights the start of its holiday season savings. Consumers can save <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://store.google.com/product/fitbit_ace_lte?utm_source=keyword&utm_medium=google_oo&utm_campaign=GS108186">$50 on the Fitbit Ace LTE</a> and <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://store.google.com/collection/accessories_wall?utm_source=keyword&utm_medium=google_oo&utm_campaign=GS108186">$20 on its bands</a> through the Google Store.</p><p>This runs from November 21 through December 4. Moreover, if you're purchasing a second Ace Pass annual plan for a sibling, consumers can receive a 50% discount from now until January 31, 2025.</p><p>These updates for the Ace LTE are rolling out today (Nov 13), but it may take a couple of days before it appears for download. In the meantime, Google rolled out an update for kids this summer <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fitbit-ace-lte-debit-card-school-returns-update">ahead of the 2024-2025 school year</a>. The patch lets parents set spending limits and other features to facilitate "healthier spending" among children. What's more, "School Time" lets parents ensure their kids remain focused on their schoolwork as they implement a set time limiting access to distracting apps.</p>
<ul><li> <strong>Smartwatch deals: </strong><a href="https://shop-links.co/link?st=smartwatch&_dyncharset=UTF-8&_dynSessConf=&id=pcat17071&type=page&sc=Global&cp=1&nrp=&sp=&qp=&list=n&af=true&iht=y&usc=All+Categories&ks=960&keys=keys&publisher_slug=future&exclusive=1&u1=ac-us-6717096264554300457&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fsearchpage.jsp%3Fst%3Dsmartwatch%26_dyncharset%3DUTF-8%26_dynSessConf%3D%26id%3Dpcat17071%26type%3Dpage%26sc%3DGlobal%26cp%3D1%26nrp%3D%26sp%3D%26qp%3D%26list%3Dn%26af%3Dtrue%26iht%3Dy%26usc%3DAll%2BCategories%26ks%3D960%26keys%3Dkeys&article_name=Fitbit%20Ace%20LTE%20update%20helps%20kids%20manage%20money%20and%20live%20healthier%20as%20school%20returns%20%7C%20Android%20Central&article_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.androidcentral.com%2Fwearables%2Ffitbit-ace-lte-debit-card-school-returns-update" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1943169/565706/9383?subId1=ac-us-2816440848012421200&sharedId=ac-us&u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fsearch%3Fq%3Dsmartwatch" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://target.georiot.com/Proxy.ashx?tsid=169923&GR_URL=https%3A%2F%2Famazon.com%2Fs%3Fk%3Dsmartwatch%26crid%3D19YAPQ38561AK%26sprefix%3Dsmartwatch%252Caps%252C138%26ref%3Dnb_sb_ss_ts-doa-p_1_10%26tag%3Dhawk-future-20%26ascsubtag%3Dac-us-9874580629840816079-20" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://shop-links.co/link?publisher_slug=future&exclusive=1&u1=ac-us-8081774165221710325&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.samsung.com%2Fus%2Fshop%2Fall-deals%2Fwatches-audio-accessories-deals%2F&article_name=Fitbit%20Ace%20LTE%20update%20helps%20kids%20manage%20money%20and%20live%20healthier%20as%20school%20returns%20%7C%20Android%20Central&article_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.androidcentral.com%2Fwearables%2Ffitbit-ace-lte-debit-card-school-returns-update" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-100048248-12578053?sid=ac-us-4717274204714238160&url=https://www.dell.com/en-us/search/smartwatch" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><u><strong>Dell</strong></u></a></li></ul>
        <div class="featured_product_block featured_block_horizontal" data-id="65d7be51-7342-470c-a905-2ed037a43067">
            <div class='product-image-widthsetter'><p class='vanilla-image-block' data-bordeaux-image-check style='padding-top:125.00%';><img style='width: 100%' class='featured_image' src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/K58wTeYN7pbMUo36ASBFaH.jpg' alt="Fitbit Ace LTE"></p></div>
            <div class="featured_product_details_wrapper">
                <div class="featured_product_title_wrapper">
                    
                    <div class="featured__title">Fitbit Ace LTE</div>
                    
                </div>
                <div class="subtitle__description">
                    
                    
                    <p><p><em><strong>Get moving, together</strong></em></p><p>The Fitbit Ace LTE is a surprisingly fun watch for kids. Its performance is reminiscent of the Pixel Watch 2, but the added games and color make for an experience that's hard to let go of. The Ace LTE encourages healthier living among families and these latest features ensure those lines of communication remain open.</p></p>
                </div>
                <div class="pro-con"></div>
            </div>
        </div>

 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fitbit-ace-lte-new-features-family-siblings-chat-more</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google detailed its latest Fitbit Ace LTE update for kids and families. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">7modE2UbR9mGg9yetFbobb</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/z4cgFNx7WS4aUWgEu9edBn.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 18:20:28 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/z4cgFNx7WS4aUWgEu9edBn.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Fitbit Ace LTE with its box and all the contents]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Fitbit Ace LTE with its box and all the contents]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The RedMagic 10 Pro Plus is basically a power bank attached to a gaming phone ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>ZTE's Nubia unveiled the RedMagic 10 Pro series in China, with two models available: 10 Pro and 10 Pro Plus.</li><li>Both models are identical, but the 10 Pro Plus has a bigger 7050mAh battery, 16GB of RAM, and 512GB of storage.</li><li>Both devices use the latest Qualcomm silicon and come with Android 15.</li><li>The devices will be available globally — including North America — starting December 3.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>ZTE's Nubia sub-brand does a good job catering to enthusiasts, and the RedMagic series is always a good choice if you want a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-phone-gamers">gaming-focused device</a>. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/redmagic-9-pro-review">RedMagic 9 Pro</a> got a lot right, but Nubia is turning things up a notch with the debut of the RedMagic 10 Pro Plus.</p><p>The device continues Nubia's distinct gamer aesthetic with bold styling and a boxy design. You still get plenty of buttons on the right, an all-screen design that isn't marred by a cutout, and with a sizeable 6.85-inch 144Hz AMOLED panel, the phone is an absolute unit.</p><p>What's immediately interesting about the phone is that the RedMagic 10 Pro Plus has a gargantuan 7,050mAh battery with 120W charging, which is a lot even by 2025 standards. Like other Chinese brands, Nubia uses silicon-carbon battery tech to increase the density, which is how the brand was able to cram a larger battery while retaining the same 229g weight as the 9 Pro.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2560px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="uzqgZwwxVhXpHiySMgqjen" name="RedMagic-10-Pro-Plus-side-back" alt="The RedMagic 10 Pro" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uzqgZwwxVhXpHiySMgqjen.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2560" height="1440" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: RedMagic)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Similar to other 2025 flagships, Nubia went with Qualcomm's latest <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/snapdragon-8-elite">Snapdragon 8 Elite</a> on both RedMagic phones. Although the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 is still plenty powerful, the new platform has sizeable gains across the board.</p><p>There's also a regular RedMagic 10 Pro that has a 6,500mAh battery and 80W charging, and that model comes with 12GB of RAM and 256GB of storage. While other brands usually differentiate models with cameras, Nubia isn't going that here — both the 10 Pro and 10 Pro Plus have the same design, same AMOLED panel, and identical cameras. The only difference is the storage configurations and battery size.</p><p>The 10 Pro Plus, meanwhile, comes with 16GB of RAM and 512GB of UFS 4.0 storage as standard. Both devices run <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-review">Android 15</a> out of the box, and Nubia has unique extras that cater to gamers on the software side of things.</p><p>The devices are now available in China, with an international debut on December 3 — you can <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://global.redmagic.gg/pages/redmagic-10-pro-launch">sign up on Nubia's global website</a> if you're interested. The series starts at 4,999 RMB ($693) in China, and it should cost about the same globally.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/the-redmagic-10-pro-is-basically-a-power-bank-attached-to-a-gaming-phone</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ RedMagic just unveiled the 10 Pro Plus in China, and it is a beast of a gaming phone. With the latest Qualcomm hardware, a massive 6.85-inch 144Hz panel, and ridiculous 7050mAh battery, it ticks all the right boxes.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">SDyzbGQ2RG5fieXhq8ZsrK</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6vzn4EYdYXZA4tM7rhJGh6.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 13:58:42 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/6vzn4EYdYXZA4tM7rhJGh6.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nubia]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Redmagic 10 Pro render]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Redmagic 10 Pro render]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ LG’s stretchable screen is pushing the limits and bending like never before ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-32">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>LG is pushing the future of flexible displays with a new prototype that stretches up to 50% beyond its original size.</li><li>The screen starts at 12 inches and stretches to 18 inches, but its 100 ppi pixel density lags behind modern smartphones.</li><li>Made from contact lens material, this display has the highest elongation rate in the industry, allowing it to stretch without damage.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>LG envisions a future ruled by flexible displays, and its latest concept screen brings that vision to life. Stretching up to 50% beyond its original size, LG's new stretchable display is pushing screen tech to new limits.</p><p>LG Display recently <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.lgdisplay.com/eng/company/media-center/latest-news?contentId=5362" target="_blank">showed off</a> its game-changing display tech at LG Science Park in Seoul. The prototype screen starts at 12 inches but can stretch all the way to 18 inches. It features a pixel density of 100 ppi across its RGB subpixels.</p><p>While impressive, this falls behind modern smartphone displays like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/google-pixel-9-pro-review">Google Pixel 9 Pro</a>, which sports a 495 ppi screen. So, it’s probably not ready for mobile devices just yet.</p><p>The panel is crafted from the same material found in contact lenses. LG claims this stretchable display has the industry's highest elongation rate, allowing the screen to stretch beyond its usual size without damage.</p><p>Though unconventional, the Korean company sees this stretchable display as a game-changer for innovation in the consumer electronics world.</p><p>The latest concept display is similar to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/lg/lg-demos-stretchable-high-resolution-display">LG’s 2022 reveal</a>, but this new version takes it up a notch by doubling its stretch. The new display tech isn’t just stretchable and twistable—it also shows a full color spectrum, thanks to microLED tech. Like OLED, it emits light directly, so there's no need for a backlight.</p><p>With its microLED light source, the new display can be stretched over 10,000 times, according to the company. MicroLED's tiny size opens up some pretty unique possibilities, like LG’s prototype.</p><p>Even though flexible displays are already in products like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-foldable-phone">foldable phones</a> and rollable TVs, LG Display hasn’t revealed any plans to roll out its stretchable screen tech commercially yet.</p><p>Nevertheless, the company expects this tech to have plenty of uses, like wearable displays that fit into clothing comfortably and in-car screens that mold to the dashboard’s shape without messing with the design.</p><p>It's likely, though, that these stretchable screens won't hit consumer products anytime soon.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/lgs-stretchable-screen-is-pushing-the-limits-and-bending-like-never-before</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ LG's new display is a shapeshifter, stretching from palm-sized to tablet-sized. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">AUmu26ysZT9qtY5sY6ZkoE</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QbC6wSH2tUgn5DxByx4b5k.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 12:27:32 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/QbC6wSH2tUgn5DxByx4b5k.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[LG]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[LG display being stretched and bent like a rubber band]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[LG display being stretched and bent like a rubber band]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>