<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 05:25:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Power your Black Friday binge-scrolling with Anker's 24,000mAh power bank — now just $79 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>There are dozens of great choices if you want a good power bank with a sizeable battery, and while I tend to use UGREEN products regularly, Anker is the dominant brand in this segment. I got back to using its products recently, and I can see why the brand outsells its rivals — the 737 power Bank in particular is one of the best you can get today, with the power bank offering three ports and a massive 24,000mAh battery.</p><p>The power bank debuted for $149 last year, but it is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Anker-PowerCore-Portable-Charger-Compatible/dp/B09VPHVT2Z">now on sale for just $79</a>, its lowest price yet. Pricing data for 2024 shows that it went down to $109 in sporadic bursts this year, but the Black Friday deal on this power bank makes it an instant recommendation if you&apos;re looking to pick one up.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="221bce3d-e466-444d-9fad-254e91bda332" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$79 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$79 at Amazon" href="https://www.amazon.com/Anker-PowerCore-Portable-Charger-Compatible/dp/B09VPHVT2Z" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:900px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="gfCfndzjdd52vzD8GoLW6X" name="Anker-737-GaNPrime-Power-bank-square.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/gfCfndzjdd52vzD8GoLW6X.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="900" height="900" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Anker 737 24,000mAh 140W Power Bank:</strong> <del><strong>$149</strong></del> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Anker-PowerCore-Portable-Charger-Compatible/dp/B09VPHVT2Z" data-dimension112="221bce3d-e466-444d-9fad-254e91bda332" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$79 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$79 at Amazon"><strong>$79 at Amazon</strong></a></p>
<p>Anker makes the best power banks, and this model is its best yet. It has dual USB-C ports and a USB-A port, has a built-in screen that shows real-time charging stats, and goes up to 140W over USB PD 3.1 via the USB-C ports. I test dozens of power banks over the course of the year, and the 737 is the one you should get — particularly now that it's just $79.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/Anker-PowerCore-Portable-Charger-Compatible/dp/B09VPHVT2Z" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="221bce3d-e466-444d-9fad-254e91bda332" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="$79 at Amazon" data-dimension48="$79 at Amazon">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>There&apos;s plenty to like with the 737 Power Bank. The 24,000mAh battery is big enough to charge all your tech — including a notebook and two phones — without any issues. There are dual USB-C ports based on the USB PD 3.1 standard, and each port goes up to 140W, making it a great choice to charge MacBooks and other notebooks. What&apos;s also great is that the internal battery also charges at 140W — provided you use a charger that goes up to 140W (I <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Anker-Charger-GaNPrime-Compact-Foldable/dp/B09W2PNLX7">recommend this one</a>).</p><p>I also like that there&apos;s an LCD panel that shows real-time charging details. This is particularly handy if you&apos;re on the go and need to see how long it will take to charge your device. There&apos;s a USB-A port as well, and you can easily charge three devices at once, with 18W going to USB-A, and 122W split amongst the two USB-C ports.</p><p>You get a 140W USB-C to USB-C cable bundled in the package, and the design of the power bank makes it easy to throw in a bag or use at your desk. There isn&apos;t anything missing here, and given what you&apos;re getting, the 737 Power Bank <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Anker-PowerCore-Portable-Charger-Compatible/dp/B09VPHVT2Z">is a steal at $79</a>.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/i-tested-over-a-dozen-power-banks-in-2024-this-anker-model-is-the-only-one-you-need-to-buy-this-black-friday</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ The Anker 737 Power Bank is one of the best you can buy today. While it usually sells for around $109, it's now down to $79 for Black Friday, making it a stellar deal.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">prpTEkC58a6bRJgGnv5f2E</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4d5aa2YQq3chqYt8UNdkKk.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 03:48:30 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ harish.jonnalagadda@futurenet.com (Harish Jonnalagadda) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4d5aa2YQq3chqYt8UNdkKk.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Anker]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Anker 737 GaNPrime 140W Power Bank]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Anker 737 GaNPrime 140W Power Bank]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google's 'At a Glance' widget could help you follow sports scores on your Pixel ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Pixel phones feature an At a Glance widget that smartly shows the information you need, when you need it.</li><li>Google appears to be working on a new At a Glance mode that will show live sports scores on your home screen.</li><li>This functionality could give Pixels a competing feature to the iPhone's Dynamic Island, which can already be used to show live sports scores.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>The <strong>At a Glance</strong> widget is a staple of Google Pixel home screens, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-pixel-launcher-default-search-engine-picker-spotted">even if it's now removable</a>. That's because it's a fairly unobtrusive, but useful widget. It smartly switches what information is displayed on your screen based on your habits, the time of day, and the status of your smart home devices. However, the At a Glance home screen widget could be gaining the ability to show sports scores, according to an APK teardown from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/11/22/pixel-at-a-glance-sports/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a>.</p><p>The folks over at 9to5Google unpacked version 13 of Android System Intelligence, the app that handles a ton of your phone's smart features, including At a Glance. In it, the team found a handful of code strings indicating that the widget could one day "show sports updates" on Pixel home and lock screens. Here's the full section of  code relating to sports cores in At a Glance:</p>
<pre class="line-numbers language-" language="" ><code><string name=”echo_smartspace_pref_sports_key”>gemini_space_sports_score</string> 
<string name=”echo_smartspace_sports_toggle_subtitle”>Show sports updates from %1$s. These might affect battery life.</string> 
<string name=”echo_smartspace_sports_toggle_title”>Sports</string> 
<string name=”echo_smartspace_sports_toggle_subtitle_provider_name”>Google</string></code></pre>
<p>As spotted by 9to5Google, the code strings reference <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini">Gemini</a> rather than Google Assistant. This could be a precursor to Google shifting the At a Glance widget to become part of the Gemini suite. It wouldn't exactly be a surprise, since Google is clearly shifting away from <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-assistant">Google Assistant</a> and toward Gemini. Additionally, it's possible that Gemini could factor in some other way, like providing summaries of big plays or game recaps.</p><p>The potential addition of sports scores to the Add a Glance widget could be a big win for Android, and more specifically, Pixel. Apple has been pushing into the sports industry aggressively of late, buying the media rights to Major League Soccer games, debuting an Apple Sports app, and showing live scores through the Dynamic Island on iPhone. By including sports scores in At a Glance, Google could help Pixels become one step closer to matching the iPhone's live sports capabilities.</p><p>However, it's important to note that this feature is clearly still in development and may never ship. If it does debut on Pixel phones, it could be a top feature for sports fans.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/googles-at-a-glance-widget-could-help-you-follow-sports-scores-on-your-pixel</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Code strings hint that you'll one day be able to follow sporting events from your Pixel home screen. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Akjtv9QTxA3YnXZK8z39n9</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ygrs523qfAZEvXe7ET3MDQ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 02:16:20 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ygrs523qfAZEvXe7ET3MDQ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Assistant At a Glance widget on the Razr Plus]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Assistant At a Glance widget on the Razr Plus]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Android 15 QPR1 Beta 3.1 rolls out ahead of expected December launch ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google is rolling out a minor update to Android 15 Beta testers, Android 15 QPR1 Beta 3.1, ahead of the update's expected public release next month.</li><li>Android 15 QPR1 Beta 3.1 includes bug fixes and other improvements, and is available for Google Pixel 6 and newer devices, including Pixel Tablet.</li><li>The update comes as most beta testers have already moved to Android 15 QPR2 Beta 1.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google is sending a minor update to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15">Android 15</a> beta testers as it gears up to release Android 15 QPR1 publicly next month. The update, Android 15 QPR1 Beta 3.1, was <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/android_beta/comments/1gxhqu3/android_15_qpr1_beta_31_now_available/" target="_blank">announced</a> today in a Reddit post. It includes bug fixes and improves overall stability, and is available for Google Pixel 6 and newer phones, plus the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tablets/google-pixel-tablet-review">Pixel Tablet</a>.</p><p>For users enrolled in the Android Beta Program, the update will be sent automatically over-the-air. The build number for Android 15 QPR1 Beta 3.1 is <strong>AP41.240925.012</strong>. However, Google notes that users will only get this update if they're enrolled in the beta program and are still running Android 15 QPR1. Those that have updated to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-qpr2-beta-1-pixel-test-start">Android 15 QPR2 Beta 1</a>, or manually flashed <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-16">Android 16 Developer Preview 1</a>, won't need Android 15 QPR1 Beta 3.1.</p>
<blockquote class="reddit-card"  ><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/android_beta/comments/1gxhqu3/android_15_qpr1_beta_31_now_available">Android 15 QPR1 Beta 3.1 now available!</a> from <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/android_beta">r/android_beta</a></blockquote><script async src="//embed.redditmedia.com/widgets/platform.js" charset="UTF-8"></script>
<p>There are no known new features or major changes in Android 15 QPR1 Beta 3.1, and that's not surprising, as beta testers are already looking ahead to Android 15 QPR2. However, there are a few bug fixes that will be appreciated by anyone still on Android 15 QPR1. That includes a fix for NFC payment failures, a problem that has plagued various pre-release versions of Android 15 for months.</p><p>Here are the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://developer.android.com/about/versions/15/release-notes-qpr1" target="_blank">full release notes</a> for Android 15 QPR1 Beta 3.1, provided by Google:</p>
<ul><li>Fixed an issue where tapping media controls closed the notification shade but didn't open the app. (<a href="https://issuetracker.google.com/issues/375447625">Issue #375447625</a>)</li><li>Fixed an issue where long pressing the device entry icon didn't work when there were many notifications and the notification shelf was overlapping the lock icon. (<a href="https://issuetracker.google.com/issues/369316295">Issue #369316295</a>)</li><li>Fixed an issue that prevented proper volume control for some Bluetooth devices. (<a href="https://issuetracker.google.com/issues/376650439">Issue #376650439</a>,<a href="https://issuetracker.google.com/issues/373681731">Issue #373681731</a>)</li><li>Fixed an issue that caused the Material You, wallpaper-derived color options to be very similar. (<a href="https://issuetracker.google.com/issues/378507373">Issue #378507373</a>)</li><li>Fixed an issue that caused the scrollbar in the system settings to be sized and styled inconsistently. (<a href="https://issuetracker.google.com/issues/366278155">Issue #366278155</a>)</li><li>Fixed an issue that sometimes caused NFC payments to fail. (<a href="https://issuetracker.google.com/issues/363914347">Issue #363914347</a>)</li><li>Fixed an issue where translations in Indonesian and Hebrew didn't display correctly for apps that are targeting Android 14 (API level 34) or lower. (<a href="https://issuetracker.google.com/issues/378200084">Issue #378200084</a>)</li><li>Fixed various other issues that were impacting system stability, camera, connectivity, localization, accessibility, and interactivity.</li></ul>
<p>This appears to be simply a quick tune-up for Android 15 QPR1 as Google prepares to release it publicly. It's largely the same as <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-qpr1-beta-3-bluetooth-foldable-update">Android 15 QPR1 Beta 3</a>, plus the bug fixes, which was the last QPR1 beta release that hit testers nearly a month ago.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-15-qpr1-beta-3-1-rolls-out-ahead-of-expected-december-launch</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Android 15 QPR1 is almost here, and Google's still tinkering with it down to the wire.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">p9fbfzqfYyrHjW7hLqp6XF</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Fj62XpwSQVUzfbwtHRey47.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:42:25 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Fj62XpwSQVUzfbwtHRey47.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android 15 Easter egg on Pixel 9 Pro XL, Pixel 9, and Pixel 9 Pro Fold]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android 15 Easter egg on Pixel 9 Pro XL, Pixel 9, and Pixel 9 Pro Fold]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Fitbit fire sale: Black Friday drops Charge 6, Pixel Watch 3 & more to match all-time lows ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>On the hunt for a new Fitbit? Then Black Friday has arrived a week ahead of schedule for you, as the Charge 6, Inspire 3, Sense 2, and Versa 4 are all at or near all-time low prices, making it a great time to buy one.</p><p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Fitbit-Exercise-Equipment-6-Months-Membership/dp/B0CC62ZG1M"><strong>Fitbit Charge 6 has hit $99 (38% off)</strong></a>, matching its lowest-ever price, as does the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Fitbit-Management-Intensity-Tracking-Midnight/dp/B0B5F9SZW7"><strong>Fitbit Inspire 3 at $69 (30% off)</strong></a>. If you're in the market for a fitness tracker but don't want to try out a budget brand like Amazfit or Xiaomi, either is a natural choice, with the Inspire 3 focused on comfort and the Charge 6 on features.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="a56785a1-1792-4e1a-bb5d-cf690606f61e" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Fitbit Charge 6" data-dimension48="Fitbit Charge 6" data-dimension25="$99.95" href="https://www.amazon.com/Fitbit-Exercise-Equipment-6-Months-Membership/dp/B0CC62ZG1M" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="KWKMozPtNvwKG537XuSSoB" name="fitbit-charge-6-health-tracker-space.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/KWKMozPtNvwKG537XuSSoB.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1000" height="1000" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>The <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fitbit-charge-6-review" data-dimension112="a56785a1-1792-4e1a-bb5d-cf690606f61e" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Fitbit Charge 6" data-dimension48="Fitbit Charge 6" data-dimension25="$99.95">Fitbit Charge 6</a> has been our number-one pick for the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-fitness-trackers">best fitness tracker</a> since its launch a year ago. It has a week-long battery life, support for Google Maps and YouTube Music, accurate health sensors for workouts and catching irregular heart rhythm, and Fitbit Premium insights. At night, it tracks everything from HRV and SpO2 to skin temperature and breathing rate.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/Fitbit-Exercise-Equipment-6-Months-Membership/dp/B0CC62ZG1M" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="a56785a1-1792-4e1a-bb5d-cf690606f61e" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Fitbit Charge 6" data-dimension48="Fitbit Charge 6" data-dimension25="$99.95">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="7ab7b386-b601-47fa-874c-45b255db366e" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Fitbit Inspire 3" data-dimension48="Fitbit Inspire 3" data-dimension25="$69.95" href="https://www.amazon.com/Fitbit-Management-Intensity-Tracking-Midnight/dp/B0B5F9SZW7" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:400px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:125.00%;"><img id="47FpanqCEBJqsw8TPjy9Q5" name="Fitbit Inspire 3 bg render.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/47FpanqCEBJqsw8TPjy9Q5.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="400" height="500" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>The <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fitbit-inspire-3-review" data-dimension112="7ab7b386-b601-47fa-874c-45b255db366e" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Fitbit Inspire 3" data-dimension48="Fitbit Inspire 3" data-dimension25="$69.95">Fitbit Inspire 3</a> is all about simplicity. It doesn't have the Charge 6's extra sensors, GPS, or tap-to-pay, but if it's truly all about a comfortable, lightweight design, basic notification pop-ups, and week-long battery life, then this petite tracker will be a better option than the heavier Charge.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/Fitbit-Management-Intensity-Tracking-Midnight/dp/B0B5F9SZW7" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="7ab7b386-b601-47fa-874c-45b255db366e" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Fitbit Inspire 3" data-dimension48="Fitbit Inspire 3" data-dimension25="$69.95">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>Outside of fitness trackers, you'll also find some Black Friday Fitbit deals on its smartwatches: the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Fitbit-Advanced-Fitness-Smartwatch-Included/dp/B0B4MV1TGL"><strong>Fitbit Sense 2 is $179.95 ($70 off)</strong></a>, while the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0B4MWCFV4"><strong>Fitbit Versa 4 is $119.95 ($80 off)</strong></a>. Both watches have technically fallen lower <em>once</em> in their deal history — the Versa 4 at $104 and the Sense 2 at $139 — but they're both at the <em>second-lowest</em> price we've ever seen.</p><p>Because Google has all but confirmed that it <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/pixel-watch-3-great-running-features-overshadowed-by-fitbit-watches-demise">won't make any more Fitbit-branded watches</a>, focusing on the expensive, short-lived, and Android-only Pixel Watches, the Sense 2 and Versa 4 are the best you're going to get, as long as they remain in stock. But despite its age, the Sense 2 remains an excellent option for health tracking paired with a gorgeous AMOLED display, while the Versa 4 is more stripped down but very affordable at this price.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="a5a67a0c-b4ef-413d-a383-3d87b2e8e9c3" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Fitbit Sense 2" data-dimension48="Fitbit Sense 2" data-dimension25="$179.95" href="https://www.amazon.com/Fitbit-Advanced-Fitness-Smartwatch-Included/dp/B0B4MV1TGL" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="pEHuPwqND4qvbnyc7HyWXX" name="fitbit-sense-2-render-w-space.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pEHuPwqND4qvbnyc7HyWXX.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1080" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>The <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fitbit-sense-2-review" data-dimension112="a5a67a0c-b4ef-413d-a383-3d87b2e8e9c3" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Fitbit Sense 2" data-dimension48="Fitbit Sense 2" data-dimension25="$179.95">Fitbit Sense 2</a> remains one of the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-smartwatches-fitness">best fitness smartwatches</a> today, thanks to its 6-day battery life, packed array of health sensors — similar to the Charge 6 but with a cEDA sensor for more accurate stress tracking — and its large, bright AMOLED display for Google Maps and notifications. It launched at an expensive $299, but now the price drop and this deal make it much more reasonable.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/Fitbit-Advanced-Fitness-Smartwatch-Included/dp/B0B4MV1TGL" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="a5a67a0c-b4ef-413d-a383-3d87b2e8e9c3" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Fitbit Sense 2" data-dimension48="Fitbit Sense 2" data-dimension25="$179.95">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="cfd4710c-7446-4e09-9465-7689e590e025" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Fitbit Versa 4" data-dimension48="Fitbit Versa 4" data-dimension25="$119.95" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0B4MWCFV4" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1364px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="47ATvzHJJX7UK6vWw2CNJ7" name="fitbit-versa-4-copper-rose-render.jpeg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/47ATvzHJJX7UK6vWw2CNJ7.jpeg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1364" height="1364" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>We initially gave the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fitbit-versa-4-review" data-dimension112="cfd4710c-7446-4e09-9465-7689e590e025" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Fitbit Versa 4" data-dimension48="Fitbit Versa 4" data-dimension25="$119.95">Fitbit Versa 4</a> a middling review because $230 felt too expensive for what it offered; at $119, however, it's a steal for the essentials. The Versa 4 lacks the Sense 2's all-around health tracking, focusing on basic heart rate, stress, and passive AFib, but shares its 1.58-inch AMOLED, Google Maps/ Wallet support, mic & speaker for Bluetooth calls, Alexa voice commands, and Fitbit Premium training tools.<a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0B4MWCFV4" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="cfd4710c-7446-4e09-9465-7689e590e025" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Fitbit Versa 4" data-dimension48="Fitbit Versa 4" data-dimension25="$119.95">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>You can even snag the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-Watch-Latest-Model/dp/B0D9138ZXM"><strong>Pixel Watch 3 for $279 ($70 off)</strong></a> thanks to Black Friday, which may not have the Fitbit branding but does come with six months of Fitbit Premium, new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/fitbit-cardio-load-and-target-load-explained">Fitbit Cardio Load</a> insights, and all of the same health sensors as the Sense 2, except with a full array of Wear OS apps and Google Assistant support.</p><p>If you're on the hunt for other fitness watch options, these <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/early-black-friday-garmin-deals-2024-ditch-your-old-smartwatch-and-save-big-on-forerunner-venu-and-more">early Garmin Black Friday deals</a> may tempt you: some are much pricier than Fitbit watches, but they're also newer, don't require a subscription, and have some in-depth training tools for runners and cyclists that Fitbit doesn't offer.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/black-friday-fitbit-deals-2024-charge-sense-pixel-watch-more</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Whether you want a tiny inspire 3, feature-packed Charge 6, health-focused Sense 2, or Wear OS-ready Pixel Watch 3, there are some great Black Friday deals for all of them. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Fe5JsYfKZWtSjZLcx37EeD</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5QRNzdBA3W3ZSudPCNQaKY.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5QRNzdBA3W3ZSudPCNQaKY.jpeg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[ Close-up of the Fitbit Charge 6]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[ Close-up of the Fitbit Charge 6]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Black Friday puzzle: Buy the Galaxy Watch 6 for 53% off or the Watch 7 for 32% off? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Samsung doesn't want you to wait until the <em>real</em> Black Friday, as it clears out its inventory of Galaxy Watch 6 models once and for all. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Bluetooth-Smartwatch-Personalized-Advanced/dp/B0C792QRW6"><strong>Watch 6 40mm ($139.99, or 53% off)</strong></a> has never come close to this price; last week, it was $169! Now, you can play chicken with Samsung and hope it falls even lower by next week, or you can snag one now before it goes out of stock for good.</p><p>The only reason not to buy the Galaxy Watch 6 is if you want the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Galaxy-Bluetooth-Smartwatch-Manufacturer/dp/B0D1YQKDML"><strong>Galaxy Watch 7 at $205 (32% off)</strong></a>. That's another all-time low according to Camelcamelcamel, on what we consider <em>the</em> best Android watch of the year.</p><p>Our <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-7-vs-galaxy-watch-6">Galaxy Watch 7 vs. 6 guide</a> will break things down in-depth, but essentially, the Watch 7 and 6 share the same design, displays, memory, and battery life, while the Watch 7 has a faster and more efficient processor, more accurate GPS, new health sensors, and more storage.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="61877c14-3d9d-4da9-9d19-e92dd3e82ffb" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Price comparison: Best Buy - $149.99" data-dimension48="Price comparison: Best Buy - $149.99" data-dimension25="$139.99" href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Bluetooth-Smartwatch-Personalized-Advanced/dp/B0C792QRW6" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1521px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="LenQPkuoNpvx6bijynpVy3" name="samsung galaxy watch 6.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LenQPkuoNpvx6bijynpVy3.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1521" height="1521" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>The Galaxy Watch 6 has a thin-bordered, 2,000-nit display, robust Exynos chipset with 2GB of RAM, three years left of Wear OS/ security updates, and a ton of accurate health sensors. Even compared to newer Wear OS watches from other brands, I'd still recommend this year-old watch instead.</p><p><strong>Price comparison: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-watch6-aluminum-smartwatch-44mm-bt-graphite/6546698.p?skuId=6546698" data-dimension112="61877c14-3d9d-4da9-9d19-e92dd3e82ffb" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Price comparison: Best Buy - $149.99" data-dimension48="Price comparison: Best Buy - $149.99" data-dimension25="$139.99">Best Buy - $149.99</a> | <a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/watches/galaxy-watch6/buy/galaxy-watch6-40mm-gold-bt-sm-r930nzedxaa/?modelCode=SM-R930NZKAXAA">Samsung - $149.99</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Bluetooth-Smartwatch-Personalized-Advanced/dp/B0C792QRW6" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="61877c14-3d9d-4da9-9d19-e92dd3e82ffb" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Price comparison: Best Buy - $149.99" data-dimension48="Price comparison: Best Buy - $149.99" data-dimension25="$139.99">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="0e1a926e-4c38-451c-b713-2fd3e3fece3a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Price comparison: Samsung - $239" data-dimension48="Price comparison: Samsung - $239" data-dimension25="$205.05" href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Galaxy-Bluetooth-Smartwatch-Manufacturer/dp/B0D1YQKDML" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1706px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="twg3XFZJ889G3SKztd3TTj" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Watch-7-official-render-green.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/twg3XFZJ889G3SKztd3TTj.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1706" height="1706" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p>Want the best possible experience and longevity? The Galaxy Watch 7 is liable to last a few hours longer per charge, offer more accurate HR and GPS data for athletes, and provide more space for your on-wrist playlists if you leave your phone at home.</p><p><strong>Price comparison: </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/watches/galaxy-watch7/buy/galaxy-watch7-40mm-green-wifi-bluetooth-sm-l300nzgdxaa/" data-dimension112="0e1a926e-4c38-451c-b713-2fd3e3fece3a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Price comparison: Samsung - $239" data-dimension48="Price comparison: Samsung - $239" data-dimension25="$205.05">Samsung - $239</a> | <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-watch7-aluminum-smartwatch-40mm-bt-cream/6585114.p?skuId=6585114">Best Buy - $239</a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Galaxy-Bluetooth-Smartwatch-Manufacturer/dp/B0D1YQKDML" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="0e1a926e-4c38-451c-b713-2fd3e3fece3a" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Price comparison: Samsung - $239" data-dimension48="Price comparison: Samsung - $239" data-dimension25="$205.05">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p>The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-7-review">Galaxy Watch 7</a> is objectively better than the Watch 6, but I know that most people deal-hunting on Black Friday prefer lower prices whenever possible. If I had to choose between the Watch 7 44mm for $247 or the Watch 6 44mm for $159, I'd lean towards the last-gen model.</p><p>Having reviewed the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-6-review">Galaxy Watch 6</a> in its smaller size, I'd recommend paying a little extra for the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Bluetooth-Smartwatch-Personalized-Advanced/dp/B0C7929YMK"><strong>Galaxy Watch 6 44mm at $159.99 (52% off)</strong></a>, another all-time low! The display jump from 1.3- to 1.5-inches makes a huge visual difference without weighing much more, and while the 40mm only has Black models left, the 44mm is available in both Black and Silver, giving you more options.</p><p>Out of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch">best Android watches</a>, the Galaxy Watch 6 is still on my list, despite the Watch 7 supplanting it, because of its longevity: It just received Wear OS 5 and will get three more system updates by 2027. Unlike other old, cheap watches, the Watch 6 will keep getting new Galaxy AI tricks and app smarts for <em>years</em>.</p><p>I'll admit that I'd miss the Watch 7's dual-band GPS tracking, but that's only because I'm a regular runner who's greedy for the most accurate stats possible. "Normal" people can happily make do with the Galaxy Watch 6, which still has all the Samsung Health tricks and third-party Wear OS apps like Strava that you need to train and get (or stay) healthy!</p><p>While I personally love my Pixel Watch 3 as a Wear OS alternative, its <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-Watch-Latest-Model/dp/B0D91268TH"><strong>early Black Friday deal of $329 ($70 off)</strong></a> isn't nearly as impressive. Only the Galaxy Watch 6 and 7 deals are especially kind to your wallet, and the Watch 6 in particular isn't likely to last very long! You can be patient on the newer watches, but this watch might very well sell out for good while you wait for something better.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/galaxy-watch-6-hits-all-time-low-week-before-black-friday-2024</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ You have a deal dilemma on your hands: The Galaxy Watch 6 is 53% off...but the Watch 7 is 32% off! We'll help you make the best choice. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">dqv2menJFLEVowxTqYMzfa</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/iCkVz8cRTnrZaEt4JzpcyF.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/iCkVz8cRTnrZaEt4JzpcyF.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Michael Hicks / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 (left, black) and Samsung Galaxy Watch 7 (right, silver) side-by-side]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 (left, black) and Samsung Galaxy Watch 7 (right, silver) side-by-side]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Forget AirPods Max, my favorite Beats over-ears are just $160 in this can't-miss deal ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>I've reviewed every single Beats product released in 2024, from the brand-new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/beats-pill-2024-review">Beats Pill</a> to the strange Beats iPhone 16 case. Once known as bass-heavy and fashion-first headphones, I'm happy to report that Beats are good now. With the same Apple tech inside as AirPods, plus full Android support, the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/beats-solo-4-review">Beats Solo 4</a> and Beats Studio Pro are some of the best-value headphones you can buy. That's especially true now that the Solo 4s are more than half off and the Studio Pro are $190 off in two killer early Black Friday deals.</p><p>Best Buy has one of the most aggressive Beats Studio Pro deals we've ever seen, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/beats-studio-pro-wireless-noise-cancelling-over-the-ear-headphones-black-gold/6501025" target="_blank" rel="sponsored">slashing the price of these headphones down to just $159.99</a>. If you're in the market for a pair of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-wireless-headphones">excellent over-ear headphones</a> this Black Friday and Cyber Monday, you may not come across a better deal.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="c462c2ec-b157-4d11-a950-ffb992507cc2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Beats Studio Pro:" data-dimension48="Beats Studio Pro:" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="nE9Enc65jgsTmi8byg6CTV" name="beats studio pro reco 600x600.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nE9Enc65jgsTmi8byg6CTV.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Beats Studio Pro:</strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/beats-studio-pro-wireless-noise-cancelling-over-the-ear-headphones-black-gold/6501025.p" target="_blank" rel="sponsored" data-dimension112="c462c2ec-b157-4d11-a950-ffb992507cc2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Beats Studio Pro:" data-dimension48="Beats Studio Pro:" data-dimension25=""> <del>$349.99</del> <strong>$159.99 at Best Buy</strong></a></p><p>The Beats Studio Pro are an excellent pair of over-ear headphones that leverages Apple's excellent audio tech inside an Android-friendly package. You'll get features like ANC, Dolby Atmos, and quick pairing on iOS and Android. It's like if AirPods Max were cheaper and made for Android users.</p><p><strong>Price comparison:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Beats-Studio-Pro-Personalized-Compatibility/dp/B0C8PWSW7T/" target="_blank" rel="sponsored">Amazon - $249.99</a> | <a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MQTR3LL/A/beats-studio-pro-wireless-headphones-sandstone" target="_blank" rel="sponsored">Apple - $349.99</a><a class="view-deal button" href="" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="c462c2ec-b157-4d11-a950-ffb992507cc2" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Beats Studio Pro:" data-dimension48="Beats Studio Pro:" data-dimension25="">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Black Friday deals</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Black Friday Google Pixel deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Black Friday Motorola deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024">Black Friday Samsung deals</a><br>-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Black Friday OnePlus deals</a></p></div></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>you want a comfortable, light pair of headphones; you value versatility with iOS and Android fast-pairing, plus a 3.5mm jack; you want premium features like Spatial and Lossless Audio, ANC, and transparency mode.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>you need the absolute best sound quality; you don't like the plastic construction of the Beats Studio Pro.</p>
<p>The amazing thing about the Beats Studio Pro is that the headphones share a lot of similarities with the AirPods Max, which retail for $549.99. I've tested both extensively, and I won't lie to you — the AirPods Max do sound better, and have better ANC. When I think about <em>how much</em> better the AirPods Max sound than the Beats Studio Pro, that's when things start to change. I don't think the AirPods Max are $400 better than the Beats Studio Pro, and that's roughly the price difference between these two headphones when you consider the $159.99 deal price of the Studio Pro.</p><p>So, with the Beats Studio Pro, you're getting about 90% of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/do-airpods-max-work-android-phones">AirPods Max</a> experience at a fraction of the price. The Beats Studio Pro still have a custom Beats chip facilitating quick, snappy connection with both iOS and Android. There's also solid active noise-canceling, transparency mode, and support for Dolby Atmos, Lossless Audio, and Spatial Audio. Plus, you get a 3.5mm jack for when you want to use a cable.</p><p>Now, the Beats Studio Pro aren't the only pair of Beats headphones on sale. Budget buyers will probably want to grab the Solo 4 instead, which are half off for a limited time, bringing the price down to $99.99. Target lists the deal as ending tomorrow, so you'll want to act fast to secure this discount.</p>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="8b9f0e17-198e-40e3-a924-d708a843552f" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Beats Solo 4:" data-dimension48="Beats Solo 4:" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:1080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="ypDF3wKbztxE9zD67UbSB3" name="beats-solo-4-square.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ypDF3wKbztxE9zD67UbSB3.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="1080" height="1080" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Beats Solo 4:</strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/beats-solo-4-true-wireless-on-ear-headphones-matte-black/6501020.p?" target="_blank" rel="sponsored" data-dimension112="8b9f0e17-198e-40e3-a924-d708a843552f" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Beats Solo 4:" data-dimension48="Beats Solo 4:" data-dimension25="">  <del>$199.99</del> <strong>$99.99 at Best Buy</strong></a> </p><p>The Beats Solo 4 are an affordable pair of on-ear headphones that are fairly lightweight and sturdy. If you don't need ANC, transparency mode, or other premium features, snag the Solo 4 headphones for under $100 this Black Friday.</p><p><strong>Price comparison:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Beats-Solo-Ear-Headphones-Compatible/dp/B0CZPGX972?" target="_blank" rel="sponsored">Amazon - $99.99</a><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Beats-Studio-Pro-Personalized-Compatibility/dp/B0C8PWSW7T/"> </a>| <a href="https://www.target.com/p/beats-solo-4-bluetooth-wireless-on-ear-headphones-cloud-pink/-/A-91747218" target="_blank" rel="sponsored">Target - $99.99</a><a class="view-deal button" href="" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="8b9f0e17-198e-40e3-a924-d708a843552f" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Beats Solo 4:" data-dimension48="Beats Solo 4:" data-dimension25="">View Deal</a></p></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if: </strong>you need a basic, cheap pair of wireless on-ear headphones; you want a pair of headphones that'll stay secure on your head during workouts; you need fast-pairing with iOS and Android; you want a 3.5mm jack.</p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>you need ANC and transparency mode; you find on-ear headphones uncomfortable.</p>
<p>The Beats Solo 4 aren't perfect, but it's easy to accept a compromise or two when the headphones are available for just under $100. There's no ANC or transparency mode support, which is a big bummer. But they have solid sound, long battery life, and a reliable connection with iOS and Android quick pairing. Strong clamping force helps the Beats Solo 4 become my top recommendation for on-ear workout headphones. These won't fall off while you're lifting weights or going for a run.</p><p>Black Friday hasn't even officially started yet, and Beats already has a discount for everyone. Not looking to spend a lot on a new pair of headphones? Pick up the Beats Solo 4. Want a premium experience at a midrange price? There's the Beats Studio Pro.</p>

<ul><li><strong>Headphone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/browse/3944_133251_1095191_1230614_1230477"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/promo/headphone-and-speaker-deals"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=headphones&crid=3JN832N1C6WXP&sprefix=headphones%2Caps%2C172&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.dell.com/en-us/search/headphones?p=1&c=8310%2C8318&f=true&ac=categoryfacetselect"><u><strong>Dell</strong></u></a></li><li><strong>Earbuds deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/promo/headphone-and-speaker-deals"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/browse/electronics/shop-headphones-by-type/3944_133251_1095191_1230614?sort=best_match&cat_id=3944_133251_1095191_1230614_1230476&stores=3081&ps=40"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=earbuds&crid=2RWE1G9N1EIF&sprefix=earbuds%2Caps%2C161&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/mobile/audio/all-audio/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.dell.com/en-us/search/earbuds"><u><strong>Dell</strong></u></a></li><li><strong>Speaker deals: </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/browse/electronics/portable-wireless-bluetooth-speakers/3944_96469_615879"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/audio/portable-speakers-docks-radios/pcmcat310200050004.c?id=pcmcat310200050004"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=bluetooth+speakers&crid=1B2AQSMN8GMER&sprefix=bluetooth+speake%2Caps%2C242&ref=nb_sb_noss_2"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.dell.com/en-us/search/bluetooth%20speakers"><u><strong>Dell</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/accessories/audio/forget-airpods-max-my-favorite-beats-over-ears-are-just-usd160-in-this-cant-miss-deal</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Beats Studio Pro and Solo 4 headphones come with massive price cuts already — they're as low as $99.99. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">7Lrx69yrbbLrABA2TgBmFH</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4s4QkUe7WVmWCfb7x78SsG.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 21:11:34 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4s4QkUe7WVmWCfb7x78SsG.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Brady Snyder / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[AirPods Max (left) hanging from a park bench beside Beats Studio Pro (right).]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[AirPods Max (left) hanging from a park bench beside Beats Studio Pro (right).]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ WhatsApp makes Voice Messages more accessible with new Transcripts feature ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>WhatsApp has announced a new Voice Message Transcripts feature for select languages.</li><li>The aim is to help users with transcripts when they cannot hear the received voice notes in select situations.</li><li>WhatsApp also notes that it can help comprehend longer voice notes more easily.</li><li>The global rollout in select languages is to happen in the coming weeks, with the promise of adding more languages soon.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>If you are a WhatsApp user, chances are you already know how voice notes work on the messaging platform. It is a handy functionality for sharing quick voice messages instead of typing long texts, and it is now getting a nifty new expansion.</p><p>WhatsApp <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://blog.whatsapp.com/introducing-voice-message-transcripts">has announced</a> that it is introducing voice message transcripts for users who often send voice notes to their friends and family. The Meta-owned company notes that although the voice message itself adds a personal touch compared to a regular text message, in certain scenarios, like when in a loud place or at a concert, it can be difficult to hear a voice message.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="nzGKSzJZVLxHZdmKzEzscj" name="whatspp-voice-message-transcripts-02" alt="WhatsApp Voice Message Transcripts" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nzGKSzJZVLxHZdmKzEzscj.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: WhatsApp)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In such cases, these newly introduced voice message transcripts aim to save time. Additionally, having transcripts of longer voice notes will be handy for comprehending or getting back to them later. WhatsApp is also adding its privacy aspect to the transcripts, as they are generated on your device so that no one, including WhatsApp, can “hear or read your personal messages.”</p><p>The transcripts feature is also optional and can be manually enabled or turned off entirely. The messaging platform users can head to <strong>WhatsApp Settings> Chats> Voice message transcripts</strong> to enable or disable the feature in their preferred language. Once the feature is enabled, users can long-press the voice message and tap on “transcribe,” and the transcript can be viewed instantly.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="88RwgPVjLM3SyFEmk3atbj" name="whatspp-voice-message-transcripts-01" alt="WhatsApp Voice Message Transcripts" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/88RwgPVjLM3SyFEmk3atbj.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: WhatsApp)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The latest addition is believed to be rolling out globally in the coming weeks, with select languages for the start, and more languages are likely to be added in the coming months. WhatsApp has provided a little <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://faq.whatsapp.com/241617298315321/?cms_platform=android">how-to guide</a> and has listed the languages currently supported by the new transcripts feature. They include English, Portuguese, Spanish, and Russian.</p><p>Meanwhile, WhatsApp has also <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/meta-whatsapp-message-drafts-rollout">introduced</a> other nifty features to keep up with the competition. These include the ability to have messages in drafts, which can be sent later to chats, just like email.</p><p>Some WhatsApp users are also seeing new typing indicators from the recipients within the chat. The rollout appears to be on the server side. It appears to be an expansion of what users are already accustomed to. Previously, users could see a Typing indicator right under the contact name.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u><strong><br></strong></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/whatsapp-introduces-voice-message-transcripts</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ WhatsApp adds transcripts to voice messages in select languages for now. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">Xc3SDuRPgXUAMqrhGk4Kpk</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/h9pWNRqudk7uyfSbpRiJtF.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 20:48:26 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/h9pWNRqudk7uyfSbpRiJtF.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[WhatsApp Voice Message Transcripts]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[WhatsApp Voice Message Transcripts]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Amazon might've drawn the EU's gaze for pushing its products more than others ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A report states the EU could have Amazon in its sights in 2025 for a potential investigation into its marketplace practices.</li><li>The EU may look into whether or not Amazon is guilty of not pushing its products and the competition's equally.</li><li>Amazon could face a fine worth up to 10% of its "global annual turnover."</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Amazon might find itself in the hot seat again in the EU over a reported "breach in tech rules."</p><p>According to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/amazon-likely-face-investigation-under-eu-tech-rules-next-year-sources-say-2024-11-21/">Reuters</a>, the EU might seek out Amazon to investigate an apparent DMA ruleset breach in 2025. What the EU is reportedly looking to learn is whether Amazon has pushed its own products to consumers more than the competition's.</p><p>Murmurings about a potential investigation started in March, per a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.reuters.com/business/media-telecom/eu-investigate-apple-google-meta-potential-digital-markets-act-breaches-2024-03-25/">previous Reuters report</a>. Back then, it was stated that the EU could look into the "ranking practices" Amazon conducts on its marketplace and whether that falls outside of the boundaries set forth by the EU.</p><p>An Amazon spokesperson said in March that the company has remained "compliant" with the set rules. The report states that Amazon "does not differentiate" between its products and those sold by third parties.</p><p>Now, the publication cites those close to the matter in saying that Amazon could face a fine worth up to 10% of its "global annual turnover."</p><p>Android Central has reached out to Amazon about this potential investigation. We will update this article when we hear back.</p><p>In September 2023, the European Commission named its first six "gatekeepers" under the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/eu-apple-imessage-gatekeeper-ruling">Digital Markets Act (DMA)</a>. Additionally, 22 services were deemed fit to fall under the "Core Platform" umbrella. In short, the DMA is the EU's ruleset for major companies to ensure that healthy competition lives on. One company shouldn't give itself an unfair advantage over another that's trying to make good on its platform.</p><p>Amazon's Marketplace fell within the EU's "intermediation" box for the DMA. As Reuters also reiterated, this was designed to ensure Amazon — like many others — couldn't promote themselves above others in the name of profit.</p><p>This also isn't the first time Amazon has fallen in the hot seat with the EU or even the FTC, for that matter. The company was forced to provide a clear process for consumers to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/amazon-prime-updated-cancellation-process-europe">cancel its Prime membership</a> in the EU. The old process was dubbed "manipulative" as consumers found it difficult to navigate the process, thus incurring another monthly charge. After complying, Amazon rolled out a simpler, two-step process to exit the membership.</p><p>A similar investigation took place in the U.S. in 2023 as the FTC said Amazon conducted "<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/ftc-sues-amazon-unfair-prime-charges">dark digital practices</a>."</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/amazon-eu-marketplace-investigation-possible-report</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A report stated Amazon could face the EU in 2025 over a possible DMA rule breach. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">mPDHxQcNxQMHJgKSxf7C63</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/toNvbWnU2ksQjHdk3DpQGD.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 20:44:50 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/toNvbWnU2ksQjHdk3DpQGD.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Andrew Martonik / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Amazon logo gray background]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Amazon logo gray background]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Gemini Live tipped to hold conversations with you about YouTube videos ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A Google app beta discovery suggests Gemini Live could grab an "Ask about this video" feature for YouTube.</li><li>Findings suggest this will let users hold a conversation, with follow-up questions, about the currently playing YouTube video.</li><li>YouTube detailed a test of its own "conversational AI" in its mobile app that would let users "Ask" about the video.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>A recent beta suggests Google is working on a more conversational experience with Gemini during your downtime.</p><p>Strings of code in the v15.46.31.ve.arm64 of the Google app's beta tease a new experience between Gemini Live and YouTube. Discovered by AssembleDebug (<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidauthority.com/gemini-conversation-mode-3500632/">Android Authority</a>), Google might roll out a "conversation mode" for the AI model when watching videos. A line of code directly mentions this feature's teamwork with YouTube; however, there's more to it.</p><p>The tipster was able to produce a small portion of the feature in the beta, showcasing what users might see. The provided image shows that producing Gemini's overlay may soon feature an "Ask about this video" chip. Speculation suggests this will open users up to an ongoing conversation with Gemini about the video's contents.</p><p>Users can reportedly ask about what's in the video with the opportunity to offer follow-up questions, too.</p><p>It's unclear if users can verbally say their query or if typing is the only way forward. Despite little else discoverable, another line of code encourages users to raise their device's volume "to hear Gemini."</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:276px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:217.39%;"><img id="pHWnBgd2usfxSErCZAnHFE" name="google-gemini-live-youtube-ask-about-this-video-early-discovery" alt="Gemini Live could receive an "Ask about this video" function for YouTube." src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/pHWnBgd2usfxSErCZAnHFE.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="276" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Authority)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While this feature seems like a likely next step after <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/how-use-circle-to-search">Circle to Search</a>, Gemini Live's alleged feature <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/youtube-highlights-premium-features-coversational-ai">looks like YouTube's</a>. A year ago, YouTube started an AI experiment with Premium users that let them playtest a conversational experience. That test included two features: AI-powered summaries for comments and a new "Ask" button for videos.</p><p>The latter was featured with a Gemini-esque star beside the Share and Like buttons under a video. Upon interaction, testers were greeted with three query suggestions: "Summarize this video," "Tell me more about this topic," and "Recommend related content."</p><p>While it <em>seems </em>like Gemini Live will lack the summarization portion, it will at least let users query about piqued their interest. Moreover, users could continue to "Ask" YouTube about the video they were watching, which is (kind of) like putting forth a follow-up question.</p><p>Aside from its official dedicated <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-gemini-on-iphone-dedicated-app-launch">app launch on iOS</a>, Gemini Live was rumored to receive <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/gemini-live-could-soon-start-messing-around-with-your-files">file management capabilities</a> through Google Drive.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/gemini-live-ask-youtube-video-spotted</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ A discovery claimed Google's Gemini Live could grab an "ask about this video" feature. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">2vYFwJmbeZihMK5SSfERNN</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Ana3sRMUiMe5FxcTuPuiGQ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 20:09:16 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nickodiaz@sbcglobal.net (Nickolas Diaz) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Ana3sRMUiMe5FxcTuPuiGQ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Gemini Live on the Pixel 9]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Gemini Live on the Pixel 9]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ How to score over $1,500 of FREE Android devices during Verizon's Black Friday sale (no, that's not a typo) ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Verizon&apos;s Black Friday deals are here, and while they aren&apos;t as straightforward as simply grabbing a discount from Amazon or Best Buy, you stand to save a ridiculous amount of cash if you play your cards right. One deal in particular has been dominating the airwaves: <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/samsung-galaxy-s24-plus/"><strong>purchase the Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus with a trade-in and eligible Unlimited plan and you&apos;ll get the phone, a Galaxy Watch 7, AND a Galaxy Tab S9 FE for free</strong></a>! Sounds pretty great, but what are the specifics? Let&apos;s dive in. </p>
<h2 id="get-the-galaxy-watch-7-galaxy-tab-s9-fe-and-samsung-galaxy-s24-plus-for-free-at-verizon-2">Get the Galaxy Watch 7, Galaxy Tab S9 FE, and Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus for FREE at Verizon</h2>
<div class="product"><a data-dimension112="8575a4e4-e81d-4385-bc4e-1cbc51d9a6c4" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Verizon Black Friday bundle: get the Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus, Galaxy Watch 7, and Galaxy Tab S9 FE for FREE with eligible trade-in and new line" data-dimension48="Verizon Black Friday bundle: get the Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus, Galaxy Watch 7, and Galaxy Tab S9 FE for FREE with eligible trade-in and new line" href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/samsung-galaxy-s24-plus/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:420px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.24%;"><img id="aLog5eLrZTgZcos2Yub4Ak" name="galaxy-s24-plus-tab-s9-fe-galaxy-watch-7-bundle-render-verizon.jpg" caption="" alt="" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/aLog5eLrZTgZcos2Yub4Ak.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="420" height="421" attribution="" endorsement="" credit="" class=""></p></div></div></figure></a><p><strong>Verizon Black Friday bundle: </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/samsung-galaxy-s24-plus/" data-dimension112="8575a4e4-e81d-4385-bc4e-1cbc51d9a6c4" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Verizon Black Friday bundle: get the Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus, Galaxy Watch 7, and Galaxy Tab S9 FE for FREE with eligible trade-in and new line" data-dimension48="Verizon Black Friday bundle: get the Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus, Galaxy Watch 7, and Galaxy Tab S9 FE for FREE with eligible trade-in and new line"><strong>get the Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus, Galaxy Watch 7, and Galaxy Tab S9 FE for FREE with eligible trade-in and new line</strong></a></p>
<p>Ready to get all of your holiday shopping done in one fell swoop? Verizon will give you over $1,500 worth of Android tech for free when you pick up the <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24-plus-review">Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus</a> with the Unlimited Ultimate plan and trade in an old or broken phone. </p>
<p>These three devices are some of the best that Samsung has to offer, with Snapdragon chipsets, AI features, and software support galore.</p>
<p>👀<strong>Alternate Black Friday deal: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-s24-256gb-unlocked-onyx-black/6569843.p"><strong>get $200 off the Galaxy S24 Plus at Best Buy</strong></a><a class="view-deal button" href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/samsung-galaxy-s24-plus/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow" data-dimension112="8575a4e4-e81d-4385-bc4e-1cbc51d9a6c4" data-action="Deal Block" data-label="Verizon Black Friday bundle: get the Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus, Galaxy Watch 7, and Galaxy Tab S9 FE for FREE with eligible trade-in and new line" data-dimension48="Verizon Black Friday bundle: get the Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus, Galaxy Watch 7, and Galaxy Tab S9 FE for FREE with eligible trade-in and new line">View Deal</a></p></div>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Black Friday deals</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><p class="fancy-box__body-text">-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-google-pixel-deals-2024-early-discounts-and-how-to-prepare">Black Friday Google Pixel deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-motorola-deals-2024-historic-razr-savings-usd150-off-moto-g-stylus-and-more">Black Friday Motorola deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/live/black-friday-samsung-deals-2024">Black Friday Samsung deals</a><br>
-<a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/black-friday-oneplus-deals">Black Friday OnePlus deals</a></p></div></div>
<p><strong>✅Recommended if:</strong> you&apos;re prepared to sign up or upgrade to a new wireless plan; you have an old or broken device to trade in. </p><p><strong>❌Skip this deal if: </strong>you&apos;re happy with your current wireless carrier; you can&apos;t afford Verizon&apos;s Unlimited Ultimate plan.</p><p>Indeed, Unlimited Ultimate is Verizon&apos;s most expensive plan, but you get a lot of bang for your buck. I&apos;m talking about 5G Ultra Wideband, 60GB of mobile hotspot data every month, and unlimited talk, text, and data in over 210 countries worldwide. The plan starts at $90 per month per line, but you can drop that down considerably by adding multiple lines at once. </p><p>Verizon is also being pretty generous with the trade-in devices it accepts for this <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/tag/black-friday-2024">Black Friday deal</a>. I was surprised to see that my old Galaxy S20 FE earned me the full amount, which means I&apos;m eligible to get the $1,500 worth of devices when I add a line with the Unlimited Ultimate plan. </p><p>For sure, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/best-verizon-phone-deals-plans">Verizon deals</a> like this aren&apos;t for everyone, but if you can make it work for you, it&apos;s quite the holiday miracle! </p>



 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/how-to-get-over-usd1-500-of-free-android-devices-during-verizons-black-friday-sale-no-thats-not-a-typo</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Verizon's Black Friday sale just kicked off, and there's one deal that could get you a ton of free stuff.. but is it legit? How does it work? ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">cgrZdvZBaPGpL9o7WHAUSk</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/B7sF4UgVguGHmefyqBo5Sg.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 20:00:01 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ patrick.farmer@futurenet.com (Patrick Farmer) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/B7sF4UgVguGHmefyqBo5Sg.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Derrek Lee / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The Galaxy S24 Plus in hand outside]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The Galaxy S24 Plus in hand outside]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>