<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
>
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <title><![CDATA[ Android Central RSS Feed ]]></title>
                <link>https://www.androidcentral.com</link>
         <description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
                                    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 21:03:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                            <language>en</language>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Snapdragon 7 Gen 3 powered OnePlus Nord CE4 gets a launch date of April 1 ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-2">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>OnePlus has a new mid-range smartphone up its sleeve for April 1, 2024.</li><li>Dubbed OnePlus Nord CE4, it will be powered by Snapdragon 7 Gen 3.</li><li>It will be available in two colorways; more details will be unveiled in the coming days.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>OnePlus is gearing up for a new mid-range smartphone and has chosen April Fool&apos;s Day to unveil it, at least in India.</p><p>The OnePlus Nord CE 4 is coming on April 1 in the Indian market. The OnePlus has already <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.oneplus.in/launch/nord-ce4-5g#subscribeLuckPrize::subscribe">listed the device</a> on its website, showcasing what to expect, including its design and the chipset it is packing underneath.</p>
<div class="see-more see-more--clipped"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet hawk-ignore" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Fast and Smooth operator, for gaming, scrolling multitasking and everything in between! #OnePlusNordCE4, with Qualcomm Snapdragon 7 Gen 3. pic.twitter.com/zF52ruKR06<a href="https://twitter.com/OnePlus_IN/status/1767143433557213442">March 11, 2024</a></p></blockquote><div class="see-more__filter"></div><div class="see-more__button-container"><span class="see-more__button" role="button" tabindex="0" aria-label="See more">See more</span></div></div>
<p>The upcoming Nord CE 4 will succeed <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/oneplus-nord-ce-5g-review">Nord CE 3</a> from last year and will be powered by Qualcomm&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phone/snapdragon-7-gen-3-launch">Snapdragon 7 Gen 3</a>. It was launched back in November with the goodness of AI aimed at <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-cheap-android-phones">mid-range Android phones</a>. The <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/vivo-v30-series-announcement">Vivo V30</a> from early this month was the first smartphone to feature the latest mid-range chipset, a 4nm chipset with clock speeds of up to 2.63GHz. </p><p>OnePlus promises smooth operations for gaming, scrolling, multitasking, and everything in between. </p><p>On the design front, the device will likely come in two color variants: a traditional black colorway and another green shade with some kind of textured finish. A triple-camera system is seen on the rear. Unlike the previous <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-oneplus-phones">OnePlus phones</a>, the company seems to be opting for a new camera placement that is similar to that of Samsung Galaxy phones, featuring a vertical array system in a dedicated visor.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:600px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:100.00%;"><img id="nWNAEKMJC5kKz7nnSNJu9B" name="oneplus-nord-ce-4-5g-01.jpg" alt="OnePlus Nord CE 4 5G" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nWNAEKMJC5kKz7nnSNJu9B.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="600" height="600" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: OnePlus)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The mid-range Nord CE 4 is now only weeks away, and OnePlus assures us that more specs will be revealed on March 14, where we expect to see other interesting details like camera specs, battery, and more. </p><p>On the other hand, tipster <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://weibo.com/6048569942/O4vUzkFVz?refer_flag=1001030103_">Digital Chat Station</a> has shared some interesting details of the OnePlus Nord CE 4, which is said to be a revamped version of the upcoming Oppo K12. Apparently, OnePlus is likely to launch the same device, dubbed the OnePlus Ace 3V, in the Chinese region. </p><p>The tipster further notes that the device will have a flat-screen accompanied by a plastic middle frame next to a glass back cover, which explains the textured finish, as aforementioned.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-nord-ce-4-to-launch-on-april-1-2024</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ After seeing Vivo V30 with Snapdragon 7 Gen 3, we might see a second device with the same SoC from OnePlus. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">MEGhbFWVLnSa4BYUgXYbze</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uZ2wNCYW3aztae36XTarGB.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 21:01:22 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/uZ2wNCYW3aztae36XTarGB.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[OnePlus]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[OnePlus Nord CE 4 5G]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[OnePlus Nord CE 4 5G]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Future Galaxy Watches may borrow the Apple Watch squircle look — and I'm on board ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-7">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>A report claims that Samsung is "bringing back the squarish design for its Galaxy Watch."</li><li>Although it's still being considered internally and probably won't apply until the Galaxy Watch 8 or later, the site's source claims it's already a certainty.</li><li>Samsung first made square AMOLED displays for its Gear watches before switching to circular designs with the Gear S2 in 2015. </li><li>Apple also released its first smartwatch in 2015, which adopted the squircle design.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Eight years after Samsung abandoned square-shaped smartwatches for circular models with rotating bezels, the popular Android watch brand allegedly has serious plans to switch back to a square- or squircle-shaped design for future Galaxy Watches. </p><p><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.sammobile.com/news/exclusive-samsung-going-back-to-square-design-for-galaxy-watch/" target="_blank">SamMobile</a> claims to have insider information that Samsung "is looking to bring back the squarish design for its smartwatches," something it hasn&apos;t done since launching the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/samsung-gear-s-review-0">Samsung Gear S</a> in November 2014. </p><p>"We hear that the idea is enthusiastically being considered internally, and it&apos;s very much on the cards that the switch is going to happen," SamMobile writer Adnan Farooqui claims. </p><p>We can&apos;t be certain that a square Galaxy Watch is a sure thing if it&apos;s still being "considered," but the source appears quite confident. Android Central has reached out to Samsung about the rumor but has not received a response in time for publication. We will update this article when we do. </p><p>So far, we&apos;ve heard <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-7">Galaxy Watch 7 rumors</a> about a new Exynos chip and revamped software, but nothing about the design. SamMobile&apos;s newser hints that the Watch 7 may or may not get the square redesign, but given its likely August 2024 release date, we doubt that Samsung has time for a drastic redesign at this stage.</p><p>If Samsung goes this route, the 2025 Galaxy Watch 8 would be a more likely candidate for the first square Galaxy Watch.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="D4z6CS7BQUty6V3hENk6uT" name="samsung-gear-s-review-16.jpg" alt="Gear S" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/D4z6CS7BQUty6V3hENk6uT.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="0" height="0" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="caption-text">The 2-inch, curved Samsung Gear S with AMOLED display. </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Alex Dobie / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Samsung&apos;s smartwatch history began with square-shaped watches like the Galaxy Gear and Gear S. It quickly moved on to its trademark circular design with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/samsung-gear-s2-review">Gear S2</a> in 2015, and our reviewer praised Samsung at the time for "finally" designing a smartwatch that "looked like a watch." </p><p>That same year, Apple released the first Apple Watch. Since then, most <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch">Android watches</a> have shied away from squircle designs entirely, aside from budget fitness brands like Fitbit or Amazfit, which also work on iPhones. Even though Samsung did square watches first, many people will see this move as copying Apple&apos;s design.</p>
<h2 id="samsung-can-have-it-both-ways-2">Samsung can have it both ways</h2>
<p>The Android Central Slack page morphed into a battleground over this news, some saying that square designs "objectively make more sense" while others shouted "HELL NO" and bashed Samsung for returning to a design area Apple has claimed for itself.</p><p>In my case, I&apos;ve been testing the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/i-never-expected-to-love-apple-watch-ultra-2-so-much">Apple Watch Ultra 2</a> long-term over the past few months, and even though it doesn&apos;t have a stylish design, the square display layout does make it a lot easier to read notifications or type on a mini keyboard, while the UI can make full use of the display space instead of being hemmed in at the top and bottom.</p><p>On the flip side, whenever people talk about Android watches, they&apos;ll note that smaller models like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/google-pixel-watch-2-review">Pixel Watch 2</a> make Android apps too cramped but are much more comfortable to wear than larger watches like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/oneplus-watch-2-review#section-oneplus-watch-2-fitness-and-health-monitoring">OnePlus Watch 2</a>. It&apos;s always a compromise, one way or the other.</p><p>Ultimately, the square vs. circular watch debate comes down to useability vs. style. And in Samsung&apos;s case, I believe it doesn&apos;t have to choose. Instead, consumers like <em>you</em> should have the choice.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2000px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="AXFvhZ69PBmXeRzxZmrSUH" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Watch-6-and-6-Classic-QWERTY.jpeg" alt="The Samsung Galaxy Watch 6 and Galaxy Watch 6 Classic, each showing their QWERTY keyboards" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AXFvhZ69PBmXeRzxZmrSUH.jpeg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2000" height="1125" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="caption-text">QWERTY keyboards would be less hemmed in on a square display </span><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Michael Hicks / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Over the past few years, Samsung has sold a basic Galaxy Watch with a digital bezel and a pricier alternative, like the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-6-review">Galaxy Watch 6 and 6 Classic</a>. You choose between a cheaper, lighter option that looks very techy and mechanically cut and a more traditional design with its trademark rotating bezel — or a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/samsung-galaxy-watch-5-pro-review">Watch 5 Pro</a> with a better battery.</p><p>There&apos;s no reason why Samsung couldn&apos;t give the base Galaxy Watch 8 a squircle design that&apos;s not as stylish but more user-friendly, while die-hard fans of Samsung&apos;s typical look can upgrade to a Watch 8 Classic or Watch 8 Pro, depending on which Samsung offers. </p><p>We&apos;ve also heard rumors about a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/leaked-samsung-galaxy-watch-fe-could-launch-in-2024">Galaxy Watch Fan Edition</a> that&apos;ll be cheaper with older specs, and Samsung could probably hit a lower price point with an aluminum squircle watch. </p><p>If Samsung can find a squircle Galaxy Watch compromise that&apos;s pleasantly light but leaves more app display space, I think it&apos;ll prove popular with plenty of Android fans. And for the Android fans who hate the squircle look on principle, they&apos;ll still have a circular option. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/future-galaxy-watches-may-adopt-apple-watch-squircle-design</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung did square watches a decade ago, but quickly switched to prioritize a more stylish, "classic" watch look. Now, it appears Samsung may go back to squircle watches. Are you on board for useability, or do you hate the idea?  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">znx4SXi3MZFdEroEKAwwPe</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="http://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MkzTFUD6hPhxTKbs5eDpJD.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 20:07:46 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Watch]]></category>
                                            <category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ michael.hicks@futurenet.com (Michael L Hicks) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MkzTFUD6hPhxTKbs5eDpJD.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[2013 Samsung Galaxy Gear]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[2013 Samsung Galaxy Gear]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ iPhone users in the EU can use Google Maps for default navigation starting next year ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-12">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>iPhone users in the EU will be able to replace Apple Maps with their preferred navigation app starting next year.</li><li>The change is part of Apple's compliance with the EU's Digital Markets Act, and it is likely to come with iOS 18.</li><li>While Google is expected to introduce a similar feature for Google Maps and Waze in the EU, no official confirmation has been provided by the company.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Starting next year, iPhone users in the EU will have the option to replace Apple Maps as their default navigation app.</p><p>The upcoming change is part of Apple&apos;s compliance with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/what-is-digital-markets-act">EU&apos;s Digital Markets Act</a>, a set of rules that tech giants in the region—known as “gatekeepers"—must follow. These companies include Apple, Google, Amazon, Meta, Microsoft, and TikTok&apos;s owner, ByteDance.</p><p>These companies could face fines as high as 20% of their yearly global earnings for multiple violations. Europe is taking the lead globally in trying to keep the big tech companies in check. In response, the tech giants are making some adjustments, albeit not always with open arms. Apple, for example, is letting you install apps from places other than its App Store.</p><p>A few days ago, the Cupertino-based tech giant published a compliance document stating that <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/apple-user-friendly-switch-android-development">iPhone users will be able to smoothly transfer data from their current phones to Android</a>.</p><p>Additionally, you will be able to finally set your favorite navigation app as the default on your iPhone starting in March 2025, as spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5mac.com/2024/03/07/apple-planning-default-navigation-app-setting-in-ios-18-for-eu-users/" target="_blank">9to5Mac</a>.</p><p>Currently, Apple Maps is the default navigation app on iPhones. Soon, you&apos;ll have the freedom to make <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-maps">Google Maps</a> or any other navigation service your go-to default.</p><p>Google is <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-details-eu-dma-changes">expected to roll out the same feature</a> for Google Maps and Waze, at least in the EU. However, as of now, there&apos;s been no official word from the company.</p><p>Apple&apos;s change is probably arriving with iOS 18, but it looks like this update might be an EU exclusive. The DMA is also taking aim at a bunch of services, from operating systems to messaging apps.</p><p>Apple&apos;s DMA Compliance Report is a bit vague on the details. It doesn&apos;t mention whether these features are going global or staying exclusive to EU users. However, if history is any guide, many of Apple&apos;s DMA-compliant services tend to stick to the EU market.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/iphone-users-in-eu-can-set-google-maps-as-default-navigation-app</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Apple is letting iPhone users in Europe ditch Apple Maps and use Google Maps instead if they want. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">YeZ8UmeUqKi8Rz7usoBXTB</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yuBWmaqBPBVsNYRK3uPqHm.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 19:40:10 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yuBWmaqBPBVsNYRK3uPqHm.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[A view of Chicago on Google Maps running on a ThinkPhone by Motorola]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[A view of Chicago on Google Maps running on a ThinkPhone by Motorola]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Ask Jerry: Why are new phones so difficult to set up? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>Welcome to Ask Jerry, where we talk about any and all the questions you might have about the smart things in your life. I&apos;m Jerry, and I have spent the better part of my life working with tech. I have a background in engineering and R&D and have been covering Android and Google for the past 15 years. </p>
<div  class="fancy-box"><div class="fancy_box-title">Ask Jerry</div><div class="fancy_box_body"><figure class="van-image-figure "  ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' ><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.25%;"><img id="rbW6k4ZmBUAZL7mR2bMnV6" name="jerrydude-avatar.gif" caption="" alt="Android Avatar of Jerry" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rbW6k4ZmBUAZL7mR2bMnV6.gif" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="" height="" attribution="" endorsement="" class="pinterest-pin-exclude"></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Future)</span></figcaption></figure><p class="fancy-box__body-text">Ask Jerry is a column where we answer your burning Android/tech questions with the help of long-time Android Central editor Jerry Hildenbrand.</p></div></div>
<p>I&apos;m also really good at researching data about everything — that&apos;s a big part of our job here at Android Central — and I love to help people (another big part of our job!). If you have questions about your tech, I&apos;d love to talk about them. </p><p>Email me at <strong>askjerryac@gmail.com</strong>, and I&apos;ll try to get things sorted out. You can remain anonymous if you like, and we promise we&apos;re not sharing anything we don&apos;t cover here.</p><p>I look forward to hearing from you!</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="why-are-new-android-phones-so-difficult-to-set-up-2">Why are new Android phones so difficult to set up?</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4166px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.24%;"><img id="NKz2vQpNaTBD9eHe6J3N75" name="Samsung-Galaxy-S24-Plus-review-5.jpg" alt="Galaxy S24 Plus with a green background" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NKz2vQpNaTBD9eHe6J3N75.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4166" height="2343" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Derrek Lee / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Anonymous writes:</p><p><em><strong>I just got my mother a new phone and she isn&apos;t very tech savvy. She&apos;s having difficulty getting everything set up the way she is used to and it seems like basic settings are spread all over the place.</strong></em></p><p><em><strong>Why are things like this? Is there a specific reason?</strong></em></p><p><em><strong>Thanks!</strong></em></p>
<p>Hi anon! This is a great question that reminds us that not everyone is a complete Android nerd who knows exactly where to look and what to do when it comes to changing phone settings. All of us started out this way.</p><p>I&apos;ll also tell you a secret — I&apos;ve used hundreds of different <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phones</a> because of my job here and have been using Android since day one. I dread setting up a new phone because digging through settings is tedious and time-consuming. It&apos;s not just about "experience" with Android. </p>
<p>In general, having a ton of settings is a good thing. I like things a certain way, so do you, and so does your mom — there&apos;s a good chance that what we all like is different. The best way to let each of us set things up how we like is to break out everything into a setting. </p><p>The bad part of this is exactly what you mention, and hundreds of settings spread over different categories may be a necessary evil, but that doesn&apos;t change how much of a pain it can be!</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="R4VZtyTWQq2B4JGu5LSdVa" name="oneplus-12-screen-settings.jpg" alt="OnePlus 12 screen" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/R4VZtyTWQq2B4JGu5LSdVa.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>This is amplified because each manufacturer does everything differently when it comes to those settings pages. Samsung is different from Google, Google is different from Motorola, Motorola is different from OnePlus and so on. In addition, every new version of Android seems to move things around, too.</p><p>This isn&apos;t done to drive users crazy though. Each phone manufacturer thinks how they do it is the best way and want to create the best user experience possible, even when it comes to setting everything up. </p>
<p>This could be "fixed" by making settings something that phone makers can&apos;t change, only adding extras to cover specific hardware used in a phone. Nobody should want this though! Part of what makes Android great is how each phone maker can make it better, and how Google is smart enough to let it happen. </p><p>Something that could be done better, and <em>should</em> be in my opinion, is backing up all your settings through a tool offered by each phone manufacturer. When you trade in your Galaxy S21 for a new <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/can-you-really-get-a-free-galaxy-s24-during-samsungs-spring-sale-yes-but-theres-a-catch">Galaxy S24</a>, you should be able to log into your Samsung account, wait a few minutes, and have everything set up the same way it was.</p>
<p>This <em>almost</em> happens now for many Android phone brands. Some settings are saved to your Samsung or Google account, for example, so your new Galaxy phone or Pixel phone can do things automatically if you choose. Apps like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-use-samsung-smart-switch">Samsung&apos;s Smart Switch</a> make the process of <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-transfer-data-your-old-android-phone-your-new-phone">transferring your data</a> easy, even if they don&apos;t cover everything.</p><p>You&apos;ll find the option when you add your account at the beginning of the setup process, providing that you&apos;ve chosen to back up things from your old phone in the first place. If you&apos;re not doing this now, it&apos;s something you should start — funny enough, you&apos;ll find the way to start in the settings of your phone.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-get-started-with-your-new-android-phone-2">How to get started with your new Android phone</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2047px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="fgw9mqwUkd23FvbKSE3r49" name="Samsung-Smart-Switch-lifestyle.jpg" alt="Samsung Smart Switch on the Galaxy S9+ and Galaxy S10e" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fgw9mqwUkd23FvbKSE3r49.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2047" height="1151" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Andrew Martonik / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Until some company finds a way to back up <strong>everything</strong> for us, I&apos;ll tell you the best way I&apos;ve found to get everything to your (or your mom&apos;s) liking: Start at the top.</p>
<p>Set aside an hour, open the settings utility, and tap the first entry to see what&apos;s inside. If you&apos;re not sure what a change will do, it&apos;s best to skip it and be <em>especially</em> careful when it comes to your network settings. There, a good policy is the old "if it ain&apos;t broke, don&apos;t fix it" routine.</p><p>For everything else, it&apos;s pretty easy to change things to something you know you&apos;ll want, like screen timeout or <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/how-to-android-navigation-gestures">using gestures instead of buttons</a>. You might even find something you like better than how it was on your old phone!</p><p>Finally, remember, Google has the answer. If you come across something that you don&apos;t understand, just Google it. If the answer about what it is seems to be confusing, remember the original setting so you can go back or just skip it completely.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/ask-jerry-setting-up-new-phone</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Have a question about the tech in your life? If so, maybe we can get them answered! ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">7JhJEpkLGtCYMScoC4LnLS</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HrmCzNcQDgwjg2sArrBf7S.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 17:30:08 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ jerry.hildenbrand@futurenet.com (Jerry Hildenbrand) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HrmCzNcQDgwjg2sArrBf7S.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Android statues]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Android statues]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ The Galaxy A55 and A35 are official with a security feature not found on older models ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p><em>Update (March 11, 3:17 pm ET):</em> <em>This article has been updated with a statement from Samsung.</em></p>
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-17">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Samsung has officially introduced two fresh mid-range phones, the Galaxy A35 and Galaxy A55, featuring sleek designs, upgraded security, and improved cameras.</li><li>The Galaxy A35 5G shares a design with the A55 5G but opts for a plastic mid-frame instead of metal.</li><li>Both phones boast robust security with Samsung Knox Vault, a hardware-based security feature, making its debut in Samsung's mid-range lineup.</li><li>The mid-rangers feature photography tricks inspired by flagship Galaxy cameras and a display with Vision Booster for enhanced visibility outdoors.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Samsung has formally introduced two fresh mid-range phones today, namely the Galaxy A35 and Galaxy A55, rocking sleek designs, upgraded security, and improved cameras.</p><p>The Galaxy A35 5G boasts a design like the Galaxy A55 5G, but it switches up the metallic mid-frame for a plastic one. There are notable similarities between this year&apos;s Galaxy A models and the previous <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-a54-5g-review">Galaxy A54</a>.</p><p>But the game-changer is the <em>Key Island</em>, which is a <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-a15-galaxy-a25-launch">new bump on the right side of the device</a>, hosting both the power and volume buttons. Plus, for the first time in the Galaxy A55, that side rail is made of metal.</p><p>Both phones pack a serious security punch with features like Samsung&apos;s <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/what-samsung-knox">Knox Vault</a>. Samsung <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://news.samsung.com/global/samsung-galaxy-a55-5g-and-galaxy-a35-5g-awesome-innovations-and-security-engineered-for-everyone" target="_blank">says</a> it&apos;s the first time this technology makes its way into <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/cheapest-samsung-phones-you-can-buy-today">Samsung&apos;s mid-range lineup</a>. The hardware-based security powerhouse shields sensitive data on Galaxy smartphones. Premiering with the Galaxy S21 series two years ago, it&apos;s been a staple on subsequent flagship models ever since.</p><p>Samsung is also pushing the <em>Auto Blocker</em> system for the fresh Galaxy A series after it was introduced in a One UI update last fall. It&apos;s an optional system that nixes sideloading of apps and unauthorized USB access. It also scans for malware, though this capability isn&apos;t live on U.S. carrier models at the moment.</p><p>Alongside Knox Vault and <em>Auto Blocker</em>, these mid-rangers step up their game with photography tricks inspired by the flagship Galaxy cameras. Plus, there&apos;s a killer display that adapts to your surroundings with Vision Booster, making your screen pop, especially outdoors in the blazing sun.</p><p>Speaking of screens, these two devices are practically twins, sporting 6.6-inch FHD+ Super AMOLED displays with punch-hole camera cutouts. Both screens boast up to 120Hz refresh rates, but the Galaxy A55 takes it up a notch with an adaptive refresh rate.</p><p>The Galaxy A55 and Galaxy A35 also share the same 5,000mAh batteries and the added perk of 25W charging support.</p>
<h2 id="what-are-the-differences-2">What are the differences?</h2>
<p>Now, here&apos;s where they mix it up. The Galaxy A55, being the higher-end model, rocks superior cameras. We&apos;re talking a 50MP main camera, a solid 12MP ultrawide, and a 5MP macro lens. The 32MP front-facing camera also promises top-notch selfies.</p><p>Meanwhile, the Galaxy A35 has a 50MP main camera, but the supporting shooters are a tad less flashy—an 8MP ultrawide and a 5MP macro lens. And for selfies, it comes with a 13MP front-facing camera.</p><p>When it comes to memory and storage, the Galaxy A55 starts off strong with 8GB of RAM in the base model, offering either 128GB or 256GB of storage. There&apos;s a second 256GB variant that cranks up the RAM to 12GB. On the flip side, the Galaxy A35 kicks off with 6GB of RAM and 128GB of storage in its base model.</p><p>Samsung hasn&apos;t disclosed the chipsets driving the Galaxy A55 and Galaxy A35. However, a few leaks spilled the beans before the launch, suggesting an Exynos 1480 for the A55 and an Exynos 1380 for the A35.</p>
<div class="inlinegallery  inline-layout"><div class="inlinegallery-wrap" style="display:flex; flex-flow:row nowrap;"><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 1 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:66.67%;"><img id="mbkyTrZSbuFjEe5tqRqtkb" name="Galaxy-A55-5G-and-A35-5G-ice-blue.jpg" alt="Samsung Galaxy A35 and A55 in ice blue color" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/mbkyTrZSbuFjEe5tqRqtkb.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4500" height="3000" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Samsung)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 2 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:66.67%;"><img id="wWm6sAkyV9Y43WbeBJfb8X" name="Galaxy-A55-5G-and-A35-5G-lilac.jpg" alt="Samsung Galaxy A35 and A55 in lilac" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wWm6sAkyV9Y43WbeBJfb8X.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4500" height="3000" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Samsung)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 3 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:66.67%;"><img id="dDdMrtG2LaCuEsnk2G6wTZ" name="Galaxy-A55-5G-and-A35-5G-lime.jpg" alt="Samsung Galaxy A35 and A55 in lime color" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dDdMrtG2LaCuEsnk2G6wTZ.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4500" height="3000" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Samsung)</span></figcaption></figure></div><div class="inlinegallery-item" style="flex: 0 0 auto;"><span class="slidecount">Image 4 of 4</span><figure class="van-image-figure " data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4500px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:66.67%;"><img id="LDYyHysPjHUf6sPEid7NnU" name="Galaxy-A55-5G-and-A35-5G-navy-blue.jpg" alt="Samsung Galaxy A35 and A55 in navy blue" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LDYyHysPjHUf6sPEid7NnU.jpg" mos="" link="" align="" fullscreen="" width="4500" height="3000" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=""><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Samsung)</span></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>
<p>Straight out of the box, the A55 and A35 run <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/samsung-one-ui-6">One UI 6.1</a> based on <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/android-14-review">Android 14</a>. Both phones are in for the long haul, scoring four years of major Android updates and five years of security patches. While not matching the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24">Galaxy S24</a> series&apos; seven-year update promise, it&apos;s still ample time to savor all the new features coming your way.</p><p>Markets are in suspense as Samsung keeps the release date under wraps for these two. Over in Europe, the Galaxy A35 starts at €379 for the 6GB RAM and 128GB storage version, as per <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.sammobile.com/news/galaxy-a35-a55-price-release-date/" target="_blank">SamMobile</a>. Meanwhile, the Galaxy A55 starts at €479, snagging you the 8GB RAM and 128GB storage variant.</p><p>Both models come in four vibrant colors: Awesome Ice Blue, Awesome Lilac, Awesome Lime, and Awesome Navy.</p><p>Samsung has also confirmed to Android Central that the Galaxy A35 is coming to the U.S. market, although the company "will not be carrying the Galaxy A55 5G at this time."</p>
<ul><li> <strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-launches-galaxy-a55-and-a35</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Samsung's new Galaxy A55 and A35 5G got you covered for years to come with software updates. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">fb7Quk9yNZpSW5CbmWboTi</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CjjW7Tg6574xoP3rDY8p4m.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 16:27:36 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Phones]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CjjW7Tg6574xoP3rDY8p4m.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Samsung]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy A35 and A55 back panels]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy A35 and A55 back panels]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Wallet update brings tickets and boarding passes straight from Gmail ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-22">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google Wallet is adding support to directly incorporate movie tickets and boarding passes from email.</li><li>It currently supports the confirmation emails received in the Gmail app.</li><li>Other nifty features are included in the update, such as the ability to archive older passes.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Google Wallet received a new update last week that makes it much easier to store movie tickets and boarding passes on the app.</p><p>Users who usually get the confirmation email for their movie tickets and boarding passes will now automatically be added to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet">Google Wallet</a>, notes Android Developers in the accompanying <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://developers.google.com/wallet/docs/release-notes">release notes</a>. </p><p>The integration is believed to be live for a few global movie chains next to some airlines, and the search giant plans to expand this further. Needless to say, this functionality is currently functional for Gmail users on their <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phones</a>.</p>
<p>With the new release, the flight passes will now utilize the DATETIME format by default to showcase the date and time on the front of the pass when added to Google Wallet.</p><p>The latest update further has some notable improvements for the Google Wallet app. It includes an easier way to manage passes that appear in the wallet app. Users can manually archive passes, which will be moved to a new “Archived Passes” section, previously dubbed “Expired Passes.” It applies to WearOS-powered <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-smartwatch">smartwatches</a> as well. Additionally, users can still unarchive their used or expired passes to view them on their home screens.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:4080px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.23%;"><img id="MqR97nhWDLouM2SmndZgF3" name="add-card-to-google-wallet-pixel-watch.jpg" alt="Add new card to Google Wallet on Pixel Watch" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MqR97nhWDLouM2SmndZgF3.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="4080" height="2294" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The new update also fixes a minor bug that prevented the title label from appearing on the back of the respective card while it was always showcased on the front, widely known as in card view. </p><p>Furthermore, the latest release of Google Wallet in the U.S. includes a new beta feature. Users who generally store Loyalty cards in the app can now view their benefits while shopping through Google Search and Google Shopping. Users interested in utilizing the feature can join the pilot program by contacting respective support.</p><p>Lastly, Google Wallet will soon gain AppLinkData definitions for card viewing, letting users access the app or website linked to the service more easily. It further prompts you to install the app if it hasn’t already been installed on your Android device.</p>
<ul><li><strong>Phone deals: </strong><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/top-deals/cell-phone-deals/pcmcat1563302848653.c?id=pcmcat1563302848653"><u><strong>Best Buy</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.walmart.com/cp/cell-phones/1105910?povid=web_globalnav_cellphones_shop_all"><u><strong>Walmart</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/shop/all-deals/cell-phone-deals/"><u><strong>Samsung</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=cell+phone&crid=19CKV7OMEPEMF&sprefix=cell+phone%2Caps%2C222&ref=nb_sb_noss_1"><u><strong>Amazon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/"><u><strong>Verizon</strong></u></a><strong> | </strong><a href="https://www.att.com/"><u><strong>AT&T</strong></u></a></li></ul>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-wallet-gains-movie-boarding-pass-support-from-gmail</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google Wallet brings notable features to the platform every year. A new update rolling out to users is more convenient. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">CPqXRogqQxcVgsAALd6r6n</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yn9qGuZok7LNMr7ARZkrAS.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 13:10:21 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ vishnu.skar@gmail.com (Vishnu Sarangapurkar) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/yn9qGuZok7LNMr7ARZkrAS.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Google]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Google Wallet new features]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Google Wallet new features]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Pixel users can now use Ultra HDR images, 10-bit HDR video on Threads ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-27">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google announced that Ultra HDR images and 10-bit HDR video in Instagram were coming to Pixel phones as part of the March Feature Drop.</li><li>Now, Ultra HDR images and 10-bit HDR video are also available in Threads following a recent update.</li><li>Instagram has supported HDR video since last year. It added Ultra HDR support for images this year, with the Samsung Galaxy S24 series being the first to work with the feature.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Meta is on a quest to bring high-quality images and video to its social media platforms, starting with HDR video for Instagram Reels. Now, both 10-bit HDR video and Ultra HDR images are headed to the Threads app on Google Pixel phones. The move, first spotted by <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/03/08/threads-ultra-hdr-10-bit-hdr-pixel/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a>, isn&apos;t all that surprising. Meta and Google first announced that the new video standards were coming to Instagram on Pixel as part of the March Feature Drop. </p><p>Though Google <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-pixel-devices-get-march-feature-drop">released the March Feature Drop</a> in most regions last week, it is only available in the U.S. as of today, March 11. According to the company, photos and videos with "brilliant colors, brighter intensity, and higher contrast" can be uploaded to Instagram. The Instagram app can be used for both recording and uploading 10-bit HDR videos to the platform. Ultra HDR photos can only be uploaded to Instagram.</p><p>The same changes are now coming to the Threads app. It was last updated earlier this month, according to the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.instagram.barcelona&hl=en&gl=US" target="_blank">Google Play Store listing</a><a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.instagram.barcelona&hl=en&gl=US">.</a> We&apos;re seeing March 4 as the date of the most recent update, per the listing, but 9to5Google reported seeing a March 8 update. It&apos;s possible that the Threads app update might be staggered <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/threads-rolling-out-in-more-eu-countries">based on user region</a> since U.S. users can&apos;t make use of the feature until today, anyway. Either way, the official update release notes merely reference bug fixes and other improvements without any specifics. </p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="sTr4waxFLtKxdJ28QubZPR" name="Instagram-Threads-app-cover-screen-03.jpg" alt="The cover screen for the Instagram Threads social app on a Motorola Edge+ (2023)" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/sTr4waxFLtKxdJ28QubZPR.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Google announced that 10-bit HDR video and Ultra HDR images will be available on Pixel 8, Pixel 8 Pro, Pixel 7, Pixel 7 Pro, or Pixel Fold devices with the Instagram app. Those same devices can also use 10-bit HDR video and Ultra HDR images in Threads. Since Instagram and Threads are so interconnected, it makes sense for the feature to arrive on both platforms around the same time.</p><p>Neither Instagram nor Threads explicitly denote which photos and videos have been captured in either 10-bit HDR or Ultra HDR formats. However, keen-eyed users will be able to spot the difference, provided they have a phone that supports viewing HDR on Instagram or Threads.</p><p>Google isn&apos;t the first to bring HDR support on Instagram or Threads to the smartphone. Samsung did so with the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-s24">Galaxy S24 series</a> earlier this year.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/pixel-users-can-now-use-ultra-hdr-images-10-bit-hdr-video-on-threads</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Following the March feature drop, Instagram gained support for Ultra HDR images and 10-bit HDR video, and now it has support for Threads.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">GQ2cGQdaBjyZJ2f4WjePvL</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WFe6c9745ogqQJrHwGZ7pQ.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 12:50:54 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/WFe6c9745ogqQJrHwGZ7pQ.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[The cover screen for the Instagram Threads social app on a Motorola Edge+ (2023)]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[The cover screen for the Instagram Threads social app on a Motorola Edge+ (2023)]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Google Maps might finally fix device orientation accuracy on Android ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-32">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>Google is introducing the Fused Orientation Provider (FOP) in Android, which is a new location orientation API that aims to be more accurate.</li><li>The release of FOP is intended to respond to user complaints about location orientation accuracy issues in Google Maps and on Android. </li><li>Compared to the Android Rotation Vector, the FOP gives users "more consistent behavior and high performance across devices."</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>Device orientation arrows on Android can be both helpful and frustrating, depending on the situation. If accurate, they can point users in the right direction without needing to rely on street signs or landmarks. But if they&apos;re incorrect, the Android orientation arrows can lead people in the wrong direction, adding time and frustration to their journey. That&apos;s why Google is trying to improve accuracy with a new orientation API in <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-maps">Google Maps</a> and Android.</p><p>Google announced the Fused Orientation Provider (FOP) in a post on the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2024/03/introducing-fused-orientation-provider-api.html">Android Developers Blog</a> (via <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2024/03/07/android-google-maps-orientation-fop/" target="_blank">9to5Google</a>). It serves as an alternative to the Android Rotation Vector, which is currently the API that provides device orientation to Android apps. However, Google says that it got some bad feedback from developers about the Android Rotation Vector in Android. </p><p>"We’ve heard from developers that orientation is challenging to get right, with frequent user complaints when orientation is incorrect," Google said. </p><p>By comparison, the Fused Orientation Provider takes in data from the accelerometer, gyroscope, and magnetometer and "fuses" these readings together. According to Google, this will result in "more consistent behavior and high performance across devices." </p><p>Here&apos;s what else Google says about the Fused Orientation Provider in its blog post:</p>
<ul><li>Provides a unified implementation across devices: an API in Google Play services means that there is no implementation variance across different manufacturers. Algorithm updates can be rolled out quickly and independent of Android platform updates;</li><li>Directly incorporates local magnetic declination, if available;</li><li>Compensates for lower quality sensors and OEM implementations (e.g., gyro bias, sensor timing).</li></ul>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="hFR48buiix3bdGhANJNSJ6" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Z-Fold-4-google-maps-02.jpg" alt="Viewing Google Maps on the Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 4's smaller cover screen" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/hFR48buiix3bdGhANJNSJ6.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The company&apos;s acknowledgment of and compensation for lower-quality sensors is a great move. It means that whether you&apos;re using the newest Pixel phone or an older <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-android-phones">Android phone</a> from another OEM, the Fused Orientation Provider should still improve accuracy. Additionally, Google said it designed the Fused Orientation Provider to be similar to Android Rotation Vector to make it easier for developers to support their apps.</p><p>The Google Maps app for Android already supports the Fused Orientation Provider following a recent update. In the release notes, Google said it "recently added changes to better cope with magnetic disturbances, to improve the reliability of the cone," which we know was referencing the FOP.</p><p>Android users should be able to use the Fused Orientation Provider in Google Maps immediately, provided their app is up-to-date. However, aside from accuracy and reliability improvements, there aren&apos;t any user-facing changes to the orientation cone. </p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/google-maps-might-finally-fix-device-orientation-accuracy-on-android</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ Google Maps is adding a "fused orientation" API, and it might finally fix device orientation accuracy when you're trying to find your way around.  ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">y2LTTszFqxtjccJ57y8iUb</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="http://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XnAD2GQS7Cxqe4F9o4P5C6.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 12:38:58 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ bradypsnyder@gmail.com (Brady Snyder) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XnAD2GQS7Cxqe4F9o4P5C6.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Viewing Google Maps on the Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 4&#039;s smaller cover screen]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Viewing Google Maps on the Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 4&#039;s smaller cover screen]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ WhatsApp is showing you straight up if your chats are encrypted ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ 
<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know-37">What you need to know</h2>
<ul><li>WhatsApp for Android is introducing a new end-to-end encryption indicator below the contact and group names within chat screens.</li><li>The encryption indicator appears briefly in the location where "last seen" details usually appear.</li><li>The feature is currently available to a select group of beta testers, with plans to roll out to a broader audience in the coming weeks.</li></ul>
<hr>
<p>WhatsApp is trying out a new beta feature to make sure users feel confident that their chats are safe from prying eyes.</p><p>According to <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://wabetainfo.com/whatsapp-beta-for-android-2-24-6-11-whats-new/" target="_blank">WABetaInfo</a>, <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/whatsapp">WhatsApp for Android</a> is now introducing a new end-to-end encryption indicator below the contact and group name within a conversation screen. Users will spot a little message in their chat windows, signaling that end-to-end encryption is active.</p><p>Right now, this feature is available only to a select group of beta testers. However, the good news is that it&apos;s on the horizon for more users in the next few weeks, as per the report. WABetaInfo first noticed this feature back in January.</p><p>You&apos;ll catch a glimpse of the indicator right where you normally find the <em>Last seen</em> details of other users, but only for a short stint. This tweak makes it a breeze for users to spot which chats are locked up with end-to-end encryption, ensuring their messages are for their eyes only.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:355px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:211.27%;"><img id="LaT4KajfcqbfUYKQfws34P" name="whatsapp-encryption-indicator.jpg" alt="Whatsapp end to end encryption indicator in a chat screen" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LaT4KajfcqbfUYKQfws34P.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="355" height="750" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: WABetaInfo)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Once that brief moment is up, the indicator will eventually disappear to let the last-seen indicator take its place.</p><p>Currently, when you start a chat with someone on WhatsApp for the first time, you get a welcome message that says, "Messages and calls are end-to-end encrypted." That said, this message pops up only the moment you start chatting with the person.</p><p>The fresh approach of showing a little status beneath the contact name to inform you about encrypted chats is a smart move to spread the word about encryption.</p><p>WhatsApp has been providing end-to-end encryption for chats and video calls for quite some time. Furthermore, the chat app has been steadily enhancing the visibility of encryption indicators. It&apos;s worth noting that, in addition to chats and video or voice calls, even status updates on the platform are end-to-end encrypted.</p><p>This recent tweak will undoubtedly come in handy for newcomers to the Meta-owned <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/best-messaging-apps">messaging app</a>, especially those who might be unsure about its encryption standards.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/whatsapp-chats-end-to-end-encryption-labels</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ WhatsApp is trying out a new feature that lets you know instantly if your chats are encrypted. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">sH4qXLtDaNCR44P2oPk63B</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TvZiRZSruCSJMJF38W3JoS.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 09:40:06 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Apps &amp; Software]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ techkritiko@gmail.com (Jay Bonggolto) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TvZiRZSruCSJMJF38W3JoS.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Jay Bonggolto / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[WhatsApp logo on an Android phone]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[WhatsApp logo on an Android phone]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
                    <item>
                                                            <title><![CDATA[ Would you rather play Doom on smart glasses or a lawn mower? ]]></title>
                                                                                                                <dc:content><![CDATA[ <p>When I was planning my first trip to MWC Barcelona this year, I waded through the massive number of emails about AI, connected devices, and just about every other buzzword lighting up the industry today. But one email immediately stood out among the rest: Doom on a lawnmower.</p><p>Husqvarna engineers contrived a brilliant PR move to garner more attention to the company&apos;s line of robot lawnmowers by creating something effectively useless. There&apos;s little hope you&apos;ll ever <em>actually</em> play Doom on your Husqvarna Automower NERA, but why wouldn&apos;t you at least want to try?</p><p>Folks in several EMEA countries who own a Husqvarna Automower NERA can <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.husqvarna.com/uk/learn-and-discover/news-and-media/doom-husqvarna-update/">sign up for the Doom beta</a> and get those mowers revving in April when the official update drops.</p><p>It was one of the <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/coolest-things-mwc-2024">coolest things we saw at MWC 2024</a> but it also begs an interesting question. As we continue to gamify chores with games like <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/my-6-year-old-son-hated-brushing-his-teeth-until-pokemon-smile-came-along">Pokemon Smile</a> to encourage us to keep doing mundane — but important — things, how far should the gamification of technology go? Do we need full-fledged games on a pair of smart glasses, or is a clever Pokemon Go-style title enough to get our legs moving after hours of sitting in a chair?</p>
<h2 id="follow-the-breadcrumb-trail-2">Follow the breadcrumb trail</h2>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="TMZEmFwaH4F9QDJfdcSB6a" name="Samsung-Galaxy-Z-Flip-4-cover-screen-pokemon-go.jpg" alt="Playing Pokemon Go on the cover display of the Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 4" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TMZEmFwaH4F9QDJfdcSB6a.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Husqvarna&apos;s marketing trick may just have worked if the company&apos;s YouTube channel is any indication. Most of the videos on its channel have a few hundred views at best and generally focus on the technology behind how the mower works and how it can improve your life.</p><p>However, the Husqvarna x Doom project video has over 46,000 views, which is 2,000 more than the number of subscribers on the channel. If the goal was to make people aware of a product rather than <em>sell</em> a certain feature, it&apos;s clear that this strategy might work.</p><p>I recently spoke with Bobak Tavangar, CEO of Brilliant Labs and creator behind <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/wearables/brilliant-labs-frame-smart-glasses-announcement">Brilliant Labs Frame</a>, a new pair of smart glasses shipping in April that promises to meld AI with svelte, wearable frames. The company&apos;s vision is grandiose but, ultimately, still somewhat limited by what current technology can deliver.</p><p>Tavangar described the company&apos;s ultimate vision of how the Brilliant Labs AI bot, Noa, can help you stay on your diet plan by identifying foods the camera sees and gently steering you toward your goals. This is just one of many examples used by Tavangar in our discussion for the company to make glasses powered by a personalized, proactive personal AI assistant.</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="NXeCLAE4ie94Q6EKufvgsR" name="OPPO-Air-Glass-3-wearing-lenses-01.jpg" alt="Hands-on with Oppo Air Glass 3 at MWC 2024 in Barcelona" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NXeCLAE4ie94Q6EKufvgsR.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>But that sort of vision would likely only impress some people before they moved on with their normal lives, never investing in the future potential of this product. That is if it weren&apos;t for one thing: the ability to play games like Doom without craning their necks down at a phone.</p><p>Admittedly, Doom (1993) only has so much appeal to non-gamers, and even then, its appeal among regular gamers is only so great. The classic title paved the way for games people love to play in 2024 but the game itself is a small seed to help people understand the potential of the gadgets we take for granted in our lives.</p><p>If a pair of glasses — like the Oppo Air Glass 3 that I wore at MWC 2024 (pictured above) or the upcoming Brilliant Labs Frame — can play games right in front of our eyes by just tapping into the power of the phone in our pocket, imagine how much more these types of products could do when fully realized?</p>
<figure class="van-image-figure  inline-layout" data-bordeaux-image-check ><div class='image-full-width-wrapper'><div class='image-widthsetter' style="max-width:2048px;"><p class="vanilla-image-block" style="padding-top:56.35%;"><img id="ZtDGRTiCvnQqdpQ8dSWmZA" name="Ray-Ban-Stories-2023-02.jpg" alt="Ray-Ban Meta Smart Glasses Wayfarer style with yellow tinted lenses" src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZtDGRTiCvnQqdpQ8dSWmZA.jpg" mos="" align="middle" fullscreen="" width="2048" height="1154" attribution="" endorsement="" class=""></p></div></div><figcaption itemprop="caption description" class=" inline-layout"><span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Brilliant Labs&apos; declared implementation of AI on a pair of smart glasses isn&apos;t "new," per se, but it certainly sounds better than what I&apos;ve used in the past. After all, Meta Ray-Ban smart glasses <a data-analytics-id="inline-link" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/meta-ray-ban-smart-glasses-ai-update">can already do many of these things</a> in some capacity. So what&apos;s stopping another company — especially a start-up with a focused vision and a small, malleable team — from making something even better than what we hoped for?</p><p>I won&apos;t hold my breath for a personalized AI to guide me along my dietary goals in 2024, but I&apos;m certainly hoping I get to play Doom on these frames when they plan to land in a month.</p><p>For me, it&apos;s the gamification of technology that ultimately gets me interested. If I&apos;m wearing a pair of smart glasses throughout the day, I want them to encourage me to do mundane things in a fun new way, even if that just means spinning Poke Stops while I&apos;m walking around the neighborhood.</p>
 ]]></dc:content>
                                                                                                                                            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/doom-husqvarna-lawnmower-brilliant-labs-smart-glasses</link>
                                                                            <description>
                            <![CDATA[ People like me have long had a fascination with getting the classic 1993 PC game Doom running on anything with a screen, and two new devices have reignited my passion for this odd project. ]]>
                                                                                                            </description>
                                                                                                                                <guid isPermaLink="false">xbbtKPKHYt3g78uK22EPWd</guid>
                                                                                                <enclosure url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZFpPhK7PboBuq5yJwhLBXo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="0"></enclosure>
                                                                        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 06:00:59 +0000</pubDate>                                                                            <category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
                                                                        <author><![CDATA[ nicholas.sutrich@futurenet.com (Nicholas Sutrich) ]]></author>                                                                                                                        <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ZFpPhK7PboBuq5yJwhLBXo.jpg">
                                                            <media:credit><![CDATA[Nicholas Sutrich / Android Central]]></media:credit>
                                                                                        <media:text><![CDATA[Playing doom on a Husqvarna Automower NERA and Brilliant Frame smart glasses]]></media:text>
                                <media:title type="plain"><![CDATA[Playing doom on a Husqvarna Automower NERA and Brilliant Frame smart glasses]]></media:title>
                                                    </media:content>
                                                                </item>
            </channel>
</rss>