<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Raspberry Pi Foundation</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/</link>
	<description>Teach, learn and make with Raspberry Pi</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 08:53:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/06/cropped-raspberrry_pi_logo-100x100.png</url>
	<title>Raspberry Pi Foundation</title>
	<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Adapting primary Computing resources for cultural responsiveness: Bringing in learners&#8217; identity</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-computing-resources-cultural-responsiveness-research-with-primary-k5-teachers/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-computing-resources-cultural-responsiveness-research-with-primary-k5-teachers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katharine Childs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 10:12:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research seminar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culturally relevant teaching]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=88263</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In recent years, the emphasis on creating culturally responsive educational practices has gained significant traction in schools worldwide. This approach aims to tailor teaching and learning experiences to better reflect and respect the diverse cultural backgrounds of students, thereby enhancing their engagement and success in school. In one of our recent research studies, we collaborated&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-computing-resources-cultural-responsiveness-research-with-primary-k5-teachers/">Adapting primary Computing resources for cultural responsiveness: Bringing in learners&#8217; identity</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In recent years, the emphasis on creating culturally responsive educational practices has gained significant traction in schools worldwide. This approach aims to <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/culturally-relevant-computing-curriculum-guidelines-for-teachers/">tailor teaching and learning experiences to better reflect and respect the diverse cultural backgrounds of students</a>, thereby enhancing their engagement and success in school. In one of <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research/">our recent research studies</a>, we collaborated with a small group of primary school Computing teachers to adapt existing resources to be more culturally responsive to their learners.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="500" height="355" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image1-500x355.png" alt="Teachers work together to identify adaptations to Computing lessons. " class="wp-image-88271" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image1-500x355.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image1-300x213.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image1-768x545.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image1-800x567.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image1-450x319.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image1-900x638.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image1.png 1210w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">At a workshop for the study, teachers collaborated to identify adaptations to Computing lessons</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>We used a <a href="https://static.raspberrypi.org/files/curriculum/quickreads/20-Pedagogy_Summary_Cultural_Relevance_Areas_of_Opportunity_2024.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">set of ten areas of opportunity</a> to scaffold and prompt teachers to look for ways that Computing resources could be adapted, including making changes to the content or the context of lessons, and using pedagogical techniques such as collaboration and open-ended tasks. </p>



<p>Today&#8217;s blog lays out our findings about how teachers can bring students&#8217; identities into the classroom as an entry point for culturally responsive Computing teaching.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Collaborating with teachers</h2>



<p>A group of twelve primary teachers, from schools spread across England, volunteered to participate in the study. The primary objective was for our research team to collaborate with these teachers to adapt two units of work about creating digital images and vector graphics so that they better aligned with the cultural contexts of their students. The research team facilitated an <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/research-teacher-workshop-culturally-relevant-computing-lessons/">in-person, one-day workshop</a> where the teachers could discuss their experiences and work in small groups to adapt materials that they then taught in their classrooms during the following term.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A shared focus on identity</h2>



<p>As the workshop progressed, an interesting pattern emerged. Despite the diversity of schools and student populations represented by the teachers, each group independently decided to focus on the theme of identity in their adaptations. This was not a directive from the researchers, but rather a spontaneous alignment of priorities among the teachers.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image4-500x281.jpg" alt="An example slide from a culturally adapted activity to create a vector graphic emoji. " class="wp-image-88268" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image4-500x281.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image4-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image4-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image4-800x450.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image4-450x253.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image4-900x506.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image4.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">An example of an adapted Computing activity to create a vector graphic emoji.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>The focus on identity manifested in various ways. For some teachers, it involved adding diverse role models so that students could see themselves represented in computing, while for others, it meant incorporating discussions about students&#8217; own experiences into the lessons. However, the most compelling commonality across all groups was the decision to have students create a digital picture that represented something important about themselves. This digital picture could take many forms — an emoji, a digital collage, an avatar to add to a game, or even <a href="https://computingeducationresearch.org/blog-creating-culturally-relevant-resources/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">creating fantastical animals</a>. The goal of these activities was to provide students with a platform to express aspects of their identity that were significant to them whilst also practising the skills to manipulate vector graphics or digital images.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Funds of identity theory</h2>



<p>After the teachers had returned to their classrooms and taught the adapted lessons to their students, we analysed the digital pictures created by the students using <a href="https://d1wqtxts1xzle7.cloudfront.net/50416384/Funds_of_identity._A_new_concept_based_o20161119-22911-3gzfts-libre.pdf?1479562273=&amp;response-content-disposition=inline%3B+filename%3DFunds_of_Identity_A_new_concept_based_on.pdf&amp;Expires=1724153622&amp;Signature=gIu9G2gOiNBEjpbxnF6t5MbsAXt7eeIjFFIlFWhM5OaYdUKflRTfA-Du39l5vDBR8tOI8LjYUGEx-pIF9EdaE~icmCknxD3-FX7v913ROZBVxPisWvq-W96gw9MzvRx--qeyXfwDyAah7JRaKqIaq0wXtIsuD5OFgMR8lAoSTOl-GLxV6nY-cFpwCpg1BOUS36Nqg-1oI04GrsCI1EKczK3ZOofAQAl9hORQh-t8DVIHRBFiQTmUv8trPb3PtZ2eiJskwgojL-4ZH0zxth78n0cOAhzYGKktfEOLkMlg3aRG1qXRRr8sybUBGyw9~CvNqqyXAkmL37Rrxj2NqLv2sw__&amp;Key-Pair-Id=APKAJLOHF5GGSLRBV4ZA" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>funds of identity theory</strong></a>. This theory explains how our personal experiences and backgrounds shape who we are and what makes us unique and individual, and argues that our identities are not static but are continuously shaped and reshaped through interactions with the world around us. </p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img decoding="async" width="371" height="311" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image3.png" alt="Keywords for the funds of identity framework, drawing on work by Esteban-Guitart and Moll (2014) and Poole (2017)." class="wp-image-88269" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image3.png 371w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image3-298x250.png 298w" sizes="(max-width: 371px) 100vw, 371px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Funds of identity framework, drawing on work by Esteban-Guitart and Moll (2014) and Poole (2017).</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>In the context of our study, this theory argues that students bring their funds of identity into their Computing classrooms, including their cultural heritage, family traditions, languages, values, and personal interests. Through the image editing and vector graphics activities, students were able to create what the funds of identity theory refers to as <strong>identity artefacts</strong>. This allowed them to explore and highlight the various elements that hold importance in their lives, illuminating different facets of their identities. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Students’ funds of identity</h2>



<p>The use of the funds of identity theory provided a robust framework for understanding the digital artefacts created by the students. We analysed the teachers’ descriptions of the artefacts, paying close attention to how students represented their identities in their creations.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>1. Personal interests and values&nbsp;</strong></h4>



<p>One significant aspect of the analysis centered around the personal interests and values reflected in the artefacts. Some students chose to draw on their <strong>practical</strong> funds of identity and create images about hobbies that were important to them, such as drawing or playing football. Others focused on <strong>existential </strong>&nbsp;funds of identity and represented values that were central to their personalities, such as cool, chatty, or quiet.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>2. Family and community connections</strong></h4>



<p>Many students also chose to include references to their family and community in their artefacts. <strong>Social</strong> funds of identity were displayed when students featured family members in their images. Some students also drew on their <strong>institutional </strong>funds, adding references to their school, or <strong>geographical </strong>funds, by showing places such as the local area or a particular country that held special significance for them. These references highlighted the importance of familial and communal ties in shaping the students&#8217; identities.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>3. Cultural representation</strong></h4>



<p>Another common theme was the way students represented their cultural backgrounds. Some students chose to highlight their <strong>cultural</strong> funds of identity, creating images that included their heritage, including their national flag or traditional clothing. Other students incorporated <strong>ideological </strong>aspects of their identity that were important to them because of their faith, including Catholicism and Islam. This aspect of the artefacts demonstrated how students viewed their cultural heritage as an integral part of their identity.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Implications for culturally responsive Computing teaching</h2>



<p>The findings from this study have several important implications. Firstly, the spontaneous focus on identity by the teachers suggests that identity is a powerful entry point for culturally responsive Computing teaching. Secondly, the application of the funds of identity theory to the analysis of student work demonstrates the diverse cultural resources that students bring to the classroom and highlights ways to adapt Computing lessons in ways that resonate with students&#8217; lived experiences.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="297" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image2-500x297.png" alt="An example of an identity artefact made by one of the students in a culturally adapted lesson on vector graphics. " class="wp-image-88270" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image2-500x297.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image2-300x178.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image2-768x456.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image2-800x475.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image2-450x267.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image2-900x534.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image2.png 1098w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">An example of an identity artefact made by one of the students in the culturally adapted lesson on vector graphics. </figcaption></figure></div>


<p>However, we also found that teachers often had to carefully support students to illuminate their funds of identity. Sometimes students found it difficult to create images about their hobbies, particularly if they were from backgrounds with fewer social and economic opportunities. We also observed that when teachers modelled an identity artefact themselves, perhaps to show an example for students to aim for, students then sometimes copied the funds of identity revealed by the teacher rather than drawing on their own funds. These points need to be taken into consideration when using identity artefact activities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Finally, these findings relate to lessons about image editing and vector graphics that were taught to students aged 8- to 10-years old in England, and it remains to be explored how students in other countries or of different ages might reveal their funds of identity in the Computing classroom.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Moving forward with cultural responsiveness</h2>



<p>The study demonstrated that when Computing teachers are given the opportunity to collaborate and reflect on their practice, they can develop innovative ways to make their teaching more culturally responsive. The focus on identity, as seen in the creation of identity artefacts, provided students with a platform to express themselves and connect their learning to their own lives. By understanding and valuing the funds of identity that students bring to the classroom, teachers can create a more equitable and empowering educational experience for all learners.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/02/Purford-Computing-Kits-15-copy-500x333.jpg" alt="Two learners do physical computing in the primary school classroom." class="wp-image-78257" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/02/Purford-Computing-Kits-15-copy-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/02/Purford-Computing-Kits-15-copy-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/02/Purford-Computing-Kits-15-copy-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/02/Purford-Computing-Kits-15-copy-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/02/Purford-Computing-Kits-15-copy-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/02/Purford-Computing-Kits-15-copy-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/02/Purford-Computing-Kits-15-copy-900x600.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/02/Purford-Computing-Kits-15-copy.jpg 1680w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>We’ve written about this study in more detail in a <a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/3677619.3678106" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">full paper</a> and a <a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/3677619.3678120" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">poster paper</a>, which will be published at the <a href="https://www.wipsce.org/2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">WiPSCE conference</a> next week. </p>



<p>We would like to thank all the researchers who worked on this project, including our collaborations with Lynda Chinaka from the University of Roehampton, and Alex Hadwen-Bennett from King’s College London. Finally, we are grateful to Cognizant for funding this academic research, and to the cohort of primary Computing teachers for their enthusiasm, energy, and creativity, and their commitment to this project.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-computing-resources-cultural-responsiveness-research-with-primary-k5-teachers/">Adapting primary Computing resources for cultural responsiveness: Bringing in learners&#8217; identity</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-computing-resources-cultural-responsiveness-research-with-primary-k5-teachers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Experience AI at UNESCO’s Digital Learning Week</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-unescos-digital-learning-week/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-unescos-digital-learning-week/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben Garside]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 10:50:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Experience AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI literacy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=88222</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Last week, Andrew Csizmadia and I were honoured to attend UNESCO’s Digital Learning Week conference to present our free Experience AI resources and how they can help teachers demystify AI for their learners.   The conference drew a worldwide audience in-person and online to hear about the work educators and policy makers are doing to support&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-unescos-digital-learning-week/">Experience AI at UNESCO’s Digital Learning Week</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Last week, Andrew Csizmadia and I were honoured to attend <a href="https://www.unesco.org/sites/default/files/medias/fichiers/2024/09/DLW_programme_FINAL_2Sept2024_0.pdf?hub=83250">UNESCO’s Digital Learning Week</a> conference to present our free Experience AI resources and how they can help teachers demystify AI for their learners.  </p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="329" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco-500x329.jpg" alt="A group of educators at a UNESCO conference." class="wp-image-88243" style="width:632px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco-500x329.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco-300x197.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco-768x505.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco-800x526.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco-450x296.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco-900x592.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>The conference drew a worldwide audience in-person and <a href="https://webcast.unesco.org/events/2024-09-DLW/#">online</a> to hear about the work educators and policy makers are doing to support teachers&#8217; use of AI tools in their teaching and learning. Speaker after speaker reiterated that the shared goal of our work is to support learners to become critical consumers and responsible creators of AI systems.</p>



<p>In this blog, we share how our conference talk demonstrated the use of Experience AI for pursuing this globally shared goal, and how the Experience AI resources align with UNESCO&#8217;s newly launched AI competency framework for students.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Presenting the design principles behind Experience AI</h2>



<p>Our talk about <a href="https://experience-ai.org/">Experience AI</a>, our learning programme developed with Google DeepMind, focused on the research-informed approach we are taking in our resource development. Specifically, we spoke about three key design principles that we embed in the Experience AI resources:</p>



<p>Firstly, using AI and machine learning to solve problems requires learners and educators to think differently to traditional computational thinking and use a data-driven approach instead, as laid out in the research around <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/machine-learning-education-school-computational-thinking-2-0-research-seminar/">computational thinking 2.0</a>.</p>



<p>Secondly, every word we use in our teaching about AI is important to help young people form accurate mental models about how AI systems work. In particular, we focused our examples around <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ai-education-anthropomorphism/">the need to avoid anthropomorphising language when we describe AI systems</a>. Especially given that some developers produce AI systems with the aim to make them appear human-like in their design and outputs, it’s important that young people understand that <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/why-were-taking-a-problem-first-approach-to-the-development-of-ai-systems/">AI systems are in fact built and designed by humans</a>.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="283" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-5-500x283.png" alt="" class="wp-image-88234" style="width:710px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-5-500x283.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-5-300x170.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-5-768x435.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-5-1536x870.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-5-800x453.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-5-450x255.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-5-900x510.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-5.png 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>Thirdly we described how we used the <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ai-education-resources-what-to-teach-seame-framework/">SEAME framework</a> we adapted from work by Jane Waite (Raspberry Pi Foundation) and Paul Curzon (Queen Mary University, London) to categorise hundreds of AI education resources and inform the design of our Experience AI resources. The framework offers a common language for educators when assessing the content of resources, and when supporting learners to understand the different aspects of AI systems.&nbsp;</p>



<p>By presenting our design principles, we aimed to give educators, policy makers, and attendees from non-governmental organisations practical recommendations and actionable considerations for designing learning materials on AI literacy.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How Experience AI aligns with UNESCO&#8217;s new AI competency framework for students</h2>



<p>At Digital Learning Week, UNESCO launched two AI competency frameworks:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>A <a href="https://unesdoc.unesco.org/ark:/48223/pf0000391105">framework for students</a>, intended to help teachers around the world with integrating AI tools in activities to engage their learners</li>



<li>A <a href="https://unesdoc.unesco.org/search/10c7faad-c984-4e37-add4-3d455d104046">framework for teachers</a>, &#8220;defining the knowledge, skills, and values teachers must master in the age of AI&#8221;</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>AI competency framework for students</strong></p>



<p>We have had the chance to map the Experience AI resources to UNESCO’s AI framework for students at a high level, finding that the resources cover 10 of the 12 areas of the framework (see image below).</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="297" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-6-500x297.png" alt="" class="wp-image-88235" style="width:677px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-6-500x297.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-6-300x178.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-6-450x268.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-6.png 565w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">An adaptation of a summary table from UNESCO&#8217;s new student competency framework (<a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/igo/">CC-BY-SA 3.0 IGO</a>), highlighting the 10 areas covered by our Experience AI resources</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>For instance, throughout the Experience AI resources runs a thread of promoting &#8220;citizenship in the AI era&#8221;: the social and ethical aspects of AI technologies are highlighted in all the lessons and activities. In this way, they provide students with the foundational knowledge of how AI systems work, and where they may work badly. Using the resources, educators can teach their learners core AI and machine learning concepts and make these concepts concrete through practical activities where learners create their own models and critically evaluate their outputs. Importantly, by learning with Experience AI, students not only learn to be responsible users of AI tools, but also to consider fairness, accountability, transparency, and privacy when they create AI models.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Teacher competency framework for AI&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>UNESCO’s <a href="https://unesdoc.unesco.org/ark:/48223/pf0000391104">AI competency framework for teachers</a> outlines 15 competencies across 5 dimensions (see image below).&nbsp; We enjoyed listening to the launch panel members talk about the strong ambitions of the framework as well as the realities of teachers&#8217; global and local challenges. The three key messages of the panel were:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>AI will not replace the expertise of classroom teachers</li>



<li>Supporting educators to build AI competencies is a shared responsibility</li>



<li>Individual countries&#8217; education systems have different needs in terms of educator support</li>
</ul>



<p>All three messages resonate strongly with the work we&#8217;re doing at the Raspberry Pi Foundation. Supporting all educators is a fundamental part of our resource development. For example, Experience AI offers everything a teacher with no technical background needs to deliver the lessons, including lesson plans, videos, worksheets and slide decks. We also provide a free online training course on understanding AI for educators. And in <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-expands-to-reach-over-2-million-students/">our work with partner organisations around the world</a>, we <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/localising-ai-education-adapting-experience-ai-resources/">adapt and translate Experience AI resources</a> so they are culturally relevant, and we organise locally delivered teacher professional development.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="245" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-7-500x245.png" alt="" class="wp-image-88236" style="width:627px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-7-500x245.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-7-300x147.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-7-768x376.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-7-800x392.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-7-450x221.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-7-900x441.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-7.png 1306w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">A summary table from UNESCO&#8217;s new teacher competency framework (<a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/igo/">CC-BY-SA 3.0 IGO</a>)</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>&nbsp;The teachers&#8217; competency framework is meant as guidance for educators, policy makers, training providers, and application developers to support teachers in using AI effectively, and in helping their learners gain AI literacy skills. We will certainly consult the document as we develop our training and professional development resources for teachers further.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Towards AI literacy for all young people</h2>



<p>Across this year’s UNESCO’s Digital Learning Week, we saw that the role of AI in education took centre stage across the presentations and the informal conversations among attendees. It was a privilege to present our work and see how well Experience AI was received, with attendees recognising that our design principles align with the values and principles in UNESCO’s new AI competency frameworks.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="377" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco_2-500x377.jpg" alt="A conference table setup with a pair of headphones resting on top of a UNESCO brochure." class="wp-image-88245" style="width:628px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco_2-500x377.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco_2-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco_2-768x578.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco_2-1536x1157.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco_2-800x603.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco_2-450x339.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco_2-900x678.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco_2.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>We look forward to continuing this international conversation about AI literacy and working in aligned ways to support all young people to develop a foundational understanding of AI technologies.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-unescos-digital-learning-week/">Experience AI at UNESCO’s Digital Learning Week</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-unescos-digital-learning-week/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Experience AI expands to reach over 2 million students</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-expands-to-reach-over-2-million-students/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-expands-to-reach-over-2-million-students/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Philip Colligan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 11:29:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Experience AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI literacy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=88144</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Two years ago, we announced Experience AI, a collaboration between the Raspberry Pi Foundation and Google DeepMind to inspire the next generation of AI leaders. Today I am excited to announce that we are expanding the programme with the aim of reaching more than 2 million students over the next 3 years, thanks to a&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-expands-to-reach-over-2-million-students/">Experience AI expands to reach over 2 million students</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Two years ago, we <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-deepmind-ai-education/">announced</a> Experience AI, a collaboration between the Raspberry Pi Foundation and <a href="https://deepmind.google/about/?_gl=1*1dknnl3*_up*MQ..*_ga*OTM4ODUzMjYzLjE3MjM1NDAyNjA.*_ga_LS8HVHCNQ0*MTcyMzU0MDI1OS4xLjAuMTcyMzU0MDI2Mi4wLjAuMA..">Google DeepMind</a> to inspire the next generation of AI leaders.</p>



<p>Today I am excited to announce that we are expanding the programme with the aim of reaching more than 2 million students over the next 3 years, thanks to a generous grant of $10m from Google.org.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="541" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Philip-cropped-1-500x541.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-88292" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Philip-cropped-1-500x541.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Philip-cropped-1-231x250.jpg 231w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Philip-cropped-1-768x831.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Philip-cropped-1-1419x1536.jpg 1419w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Philip-cropped-1-1892x2048.jpg 1892w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Philip-cropped-1-800x866.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Philip-cropped-1-450x487.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Philip-cropped-1-900x974.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Why do kids need to learn about AI</strong></h2>



<p>AI technologies are already changing the world, and we are told that their potential impact is unprecedented in human history. But just like every other wave of technological innovation, along with all of the opportunities, the advancement of AI has the potential to leave people behind, to exacerbate divisions, and to create more problems than it solves.</p>



<p>Part of the answer to this challenge lies in ensuring that all young people develop a foundational understanding of AI technologies and the role that they can play in their lives.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="342" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/04/Experience-AI-classroom-scaled-e1681724472404-500x342.jpg" alt="An educator points to an image on a student's computer screen." class="wp-image-83703" style="width:592px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/04/Experience-AI-classroom-scaled-e1681724472404-500x342.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/04/Experience-AI-classroom-scaled-e1681724472404-300x205.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/04/Experience-AI-classroom-scaled-e1681724472404-768x526.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/04/Experience-AI-classroom-scaled-e1681724472404-1536x1051.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/04/Experience-AI-classroom-scaled-e1681724472404-800x548.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/04/Experience-AI-classroom-scaled-e1681724472404-450x308.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/04/Experience-AI-classroom-scaled-e1681724472404-900x616.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/04/Experience-AI-classroom-scaled-e1681724472404.jpg 1683w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>That&#8217;s why the conversation about AI in education is so important. A lot of the focus of that conversation is on how we harness the power of AI technologies to improve teaching and learning. Enabling young people to use AI to learn is important, but it&#8217;s not enough.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We need to equip young people with the knowledge, skills, and mindsets to use AI technologies to create the world they want. And that means supporting their teachers, who once again are being asked to teach a subject that they didn&#8217;t study.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Experience AI&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p>That&#8217;s the work that we&#8217;re doing through <a href="https://experience-ai.org/en/">Experience AI</a>, an ambitious programme to provide teachers with free classroom resources and professional development, enabling them to teach their students about AI technologies and how they are changing the world. All of our resources are grounded in research defining the concepts that make up AI literacy, they are rooted in real-world examples drawing on the work of Google DeepMind, and they involve hands-on, interactive activities.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9721_XAI_Infographic_Update_V2.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="652" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9721_XAI_Infographic_Update_V2-500x652.png" alt="" class="wp-image-88155" style="width:515px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9721_XAI_Infographic_Update_V2-500x652.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9721_XAI_Infographic_Update_V2-192x250.png 192w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9721_XAI_Infographic_Update_V2-768x1001.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9721_XAI_Infographic_Update_V2-1179x1536.png 1179w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9721_XAI_Infographic_Update_V2-1572x2048.png 1572w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9721_XAI_Infographic_Update_V2-800x1043.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9721_XAI_Infographic_Update_V2-450x586.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9721_XAI_Infographic_Update_V2-900x1173.png 900w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></a></figure></div>


<p>The Experience AI resources have already been downloaded 100,000 times across 130 countries, and we estimate that 750,000 young people have taken part in an Experience AI lesson so far.</p>



<p>In November 2023, we announced that we were building a global network of partners that we would work with to localise and translate the Experience AI resources, ensuring they are culturally relevant, and to organise locally delivered teacher professional development. We&#8217;ve made a fantastic start working with partners in Canada, India, Kenya, Malaysia, and Romania, and it&#8217;s been brilliant to see the enthusiasm and demand for AI literacy from teachers and students across the globe.</p>



<p>Thanks to an incredibly generous donation of $10m from Google.org — announced at Google.org&#8217;s first impact summit — we will shortly be welcoming new partners in 17 countries across Europe, the Middle East, and Africa, with the aim of reaching more than 2 million students in the next three years.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">New resources on AI safety</h2>



<p>Alongside the expansion of the global network of Experience AI partners, we are also launching three new resources that focus on critical issues of AI safety:&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>AI and your data</strong>: Helping young people reflect on the data they are already providing to AI applications in their lives, and on how the prevalence of AI tools might change the way they protect their data.</p>



<p><strong>Media literacy in the age of AI</strong>: Highlighting to young people the ways AI tools can be used to perpetuate misinformation, and how AI applications can help combat misleading claims.</p>



<p><strong>Using generative AI responsibly</strong>: Empowering young people to reflect on their responsibilities when using generative AI, and their expectations of developers who release AI tools.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/aisafetyimage1-500x281.png" alt="A laptop surrounded by various screens displaying images, videos, and a world map." class="wp-image-88156" style="width:593px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/aisafetyimage1-500x281.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/aisafetyimage1-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/aisafetyimage1-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/aisafetyimage1-1536x864.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/aisafetyimage1-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/aisafetyimage1-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/aisafetyimage1-900x506.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/aisafetyimage1.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Get involved</strong></h2>



<p>In many ways, this moment in the development of AI technologies reminds me of the internet in the 1990s (yes, I am that old). We all knew that it had potential, but no-one could really imagine the full scale of what would follow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We failed to rise to the educational challenge of that moment and are still living with the consequences of that failure: a dire shortage of talent; a tech sector that doesn&#8217;t represent all communities and voices; and young people and communities who are still missing out on economic opportunities and unable to use technology to solve the problems that matter to them.</p>



<p>We have an opportunity to do a better job this time. If you&#8217;re interested in getting involved, we&#8217;d love to hear from you.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-1 wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://form.raspberrypi.org/4873612">Contact us</a></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-expands-to-reach-over-2-million-students/">Experience AI expands to reach over 2 million students</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-expands-to-reach-over-2-million-students/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Join the UK Bebras Challenge 2024</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/uk-bebras-challenge-2024/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/uk-bebras-challenge-2024/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Csizmadia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 10:19:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bebras]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computational thinking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UK Bebras Computational Thinking Challenge]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=88087</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The UK Bebras Challenge, the nation&#8217;s largest computing competition, is back and open for entries from schools. This year’s challenge will be open for entries from 4–15 November. Last year, over 400,000 students from across the UK took part. Read on to learn how your school can get involved. What is UK Bebras? UK Bebras&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/uk-bebras-challenge-2024/">Join the UK Bebras Challenge 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9638_Bebras_2024_Assets_V3_4_B-500x281.png" alt="" class="wp-image-88219" style="width:614px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9638_Bebras_2024_Assets_V3_4_B-500x281.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9638_Bebras_2024_Assets_V3_4_B-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9638_Bebras_2024_Assets_V3_4_B-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9638_Bebras_2024_Assets_V3_4_B-1536x864.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9638_Bebras_2024_Assets_V3_4_B-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9638_Bebras_2024_Assets_V3_4_B-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9638_Bebras_2024_Assets_V3_4_B-900x506.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9638_Bebras_2024_Assets_V3_4_B.png 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>The <a href="https://www.bebras.uk/index.php?action=welcome">UK Bebras Challenge</a>, the nation&#8217;s largest computing competition, is back and open for entries from schools. This year’s challenge will be open for entries from 4–15 November. Last year, over 400,000 students from across the UK took part. Read on to learn how your school can get involved.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-2 wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://www.bebras.uk/admin/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">I want to register my school for Bebras</a></div>
</div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What is UK Bebras?</strong></h2>



<p>UK Bebras is a free-to-enter annual competition that is designed to spark interest in computational thinking among students aged 6 to 19 by providing engaging and thought-provoking activities. The 45-minute challenge is accessible to everyone, offering age-appropriate interactive questions for students at different levels, including a tailored version for students with severe sight impairments.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The questions are designed to give every student the opportunity to showcase their potential, whether they excel in maths or computing, or not. With self-marking questions and no programming required, it’s easy for schools to participate.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Thank you for another fantastic Bebras event! My students have really enjoyed it. This is the first year that one of my leadership team actually did the Bebras to understand what we are preparing the children for — she was very impressed!” Reference 5487</p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2016/01/widcombe-500x333.jpg" alt="A class of primary school students do coding at laptops." class="wp-image-18911" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2016/01/widcombe-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2016/01/widcombe-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2016/01/widcombe.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;I really enjoyed doing the Bebras challenge yesterday. It was the most accessible it’s ever been for me as a braillist/screen reader user.&#8221; Reference 5372</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What does a UK Bebras question look like?</strong></h2>



<p>The questions are inspired by classic computing problems but are presented in a fun, age-appropriate way. For instance, a puzzle for 6- to 8-year-olds might involve guiding a hungry tortoise along the most efficient path across a lawn, while 16- to 19-year-olds could be asked to sort members for quiz teams based on who knows who — a challenging problem relating to graph theory.</p>



<p>Here’s a question we ran in 2023 for the Castors group (ages 8 to 10). Can you solve it?&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Planting carrots</strong></p>



<p>A robotic rabbit is planting carrot seeds in these four earth mounds.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="225" height="43" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-7.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-88100" style="width:293px;height:auto"/></figure>



<p>It can respond to these commands:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table class="has-fixed-layout"><tbody><tr><td><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://lh7-qw.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXe6XQe8OIx6mGtLrZYBxodHqE-sLBjCGpcGCpK3D2AlP9dBkayuUgBRciwiWdMPE9hFVg9ERlzQmeDlcVST_FfiUObCCAZEuFixwIPXO7UXwPVGvSDISshP_F7EJYN-TmCk45Hlo3Y8NDeHCwF_MMclmoau?key=TpmqmkWyz_d1J4QC40Gf-g" width="133" height="101"><strong></strong></td><td>jump left to the next mound<strong><br></strong></td></tr><tr><td><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://lh7-qw.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXcFEXDkECY9nsqWwMkbPbt2SkA3ngByTkIlkCdXyO_wNWlsvOBiNQdgKzIa8PAiA1GubRTMHg_W_z2J_McdtO4mSYKk7cmSiacWeLhyyo8i9mW5c56TT-qpL7x6sZrB5YE2DNEZGf2WsenpC6aiDqNbJ_8?key=TpmqmkWyz_d1J4QC40Gf-g" width="133" height="102"><strong></strong></td><td><strong></strong>jump right to the next mound<br></td></tr><tr><td><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://lh7-qw.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXf6_W_qGu8srmuQWiNSS7yh096xzuFmXxO9cuhkXDCTIw6szGhs0RHZnnZyscrKujYfkU9tCNyDJcV-e2iTJQg7MzlvO6DeLjyN5MlnwLM90pIKoQrLnW-MOdrrZ3yBIIx4W_ARDyklLoJFaxuKT9pwxo1W?key=TpmqmkWyz_d1J4QC40Gf-g" width="132" height="103"><strong></strong></td><td>plant a carrot seed in the mound you are on</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>Here is a sequence of commands for the rabbit:</p>



<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://lh7-qw.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXdsWWjDCqmMltQAx81lB8IpisGRojPADijS1BZ_ylKXvypZTNgGzkCiXY3bSnFfS5CYrsrB0BVBYtL_SjNx4MknFWmZQZVohRkLzjHFXIP5x4IUftsAheOGZiyBQHqmTV35og3iR_ayu3YiRAwUNSWY0Hk1?key=TpmqmkWyz_d1J4QC40Gf-g" width="602" height="81"><br><strong><br></strong>We don&#8217;t know which mound the rabbit started on, but we do know that, when it followed this sequence, it placed each of three carrot seeds on different mounds.</p>



<p><strong>Question:</strong>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Which picture shows how the carrot seeds could have been planted by the robot following the sequence of commands?</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="103" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-7-500x103.png" alt="" class="wp-image-88096" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-7-500x103.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-7-300x62.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-7-450x93.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-7.png 740w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure>



<p><strong>Example puzzle answer</strong></p>



<p>The correct answer is: <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://lh7-qw.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXd1lKmLPIkyPrWKK-4b-nThS3bEOPLee-6fd1b2LsZdbXQ1S7vdEsAJESP0rdvFGgUd6sjekeBwe5jko6GG8thJ62aMYFLUta1NeqRDvTKGe20JfLKKigOK1WsHqtIqVpZ8N_lrJ561Oh3dPEx31Zkd4YcD?key=TpmqmkWyz_d1J4QC40Gf-g" width="253" height="40"></p>



<p>The image below shows the route the robot takes by following the instructions:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="67" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-6-500x67.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-88095" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-6-500x67.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-6-300x40.jpeg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-6-450x60.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-6.jpeg 626w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="258" height="70" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-88088"/></figure>



<p>After executing the first two commands</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="136" height="62" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-1.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-88089"/></figure>



<p>the rabbit places the seed on the mound to the far right:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="258" height="55" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-2.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-88090"/></figure>



<p>It then executes the commands</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="139" height="61" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-3.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-88091"/></figure>



<p>and lays the next seed:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="259" height="56" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-4.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-88092"/></figure>



<p>Then it jumps to the left twice and lays the last seed</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="201" height="64" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-6.png" alt="" class="wp-image-88093"/></figure>



<p>So the carrot seeds will be on the hills in the order:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="253" height="40" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-5.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-88094"/></figure>



<p>Did you get it right?</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How do I get my school involved?</strong></h2>



<p>Visit the <a href="https://www.bebras.uk/">UK Bebras website</a> for more information and to register your school. Once you’ve registered, you&#8217;ll get access to the entire UK Bebras back catalogue of questions, allowing you to create custom quizzes for your students to tackle at any time throughout the year. These quizzes are self-marking, and you can download your students&#8217; results to keep track of their progress. Schools have found these questions perfect for enrichment activities, end-of-term quizzes, lesson starters, and even full lessons to develop computational thinking skills.</p>



<p>Join for free at <a href="https://bebras.uk/admin">bebras.uk/admin</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/uk-bebras-challenge-2024/">Join the UK Bebras Challenge 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/uk-bebras-challenge-2024/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bridging the gap from Scratch to Python: Introducing &#8216;Paint with Python&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/learn-to-code-python/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/learn-to-code-python/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Marc Scott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 09:34:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Python]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding for kids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[text-based programming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=88064</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We have developed an innovative activity to support young people as they transition from visual programming languages like Scratch to text-based programming languages like Python. This activity introduces a unique interface that empowers learners to easily interact with Python while they create a customised painting app. “The kids liked the self-paced learning, it allowed them&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/learn-to-code-python/">Bridging the gap from Scratch to Python: Introducing &#8216;Paint with Python&#8217;</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We have developed an innovative activity to support young people as they transition from visual programming languages like Scratch to text-based programming languages like Python.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="375" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-2-500x375.png" alt="An illustration of a web browser window with colourful tags and labels around it." class="wp-image-88065" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-2-500x375.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-2-300x225.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-2-768x576.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-2-800x600.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-2-450x338.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-2.png 900w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>This activity introduces a unique interface that empowers learners to easily interact with Python while they create a customised painting app.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The kids liked the self-paced learning, it allowed them to work at their own rate. They liked using RGB tables to find their specific colours.” – Code Club mentor</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Why learn to code Python?</strong></h2>



<p>We&#8217;ve long been championing Python as an ideal tool for young people who want to start text-based programming. Python has simple syntax and needs very few lines of code to get started, and there is a vibrant community of supportive programmers surrounding it.</p>



<p>However, we know that starting with Python can be challenging for young people who have never done any text-based coding. They can face obstacles such as software installation issues, getting used to a new syntax, and the need for appropriate typing skills.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How &#8216;Paint with Python&#8217; helps learners get started</strong></h2>



<p>&#8216;Paint with Python&#8217; is an online educational activity that addresses many of these challenges and helps young people learn to code Python for the first time. It’s entirely web-based, requiring no software installation beyond a web browser. Instructions are displayed in a side panel, allowing learners to read and code without needing to switch tabs.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="186" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-4-500x186.png" alt="" class="wp-image-88067" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-4-500x186.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-4-300x112.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-4-768x286.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-4-1536x572.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-4-800x298.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-4-450x168.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-4-900x335.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-4.png 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>To help young people with creating their painting app, much of the initial code is pre-written behind the scenes, which enables learners to focus on experimenting with Python and observing the outcomes. They engage with the code by clicking on suggested options or, in some cases, by typing small snippets of Python. For example, they can select colours from a range of options or, as they grow more confident, type RGB values to create custom colours.</p>



<p>The activity is fully responsive for mobile and tablet devices and provides a final view of the full program on the last page, together with suggested routes to continue learning text-based programming.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>An accessible introduction to text-based programming</strong></h2>



<p>We believe this activity offers an accessible way for young learners to begin their journey with text-based programming and learning to code Python. The code they write is straightforward and the activity is designed to minimise errors. When mistakes do occur, the interface provides clear, constructive feedback, guiding learners to make corrections.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="297" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-5-500x297.png" alt="" class="wp-image-88068" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-5-500x297.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-5-300x178.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-5-768x456.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-5-1536x911.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-5-800x475.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-5-450x267.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-5-900x534.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-5.png 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>Try out &#8216;Paint with Python&#8217; at<a href="http://rpf.io/paint-with-python"> rpf.io/paint-with-python</a>. We’d love to hear your feedback! Please send any thoughts you have to uxresearch@raspberrypi.org.&nbsp;</p>



<p><em>This activity was developed with support from the Cisco Foundation. Through our funding partnership with them, we&#8217;ve been able to provide thousands of young people with the inspiration and opportunity to progress their coding skills anywhere, and on any device.</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/learn-to-code-python/">Bridging the gap from Scratch to Python: Introducing &#8216;Paint with Python&#8217;</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/learn-to-code-python/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Get ready for Moonhack 2024: Projects on climate change</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/moonhack-2024/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/moonhack-2024/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Isabel Ronaldson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 10:17:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Code Club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moonhack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding for kids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Code Club Australia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=88036</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Moonhack is a free, international coding challenge for young people run online every year by Code Club Australia, powered by our partner the Telstra Foundation. The yearly challenge is open to young people worldwide, and in 2023, over 44,500 young people registered to take part. Moonhack 2024 runs from 14 to 31 October. This year’s&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/moonhack-2024/">Get ready for Moonhack 2024: Projects on climate change</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Moonhack is a free, international coding challenge for young people run online every year by Code Club Australia, powered by our partner the Telstra Foundation. The yearly challenge is open to young people worldwide, and <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/moonhack-2023/">in 2023</a>, over 44,500 young people registered to take part.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="143" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Moonhack-2024-Logo-500x143.png" alt="A Moonhack 2024 logo." class="wp-image-88037" style="width:640px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Moonhack-2024-Logo-500x143.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Moonhack-2024-Logo-300x86.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Moonhack-2024-Logo-768x220.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Moonhack-2024-Logo-800x229.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Moonhack-2024-Logo-450x129.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Moonhack-2024-Logo-900x258.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Moonhack-2024-Logo.png 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p><a href="https://moonhack.com/">Moonhack 2024</a> runs from 14 to 31 October. This year’s theme is taken from <a href="https://www.worldspaceweek.org/">World Space Week 2024</a>: climate change. As always, the projects cater for everyone from brand-new beginners to more experienced coders. And young people have a chance to win a prize for their submitted project!</p>



<p>We caught up with Kaye North, Community and Engagement Manager at Code Club Australia, to find out more.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What to expect from Moonhack in 2024</strong></h2>



<p>For this year’s projects, Kaye told us that she collaborated with farmers, scientists, and young people from across Australia to cover diverse topics related to climate change and space. The projects will help participants learn about topics from how people who work in agriculture use climate data to increase crop yields and practise sustainable farming, to the impact of rising global temperatures on sea life populations.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="232" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Full-graphic-background-small-500x232.png" alt="An illustration depicting various elements related to the environment and sustainability." class="wp-image-88038" style="width:670px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Full-graphic-background-small-500x232.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Full-graphic-background-small-300x139.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Full-graphic-background-small-768x357.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Full-graphic-background-small-1536x714.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Full-graphic-background-small-2048x952.png 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Full-graphic-background-small-800x372.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Full-graphic-background-small-450x209.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Full-graphic-background-small-900x418.png 900w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>Kaye also hopes to help young people understand the role of satellite data related to climate change, such as the data NASA collects and shares via satellite. Satellite data on rising sea levels, called out in <a href="https://sdgs.un.org/goals/goal13">United Nations Sustainable Development Goal 13</a>, forms the basis of one of the Moonhack projects this year.</p>



<p>Moonhack participants will be able to code with Scratch, micro:bit, or Python. They can also take on a project brief where they may choose their favourite programming language and even include physical computing if they wish.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1058-500x333.jpg" alt="A computing classroom filled with learners." class="wp-image-32214" style="width:685px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1058-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1058-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1058-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1058-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1058-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1058-900x600.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1058.jpg 1132w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>All six projects will be available from 1 September when registration opens, and projects can be submitted until 30 November.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Inspiring young people to create a better future</strong></h2>



<p>Climate change is an issue that affects everyone, and for many young people it’s a source of concern. Kaye’s aim this year is to show small changes young people can make to contribute to a big, global impact.</p>



<p>&#8220;Moonhack&#8217;s question this year is &#8216;Can we create calls to action through our coding to influence others to make better choices, or even inform them of things that they didn’t know that they can share with others?'&#8221; – Kaye North, Code Club Australia</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Moonhack support for volunteers, teachers and parents</strong></h2>



<p>This year’s Moonhack includes new resources to help educators and mentors who are supporting young people to take part:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>You can access <a href="https://moonhack.com/host-an-event/">support guides</a> on the Moonhack website now</li>



<li>Once the projects go live on 1 September, Kaye will share project blogs and host online codealongs</li>



<li>You can <a href="https://www.facebook.com/codeclubaus/">connect with Code Club Australia on Facebook</a> to ask questions</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Get your young coders involved: Key info</strong></h2>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Registration for Moonhack 2024 opens on 1 September</li>



<li>The challenge runs from 14 to 31 October, and projects can be submitted until 30 November</li>



<li>Participation is free and open to any young coder worldwide, whether they are part of a Code Club or not</li>



<li>Everyone from beginners to advanced coders can participate</li>



<li>The six projects for Moonhack 2024 will be available in around 30 languages</li>
</ul>



<p>To find out more, visit the <a href="https://moonhack.com/">Moonhack website</a> and sign up to the <a href="https://mailchi.mp/d689f2c0172d/moonhack2024signup">Moonhack newsletter</a>.</p>



<p>Code Club Australia is powered by the <a href="https://www.telstra.com.au/aboutus/telstra-foundation">Telstra Foundation</a> as part of a strategic partnership with us at the Raspberry Pi Foundation.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/moonhack-2024/">Get ready for Moonhack 2024: Projects on climate change</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/moonhack-2024/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Celebrating the community: Isabel</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/celebrating-the-community-isabel/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/celebrating-the-community-isabel/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sophie Ashford]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 08:56:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[STEM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ada Computer Science]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=87997</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>One of our favourite things is sharing the stories of amazing young people, volunteers, and educators who are using their passion for technology to create positive change in the world around them. Recently, we had the pleasure of speaking with Isabel, a computer science teacher at Barton Peveril Sixth Form College in Eastleigh, England. She&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/celebrating-the-community-isabel/">Celebrating the community: Isabel</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>One of our favourite things is sharing the stories of amazing young people, volunteers, and educators who are using their passion for technology to create positive change in the world around them.</p>



<p>Recently, we had the pleasure of speaking with Isabel, a computer science teacher at Barton Peveril Sixth Form College in Eastleigh, England. She told us her fascinating journey from industry to education, along with how she is helping to make the tech space inviting to all.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">From industry to the classroom: Isabel&#8217;s journey to encourage diversity in tech</h2>



<p>Isabel&#8217;s path to working in the tech sector started with her early exposure to engineering thanks to her father&#8217;s career in telecoms.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I find this is true for a lot of female engineers my age: you will find that their dad or their uncle was an engineer. I remember that when I made the decision to study engineering, my teachers asked me if I was sure that it was something I wanted to do.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Isabel pursued a degree in engineering because she loved the technical aspects, and during her studies she found a passion for programming. She went to work as a software engineer in Hampshire, contributing to the development of 3G mobile phone technology.</p>



<p>Despite enjoying her career in tech, Isabel felt a strong pull towards teaching due to her long-standing involvement with youth groups and a desire to give back to the community.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“While I was at university in London, I took part in a scheme where we could go into local primary schools and help with their science teaching. At the time, I just thought this was my way of giving back, I hadn’t really thought of it as a career. But actually, after a while, I thought &#8216;I’m enjoying this programming, but I really liked helping the young kids as well&#8217;.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The transition wasn&#8217;t easy, as Computer Science was not widely taught in schools at the time, but Isabel persevered, teaching IT and Media to her classes as well.</p>



<p>Once Isabel settled into her teaching role, she began thinking about how she could tackle a problem she noticed in the STEM field.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Championing diversity in tech</h2>



<p>Having experienced first-hand what it was like to be the only woman in STEM spaces, Isabel&#8217;s commitment to diversity in technology is at the core of her teaching philosophy. She works hard to create an inclusive environment and a diversity of opportunities in her classroom, making sure girls feel encouraged to pursue careers in tech through exploring various enrichment activities.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/ada-event-26-500x333.jpg" alt="Two educators at a desk using their computers. " class="wp-image-88013" style="width:606px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/ada-event-26-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/ada-event-26-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/ada-event-26-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/ada-event-26-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/ada-event-26-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/ada-event-26.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>Isabel focuses on enrichment activities that bridge the gap between academic learning and real-world application. She runs various projects and competitions, ensuring a balanced representation of girls in these initiatives, and gives her students the opportunity to participate in programs like the <a href="https://www.etrust.org.uk/industrial-cadets">Industrial Cadets</a>, <a href="https://studentrobotics.org/">Student Robotics</a>, and <a href="https://online.coolestprojects.org/">Coolest Projects</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Isabel told us that she feels these opportunities provide essential soft skills that are crucial for success in any career.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The A level environment is so academic; it is heavily focused on working on your own on very abstract topics. Having worked in industry and knowing the need to collaborate, I found that really hard. So I’ve always made sure to do lots of projects with my students where we actually work with real engineers, do real-world projects. I believe strongly in teaching soft skills like team working, project management, and time management.”</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Harnessing trusted resources</strong></h2>



<p>A key resource in Isabel&#8217;s teaching toolkit is the <a href="https://adacomputerscience.org/">Ada Computer Science platform</a>. She values its reliability and the timely updates to the topics, which are crucial in a rapidly evolving subject like Computer Science.</p>



<p>She said she encourages both her students and fellow teachers, especially those who have retrained in Computer Science, to use the platform as a resource.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Ada Computer Science is amazing. We know we can rely on saying to the students ‘look on Ada, the information will be correct’ because I trust the people creating the resources. And we even found ourselves as teachers double-checking things on there. We struggle to get Computer science teachers, so actually only two of us are Computer Science teachers, and the other three are Maths teachers we have trained up. To be able to say &#8216;if you are not sure about something, look on Ada&#8217; is a really nice thing to have.”</p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/ada-event-13-500x333.jpg" alt="A large group of educators at a workshop.  " class="wp-image-88014" style="width:608px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/ada-event-13-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/ada-event-13-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/ada-event-13-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/ada-event-13-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/ada-event-13-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/ada-event-13.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The ongoing challenge and hope for the future</strong></h2>



<p>Despite her efforts, Isabel acknowledges that progress in getting more girls to pursue tech careers is slow. Many girls still view tech as an uninviting space and feel like they don’t belong when they find themselves as one of a few girls — if not the only one — in a class. But Isabel remains hopeful that continuous exposure and positive experiences can change these perceptions.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I talk to students who are often the only girl in the class and they find that really hard. So, if at GCSE they are the only girl in the class, they won’t do [the subject] at A level. So, if we leave it until A level, it is almost too late. Because of this, I try as much as I can to get as many girls as possible onto my engineering enrichment projects to show them as many opportunities in engineering as possible early on.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Her work with organisations like the UK Electronics Skills Foundation reflects her commitment to raising awareness about careers in electronics and engineering. Through her outreach and enrichment projects, Isabel educates younger students about the opportunities in these fields, hoping to inspire more girls to consider them as viable career paths.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Looking ahead</strong></h2>



<p>As new technology continues to be built, Isabel recognises the challenges in keeping up with rapid changes, especially with fields like artificial intelligence (AI). She stays updated through continuous learning and collaborating with her peers, and encourages her students to be adaptable and open to new developments. &#8220;The world of AI is both exciting and daunting,&#8221; she admits. &#8220;We need to prepare our students for a future that we can hardly predict.&#8221;</p>



<p>Isabel&#8217;s dedication to teaching, her advocacy for diversity, and her efforts to provide real-world learning opportunities make her an inspiring educator. Her commitment was recognised by the <a href="https://www.erafoundation.org/news/2023/06/13/2023-clark-prize-winners/">Era Foundation in 2023</a>: Isabel was named as one of their David Clark Prize recipients. The award recognises those who &#8220;have gone above and beyond the curriculum to inspire students and showcase real-world engineering in the classroom&#8221;.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="360" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/isabel-culmer-1-500x360.jpg" alt="A woman receives a certificate of recognition. " class="wp-image-88009" style="width:601px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/isabel-culmer-1-500x360.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/isabel-culmer-1-300x216.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/isabel-culmer-1-768x553.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/isabel-culmer-1-800x576.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/isabel-culmer-1-450x324.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/isabel-culmer-1-900x648.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/isabel-culmer-1.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>Isabel not only imparts technical knowledge — she inspires her students to believe in their potential, encouraging a new generation of diverse tech professionals.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If Isabel’s story has inspired you to encourage the next generation of young tech creators, check out the <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/teach/">free teaching and training resources</a> we provide to support your journey.</p>



<p>If you are working in Computer Science teaching for learners age 14 and up, take a look at how <a href="https://adacomputerscience.org/">Ada Computer Science</a> will support you.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/celebrating-the-community-isabel/">Celebrating the community: Isabel</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/celebrating-the-community-isabel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title> CSTA 2024: What happened in Las Vegas</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/csta-2024/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/csta-2024/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[James Robinson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 11:05:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CSTA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[North america]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=87935</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>About three weeks ago, a small team from the Raspberry Pi Foundation braved high temperatures and expensive coffees (and a scarcity of tea) to spend time with educators at the CSTA Annual Conference in Las Vegas. With thousands of attendees from across the US and beyond participating in engaging workshops, thought-provoking talks, and visiting the&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/csta-2024/"> CSTA 2024: What happened in Las Vegas</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>About three weeks ago, a small team from the Raspberry Pi Foundation braved high temperatures and expensive coffees (and a scarcity of tea) to spend time with educators at the CSTA Annual Conference in Las Vegas.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="375" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image7-500x375.png" alt="A team of 6 educators inside a conference hall. " class="wp-image-87938" style="width:727px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image7-500x375.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image7-300x225.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image7-768x576.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image7-800x600.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image7-450x338.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image7-900x675.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image7.png 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>With thousands of attendees from across the US and beyond participating in engaging workshops, thought-provoking talks, and visiting the fantastic expo hall, the CSTA conference was an excellent opportunity for us to connect with and learn from educators.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Meeting educators &amp; sharing resources</h2>



<p>Our hope for the conference week was to meet and learn from as many different educators as possible, and we weren&#8217;t disappointed. We spoke with a wide variety of teachers, school administrators, and thought leaders about the progress, successes, and challenges of delivering successful computer science (CS) programs in the US (more on this soon). We connected and reconnected with so many educators at our stand, gave away loads of stickers… and we even gave away a Raspberry Pi Pico to one lucky winner each day.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="375" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image5-500x375.png" alt="A group of educators taking a selfie at a conference. " class="wp-image-87939" style="width:699px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image5-500x375.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image5-300x225.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image5-768x576.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image5-800x600.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image5-450x338.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image5-900x675.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image5.png 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">The team with one of the winners of a Raspberry Pi Pico</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>As well as learning from hundreds of educators throughout the week, we shared some of the ways in which the Foundation supports teachers to deliver effective CS education. Our team was on hand to answer questions about our wide range of free learning materials and programs to support educators and young people alike. We focused on sharing <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our projects site</a> and all of the ways educators can use the site&#8217;s <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/paths" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">unique projects pathways</a> in their classrooms. And of course we talked to educators about <a href="https://codeclub.org/en/start-a-code-club" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Code Club</a>. It was awesome to hear from club leaders about the work their students accomplished, and many educators were eager to start a new club at their schools! </p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="282" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image6-500x282.png" alt="An educator is holding Hello World magazine. " class="wp-image-87940" style="width:740px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image6-500x282.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image6-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image6-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image6-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image6-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image6-900x507.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image6.png 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">We gave a copy of the second Big Book to all conference attendees.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Back <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/what-we-learnt-from-the-csta-2022-annual-conference/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in 2022 at the last in-person CSTA conference</a>, we had donated a copy of our first special edition of Hello World magazine, <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/issues/the-big-book-of-computing-pedagogy" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>The Big Book of Computing Pedagogy</em></a>, for every attendee. This time around, we donated copies of our follow-up special edition, <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/issues/the-big-book-of-computing-content" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>The Big Book of Computing Content</em></a>. Where the first Big Book focuses on <strong>how</strong> to teach computing, the second Big Book delves deep into <strong>what</strong> we teach as the subject of computing, laying it out in 11 content strands.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>If you weren&#8217;t able to get your hands on a copy of <em>The Big Book of Computing Content</em>, you can <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/issues/the-big-book-of-computing-content" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">download yours for free</a>. </li>



<li>If you&#8217;d like to write about your teaching for Hello World, <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/write-for-us" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">find out more and share your idea today</a>.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Our talks about teaching (with) AI</h2>



<p>One of the things that makes CSTA conferences so special is the fantastic range of talks, workshops, and other sessions running at and around the conference. We took the opportunity to share some of our work in flash talks and two full-length sessions.</p>



<p>One of the sessions was led by one of our Senior Learning Managers, Ben Garside, who gave a talk to a packed room on what we&#8217;ve learned from developing AI education resources for <a href="https://experience-ai.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Experience AI</a>. Ben shared insights we&#8217;ve gathered over the last two years and talked about the design principles behind the Experience AI resources.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="375" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image2-1-500x375.png" alt="An educator is giving a talk at a conference. " class="wp-image-87942" style="width:721px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image2-1-500x375.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image2-1-300x225.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image2-1-768x576.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image2-1-800x600.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image2-1-450x338.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image2-1-900x675.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image2-1.png 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Ben discussed AI education with attendees.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Being in the room for Ben&#8217;s talk, I was struck by two key takeaways:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li>The issue of anthropomorphism, that is, projecting human-like characteristics onto artificial intelligence systems and other machines. This presents several risks and obstacles for young people trying to understand AI technology. In our teaching, we need to take care to <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/why-were-taking-a-problem-first-approach-to-the-development-of-ai-systems/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">avoid anthropomorphizing AI systems</a>, and to help young people shift false conceptions they might bring into the classroom.</li>



<li>Teaching about AI requires fostering a shift in thinking. When we teach traditional programming, we show learners that this is a rules-based, deterministic approach; meanwhile, AI systems based on machine learning are <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/machine-learning-education-school-computational-thinking-2-0-research-seminar/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">driven by data and statistical patterns</a>. These two approaches and their outcomes are distinct (but often combined), and we need to help learners develop their understanding of the significant differences.</li>
</ol>



<p>Our second session was led by Diane Dowling, another Senior Learning Manager at the Foundation. She shared some of the development work behind <a href="https://adacomputerscience.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ada Computer Science</a>, our free platform providing educators and learners with a vast set of questions and content to help understand CS.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="376" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-1-500x376.png" alt="An educator is presenting at a conference." class="wp-image-87943" style="width:739px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-1-500x376.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-1-300x225.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-1-450x339.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-1.png 720w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Diane presented our trial with using LLM-based automated feedback.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Recently, we&#8217;ve been experimenting with <a href="https://adacomputerscience.org/pages/20240717_development_diary?examBoard=ada&amp;stage=all" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the use of a large language model</a> (LLM) on Ada to provide assessment feedback on long-form questions. This led to a great conversation between Diane and the audience about the practicalities, risks, and implications of such feature.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">More on what we learned from CSTA coming soon</h2>



<p>We had a fantastic time with the educators in Vegas and are grateful to CSTA and their sponsors for the opportunity to meet and learn from so many different people. We&#8217;ll be sharing some of what we learned from the educators we spoke to in a future blog post, so watch this space.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="375" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image1-500x375.png" alt="A group of educators standing outside a conference venue. " class="wp-image-87944" style="width:746px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image1-500x375.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image1-300x225.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image1-768x576.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image1-800x600.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image1-450x338.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image1-900x675.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image1.png 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div><p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/csta-2024/"> CSTA 2024: What happened in Las Vegas</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/csta-2024/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why we’re taking a problem-first approach to the development of AI systems</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/why-were-taking-a-problem-first-approach-to-the-development-of-ai-systems/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/why-were-taking-a-problem-first-approach-to-the-development-of-ai-systems/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben Garside]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 11:02:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Experience AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI literacy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=87923</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If you are into tech, keeping up with the latest updates can be tough, particularly when it comes to artificial intelligence (AI) and generative AI (GenAI). Sometimes I admit to feeling this way myself, however, there was one update recently that really caught my attention. OpenAI launched their latest iteration of ChatGPT, this time adding&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/why-were-taking-a-problem-first-approach-to-the-development-of-ai-systems/">Why we’re taking a problem-first approach to the development of AI systems</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>If you are into tech, keeping up with the latest updates can be tough, particularly when it comes to artificial intelligence (AI) and generative AI (GenAI). Sometimes I admit to feeling this way myself, however, there was one update recently that really caught my attention. OpenAI launched their latest iteration of ChatGPT, this time adding a female-sounding voice. Their <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DQacCB9tDaw">launch video</a> demonstrated the model supporting the presenters with a maths problem and giving advice around presentation techniques, sounding friendly and jovial along the way.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="334" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/solen-feyissa-sTq_Iuri06Q-unsplash-500x334.jpg" alt="A finger clicking on an AI app on a phone. " class="wp-image-87973" style="width:638px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/solen-feyissa-sTq_Iuri06Q-unsplash-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/solen-feyissa-sTq_Iuri06Q-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/solen-feyissa-sTq_Iuri06Q-unsplash-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/solen-feyissa-sTq_Iuri06Q-unsplash.jpg 640w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>Adding a voice to these AI models was perhaps inevitable as big tech companies try to compete for market share in this space, but it got me thinking, why would they add a voice? Why does the model have to flirt with the presenter?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Working in the field of AI, I’ve always seen AI as a really powerful problem-solving tool. But with GenAI, I often wonder what problems the creators are trying to solve and how we can help young people understand the tech.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What problem are we trying to solve with GenAI?</strong></h2>



<p>The fact is that I’m really not sure. That’s not to suggest that I think that GenAI hasn’t got its benefits — it does. I’ve seen so many great examples in education alone: teachers using large language models (LLMs) to generate ideas for lessons, to help differentiate work for students with additional needs, to create example answers to exam questions for their students to assess against the mark scheme. Educators are creative people and whilst it is cool to see so many good uses of these tools, I wonder if the developers had solving specific problems in mind while creating them, or did they simply hope that society would find a good use somewhere down the line?</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="342" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/04/Experience-AI-classroom-scaled-e1681724472404-500x342.jpg" alt="An educator points to an image on a student's computer screen." class="wp-image-83703" style="width:632px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/04/Experience-AI-classroom-scaled-e1681724472404-500x342.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/04/Experience-AI-classroom-scaled-e1681724472404-300x205.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/04/Experience-AI-classroom-scaled-e1681724472404-768x526.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/04/Experience-AI-classroom-scaled-e1681724472404-1536x1051.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/04/Experience-AI-classroom-scaled-e1681724472404-800x548.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/04/Experience-AI-classroom-scaled-e1681724472404-450x308.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/04/Experience-AI-classroom-scaled-e1681724472404-900x616.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/04/Experience-AI-classroom-scaled-e1681724472404.jpg 1683w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>Whilst there are good uses of GenAI, you don’t need to dig very deeply before you start unearthing some major problems.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Anthropomorphism</strong></h2>



<p>Anthropomorphism relates to assigning human characteristics to things that aren’t human. This is something that we all do, all of the time, without it having consequences. The problem with doing this with GenAI is that, unlike an inanimate object you’ve named (I call my vacuum cleaner Henry, for example), chatbots are designed to be human-like in their responses, so it’s easy for people to forget they’re not speaking to a human.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/AlanWarburton-SocialMedia-640x360-1-500x281.jpg" alt="A photographic rendering of a smiling face emoji seen through a refractive glass grid, overlaid with a diagram of a neural network." class="wp-image-87975" style="width:678px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/AlanWarburton-SocialMedia-640x360-1-500x281.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/AlanWarburton-SocialMedia-640x360-1-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/AlanWarburton-SocialMedia-640x360-1-450x253.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/AlanWarburton-SocialMedia-640x360-1.jpg 640w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Image by Alan Warburton / © BBC / Better Images of AI / Social Media / CC-BY 4.0</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>As feared, since <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ai-education-anthropomorphism/">my last blog post</a> on the topic, evidence has started to emerge that some young people are showing a desire to befriend these chatbots, going to them for advice and emotional support. It’s easy to see why. Here is an extract from an exchange between the presenters at the ChatGPT-4o launch and the model:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table class="has-fixed-layout"><tbody><tr><td>ChatGPT (presented with a live image of the presenter): “It looks like you’re feeling pretty happy and cheerful with a big smile and even maybe a touch of excitement. Whatever is going on? It seems like you’re in a great mood. Care to share the source of those good vibes?”<br>Presenter: “The reason I’m in a good mood is we are doing a presentation showcasing how useful and amazing you are.”<br>ChatGPT: “Oh stop it, you’re making me blush.”&nbsp;</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-500x281.png" alt="" class="wp-image-87924" style="width:688px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-500x281.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-900x506.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image.png 1279w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>The Family Online Safety Institute (FOSI) conducted a study looking at <a href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5f4dd3623430990e705ccbba/654e85135ac3a85e4e3ce83b_FOSI_GenAI%20Emerging%20Habits%2C%20Hopes%20and%20Fears_Full%20Report_Nov%202023.pdf">the emerging hopes and fears that parents and teenages have around GenAI</a>.</p>



<p>One quote from a teenager said:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Some people just want to talk to somebody. Just because it’s not a real person, doesn’t mean it can’t make a person feel — because words are powerful. At the end of the day, it can always help in an emotional and mental way.”&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The prospect of teenagers seeking solace and emotional support from a generative AI tool is a concerning development. While these AI tools can mimic human-like conversations, their outputs are based on patterns and data, not genuine empathy or understanding. The ultimate concern is that this exposes vulnerable young people to be manipulated in ways we can’t predict. Relying on AI for emotional support could lead to a sense of isolation and detachment, hindering the development of healthy coping mechanisms and interpersonal relationships.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/AlanWarburton-VirtualHuman-640x360-1-500x281.jpg" alt="A photographic rendering of a simulated middle-aged white woman against a black background, seen through a refractive glass grid and overlaid with a distorted diagram of a neural network." class="wp-image-87978" style="width:676px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/AlanWarburton-VirtualHuman-640x360-1-500x281.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/AlanWarburton-VirtualHuman-640x360-1-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/AlanWarburton-VirtualHuman-640x360-1-450x253.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/AlanWarburton-VirtualHuman-640x360-1.jpg 640w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Image by Alan Warburton / © BBC / Better Images of AI / Virtual Human / CC-BY 4.0</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Arguably worse is the recent news of the world&#8217;s first <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/11/style/miss-ai-pageant-winner-kenza-layli/index.html">AI beauty pageant</a>. The very thought of this probably elicits some kind of emotional response depending on your view of beauty pageants. There are valid concerns around misogyny and reinforcing misguided views on body norms, but it’s also important to note that the winner of “Miss AI” is being described as a lifestyle influencer. The questions we should be asking are, who are the creators trying to have influence over? What influence are they trying to gain that they couldn’t get before they created a virtual woman?&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>DeepFake tools</strong></h2>



<p>Another use of GenAI is the ability to create DeepFakes. If you’ve watched the most recent <em>Indiana Jones</em> movie, you’ll have seen the technology in play, making Harrison Ford appear as a younger version of himself. This is not in itself a bad use of GenAI technology, but the application of DeepFake technology can easily become problematic. For example, recently a teacher was arrested for creating a <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-68907895">DeepFake audio clip of the school principal making racist remarks</a>. The recording went viral before anyone realised that AI had been used to generate the audio clip.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Easy-to-use DeepFake tools are freely available and, as with many tools, they can be used inappropriately to cause damage or even break the law. One such instance is the rise in using the <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-68673390">technology for pornography</a>. This is particularly dangerous for young women, who are the more likely victims, and can cause severe and long-lasting emotional distress and harm to the individuals depicted, as well as reinforce harmful stereotypes and the objectification of women.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Why we should focus on using AI as a problem-solving tool</strong></h2>



<p>Technological developments causing unforeseen negative consequences is nothing new. A lot of our job as educators is about helping young people navigate the changing world and preparing them for their futures and education has an essential role in helping people understand AI technologies to avoid the dangers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our approach at the Raspberry Pi Foundation is not to focus purely on the threats and dangers, but to teach young people to be critical users of technologies and not passive consumers. Having an understanding of how these technologies work goes a long way towards achieving sufficient AI literacy skills to make informed choices and this is where our <a href="https://www.experience-ai.org">Experience AI</a> program comes in.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="263" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/09/8792_Exp_AI_Social_1-500x263.png" alt="An Experience AI banner." class="wp-image-84757" style="width:542px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/09/8792_Exp_AI_Social_1-500x263.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/09/8792_Exp_AI_Social_1-300x158.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/09/8792_Exp_AI_Social_1-768x404.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/09/8792_Exp_AI_Social_1-800x420.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/09/8792_Exp_AI_Social_1-450x236.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/09/8792_Exp_AI_Social_1-900x473.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/09/8792_Exp_AI_Social_1.png 1201w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>Experience AI is a set of lessons developed in collaboration with Google DeepMind and, before we wrote any lessons, our team thought long and hard about what we believe are the important principles that should underpin teaching and learning about artificial intelligence. One such principle is taking a problem-first approach and emphasising that computers are tools that help us solve problems. In the Experience AI fundamentals unit, we teach students to think about the problem they want to solve before thinking about whether or not AI is the appropriate tool to use to solve it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Taking a problem-first approach doesn’t by default avoid an AI system causing harm — there’s still the chance it will increase bias and societal inequities — but it does focus the development on the end user and the data needed to train the models. I worry that focusing on market share and opportunity rather than the problem to be solved is more likely to lead to harm.</p>



<p>Another set of principles that underpins our resources is teaching about fairness, accountability, transparency, privacy, and security (<a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2666920X23000310?via%3Dihub">Fairness, Accountability, Transparency, and Ethics (FATE) in Artificial Intelligence (AI) and higher education</a>, <a href="https://zenodo.org/records/3240529">Understanding Artificial Intelligence Ethics and Safety</a>) in relation to the development of AI systems. These principles are aimed at making sure that creators of AI models develop models ethically and responsibly. The principles also apply to consumers, as we need to get to a place in society where we expect these principles to be adhered to and consumer power means that any models that don’t, simply won’t succeed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Furthermore, once students have created their models in the Experience AI fundamentals unit, we teach them about <a href="https://modelcards.withgoogle.com/about">model cards</a>, an approach that promotes transparency about their models. Much like how nutritional information on food labels allows the consumer to make an informed choice about whether or not to buy the food, model cards give information about an AI model such as the purpose of the model, its accuracy, and known limitations such as what bias might be in the data. Students write their own model cards based on the AI solutions they have created.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What else can we do?</strong></h2>



<p>At the Raspberry Pi Foundation, we have set up an AI literacy team with the aim to embed principles around AI safety, security, and responsibility into our resources and align them with the Foundations’ mission to help young people to:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Be critical consumers of AI technology</li>



<li>Understand the limitations of AI</li>



<li>Expect fairness, accountability, transparency, privacy, and security and work toward reducing inequities caused by technology</li>



<li>See AI as a problem-solving tool that can augment human capabilities, but not replace or narrow their futures&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<p>Our call to action to educators, carers, and parents is to have conversations with your young people about GenAI. Get to know their opinions on GenAI and how they view its role in their lives, and help them to become critical thinkers when interacting with technology.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/why-were-taking-a-problem-first-approach-to-the-development-of-ai-systems/">Why we’re taking a problem-first approach to the development of AI systems</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/why-were-taking-a-problem-first-approach-to-the-development-of-ai-systems/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Celebrating Astro Pi 2024</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/celebrating-astro-pi-2024/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/celebrating-astro-pi-2024/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vicky Fisher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 10:33:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Astro Pi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Impact of our work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[astro pi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mission Space Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mission Zero]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=87886</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>About the projects Over the past few months, young people across Europe have run their computer programs&#160; on the International Space Station (ISS) as part of Astro Pi Mission Zero and Mission Space Lab. Mission Zero offers young people the chance to write a simple program that takes a reading from the colour and luminosity&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/celebrating-astro-pi-2024/">Celebrating Astro Pi 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>About the projects</strong></h2>



<p>Over the past few months, young people across Europe have run their computer programs&nbsp; on the International Space Station (ISS) as part of Astro Pi Mission Zero and Mission Space Lab.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="334" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/MZ_Code-deployment-image-Credits_-ESA_NASA-500x334.jpg" alt="Mission Zero code deployment" class="wp-image-87891" style="width:584px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/MZ_Code-deployment-image-Credits_-ESA_NASA-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/MZ_Code-deployment-image-Credits_-ESA_NASA-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/MZ_Code-deployment-image-Credits_-ESA_NASA-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/MZ_Code-deployment-image-Credits_-ESA_NASA-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/MZ_Code-deployment-image-Credits_-ESA_NASA-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/MZ_Code-deployment-image-Credits_-ESA_NASA-900x600.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/MZ_Code-deployment-image-Credits_-ESA_NASA.jpg 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Mission Zero code deployment | Credits: ESA/NASA</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Mission Zero offers young people the chance to write a simple program that takes a reading from the colour and luminosity sensor on an Astro Pi computer on board the ISS, and uses it to set the background colour in a personalised image for the astronauts to see as they go about their daily tasks. In total, 16,039 teams and 24,663 young people participated in Mission Zero this year. This was a 3% increase in teams entering compared to last year.</p>



<p>Mission Space Lab offers teams of young people the chance to run scientific experiments on board the ISS. This year, 564 teams and 2,008 young people participated in Mission Space Lab. Compared with last year, there was a 4% increase in the number of teams who managed to achieve flight status and run their code in space.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="375" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Photo_14-Mission-Zero-500x375.jpeg" alt="Two young people at a computer. " class="wp-image-87912" style="width:564px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Photo_14-Mission-Zero-500x375.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Photo_14-Mission-Zero-300x225.jpeg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Photo_14-Mission-Zero-768x576.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Photo_14-Mission-Zero-800x600.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Photo_14-Mission-Zero-450x338.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Photo_14-Mission-Zero-900x675.jpeg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Photo_14-Mission-Zero.jpeg 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>To evaluate the projects, we encouraged mentors to complete surveys once their teams had submitted their computer programs. Overall, 135 Mission Zero mentors (11% of mentors) and 56 Mission Space Lab mentors (15% of mentors) completed surveys. We also ran focus groups with mentors from both projects to understand their experiences and the impact of these projects on young people.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Impact on young people</strong></h2>



<p><strong>Understanding how technology is changing the world</strong></p>



<p>The mentors we spoke to told us how valuable Mission Zero and Mission Space Lab are because these experiences connect young people to real technology. Mentors felt that Mission Zero and Mission Space Lab bridge the gap between theoretical coding and tangible outcomes, giving young people the confidence to engage with technology.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>&#8220;Participating in Mission Space Lab offers students a great opportunity to work with the International Space Station, to see the Earth from above, to challenge them to overcome the terrestrial limits. It&#8217;s very important.&#8221; — Mission Space Lab mentor</em></p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="375" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Photo_8-Sense-Hat-500x375.jpeg" alt="A young person working on a coding project on a computer." class="wp-image-87907" style="width:566px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Photo_8-Sense-Hat-500x375.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Photo_8-Sense-Hat-300x225.jpeg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Photo_8-Sense-Hat-768x576.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Photo_8-Sense-Hat-800x600.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Photo_8-Sense-Hat-450x338.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Photo_8-Sense-Hat-900x675.jpeg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Photo_8-Sense-Hat.jpeg 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>&#8220;We want students to use their digital skills as superpowers to make the world a better place and this competition really aligns with that because regardless of your race, your ethnicity, your gender, you can write some code that actually runs in space. And if you can do that, then you can make medical tech, or you can solve the big problem that the adults of the world are still grappling with, so it&#8217;s the opening up [of] opportunities.&#8221; — Mission Zero mentor</em></p>
</blockquote>



<p>Mentors observed that the project inspired children to consider careers they previously thought were out of reach. Space exploration was no longer a far away and theoretical idea for the children, but something connected to their everyday lives and their own learning.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>&#8220;Some of the people that I was teaching this to felt like becoming an astronaut was really difficult to learn… now it&#8217;s not necessarily a distant thing to study.&#8221; — Mission Zero mentor</em></p>
</blockquote>



<p>Mentors also described how the young people gained confidence in their ability to engage with technologies. One mentor described the “self-esteem” and “pride” younger pupils gained from participation. Others talked about the confidence that came with achieving something like having their code run in space and receiving certificates proving they were &#8220;space scientists&#8221;.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Our mentors</strong></h2>



<p>None of this would be possible without the hard work and dedication of our mentors. So, as part of our evaluation, we wanted to understand how we can best support them. For Mission Space Lab, that took the form of assessing the new guidance that we published this year and that sits alongside the project. When we spoke to mentors, they told us this guide provided clear, step-by-step guidance that enabled the young people to work through the project, and the majority of survey respondents agreed: 89% rated the Mission Space Lab project guide as somewhat or very understandable. </p>



<p>We also heard from mentors about the ways they are using Mission Zero in a wider context. Some told us that their schools ran the project as part of space-themed weeks where they used Mission Zero in conversations about space exploration, the Hubble telescope, and learning the names of the stars. Others used Mission Zero across multiple subjects by designing images and holding art competitions based on the design, as well as learning about pixels and animations. </p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="413" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Photo_13-500x413.jpeg" alt="A young person at a desk using a computer. " class="wp-image-87916" style="width:493px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Photo_13-500x413.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Photo_13-300x248.jpeg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Photo_13-768x634.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Photo_13-800x660.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Photo_13-450x371.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Photo_13-900x743.jpeg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/Photo_13.jpeg 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>Additionally, it was a pleasure to hear about young people who had participated in Mission Zero in previous years gaining leadership skills by supporting other young people to complete Mission Zero this year.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Next steps</strong></h2>



<p>Thank you to all the mentors who provided constructive feedback through surveys and focus groups. We have read and considered every comment and will continue to consider how to improve the experience for mentors and young people. </p>



<p>We will publish an in-depth report with the findings of our evaluation later in the year; however, we’ve already made some changes to the programme that will be launching for the 2024/25 Astro Pi challenge and wanted to share these updates with you now.</p>



<p>Improvements for next year:</p>



<p><strong>Mission Zero</strong></p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>We’re adding a save button to Mission Zero to allow young people to work on this across multiple sessions.</li>



<li>We’re adding new code examples to the Mission Zero project guide. These have been selected from team submissions from the 2023/24 challenge.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Mission Space Lab</strong></p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>We’re creating an online testing tool for Mission Space Lab so that it will be easier for teams to test whether or not their code works. It will feature new data and images captured from the ISS in spring 2024.</li>
</ul>



<p>We hope that all the young people and mentors who participated in last year’s Astro Pi challenge enjoyed the experience and learnt a lot. With the exciting updates we’re working on for the 2024/25 Astro Pi challenge, we hope to see even more young people participate and share their creative projects next year.</p>



<p><strong>Project launch dates</strong></p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>16 September 2024: Mission Zero and Mission Space Lab launch</li>



<li>24 February 2025: Mission Space Lab submissions close</li>



<li>24 March 2025: Mission Zero submissions close</li>



<li>April – May 2025: Programs run on the International Space Station</li>



<li>June 2025: Teams receive certificates&nbsp;</li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/celebrating-astro-pi-2024/">Celebrating Astro Pi 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/celebrating-astro-pi-2024/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
