<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Raspberry Pi Foundation</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/</link>
	<description>Teach, learn and make with Raspberry Pi</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 10:26:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.8.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/06/cropped-raspberrry_pi_logo-100x100.png</url>
	<title>Raspberry Pi Foundation</title>
	<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Hello World podcast: What does AI education look like around the world?</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/hello-world-podcast-what-does-ai-education-look-like-around-the-world/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/hello-world-podcast-what-does-ai-education-look-like-around-the-world/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liz Eaton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 10:26:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Experience AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hello World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hello world podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI literacy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=91053</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In a rapidly evolving digital landscape, AI literacy is becoming as fundamental as traditional reading and writing. The latest episode of the Hello World podcast explores this crucial topic, bringing together experts from Kenya, Lithuania, and Malaysia to discuss the current state of AI literacy in their countries. Together, they shed light on the challenges&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/hello-world-podcast-what-does-ai-education-look-like-around-the-world/">Hello World podcast: What does AI education look like around the world?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In a rapidly evolving digital landscape, AI literacy is becoming as fundamental as traditional reading and writing. The <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/podcast/what-does-ai-education-look-like-around-the-world" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">latest episode of the Hello World podcast</a> explores this crucial topic, bringing together experts from Kenya, Lithuania, and Malaysia to discuss the current state of AI literacy in their countries. Together, they shed light on the challenges and immense potential of AI education globally.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/podcast/what-does-ai-education-look-like-around-the-world"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1300" height="731" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.4-Experience-AI-AI-Ed-Global-Perspectives-Title-YT-Player-1.jpg" alt="HW Podcast Thumbnail: AI education: Global perspectives " class="wp-image-91121" style="width:715px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.4-Experience-AI-AI-Ed-Global-Perspectives-Title-YT-Player-1.jpg 1300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.4-Experience-AI-AI-Ed-Global-Perspectives-Title-YT-Player-1-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.4-Experience-AI-AI-Ed-Global-Perspectives-Title-YT-Player-1-500x281.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.4-Experience-AI-AI-Ed-Global-Perspectives-Title-YT-Player-1-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.4-Experience-AI-AI-Ed-Global-Perspectives-Title-YT-Player-1-800x450.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.4-Experience-AI-AI-Ed-Global-Perspectives-Title-YT-Player-1-450x253.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.4-Experience-AI-AI-Ed-Global-Perspectives-Title-YT-Player-1-900x506.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 1300px) 100vw, 1300px" /></a></figure></div>


<p>This episode features a conversation led by Ben Garside (Raspberry Pi Foundation), with contributions from Leonida Soi (Raspberry Pi Foundation, Kenya), Aimy Lee (Penang Science Cluster, Malaysia), and Monika Katkutė-Gelžinė (Vedliai, Lithuania). All are key collaborators in the Raspberry Pi Foundation&#8217;s AI literacy programme, Experience AI.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GvVe9a54cpE" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Watch here</a></div>
</div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The digital literacy gap</strong></h2>



<p>One of the most striking takeaways from the conversation is the universal excitement surrounding AI, coupled with a significant need for foundational digital literacy. As Leonida explains:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>&#8220;There&#8217;s an excitement about AI literacy, both from the learners and the teachers&#8230; However, one thing to look into is, we still have low digital literacy. As much as we are bringing in AI, if it is not bundled up together with digital literacy, then there is also misuse.&#8221;&nbsp;</em></p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="1080" height="720" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image1.jpg" alt=" Leonida Soi, Learning Manager, Raspberry Pi Foundation" class="wp-image-91056" style="width:616px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image1.jpg 1080w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image1-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image1-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image1-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image1-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 1080px) 100vw, 1080px" /></figure></div>


<p>This highlights a crucial point: simply introducing AI tools isn&#8217;t enough. A solid understanding of digital fundamentals is essential for responsible and effective use of AI.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Different contexts, shared challenges</strong></h2>



<p>The discussion also reveals the varying approaches to AI education in different countries. Monika shares her experience in Lithuania:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>&#8220;We&#8217;ve been teaching AI for the last 5 years&#8230; I see a lot of opportunity in it, but a lot of challenges not to overburden teachers with the noise and changes.&#8221;</em></p>
</blockquote>



<p>Her insight highlights the ongoing need for teacher training and sustainable pedagogical strategies, particularly in a field that evolves so quickly.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>AI literacy beyond computer science</strong></h2>



<p>A key theme throughout the podcast is the importance of integrating AI literacy beyond traditional computer science classrooms. As Leonida emphasises:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>&#8220;It&#8217;s time that AI literacy is looked at from a broader view, not just in computing&#8230; something that cuts across all the learning areas.&#8221;</em></p>
</blockquote>



<p>This sentiment is echoed by Monika, who suggests:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>&#8220;I feel like the entire education system needs to go through an AI filter and come out of it with a bit more efficiency, with a bit more understanding, so it lives in a 21st-century AI world. And I see AI as a form of, you know, building and also as a co-worker for everyone in the future.&#8221;</em></p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="1999" height="1325" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image2.jpg" alt="Monica Katkute-Gelzine, Vedliai, Experience AI global partner, Lithuania." class="wp-image-91059" style="width:564px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image2.jpg 1999w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image2-300x199.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image2-500x331.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image2-768x509.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image2-1536x1018.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image2-800x530.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image2-450x298.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image2-900x597.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /></figure></div>


<p>The vision of AI as a &#8220;co-worker&#8221; for all, empowering young people rather than replacing them, offers a powerful perspective for future education.<br></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Addressing the digital divide</strong></h2>



<p>Equity is another critical issue, particularly in rural areas. Aimy highlights the ongoing challenge of access:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>&#8220;The digital divide is in the access to devices, as well as access to high-speed internet connections&#8230; but the other thing is also in terms of trained teachers as well.&#8221;</em></p>
</blockquote>



<p>Leonida adds that in Kenya there&#8217;s a need for unplugged activities to give students an idea of what the world is doing, so that we can start to bridge that gap.</p>



<p>These insights highlight the need for equitable access and innovative teaching methods to ensure no one is left behind.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Encouragement for educators: start small, support each other</strong></h2>



<p>For teachers who might feel overwhelmed by the prospect of teaching AI, the advice is clear and encouraging. Aimy suggests:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>&#8220;Start small, cover one topic at a time, one concept at a time. Don&#8217;t feel the need to cover everything all at the same time.&#8221; </em></p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="1000" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image3.png" alt="Aimy Lee, Penang Science Cluster, Experience AI global partner, Malaysia." class="wp-image-91061" style="width:416px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image3.png 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image3-250x250.png 250w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image3-500x500.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image3-150x150.png 150w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image3-768x768.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image3-800x800.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image3-100x100.png 100w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image3-300x300.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image3-450x450.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image3-900x900.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p><br>Leonida advocates for the power of community, suggesting a <em>&#8220;community of practice where [teachers] can share amongst each other and where they can encourage others.&#8221;</em><br><br>Building a network of support and shared resources is key as educators take their first steps into teaching AI.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Listen now</strong></h2>



<p>This episode of the Hello World podcast is a powerful reminder that AI literacy is not just a skill, but a mindset that needs to be nurtured across all subjects and communities. It also underscores that the commitment to prepare the next generation for an AI-powered world is global.</p>



<p>Listen to the full episode of the Hello World podcast to learn more about the global state of AI literacy and gain practical insights for your classroom.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/podcast/what-does-ai-education-look-like-around-the-world" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Listen to the full episode</a></div>
</div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Learn more about Experience AI</strong></h2>



<p>The Experience AI programme is a collaboration between the Raspberry Pi Foundation and Google DeepMind to help young people and educators understand and engage with artificial intelligence. Through free, classroom-ready resources, professional development for teachers, and global partnerships, the programme aims to make AI literacy accessible to all, regardless of geography or background. By supporting educators and inspiring students, Experience AI is helping to prepare the next generation to thrive in a world increasingly shaped by artificial intelligence.</p>



<p><a href="https://experience-ai.org/">Find out more about Experience AI</a> and how it can support you to bring AI literacy skills to your learners.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/hello-world-podcast-what-does-ai-education-look-like-around-the-world/">Hello World podcast: What does AI education look like around the world?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/hello-world-podcast-what-does-ai-education-look-like-around-the-world/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Creating a space for connection and code: Meet Seung Woo (Tony), Canada</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/creating-a-space-for-connection-and-code-meet-seung-woo-tony-canada/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/creating-a-space-for-connection-and-code-meet-seung-woo-tony-canada/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sophie Ashford]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 09:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Code Club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=91087</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We love hearing from members of the community and sharing the stories of amazing young people, volunteers, and educators who are using their passion for technology to create positive change in the world around them. Seung Woo, also known as Tony, is a 17-year-old student from Canada and the co-founder of his school’s Code Club,&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/creating-a-space-for-connection-and-code-meet-seung-woo-tony-canada/">Creating a space for connection and code: Meet Seung Woo (Tony), Canada</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We love hearing from members of the community and sharing the stories of amazing young people, volunteers, and educators who are using their passion for technology to create positive change in the world around them.</p>



<p>Seung Woo, also known as Tony, is a 17-year-old student from Canada and the co-founder of his school’s Code Club, alongside his teacher, Kay. A curious and driven teen with big ambitions in computer science, Tony is not only passionate about technology, but also dedicated to building a safe, welcoming space where others can learn, explore, and grow alongside him.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="800" height="600" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Image-1.jpg" alt="Tony working on a programming project using a laptop." class="wp-image-91091" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Image-1.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Image-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Image-1-500x375.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Image-1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Image-1-450x338.jpg 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>A spark of inspiration</strong></h2>



<p>Tony’s fascination with computers started early, driven by his love of video games, coding, and, perhaps most memorably, his admiration for Tony Stark, the comic-book and film character who becomes the superhero Iron Man! The idea of building something powerful from scratch stuck with him.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“My whole life, I have been curious about the inner workings of a computer and my inspiration for coding is Tony Stark or Iron Man from the Marvel Cinematic Universe!”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Tony’s early coding journey wasn’t without its challenges. Finding the right resources was difficult, and staying motivated during tough moments was often hard without a support system.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Like many others, I was independently taught, and during this time of independent learning I’d find many different roadblocks and challenges that I had to overcome alone. A big setback for me was finding the right resources in order to learn how to code. Another big obstacle for me was motivation. I would find myself losing interest in a project. I didn’t have the exterior motivation to help me push through the inevitable hardships that come with coding.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>That’s where the idea for a coding club began to take shape.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Creating a community of coders</strong></h2>



<p>Tony co-founded the Code Club at Collège Jeanne-Sauvé in December 2024 with that exact vision in mind — he wanted to provide a fun, collaborative, and welcoming environment where students of all skill levels could explore their love of technology together.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I created the coding club to help everyone on their journey of computer science, no matter their skill level, and that is exactly what it is turning out to be. Finding resources is easier than ever with a teacher and all of the amazing members.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Tony’s teacher and co-founder, Kay, shared why Code Club was the right fit for the school.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I thought Code Club was the best way to start our club for a few reasons. The amount of coding language options was varied and appealed to the different learners in our club. It was also important for us to promote our club and let our community know about the presence of a coding club in our school, and Code Club helped us do so via their online presence.”</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What makes Code Club special</strong></h2>



<p>For Tony, the secret ingredient behind his club’s success is simple: teamwork.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Without teamwork, our club wouldn&#8217;t really be a club, it would simply be an ensemble of people coding in their own little cubicles, much like a stereotypical office job, and to me, that does not sound too enjoyable. Teamwork is our little secret ingredient in problem-solving and building motivation, we embrace it by creating a safe space where everyone can speak their minds without judgement!”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Members are free to choose their own learning paths. No matter the project, the atmosphere is always filled with laughter, energy, and curiosity.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Coding should be something that is fun — not stressful like others may make it seem. Celebrating achievements, making short term goals, and problem solving with friends are all great ways that we make coding fun in our club. A second word would be teamwork. Without teamwork, our club wouldn’t really be a club.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Teamwork, he adds, transforms what could be a solitary activity into something social and deeply motivating.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Looking to the future</strong></h2>



<p>Tony hopes the club will continue to grow, bringing more students into the world of coding and helping them feel at home in it. His story is a great reminder that learning to code isn’t just about computers — it’s about building community, confidence, and creativity.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I wanted to create a space where everyone would be accepted and encouraged to learn more about coding and not be ashamed to ‘nerd out’ about this subject like I do very frequently. I’ve dreamed of creating a space that embraces this beautiful passion.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>If you’d like to explore coding, you can get started at home with <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">over 250 free projects</a>. </p>



<p>For a little more support, or if you’re open to mentoring others, you can also join a Code Club. <a href="https://codeclub.org/en/find" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Check our website to find a club near you</a> and become part of a like-minded and welcoming community.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/creating-a-space-for-connection-and-code-meet-seung-woo-tony-canada/">Creating a space for connection and code: Meet Seung Woo (Tony), Canada</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/creating-a-space-for-connection-and-code-meet-seung-woo-tony-canada/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Essential tips to integrate computer science into your lessons: Teacher tips from CSTA 2025</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teacher-tips-csta-2025-integrating-computer-science/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teacher-tips-csta-2025-integrating-computer-science/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Sayers]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 14:49:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hello World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CSTA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teacher tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CSTA2025]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=91014</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In our latest podcast miniseries, we spoke to educators live from the CSTA 2025 annual conference in Cleveland, Ohio, to hear their top tips for integrating computer science (CS) into other subjects. Hello World editor, Meg Wang and the team met teachers in the exhibit hall for real-time reflections and essential teacher tips on teaching&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teacher-tips-csta-2025-integrating-computer-science/">Essential tips to integrate computer science into your lessons: Teacher tips from CSTA 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In our latest podcast miniseries, we spoke to educators live from the CSTA 2025 annual conference in Cleveland, Ohio, to hear their top tips for integrating computer science (CS) into other subjects.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1200" height="1600" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image.jpeg" alt="Behind the scenes of Meg Wang, editor of the Hello World magazine presenting the latest episodes of the Hello World podcast, from CSTA 2025." class="wp-image-91017" style="width:403px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image.jpeg 1200w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-188x250.jpeg 188w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-500x667.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-768x1024.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-1152x1536.jpeg 1152w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-800x1067.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-450x600.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-900x1200.jpeg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></figure></div>


<p>Hello World editor, Meg Wang and the team met teachers in the exhibit hall for real-time reflections and essential teacher tips on teaching cross-curricular CS. They spoke to some amazing educators from across the United States and had a great time interacting with everyone in attendance.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Meeting teachers and hearing first-hand about their experiences, challenges, and triumphs was invaluable. It was amazing to meet Hello World writers in person, and to also meet future writers. Like I said at the conference, Hello World is for educators, by educators, so that means you! Everyone has valuable experience or useful advice to share, and we’re here to help you amplify that.” – Meg Wang, editor of the Hello World magazine</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Who features in the episode, and what are their tips?</strong></h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Lisa Wenzel, CS teacher from Maryland, USA</h3>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-qw.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXd-4xIDnUeEND7pwPV11mhoJ5TuSDSL8WLp0_k-tvwYtGk6030rtnvZCmNlwcQkQbGIax7WrcQAvUwycf20HOZTq62l-7b9ii0Q95t9Q_eessI1ZTUY7lVmXH1oYcBenGeL6h7H?key=7RhKhvZxEipxlaKP-6eDxA" alt="Lisa Wenzel, CS teacher in Maryland, USA, smiling and holding a physical copy of Hello World, issue 27." style="width:736px;height:auto"/></figure></div>


<p>Lisa&#8217;s top tip for integrating computer science into your lessons is to start with topics that you&#8217;re passionate about. If you&#8217;re not a CS teacher yourself, Lisa suggests finding a colleague who teaches the subject. She advises having a chat with them to explore how you can include CS concepts into subjects you&#8217;re particularly interested in.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;I guarantee you that they&#8217;re going to have something [&#8230;] to teach [another subject], and it&#8217;s going to involve computer science.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Through peer discussions and collaboration between educators, you’ll discover engaging ways that you can incorporate CS into your teaching. Give it a try the next time you’re chatting to a CS teacher.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Tiffany N. Jones, CS and Cybersecurity teacher in Georgia, USA</h3>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-qw.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXdnhiKOz-voQhdjuyhXwwsswUfrJXZCk-4yrptvIjZlbdy0-J-ETwByI4ujl8a2yXx5yPpOitz6GH7x1ccbbP0vZzEa8E35uemeKYKzDYs1Yvn0w5qBewD6TDpg7ytzGVD4uhOQ?key=7RhKhvZxEipxlaKP-6eDxA" alt="Tiffany N. Jones CS &amp; Cybersecurity teacher in Georgia, USA smiling showcasing her article in Hello World Issue 27." style="width:257px;height:auto"/></figure></div>


<p>Tiffany N. Jones, author of ‘Belonging in Tech’ (featured on page 82 of <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/issues/27" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hello World Issue 27</a>), shares her top tip to seamlessly integrate computer science into other subjects.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Using the example of a class studying ocean health and pollution, Tiffany shares how you can introduce students to real-world applications of computer science by exploring how sensors and microcontrollers can be used to collect environmental data.&nbsp;</p>



<p>She then suggests exploring how databases and programming languages can be used to analyse and visualise the data that the sensors and microcontrollers have recorded. This not only deepens your learner&#8217;s scientific understanding but also demonstrates how computing concepts are used in real-world industry practices.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Rick Ballew, CS and Engineering teacher in Minnesota, USA</h3>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-qw.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXfSDI8LnhX0lo4bHMS561Nu_oCpHQRpWQSm1sq5xxlvA9RbbVAUXgqG9AprjKqwQj4TGYfObiEnVsWYzTFPgUPwIk_qjVoDIgsFqC_3BGH3Ndc1-IerUCfouWR-tBBHxhYlNpfL5g?key=7RhKhvZxEipxlaKP-6eDxA" alt="Rick Ballew CS &amp; Engineering teacher in Minnesota, USA smiling holding a physical copy of Hello World issue 27" style="width:320px;height:auto"/></figure></div>


<p>Rick’s top tip for integrating CS is to first think about your favourite lesson and consider ways that you can introduce computational thinking.</p>



<p>In the podcast, Rick says:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p> “chances are, computational thinking is already a part of that lesson you&#8217;re doing. Call it out to the students, and that&#8217;s going to help them to start understanding how computer science is baked into everything we do.”&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Rick also offers a great example from his experience as a band teacher. He shares how learning to read a new piece of music is very similar to the steps involved in computational thinking.&nbsp;s</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“[You’ve] got to break it down. There&#8217;s abstraction. You&#8217;ve got to figure out the sequencing, and you create the way that you&#8217;re going to learn it. And that is all part of computational thinking.”&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>This approach shows students that CS isn&#8217;t just coding; it&#8217;s a way of thinking that can be applied across disciplines.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Listen now</strong></h2>



<p>To hear more practical teacher tips and discover what else our guest teachers had to say, <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/podcast/teacher-tips-csta-2025" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">listen to or watch the full episode here</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We hope this episode inspires you and helps you to engage your students in computing. We’d love to hear your thoughts, your feedback, and any of your own tips on how to integrate CS into other subjects. Share your advice in the comments section below.</p>



<p>We hope you enjoy the episode!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>More to listen to next week</strong></h2>



<p>Next week, we’ll be sharing an interesting conversation between Ben Garside, Senior Learning Manager (AI Literacy) at the Raspberry Pi Foundation, Leonida Soi, Learning Manager (Kenya) at the Raspberry Pi Foundation, and two of our global <a href="https://experience-ai.org/en/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Experience AI</a> partners, Monika Katkutė-Gelžinė from Vedliai in Lithuania, and Aimy Lee from Penang Science Cluster in Malaysia.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-qw.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXcLKAKrtJ25fjJT2E4r7AHOU3g52XjpM_BzF7h6bLohXv5jXqzqhpGYeYimSnoofDuwSwbY_f9HBris0uckm14poC3pi8FUuhaClS4nJoyeg6T3UyOiHIaw70s8w-rdYneqKG8z5A?key=7RhKhvZxEipxlaKP-6eDxA" alt="Selfie with the Hello World Podcast team" style="width:368px;height:auto"/></figure></div>


<p>They’ll be exploring what AI education looks like around the world and what teachers need to feel confident teaching it.</p>



<p>You can watch or listen to each episode of our podcast on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLxyaWvsfmq49s-6lJKH1sNcYAeBUizoMr" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">YouTube</a>, or listen via your preferred audio streaming service, whether that’s <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/hello-world/id1564031383" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Apple Podcasts</a>, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/1CagYUqVlkJK9zRN6yaQwG">Spotify</a>, or <a href="https://music.amazon.com/podcasts/7954c4f7-884c-4a91-90e3-1fbd3fdc4ff3/hello-world" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Amazon Music</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Subscribe to Hello World today</a> to ensure you never miss a podcast episode or issue of the magazine.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world">Subscribe</a></div>
</div>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teacher-tips-csta-2025-integrating-computer-science/">Essential tips to integrate computer science into your lessons: Teacher tips from CSTA 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teacher-tips-csta-2025-integrating-computer-science/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Giving back through Code Club: Meet Douglas</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/giving-back-through-code-club-meet-douglas/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/giving-back-through-code-club-meet-douglas/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sophie Ashford]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 10:03:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Code Club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=90978</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We love hearing from members of the community and sharing the stories of amazing young people, volunteers, and educators who are using their passion for technology to create positive change in the world around them. Growing up in Mathare, one of Nairobi’s largest informal settlements, Douglas experienced first-hand what it meant to go without access&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/giving-back-through-code-club-meet-douglas/">Giving back through Code Club: Meet Douglas</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We love hearing from members of the community and sharing the stories of amazing young people, volunteers, and educators who are using their passion for technology to create positive change in the world around them.</p>



<p>Growing up in Mathare, one of Nairobi’s largest informal settlements, Douglas experienced first-hand what it meant to go without access to education and opportunity. His experience sparked a <a href="https://codeclub.org/en/">Code Club</a> journey that is already hugely inspiring… and it’s only just getting started.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="668" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6616.jpg" alt="Douglas (second from left) with members of the Raspberry Pi Foundation team" class="wp-image-90980" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6616.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6616-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6616-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6616-768x513.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6616-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6616-450x301.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6616-900x601.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Douglas (second from left) with members of the Raspberry Pi Foundation team</figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Driven by a desire to help&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p>For Douglas and many of his peers, the limited access to education in Mathare often meant being left with no clear path to earn a livelihood. Douglas saw opportunity in technology — he wanted to increase access in this field for the young people in Mathare and raise their ambitions.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Why are we doing technology? Because we believe that tech does not have a boundary. As long as you have access to the internet and you can learn some basic skills… the opportunities are limitless.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>That belief became the keystone of Oasis Mathare, an organisation co-founded by Douglas and a group of others with similar lived experiences. Like Douglas, most of the founding members haven’t followed a standard path with formal schooling, but all understand the power of technology to transform lives.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>From Photoshop to programming</strong></h2>



<p>Douglas’ own tech journey began humbly, and was sparked by his curiosity.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“After primary, I didn’t go straight to high school. I spent two years working in a nearby barber shop. Then I think I just fell in love with computers. I learned how to do some basic stuff with design and used to play around with Photoshop.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>From there, he taught himself web design and programming skills, which began to open new doors. Eventually, he went back to university to study business and information technology to deepen his knowledge, but even before that, Douglas had already started giving back.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“We used to hold a club providing a space for kids to come and play games on computers. That sort of grew from just Saturdays to a few times a week… and now it&#8217;s full time.”</p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="668" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6548.jpg" alt="One of Oasis Mathare’s Code Clubs in action" class="wp-image-90982" style="width:720px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6548.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6548-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6548-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6548-768x513.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6548-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6548-450x301.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6548-900x601.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>One of Oasis Mathare’s Code Clubs in action</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Why Code Clubs?</strong></h2>



<p>Today, Oasis Mathare runs intensive software engineering and robotics programs that last between 9 and 12 months. But back in the early days of the organisation, Douglas quickly realised that many young people were struggling to keep up — not because of ability, but because they’d never used a computer before.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“So, we started Code Clubs to introduce these principles of programming at an early age… and we actually realised that those who have gone through Code Club take less time to complete our software engineering and robotics classes.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Code Clubs now serve as a stepping stone at Oasis Mathare. They help introduce computer literacy and programming concepts to young people early, making it easier for them to thrive in more advanced programs.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The power of role models</strong></h2>



<p>The impact of the program is already visible. Many graduates of Oasis Mathare programs go on to volunteer and eventually teach, serving as role models for the younger learners.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Oasis Mathare has 6 full-time staff. There are 12 Code Club leaders. They are our graduates from the software engineering program. We are plugging them into the Code Clubs to help them gain confidence and help the next generation.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The Code Clubs are held both in schools and at the Oasis Mathare centre, creating safe, structured environments for learning, experimenting, and collaborating.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="668" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6534.jpg" alt="Douglas supporting a Code Club mentor" class="wp-image-90983" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6534.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6534-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6534-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6534-768x513.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6534-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6534-450x301.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6534-900x601.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Douglas supporting a Code Club mentor</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Building with what they have</strong></h2>



<p>Before setting up Code Clubs, Oasis Mathare ran STEM clubs that used a variety of resources, but the cost and maintenance became a barrier. When they discovered Code Club’s free-to-access resources, everything changed.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“We found [the resources] very useful. The good thing about Code Club is you can plan sessions using resources that are freely available, like Scratch. It&#8217;s really straightforward.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The biggest challenge now? Internet access is limited, so Douglas and his team often work offline. The team have started using the Raspberry Pi Foundation’s offline resources, and look forward to more being available in the future.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What’s next for Douglas and Oasis Mathare?</strong></h2>



<p>Douglas and the Oasis Mathare team have already achieved so much. This was recognised with a royal seal of approval in 2018, when Douglas was honoured with the Queen’s Young Leaders Award by Queen Elizabeth at Buckingham Palace. Through the award, he gained access to world-class mentoring and leadership training from the University of Cambridge, helping him to amplify his impact back home.</p>



<p>So, what’s next? Douglas’ vision for the future is bold and clear.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The main idea is to ensure that all kids in Mathare know at least one computer language. Not for the sake of it, but to use the principles of programming to solve their local problems.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>By learning coding, young people build more than just technical skills. They learn to think critically, work in teams, and solve problems in their communities. For Douglas, that’s the real impact.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The overall goal is to ensure that no youth in Mathare are left behind and they all have the opportunity to develop essential skills from an early age.”</p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="668" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6594.jpg" alt="Students at an Oasis Mathare Code Club working together" class="wp-image-90984" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6594.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6594-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6594-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6594-768x513.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6594-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6594-450x301.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6594-900x601.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Looking further ahead</strong></h2>



<p>Oasis Mathare runs Code Clubs weekly, all year round, and Douglas is always looking for ways to expand the program’s reach, especially through partnerships, sponsorships, and sharing their successes so far.</p>



<p>With more resources, more local leaders, and a whole community behind him, Douglas is rewriting the narrative for young people in Mathare. You can find out more about Oasis Mathare on their <a href="https://www.oasismathare.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">official website.</a></p>



<p>If you’d like to support young people in your community to explore coding, why not start a Code Club? The team will support you every step of the way with resources, training, and a collaborative community. Find out more on the <a href="https://codeclub.org/en/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Code Club</a> website.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/giving-back-through-code-club-meet-douglas/">Giving back through Code Club: Meet Douglas</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/giving-back-through-code-club-meet-douglas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Code, karaoke, and creativity: Meet Matthew</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-karaoke-and-creativity-meet-matthew/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-karaoke-and-creativity-meet-matthew/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sophie Ashford]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 09:31:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Code Club]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=90961</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We love hearing from members of the community and sharing stories of amazing young people, volunteers, and educators who are using their passion for technology to create positive change in the world around them. It’s especially inspiring to hear about young people who are not only passionate about technology, but who are also driven to&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-karaoke-and-creativity-meet-matthew/">Code, karaoke, and creativity: Meet Matthew</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We love hearing from members of the community and sharing stories of amazing young people, volunteers, and educators who are using their passion for technology to create positive change in the world around them.</p>



<p>It’s especially inspiring to hear about young people who are not only passionate about technology, but who are also driven to share that passion with others. Meet Matthew, a 15-year-old creator and youth mentor at Code Club, who builds his own projects and inspires peers by organising hackathons.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="667" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/B75E500F-1628-4FF9-B924-D7CA70562AA4_1_102_o.jpeg" alt="Matthew and his team at Cool as Hack at the RPF offices" class="wp-image-90962" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/B75E500F-1628-4FF9-B924-D7CA70562AA4_1_102_o.jpeg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/B75E500F-1628-4FF9-B924-D7CA70562AA4_1_102_o-300x200.jpeg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/B75E500F-1628-4FF9-B924-D7CA70562AA4_1_102_o-500x334.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/B75E500F-1628-4FF9-B924-D7CA70562AA4_1_102_o-768x512.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/B75E500F-1628-4FF9-B924-D7CA70562AA4_1_102_o-800x534.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/B75E500F-1628-4FF9-B924-D7CA70562AA4_1_102_o-450x300.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/B75E500F-1628-4FF9-B924-D7CA70562AA4_1_102_o-900x600.jpeg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Matthew and his team at Cool as Hack at the RPF offices</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Matthew’s early experience with coding&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p>Matthew’s journey into the world of coding began at a young age. His initial exposure was through Scratch at school in Singapore. From there, he began exploring self-learn platforms in his own time, getting to grips with HTML and basic web development.</p>



<p>His enthusiasm for creating led him to participate in a technology week in Year 6, where he took on a BBC micro:bit challenge. He dedicated his summer holiday to developing a token system that encouraged community recycling, using an ultrasonic sensor to award points for good behaviour. This early project showcased his knack for problem-solving and innovation.</p>



<p>What truly captivated Matthew was the possibility of combining the logical challenges of competitive programming with the joy of project creation.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1080" height="1440" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6750.jpeg" alt="Matthew with his device developed in Year 6 to promote recycling behaviour in his residential community" class="wp-image-90963" style="width:520px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6750.jpeg 1080w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6750-188x250.jpeg 188w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6750-500x667.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6750-768x1024.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6750-800x1067.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6750-450x600.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6750-900x1200.jpeg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1080px) 100vw, 1080px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Matthew with his device developed in Year 6 to promote recycling behaviour in his residential community</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Connecting with the community</strong></h2>



<p>Through <a href="https://youthacks.org/">Youthhacks</a>, an initiative he co-founded to support teenage hackathon organisers, Matthew aims to expand access to hackathons across the UK (a hackathon is an event where individuals or teams work intensively over a relatively short time period to build software, hardware, or other kinds of technology). Matthew wants to offer advice and support, making it easier for young people to run their own hackathons. He puts a lot of time into ensuring that the content and atmosphere truly resonate with the participants.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“So, we made Youthhacks basically as an idea to be able to support these teenage organisers, you know, like hackathons for teenagers by teenagers.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Matthew’s connection with the Raspberry Pi Foundation came from his keen interest in the hackathon community and a need for a local venue. Having previously toured the Foundation’s offices for a school robotics club, he decided to reach out when organising a satellite hackathon called Counterspell.</p>



<p>This initial collaboration led to further events at the Foundation, including Scrapyard Cambridge and, more recently, Cool as Hack.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Coolest Projects hackathon: A new approach to collaborative coding&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p><a href="https://coolashack.youthacks.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Cool as Hack</a> was Matthew’s third event held at the Raspberry Pi Foundation offices. Unlike traditional hackathons with intense time pressure, this event, inspired by the spirit of <a href="https://online.coolestprojects.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Coolest Projects</a>, aimed to be more relaxed and collaborative.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“For this, people could bring in their own project scraps and then they could put it together with a team, finalise it, and then enter it to Coolest Projects.”&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The focus was on showcasing creativity and sharing projects globally, rather than competitive prizes. Everyone then entered their creations into the Coolest Projects online showcase.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="667" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9590.jpg" alt="Young coders at Cool as Hack" class="wp-image-90964" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9590.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9590-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9590-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9590-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9590-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9590-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9590-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Cool as Hack in progress at RPF HQ. Credit: W O Wallace</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Cool as Hack was a huge success. The atmosphere was incredible — there was even a karaoke session and a “swag shop” where participants could exchange tokens earned for innovative ideas or project milestones. This token system, designed by Matthew and harking back to his own recycling project from years ago, created a fun and engaging reward system.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Inspiring the next generation</strong></h2>



<p>Matthew’s drive to organise these events and encourage other young people to code stems from his enjoyment of project creation and the community aspect of hackathons.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Well, I suppose it links back to me enjoying making projects and when you attend a hackathon, it&#8217;s not a competition really. It&#8217;s more of a social event. So, you&#8217;re making a project and then you&#8217;re meeting quite a lot of coders, or even artists and musicians, and so many other people.”</p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="667" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9679.jpg" alt="Young coders at Cool as Hack at the RPF offices" class="wp-image-90966" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9679.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9679-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9679-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9679-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9679-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9679-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9679-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">All of the creators that took part in Cool as Hack. Credit: W O Wallace</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Now a regular volunteer at the Raspberry Pi Foundation’s monthly Code Club in Cambridge, Matthew remains focused on encouraging others into tech. For aspiring young coders, he says that coding is far more diverse and creative than many might initially perceive, encompassing art, storytelling, and problem-solving. Matthew’s advice is simple:&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Enjoy the process and as you learn new things you’ll realise that all of this is like super interesting, and that there are so many ways to make what you want. Just enjoy it and continue meeting new people and, yeah, be creative.”&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Matthew’s journey shows how an intro to computing at a young age can lead to an incredible amount of impact. With his continued dedication, he&#8217;s sure to inspire many more young minds to start on their own coding adventures.</p>



<p><strong>If you would like to explore coding, you can get started at home with <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">over 250 free projects</a>.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p><strong>Looking for a little extra support in your own coding journey or open to mentoring others? <a href="https://codeclub.org/en/join-a-club" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Join a Code Club</a> near you to meet a like-minded and supportive community.</strong></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-karaoke-and-creativity-meet-matthew/">Code, karaoke, and creativity: Meet Matthew</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-karaoke-and-creativity-meet-matthew/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Hello World podcast series: Bringing computer science into every classroom</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/new-hello-world-podcast-series-bringing-computer-science-into-every-classroom/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/new-hello-world-podcast-series-bringing-computer-science-into-every-classroom/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Sayers]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 11:34:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hello World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cross-disciplinary computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CSTA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Integrated CS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hello world podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cross-curricular teaching]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=90935</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Hello World podcast is back, accompanying the latest issue of Hello World magazine. This new three-part miniseries explores some of the topics from issue 27 of Hello World, which focuses on integrating computing education across the curriculum. Whether you&#8217;re a seasoned educator or just starting your journey with computing education, this podcast audio and&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/new-hello-world-podcast-series-bringing-computer-science-into-every-classroom/">New Hello World podcast series: Bringing computer science into every classroom</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Hello World podcast is back, accompanying the latest issue of <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world">Hello World</a> magazine. This new three-part miniseries explores some of the topics from <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/issues/27">issue 27 of Hello World</a>, which focuses on integrating computing education across the curriculum.<br></p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="https://youtu.be/2NT2R-kbZaA"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.1-Thumbnail-Title-Positioned-Bottom-YT-Player.png" alt="" class="wp-image-90944" style="width:698px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.1-Thumbnail-Title-Positioned-Bottom-YT-Player.png 1920w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.1-Thumbnail-Title-Positioned-Bottom-YT-Player-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.1-Thumbnail-Title-Positioned-Bottom-YT-Player-500x281.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.1-Thumbnail-Title-Positioned-Bottom-YT-Player-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.1-Thumbnail-Title-Positioned-Bottom-YT-Player-1536x864.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.1-Thumbnail-Title-Positioned-Bottom-YT-Player-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.1-Thumbnail-Title-Positioned-Bottom-YT-Player-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.1-Thumbnail-Title-Positioned-Bottom-YT-Player-900x506.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /></a></figure></div>


<p>Whether you&#8217;re a seasoned educator or just starting your journey with computing education, this podcast audio and video series is full of insights, inspiration, and practical tips from educators and experts around the world. </p>



<p>If you’re already subscribed, the new episodes will appear automatically in your favourite podcast app every Tuesday.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Episode 1: Why kids still need to learn to code in the age of AI</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Out now</strong></h3>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="https://youtu.be/_pWmaytjLBA"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.2-No-James-Kids-and-code-in-the-age-of-AI-Title-Positioned-Bottom-Plain-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-90945" style="width:759px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.2-No-James-Kids-and-code-in-the-age-of-AI-Title-Positioned-Bottom-Plain-1.jpg 1920w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.2-No-James-Kids-and-code-in-the-age-of-AI-Title-Positioned-Bottom-Plain-1-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.2-No-James-Kids-and-code-in-the-age-of-AI-Title-Positioned-Bottom-Plain-1-500x281.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.2-No-James-Kids-and-code-in-the-age-of-AI-Title-Positioned-Bottom-Plain-1-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.2-No-James-Kids-and-code-in-the-age-of-AI-Title-Positioned-Bottom-Plain-1-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.2-No-James-Kids-and-code-in-the-age-of-AI-Title-Positioned-Bottom-Plain-1-800x450.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.2-No-James-Kids-and-code-in-the-age-of-AI-Title-Positioned-Bottom-Plain-1-450x253.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.2-No-James-Kids-and-code-in-the-age-of-AI-Title-Positioned-Bottom-Plain-1-900x506.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /></a></figure></div>


<p>In our first episode, Raspberry Pi Foundation CEO Philip Colligan, CBE, sits down with teacher Janine Kirk to discuss <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/why-kids-still-need-to-learn-to-code-in-the-age-of-ai/">why, in the age of AI, it’s more important than ever for young people to learn to code</a>. Their conversation draws on ideas from <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/why-kids-still-need-to-learn-to-code-in-the-age-of-ai/">our downloadable position paper</a>, which is also featured in issue 27 of Hello World magazine.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Episode 2: Voices &amp; tips from CSTA conference</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Released Tuesday 15 July</strong></h3>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="667" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6707-500x667.jpg" alt="Photo of Hello World editor, Meg Wang, and contributing editor Dominick Sanders at CSTA 2025." class="wp-image-90946" style="width:350px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6707-500x667.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6707-188x250.jpg 188w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6707-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6707-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6707-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6707-800x1067.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6707-450x600.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6707-900x1200.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6707-scaled.jpg 1920w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>Next week, we’ll bring you the buzz from the Computer Science Teachers Association’s annual conference in Cleveland, USA. We’re speaking with educators at the conference to hear how they’re integrating computer science across subjects, and you&#8217;ll hear their top classroom tips for teaching CS in context.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Episode 3: Global perspectives on AI education</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Released Tuesday 22 July</strong></h3>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2560" height="1706" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Photo-Episode-27.4-1-scaled.jpg" alt="Episode 3 of the Hello World Podcast set" class="wp-image-90936" style="width:674px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Photo-Episode-27.4-1-scaled.jpg 2560w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Photo-Episode-27.4-1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Photo-Episode-27.4-1-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Photo-Episode-27.4-1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Photo-Episode-27.4-1-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Photo-Episode-27.4-1-2048x1365.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Photo-Episode-27.4-1-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Photo-Episode-27.4-1-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Photo-Episode-27.4-1-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /></figure></div>


<p>The miniseries wraps up with an in-depth discussion about <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/teach/ai-education">AI education</a> around the world. Hosted by <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/author/ben-garside/">Ben Garside</a>, Senior Learning Manager for <a href="https://experience-ai.org/?utm_source=web&amp;utm_medium=rpf-ai-education-page">Experience AI</a>, the conversation features Leonida Soi, Learning Manager in Kenya; Monika Katkute-Gelzine, CEO of Vedliai in Lithuania; and <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teaching-a-generation-of-ai-innovators-in-malaysia-with-experience-ai/">Aimy Lee</a>, COO of Penang Science Cluster in Malaysia. Monika and Aimy work with us in our <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-expands-to-reach-over-2-million-students/">global Experience AI partner programme</a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Listen, read, learn, subscribe, and share</h2>



<p>Each of these three podcast episode builds on the themes in the latest Hello World issue, where you&#8217;ll find inspiration and practical tips from educators who are integrating CS across a variety of subjects and for all school ages.</p>



<p>Subscribe to the Hello World podcast wherever you get your podcasts to never miss an episode, and to help us reach more teachers. If you&#8217;re subscribe to Hello World magazine (it&#8217;s free), we’ll also let you know when new podcast episodes are available.</p>



<p>And, don’t forget to share this new podcast series with your fellow educators.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/new-hello-world-podcast-series-bringing-computer-science-into-every-classroom/">New Hello World podcast series: Bringing computer science into every classroom</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/new-hello-world-podcast-series-bringing-computer-science-into-every-classroom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to build young people&#8217;s agency through accessible learning</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-build-young-peoples-agency-through-accessible-learning/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-build-young-peoples-agency-through-accessible-learning/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Sayers]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 13:10:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quick reads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research and impact]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pedagogy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[universal design for learning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=90907</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We think computing or computer science (CS) needs to be accessible to all learners, and we know that teachers work hard towards this. Traditional CS approaches can lack flexibility, creating barriers to learning and excluding some young people. In today’s blog, we’re highlighting the ‘Universal design for learning’ (UDL) framework and how you can use&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-build-young-peoples-agency-through-accessible-learning/">How to build young people&#8217;s agency through accessible learning</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We think computing or computer science (CS) needs to be accessible to all learners, and we know that teachers work hard towards this. Traditional CS approaches can lack flexibility, creating barriers to learning and excluding some young people. In today’s blog, we’re highlighting the ‘Universal design for learning’ (UDL) framework and how you can use it to make computing education more accessible to all your learners.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="600" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/01/primary-ed.png" alt="Children in the classroom learning  Computer Science" class="wp-image-86110" style="width:684px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/01/primary-ed.png 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/01/primary-ed-300x180.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/01/primary-ed-500x300.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/01/primary-ed-768x461.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/01/primary-ed-800x480.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/01/primary-ed-450x270.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/01/primary-ed-900x540.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>We also share our <a href="https://the-cc.io/QR26" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new UDL-focused Pedagogy Quick Read</a>, which you can download for free to:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Find practical tips for how to use the UDL framework and related approaches with your learners</li>



<li>Read a summary of the research behind the framework</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Universal Design for Learning: Because one size does not fit all</h2>



<p>Everyone is different and has their own way of learning. What works for one young person may not work for the next. So why should we expect learners to be taught the same material in the same way?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Todd Rose, a contributor to the UDL framework, highlights the factors involved with a young person’s ability to engage and participate in learning. These include cognitive, social-emotional, family background and academic factors. He dispels the idea of an “average” learner, and instead suggests the concept of learner variability.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="https://the-cc.io/QR26"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1200" height="630" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/UDL-Framework-.png" alt="Picture of our new UDL-focused Pedagogy Quick Read" class="wp-image-90917" style="width:723px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/UDL-Framework-.png 1200w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/UDL-Framework--300x158.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/UDL-Framework--500x263.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/UDL-Framework--768x403.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/UDL-Framework--800x420.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/UDL-Framework--450x236.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/UDL-Framework--900x473.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">The new Quick Read</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>As educators, it’s important to consider that students will likely be at different stages of understanding, and a one-size-fits-all approach isn’t suitable. The UDL framework avoids this mindset and provides teachers with structured guidelines to design accessible lessons from the beginning.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What is the UDL framework?</h2>



<p>The UDL framework encourages educators to provide flexibility for learners in three areas:&nbsp;</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Multiple means of engagement: The “why of learning”, which helps to pique students&#8217; curiosity and motivates them to stay engaged</li>



<li>Multiple means of representation: The “what of learning”, which focuses on presenting information in different ways to make the content accessible</li>



<li>Multiple means of action and expression: The “how of learning”, which relates to different ways for students to access learning and express their understanding</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How can I apply the UDL framework?</h2>



<p>Two things are key while you are planning how to apply the UDL framework with your learners:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Try not to introduce all three areas at once to your practice. Instead, focus on one area of the framework at a time and reflect to identify where there might be gaps. Focus on these first and make changes one by one.</li>



<li>Consider how different approaches will work for different groups and individuals. Try to identify what works for your learners and vary or adapt your approach as necessary.</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Applying UDL: Some ideas for teaching programming</h3>



<p>Multiple means of engagement — show learners different reasons for engaging in programming. For example:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Solving real-life problems</li>



<li>Interest in technology or logical thinking</li>



<li>Creative expression</li>
</ul>



<p>Multiple means of representation — teach programming concepts in multiple ways. For example:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Demonstrate through live coding</li>



<li>Write on a blackboard with a flowchart</li>



<li>Let learners label and assemble bits of paper into a &#8216;program&#8217;</li>
</ul>



<p>Multiple means of action and expression — teach with accessibility in mind. For example:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Use tools appropriate for learners&#8217; mouse and keyboard skills</li>



<li>Let learners demonstrate their understanding in different ways (e.g. verbally, by writing/drawing, by creating a program)</li>
</ul>



<p>The UDL framework aligns closely with several key research-supported pedagogies that you can use for effective instruction in computational thinking and programming. For example, the pedagogy approach ‘Use-Modify-Create’ (UMC) can be paired with the UDL categories. The <a href="https://the-cc.io/QR26" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new Quick Read</a> explores these connections in more detail.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2362" height="1575" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Spencer-5-.jpg" alt="Students in the classroom" class="wp-image-90921" style="width:694px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Spencer-5-.jpg 2362w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Spencer-5--300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Spencer-5--500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Spencer-5--768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Spencer-5--1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Spencer-5--2048x1366.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Spencer-5--800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Spencer-5--450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Spencer-5--900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 2362px) 100vw, 2362px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The benefits of the UDL framework</h2>



<p>Potential benefits for teachers:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>The framework provides a clear structure for designing learning activities that appeal to and engage the widest set of learners</li>



<li>It can help you consider all the ways you might engage your learners and make CS lessons more accessible.</li>



<li>UDL encourages you to reflect on the different ways in which you might represent concepts and ideas</li>



<li>It can help you to build learner agency and independence in your students by offering them different ways to express their learning in CS topics.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<p>Potential benefits for learners:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>The framework promotes a sense of ownership over their learning. Which can boost their motivation and resilience to sticking with difficult challenges.&nbsp;</li>



<li>They will likely find content that resonates with them, leading to higher engagement and therefore learning.</li>



<li>They will be able to demonstrate their CS knowledge confidently and engage limitlessly in CS contexts.</li>
</ul>



<p>Our new Quick Read shares tips on how to best use the framework in your teaching.&nbsp;</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://the-cc.io/QR26">Download the Quick Read&nbsp;</a></div>
</div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Inclusive computer science: The wider context</h2>



<p>We know there is a lack of representation within the field of CS. Our recent position paper ‘<a href="https://static.raspberrypi.org/files/about/Why-kids-still-need-to-learn-to-code-in-the-age-of-AI-2025-Raspberry-Pi-Foundation-position-paper.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Why kids still need to learn to code in the age of AI</a>’ and an episode of the  <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/podcast" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hello World podcast</a>, ‘<a href="https://youtu.be/G3XXzxP8bdI" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">How can we empower girls in computing</a>’ touched on this. Both highlight why it&#8217;s important that learners from all backgrounds are empowered to contribute their perspectives and experiences and shape the future with computing.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1417" height="919" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/26.3-Host-and-guests-smiling-2.jpg" alt="Photo from the Hello World podcast, ‘How can we empower girls in computing" class="wp-image-90913" style="width:711px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/26.3-Host-and-guests-smiling-2.jpg 1417w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/26.3-Host-and-guests-smiling-2-300x195.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/26.3-Host-and-guests-smiling-2-500x324.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/26.3-Host-and-guests-smiling-2-768x498.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/26.3-Host-and-guests-smiling-2-800x519.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/26.3-Host-and-guests-smiling-2-450x292.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/26.3-Host-and-guests-smiling-2-900x584.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1417px) 100vw, 1417px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Guests and host during the recording of our ‘<a href="https://youtu.be/G3XXzxP8bdI" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">How can we empower girls in computing</a>’ episode</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>“The reality is that access to the opportunities to learn about computer science, programming, and coding has remained deeply unequal, both within and between countries. That has helped create a technology sector that doesn’t reflect the broad diversity of human backgrounds, perspectives, and experiences. And we are all living with the consequences.” – <a href="https://static.raspberrypi.org/files/about/Why-kids-still-need-to-learn-to-code-in-the-age-of-AI-2025-Raspberry-Pi-Foundation-position-paper.pdf">Philip Colligan, Mark Griffiths, Veronica Cucuiat</a></p>



<p>“If we don&#8217;t have a diverse range of people designing and implementing that tech, then we are going to come across issues.” – Becky Patel, Tech She Can, Hello World podcast”</p>



<p>By embracing the principles of ‘Universal design for learning’ and similar approaches, we can create a more inclusive and equitable learning environment in computer science for everyone.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-build-young-peoples-agency-through-accessible-learning/">How to build young people&#8217;s agency through accessible learning</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-build-young-peoples-agency-through-accessible-learning/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hello World 27 out now: Integrated computer science</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/hello-world-27-out-now-integrated-computer-science/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/hello-world-27-out-now-integrated-computer-science/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Meg Wang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 13:58:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hello World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cross-disciplinary computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hello world magazine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Integrated CS]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=90879</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>While in some countries, such as England, computing is taught as a standalone subject, in others, like the USA, computing concepts are integrated across the school curriculum. In our brand-new issue of Hello World, out today for free, educators share ways to integrate computer science into your classroom. Integrating CS to broaden participation The argument&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/hello-world-27-out-now-integrated-computer-science/">Hello World 27 out now: Integrated computer science</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>While in some countries, such as England, computing is taught as a standalone subject, in others, like the USA, computing concepts are integrated across the school curriculum. In our brand-new issue of Hello World, <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org//hello-world/issues/27" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">out today for</a><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org//hello-world/issues/27"> free</a>, educators share ways to integrate computer science into your classroom.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/issues/27"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1200" height="628" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/10798_HW_Twitter_Image-1.png" alt="Hello World Issue 27 front cover" class="wp-image-90890" style="width:726px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/10798_HW_Twitter_Image-1.png 1200w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/10798_HW_Twitter_Image-1-300x157.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/10798_HW_Twitter_Image-1-500x262.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/10798_HW_Twitter_Image-1-768x402.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/10798_HW_Twitter_Image-1-800x419.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/10798_HW_Twitter_Image-1-450x236.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/10798_HW_Twitter_Image-1-900x471.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></a></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Integrating CS to broaden participation</h2>



<p>The argument for making computing and computer science (CS) standalone has often been about quality. We’ve heard educators say that teaching CS as part of other subjects can be hard, especially if you don’t have a CS background. On the other hand, <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-cs-a-free-integrated-curriculum-for-computer-science/">integrating computer science into other subjects</a> can offer a more accessible entry point for young people, broadening participation in CS education. And the critical thinking and problem-solving skills young people gain through computer science can enhance their learning of any subject. </p>



<p>As digital technology increasingly shapes our world, it may be that thoughtful cross-curricular CS education is the most effective way to empower all young people to become confident and critical technology users.</p>



<p>Issue 27 of Hello World features a range of practical articles with ideas for integrating CS over a variety of subjects at the primary, elementary, and high-school levels.</p>



<p>For example:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>James Abela shares how to teach coding across the curriculum using <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/octostudio-app/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">OctoStudio</a> and the concepts of sequence, selection, and repetition</li>



<li>Jesualdo Martínez Molina presents hands-on examples of weaving together cross-curricular and modern foreign languages in the primary classroom</li>



<li>Jane Waite introduces the Autonomy framework, which explores whether we can effectively teach two things at once</li>



<li></li>
</ul>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-text-align-center wp-element-button" href="https://www.raspberrypi.org//hello-world/issues/27" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Download your free digital copy</a></div>
</div>



<p>Also in this issue:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Laurie Gale introduces PRIMMDebug, a new way to teach debugging</li>



<li>Teresa Harris Boag defines strategies for a whole-school approach to artificial intelligence (AI) to engage parents and school staff in developing an effective AI strategy</li>



<li>Tiffany Jones shares how she ensures that students can see themselves in tech</li>
</ul>



<p>And much, much more.</p>



<p>Jake Baskin, Executive Director of the Computer Science Teachers Association, says in this issue of Hello World: “If you’re a teacher who is implementing CS principles in your classroom, you are a computer science teacher.”</p>



<p>Whether CS is your specialist subject or not, Hello World is full of ideas from your fellow educators on how to inspire your students.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">New podcast series</h2>



<p>The Hello World podcast is also back, with a miniseries in audio and video focused on integrated CS. If you&#8217;re subscribed via a podcast app, the three new episodes will show up in your feed on Tuesdays. Or you can already listen to the new episodes today via the exclusive links inside issue 27.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2560" height="1707" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_0818_Edit-scaled.jpg" alt="Hello World Editor: Meg Wang, presenting an episode of the Hello World Podcast" class="wp-image-90892" style="width:716px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_0818_Edit-scaled.jpg 2560w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_0818_Edit-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_0818_Edit-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_0818_Edit-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_0818_Edit-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_0818_Edit-2048x1366.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_0818_Edit-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_0818_Edit-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_0818_Edit-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Share your thoughts &amp; subscribe to Hello World</h2>



<p>We hope you enjoy this issue of <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hello World</a>. Please get in touch with your article ideas or what you would like to see in the magazine.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Subscribe to Hello World for free</a> to never miss a magazine issue</li>



<li>Subscribe to the Hello World podcast using your podcast app of choice</li>



<li>Share your thoughts and ideas about the new Hello World issue and episodes with us via the Raspberry Pi Foundation social media channels</li>



<li>Find out how you can <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/write-for-us" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">write for the magazine</a></li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/hello-world-27-out-now-integrated-computer-science/">Hello World 27 out now: Integrated computer science</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/hello-world-27-out-now-integrated-computer-science/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Begin your Code Club journey: Set up a club today</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/begin-your-code-club-journey-set-up-a-club-today/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/begin-your-code-club-journey-set-up-a-club-today/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lou Loxley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 07:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Code Club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding for kids]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=90845</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Inspired to set up a Code Club but not sure where to start? In this blog we hear from the amazing network of Code Club leaders and mentors, and we give you practical tips on how to take the first steps to set up your own club.&#160; About Code Club Code Club is a thriving&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/begin-your-code-club-journey-set-up-a-club-today/">Begin your Code Club journey: Set up a club today</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Inspired to set up a Code Club but not sure where to start? In this blog we hear from the amazing network of Code Club leaders and mentors, and we give you practical tips on how to take the first steps to set up your own club.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="720" height="435" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/codeclub_camms_24-002_720.jpg" alt="Two young coders at a Code Club." class="wp-image-90855" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/codeclub_camms_24-002_720.jpg 720w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/codeclub_camms_24-002_720-300x181.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/codeclub_camms_24-002_720-500x302.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/codeclub_camms_24-002_720-450x272.jpg 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 720px) 100vw, 720px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>About Code Club</strong></h2>



<p><a href="http://rpf.io/cc-homepage-pr" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Code Club</a> is a thriving global community of clubs where young people can develop the confidence to create with digital technologies in a fun and supportive space. Code Clubs run in schools, libraries and other community settings. We have already supported 2 million school-aged young people worldwide to make things they care about with code.</p>



<p>We offer free training and ongoing support for anyone who would like to set up a Code Club — you don’t need to have a background in coding and technology to get involved.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Two teachers give their tips on setting up a Code Club</strong></h2>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“If you’re thinking of starting a Code Club, do it. The Code Club team has everything created — all the resources are available.” – Peter Hutyan, Code Club mentor, The Mease Spencer Academy, UK. </p>
</blockquote>



<p>Peter, a primary school teacher, has been running a Code Club for seven years at The Mease Spencer Academy in Derby, UK.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="563" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Peter.png" alt="A man smiling. " class="wp-image-90859" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Peter.png 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Peter-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Peter-500x282.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Peter-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Peter-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Peter-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Peter-900x507.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>“When I started Code Club, I didn’t know how to do Scratch”, says Peter about the block-based coding tool that lots of young learners start with. “So I made myself learn how to use Scratch and I was two to three lessons ahead of the kids. Basically I’ve done what the kids will do — I’ve read the instructions and created the code. It’s such a phenomenal experience of enriching young people’s lives, and you see the smile and sense of accomplishment on their faces. It’s the best day ever.”</p>



<p>Rachael Coultart is the Computer Subject Leader at St Nicholas Primary School, Stevenage, UK and has run a Code Club for over ten years.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="719" height="405" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image__12__720.png" alt="A woman laughing. " class="wp-image-90860" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image__12__720.png 719w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image__12__720-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image__12__720-500x282.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image__12__720-450x253.png 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 719px) 100vw, 719px" /></figure></div>


<p>“I think the benefits of running a Code Club for our school are that it really develops children’s collaboration skills, really develops their perseverance, their thinking skills, their independence”, Rachael says.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The key ingredients that I think make a Code Club successful is enthusiasm, from the adults who are there, a kind of passion to learn together and make mistakes together. I kind of think that sets the scene for the children to make mistakes as well. And I think having that freedom outside the classroom is what makes a Code Club really successful.” – Rachael Coultart, Computing Subject Leader, St Nicholas Primary School, UK</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Club mentors share why they were inspired to start a club</strong></h2>



<p>Saad Koubeissi runs four Code Clubs in libraries in London, UK.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="563" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Saad-2.png" alt="A man smiling." class="wp-image-90864" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Saad-2.png 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Saad-2-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Saad-2-500x282.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Saad-2-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Saad-2-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Saad-2-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Saad-2-900x507.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>“Code Club, for me personally, is about providing children with things I didn’t have when I was younger”, says Saad. “I went to youth clubs and stuff but it was never, like, so specific in tech, it was more, like, playing football. So Code Club, I think, by starting off early, it’s introducing children not only to identifying those skills, but also the terminologies, providing that. And being able to be part of that change for those children is welcome for me, to be honest.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Bob Bisland is a mentor who started his first Code Club twelve years ago after a career in technology. He now runs three clubs in Malvern, UK.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Bob.png" alt="A man smiling." class="wp-image-90865" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Bob.png 1920w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Bob-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Bob-500x281.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Bob-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Bob-1536x864.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Bob-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Bob-450x253.png 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /></figure></div>


<p>“Everyone should set up a Code Club. This is such a rewarding thing to be able to do. I am sharing my passion and my knowledge with another generation of children, and I&#8217;m seeing them learn what coding is all about.”</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Ready to start? Three steps to set up a Code Club</strong></h2>



<p>We provide everything you need to make starting a club straightforward, including <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">hundreds of free coding projects</a> to help you tailor your sessions to the interests of your young tech creators. Our projects are available in up to 40 languages.</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Choose your venue. </strong>Code Clubs are held in lots of different places, such as schools, libraries and community centres.</li>



<li><strong>Register your club. </strong>Complete your application to start your club. We’ll ask for a few details, e.g. the address of your club.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Start running your club. </strong>You can access our <a href="https://codeclub.org/en/events" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">free training</a> on how to prepare to run a Code Club. Our <a href="https://assets.ctfassets.net/zsyyd4yzh6xx/5ngzfqj5EczQNlEKn0T0lV/8c78a041b2c42c78396c73bdc921c5fb/-9770_Club_Leaders_Handbook_V8.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Code Club leader guide</a> also includes helpful information for running your club. </li>
</ol>



<p>Running a Code Club is a fun and rewarding way to engage young people and help them learn valuable skills for the future. Start your Code Club journey today by finding out more about <a href="http://rpf.io/cc-run-club-pr" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">setting up a club</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/begin-your-code-club-journey-set-up-a-club-today/">Begin your Code Club journey: Set up a club today</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/begin-your-code-club-journey-set-up-a-club-today/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New to coding? Resources to help children learn to code</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/new-to-coding-resources-to-help-children-learn-to-code-2/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/new-to-coding-resources-to-help-children-learn-to-code-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lou Loxley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 07:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Code Club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding for kids]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=90507</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Here at the Raspberry Pi Foundation we believe ensuring every child knows how to code will equip them with the skills to thrive in the future.&#160; But what do we mean by coding and how can you get started? Coding is how humans give instructions to computers. Machines process and execute these instructions to perform&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/new-to-coding-resources-to-help-children-learn-to-code-2/">New to coding? Resources to help children learn to code</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Here at the Raspberry Pi Foundation we believe ensuring every child knows how to code will equip them with the skills to thrive in the future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what do we mean by coding and how can you get started?</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="692" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/CodeClub_CamMS_24-041.jpg" alt="Two young coders at a Code Club." class="wp-image-90826" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/CodeClub_CamMS_24-041.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/CodeClub_CamMS_24-041-300x208.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/CodeClub_CamMS_24-041-500x346.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/CodeClub_CamMS_24-041-768x531.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/CodeClub_CamMS_24-041-800x554.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/CodeClub_CamMS_24-041-450x311.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/CodeClub_CamMS_24-041-900x623.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/CodeClub_CamMS_24-041-216x150.jpg 216w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>Coding is how humans give instructions to computers. Machines process and execute these instructions to perform the task you want — whether it’s making an LED light flash, designing your own avatar and making it dance, or creating a website.</p>



<p>Coding underpins the digital technologies that are ubiquitous in our daily lives: the apps on your phone, the software in your TV, and in life-saving devices in hospitals — even making sure your supermarket is fully stocked.</p>



<p>By learning to code, young people can develop the skills and knowledge that we need in an increasingly digital world.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>So how can you get started?</strong></h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Code Club</strong></h3>



<p>One of the best ways for school-aged young people to get started with coding is to find your local <a href="http://rpf.io/cc-homepage-pr" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Code Club</a> — a fun and supportive space where young people develop the skills and confidence to create with digital technologies. They might program their first-ever game or animation in Scratch, create their own step counter with a micro:bit, or use Python to control a robot!</p>



<p>There are around 2,000 Code Clubs across the UK and Ireland and nearly 6,000 more around the world, running in schools and communities – and they are totally free! As well as learning to code, young creators work together, gain confidence and a sense of belonging, and build their skills in problem solving and teamwork. You can read more about the benefits in this <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-fun-filled-code-clubs-drive-learning-new-evidence/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">independent evaluation of Code Club</a>.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="724" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/CodeClub_CamMS_24-061.jpg" alt="Two young coders at a Code Club." class="wp-image-90828" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/CodeClub_CamMS_24-061.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/CodeClub_CamMS_24-061-300x217.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/CodeClub_CamMS_24-061-500x362.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/CodeClub_CamMS_24-061-768x556.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/CodeClub_CamMS_24-061-800x579.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/CodeClub_CamMS_24-061-450x326.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/CodeClub_CamMS_24-061-900x652.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>Creators use our free, <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">step-by-step projects</a> to learn different coding languages and skills. We have hundreds of free coding and computing projects for all experience levels and interests. For example, young people can start to code to make a character catch a bus, then move on to building a musical instrument, and even try out creating a project that uses artificial intelligence.</p>



<p>This handy <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/projects/321-make-mentor-guide/9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">guide for mentors</a> will help you find which projects are right for you and your creators. Read on to find out more about our free coding resources.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Scratch&nbsp;</strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://scratch.mit.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Scratch</a> is a good way for young people to begin their journey in coding. Scratch is a block-based language, which allows children to assemble code to produce games, animations, and stories.</p>



<p>The Raspberry Pi Foundation has hundreds of Scratch projects that young creators can try out, but the best place to start is with our <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/pathways/scratch-intro" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Introduction to Scratch</a> path. This will provide young people with the basic skills they need, and then encourage them to build projects that are relevant to them, culminating in their creation of their own interactive ebook.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="720" height="480" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/codeclub_camms_24-008__1__720.jpg" alt="A mentor and a young person at a Code Club." class="wp-image-90830" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/codeclub_camms_24-008__1__720.jpg 720w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/codeclub_camms_24-008__1__720-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/codeclub_camms_24-008__1__720-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/codeclub_camms_24-008__1__720-450x300.jpg 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 720px) 100vw, 720px" /></figure></div>


<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Web design</strong></h3>



<p>Websites are integral to many of our lives, and we believe that it is important for young people to learn how the websites and apps they visit are created with code.</p>



<p>That is why we have an <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/pathways/web-intro" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Introduction to web development</a> path that enables young creators to make their own simple webpages and apps with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript and share them with their friends. The path helps them create webpages about subjects that they care about, and they also learn about accessible web design.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Python</strong></h3>



<p>Once children feel confident using Scratch, Python is a brilliant next step. It’s a real-world programming language used by professionals, but it’s also simple enough for beginners. Python helps young people move from blocks to text-based code, deepening their understanding of how programming works. It’s easy to read, which means learners can focus on thinking logically and building exciting projects. Our<a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/pathways/python-intro" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Python path for beginners</a> is the perfect place to start, and we have loads more <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/projects?software%5B%5D=python" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Python projects</a> for them to explore as their skills grow.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Artificial intelligence</strong></h3>



<p>Our new <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/collections/artificial_intelligence" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">artificial intelligence (AI) path</a> allows young people to discover the foundational concepts of machine learning through creative and interactive projects using AI applications and technologies. Working with voice recognition, facial recognition, and other AI technologies, young people gain a broader understanding of how AI can be applied in different contexts.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="720" height="497" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/cc_12-7-23_-48_720.jpg" alt="A mentor helps a young person with a coding task at a Code Club." class="wp-image-90829" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/cc_12-7-23_-48_720.jpg 720w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/cc_12-7-23_-48_720-300x207.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/cc_12-7-23_-48_720-500x345.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/cc_12-7-23_-48_720-450x311.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/cc_12-7-23_-48_720-216x150.jpg 216w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 720px) 100vw, 720px" /></figure></div>


<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Physical computing with Raspberry Pi</strong></h3>



<p>For young creators interested in interacting with the real world using code, our <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/collections/physical_computing" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">physical computing</a> projects help them discover how to use electronic components. These projects show how to build things with buttons, switches, buzzers and LEDs using <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/pathways/physical-computing-with-scratch-and-the-raspberry-pi" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Scratch and a Raspberry Pi computer</a>, or using <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/pathways/pico-intro" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Python and a Raspberry Pi Pico microcontroller</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Physical computing with micro:bit</strong></h3>



<p>Another fun option for young people who want to explore physical computing is the <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/collections/microbit" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">micro:bit</a>. This is a small programmable device with an LED display, buttons, and sensors, and it can be used to create games, animations, interactive projects, and lots more. A visual programming language called <a href="https://makecode.microbit.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">MakeCode</a> can be used to control a micro:bit. Or the micro:bit can be programmed using Scratch or text-based languages such as Python, offering an easy transition for young creators as their coding skills progress. Have a look at our free <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/projects?hardware%5B%5D=microbit" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">collection of micro:bit resources</a> to learn more.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Next steps</strong></h2>



<p>When young people are confident in these areas, they could try creating and exploring 3D worlds with the power of <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/collections/unity" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Unity</a>. And what about creating using a Raspberry Pi computer?<strong> </strong>These <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/collections/raspberry_pi" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">beginner projects</a> help you learn to set up and configure your Raspberry Pi and get started.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="720" height="480" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/codeclub_camms_24-044__1__720.jpg" alt="A mentor supports young coders at a Code Club." class="wp-image-90827" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/codeclub_camms_24-044__1__720.jpg 720w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/codeclub_camms_24-044__1__720-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/codeclub_camms_24-044__1__720-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/codeclub_camms_24-044__1__720-450x300.jpg 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 720px) 100vw, 720px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Fancy running your code in space or submitting your project to our showcase?</strong></h2>



<p>Once you’re up and running, we have two fun ways kids can get even more out of coding.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://astro-pi.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">European Astro Pi Challenge</a> allows kids to run their code in space. We have two levels:&nbsp;</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Mission Zero, suitable for beginners, where they code a personalised image for the astronauts on the International Space Station</li>



<li>Mission Space Lab, where kids&#8217; code solves a scientific task on board the International Space Station</li>
</ul>



<p>And young people can also submit their creations to <a href="https://online.coolestprojects.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Coolest Projects</a>. This is a celebration of young digital creators and the amazing things they make with technology. We have a global online showcase, as well as in-person Coolest Projects events in several countries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And if you’ve been inspired to set up a new Code Club, or volunteer at a Code Club near you, <a href="http://rpf.io/cc-run-club-pr" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">find out the next steps here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/new-to-coding-resources-to-help-children-learn-to-code-2/">New to coding? Resources to help children learn to code</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/new-to-coding-resources-to-help-children-learn-to-code-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
