<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Raspberry Pi Foundation</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/</link>
	<description>Teach, learn and make with Raspberry Pi</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:30:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.9.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/06/cropped-raspberrry_pi_logo-100x100.png</url>
	<title>Raspberry Pi Foundation</title>
	<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Embodied machine learning: From research ideas to classroom activities</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/embodied-machine-learning-from-research-ideas-to-classroom-activities/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/embodied-machine-learning-from-research-ideas-to-classroom-activities/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katharine Childs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:30:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research seminar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI literacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[micro:bit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=92555</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Where do great research ideas come from in computer science education? We might think of research breakthroughs as a single moment of genius, but in reality impactful research is often the result of many years of iterative development. In November’s research seminar, we heard from Karl-Emil Kjær Bilstrup, a researcher at the University of Copenhagen,&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/embodied-machine-learning-from-research-ideas-to-classroom-activities/">Embodied machine learning: From research ideas to classroom activities</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Where do great research ideas come from in computer science education? We might think of research breakthroughs as a single moment of genius, but in reality impactful research is often the result of many years of iterative development. In November’s research seminar, we heard from <a href="https://www.karl-emil.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Karl-Emil Kjær Bilstrup</a>, a researcher at the University of Copenhagen, about his work to develop<a href="http://ml-machine.org" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> ML-Machine</a>. This work uses embodied learning principles and the BBC micro:bit to introduce learners to machine learning concepts. Findings from this research have been used to develop the <a href="https://createai.microbit.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">micro:bit CreateAI resources</a>, and in this blog, we will explain the research journey from initial small-scale work to educational resources used by many young learners around the world.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1300" height="731" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/image1.jpg" alt="Karl-Emil Kjær Bilstrup, a tool designer and researcher from the University of Copenhagen" class="wp-image-92556" style="aspect-ratio:1.7784246915213868;width:786px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/image1.jpg 1300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/image1-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/image1-500x281.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/image1-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/image1-800x450.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/image1-450x253.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/image1-900x506.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 1300px) 100vw, 1300px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Karl-Emil Kjær Bilstrup, a tool designer and researcher from the University of Copenhagen</figcaption></figure>
</div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading">From hypothetical ethics to concrete machines</h2>



<p>In Karl-Emil’s <a href="https://pure.au.dk/ws/portalfiles/portal/190605815/StagingReflectionsOnEthicalDilemmasInMachineLearning.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">first research study</a>, students used prompt cards to develop ideas for machine learning applications that could solve real-world problems, and to discuss the ethical dilemmas associated with their solutions. Students found it difficult to address these ethical dilemmas in their designs; for example, their ideas often featured a trade-off of user privacy. The findings from this research informed Karl-Emil’s next study, which moved from hypothetical scenarios to implementing machine learning in real-world settings.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The <a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/epdf/10.1145/3430524.3440638">‘Machine Learning Machine’ study</a> made machine learning processes tangible for students through the use of two physical boxes, shown in the picture below. Students created drawings and fed them into the first box to train a model, and then tested the model by placing new drawings under a camera in the second box and having the model produce predictions of what the drawings showed. For example, students could draw pictures of the sun to represent daytime and the moon to represent nighttime to train a model to predict whether new drawings represented day or night. The machine was built for slow interaction, giving students time to think about the concepts and practices that they were developing. In <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Marianne-Petersen/publication/364264949_The_Best_of_Both_Worlds_Designing_a_Tiered_Hybrid_Interface_for_Teaching_Machine_Learning_in_K-9_Education/links/647dbc87b3dfd73b7767dd59/The-Best-of-Both-Worlds-Designing-a-Tiered-Hybrid-Interface-for-Teaching-Machine-Learning-in-K-9-Education.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a follow-up study</a>, a new version of the Machine Learning Machine had been designed, which was controlled using a graphical user interface (GUI). This allowed users to “unbox” and influence parts of the machine learning process. For example, students could adjust the number of complete passes (called ‘epochs’<em>) </em>through the training data to improve the model’s accuracy.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="772" height="314" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/image3.png" alt="The two components of the Machine Learning Machine: the training box (left) and the evaluator box (right) " class="wp-image-92558" style="width:698px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/image3.png 772w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/image3-300x122.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/image3-500x203.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/image3-768x312.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/image3-450x183.png 450w" sizes="(max-width: 772px) 100vw, 772px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">The two components of the Machine Learning Machine: the training box (left) and the evaluator box (right)</figcaption></figure>
</div>


<p>The two studies with the Machine Learning Machines provided many useful findings for teaching about machine learning with K–12 (primary and secondary) learners. However, two constraints remained: firstly, there were limited opportunities for whole-class work because there was only one Machine Learning Machine, and secondly, learning experiences needed to be better connected to examples from students’ daily lives. As a result, the next iteration in Karl-Emil’s research involved using the micro:bit, which ensured access to a tangible device for every student, and a new graphical platform called <a href="http://ml-machine.org" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ML-Machine</a> that students could interact with.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Machine learning and the micro:bit</h2>



<p>The <a href="https://microbit.org/get-started/what-is-the-microbit/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">micro:bit</a> is a small, programmable computing device that features sensors to gather data from the immediate environment. For example, the <a href="https://microbit.org/get-started/features/sensors/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">accelerometer</a> is a motion sensor that can detect when the micro:bit is tilted from left to right, backwards and forwards, and up and down. Using the micro:bit with <a href="http://ml-machine.org" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ML-Machine</a> and some common household objects, students can create simple machine learning models that use data from the micro:bit’s accelerometer to detect whether the micro:bit is moving. This is a very different approach from rule-based programs on the micro:bit, where students might use programming constructs such as if statements to detect movement if the numerical reading from the accelerometer is above a certain value. Here, a machine learning model trained using a set of 20 examples is used to analyse live data readings and produce predictions about whether the micro:bit is moving.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="808" height="367" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/image2.png" alt="A visualisation of a simple machine learning model to detect whether a micro:bit is being shaken or is still" class="wp-image-92560" style="width:772px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/image2.png 808w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/image2-300x136.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/image2-500x227.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/image2-768x349.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/image2-800x363.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/image2-450x204.png 450w" sizes="(max-width: 808px) 100vw, 808px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">A visualisation of a simple machine learning model to detect whether a micro:bit is being shaken or is still</figcaption></figure>
</div>


<p>In our seminar, Karl-Emil gave a live demonstration of the ML-Machine toolkit, so we highly recommend watching the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GnPwaIckR9c&amp;list=PLxyaWvsfmq497kQR_KGF1UoijvZHDBZfh" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">recording</a> to see how this toolkit brings machine learning concepts to life.&nbsp;</p>



<p>ML-Machine is the precursor to the <a href="https://createai.microbit.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">micro:bit CreateAI</a> resources, and the software is fully <a href="https://github.com/microbit-foundation/cctd-ml-machine" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">open-source</a>. However, the innovation doesn’t stop there: Karl-Emil also explained that he is currently developing a new tool called <a href="http://math.ml-machine.org" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">math.ml-machine.org</a>, where students can train a neural network and see a visualised k-nearest neighbour model to explore how a model makes predictions. The research journey is continuing, with new possibilities for educational opportunities to teach about machine learning.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Embodied learning</h2>



<p>The idea of embodied learning is interwoven throughout all of Karl-Emil’s research projects and is a cornerstone of all of his work. Embodied learning suggests that we learn more effectively when our whole body is involved in the learning process, not just our minds. For example, in the work described in this seminar, the Machine Learning Machines and the micro:bit were all tangible devices that students could touch and see.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Embodied learning is particularly important in activities that involve working with <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/a-research-led-framework-for-teaching-about-models-in-ai-and-data-science/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">data-driven systems</a>. In traditional programming activities, the flow of code can be traced transparently through a program. However, <a href="https://static.raspberrypi.org/files/curriculum/quickreads/21-Pedagogy_Summary_Computational_Thinking_2_2025.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">machine learning models are more opaque</a>, and their outputs cannot be traced step by step. Students can benefit from using bodily movements and sensorimotor information to help understand machine learning concepts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The ML-Machine toolkit was designed to support students to learn through embodied learning in three different ways:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Enacting machine learning processes:</strong> Students used bodily movement to collect the data samples needed for the ML-Machine model to detect and predict gestures&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Using machine learning as a design material:</strong> Students created concrete ‘objects-to-think-with’, which helps form deeper connections to abstract concepts</li>



<li><strong>Embodied exploration of machine learning:</strong> Students experienced how their bodily movements were translated into data points on the screen</li>
</ol>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2560" height="1707" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/Spencer-5--scaled.jpg" alt="Secondary school age learners in a computing classroom." class="wp-image-85670" style="aspect-ratio:1.4997489259610557;width:740px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/Spencer-5--scaled.jpg 2560w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/Spencer-5--300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/Spencer-5--500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/Spencer-5--768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/Spencer-5--1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/Spencer-5--2048x1365.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/Spencer-5--800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/Spencer-5--450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/Spencer-5--900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>Embodied learning helped students grasp concepts such as data quality. They could see how their bodily movements were being translated into digital data, and could spot when movements that appeared different to them were being classified as similar by the ML-Machine model. One case study participant described that the immediate feedback on screen made the concept of machine learning feel as if it were “coming to life as they [the students] manipulate something themselves and they’ve got control over it”.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Find out more</h2>



<p>Karl-Emil’s work shows how research ideas can be used in the classroom through a cycle of discovery, design, and reflection. From prompt cards exploring ethics to tangible machines and the micro:bit-based ML-Machine, his research shows how embodied learning can make complex ideas like machine learning not only understandable, but deeply engaging for young learners. The micro:bit CreateAI resources are a great example of how research findings can evolve into accessible, hands-on tools that empower educators and students alike. As this work continues to grow, it invites us to imagine new ways for learners to experience machine learning not as abstract theory, but as something they can see, feel, and shape with their own hands.</p>



<p>If you’d like to try out some of the ideas from this seminar, here are some useful resources:&nbsp;</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Explore machine learning projects using the micro:bit: <a href="https://createai.microbit.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">micro:bit CreateAI</a> and our <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/projects/dance-detector" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dance detector</a> project are great places to start</li>



<li>Find out more about the research: Read more about Karl-Emil’s work in this <a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/full/10.1145/3715336.3735737" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">open-access paper</a></li>



<li>Investigate new tools: Explore neural networks and k-nearest neighbours algorithms in the new maths-focused version of ML-Machine at <a href="http://math.ml-machine.org" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">math.ml-machine.org</a></li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Join our next seminar</h2>



<p>Join us at our next seminar on Tuesday 17 March from 17:00 to 18:30 GMT to hear Rebecca Fiebrink (University of the Arts London speak about teaching AI for creative practitioners. This will be the second seminar in our <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-can-we-teach-about-ai-in-the-arts-humanities-and-sciences-research-seminar-series-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new series on how to teach about AI across disciplines</a>. We hope to see you there!</p>



<p>To sign up and take part in our research seminars, click below:</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://form.raspberrypi.org/f/research-seminar-sign-up">I want to join the next seminar</a></div>
</div>



<p>You can also view the <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research/seminars" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">schedule of our upcoming seminars</a>, and catch up on past seminars on our <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research-impact/research/seminars/previous" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">previous seminars page</a>.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/embodied-machine-learning-from-research-ideas-to-classroom-activities/">Embodied machine learning: From research ideas to classroom activities</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/embodied-machine-learning-from-research-ideas-to-classroom-activities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Helping young people stay safe online in the age of AI</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/helping-young-people-stay-safe-online-in-the-age-of-ai/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/helping-young-people-stay-safe-online-in-the-age-of-ai/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rehana Al-Soltane]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 10:55:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Experience AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Safer Internet Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI literacy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=92535</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The online world that young people navigate today is different from the one we encountered just a few years ago: the search engines, social media platforms and digital tools they use to find information, interact with friends and complete schoolwork are now deeply embedded with AI technologies.&#160; While the core aims of online safety education&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/helping-young-people-stay-safe-online-in-the-age-of-ai/">Helping young people stay safe online in the age of AI</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The online world that young people navigate today is different from the one we encountered just a few years ago: the search engines, social media platforms and digital tools they use to find information, interact with friends and complete schoolwork are now deeply embedded with AI technologies.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="600" height="338" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AISAfetyImage1-1.png" alt="Experience AI Safety Image" class="wp-image-92537" style="width:690px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AISAfetyImage1-1.png 600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AISAfetyImage1-1-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AISAfetyImage1-1-500x282.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AISAfetyImage1-1-450x254.png 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>While the core aims of online safety education remain the same, the scope must now expand to include AI literacy: the ability to use, question and navigate AI tools so young people can make responsible choices online.</p>



<p>This is a shared challenge for anyone who supports young people as they navigate the online world: parents and carers, youth leaders and volunteers, and educators across all subjects. Many young people use these AI tools independently, often without guidance, so having open and useful conversations about trust, risk and responsibility matter just as much in the classroom as they do at dinner tables and <a href="https://codeclub.org/en/" type="link" id="https://codeclub.org/en/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Code Clubs</a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Why AI literacy is essential for staying safe online</strong></h2>



<p>At the Raspberry Pi Foundation, we have developed various AI literacy resources for educators, club leaders and parents to address this challenge in age-appropriate and practical ways. Our ‘<a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://experience-ai.org/en/units/ai-safety&amp;sa=D&amp;source=docs&amp;ust=1770717389628496&amp;usg=AOvVaw28EV01Fhuz9Z0QPe4hsfIB" type="link" id="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://experience-ai.org/en/units/ai-safety&amp;sa=D&amp;source=docs&amp;ust=1770717389628496&amp;usg=AOvVaw28EV01Fhuz9Z0QPe4hsfIB" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">AI safety</a>’ resources, part of our <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://experience-ai.org/en/&amp;sa=D&amp;source=docs&amp;ust=1770717389630227&amp;usg=AOvVaw3TRgOtlATMoIXXTx9jBOCR" type="link" id="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://experience-ai.org/en/&amp;sa=D&amp;source=docs&amp;ust=1770717389630227&amp;usg=AOvVaw3TRgOtlATMoIXXTx9jBOCR" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Experience AI programme</a>, are a set of free comprehensive teaching activities to support you in educating young people aged 11–14 in navigating key safety issues linked to AI, including privacy, misinformation, trust and responsibility. Delivered through videos, unplugged activities and discussions, the activities are adaptable to a range of learning settings, and reflect the real decisions young people are already making online.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="600" height="338" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AISAfetyImage2-1.png" alt="Experience AI safety image" class="wp-image-92538" style="width:746px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AISAfetyImage2-1.png 600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AISAfetyImage2-1-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AISAfetyImage2-1-500x282.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AISAfetyImage2-1-450x254.png 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>For example, in the ‘Trusted Sources’ activity from the ‘<a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://experience-ai.org/en/units/ai-safety/lessons/10&amp;sa=D&amp;source=docs&amp;ust=1770717389630681&amp;usg=AOvVaw2Jo55TLiPHrmNOKOk136Bu" type="link" id="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://experience-ai.org/en/units/ai-safety/lessons/10&amp;sa=D&amp;source=docs&amp;ust=1770717389630681&amp;usg=AOvVaw2Jo55TLiPHrmNOKOk136Bu" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Media literacy in the age of AI</a>’ lesson, young people reflect on the ways they look for information related to schoolwork, news and in their free time. They consider which sources are likely to allow the use of generative AI and how that affects their trustworthiness. Rather than labelling sources as ‘good’ or ‘bad’, learners explore questions around responsibility, credibility and oversight, and build practical skills for fact-checking and staying safe online.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Supporting responsible use of generative AI through Experience AI</strong></h2>



<p>Alongside the ‘AI safety’ resources, we have also developed a new ‘Large Language Models (LLMs)’ unit for learners aged 11–13 and 14–17, currently being tested in classrooms. The unit focuses on another important aspect of online safety: how young people interact responsibly with AI tools that generate content. While helpful, learners’ uncritical use of these tools could lead to cognitive offloading and limit the development of their higher-order thinking skills. The confident, persuasive tone of LLMs can also make it harder for young people to judge accuracy, recognise bias or notice missing information in outputs.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="600" height="338" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AISAfetyImage3-1.png" alt="Experience AI safety image" class="wp-image-92542" style="width:756px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AISAfetyImage3-1.png 600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AISAfetyImage3-1-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AISAfetyImage3-1-500x282.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AISAfetyImage3-1-450x254.png 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>To support the critical thinking skills that are essential for staying safe online, the new LLM unit includes research-informed lessons that explore how LLMs are created, why their outputs are not always accurate and how to evaluate AI-generated responses. The unit also encourages learners to reflect on when using an LLM is helpful to their learning, when it is not, and how they can remain in control of their own thinking, learning and skills development.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Starting the conversation this Safer Internet Day</strong></h2>



<p>Helping young people stay safe online in the age of AI doesn’t require having all the answers. Instead, it’s about creating the space to pause, question, and think critically about what they are encountering online. Through carefully designed, research-informed and pedagogically aligned AI literacy resources, we aim to help you start the conversations that empower young people to think critically, stay curious and remain in control of their learning and online lives.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AISAfetyImage4-1.png" alt="Experience AI safety image" class="wp-image-92544" style="width:742px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AISAfetyImage4-1.png 1920w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AISAfetyImage4-1-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AISAfetyImage4-1-500x281.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AISAfetyImage4-1-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AISAfetyImage4-1-1536x864.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AISAfetyImage4-1-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AISAfetyImage4-1-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AISAfetyImage4-1-900x506.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>This Safer Internet Day, we invite educators, parents and anyone who supports young people to explore our AI literacy resources and start the conversation. Visit the <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://experience-ai.org/en&amp;sa=D&amp;source=docs&amp;ust=1770717389630426&amp;usg=AOvVaw0L69xYI2VfzZHm1uudOFBi" type="link" id="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://experience-ai.org/en&amp;sa=D&amp;source=docs&amp;ust=1770717389630426&amp;usg=AOvVaw0L69xYI2VfzZHm1uudOFBi" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Experience AI website </a>for more information.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/helping-young-people-stay-safe-online-in-the-age-of-ai/">Helping young people stay safe online in the age of AI</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/helping-young-people-stay-safe-online-in-the-age-of-ai/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Join our new study on AI and data-driven computing in UK primary classrooms</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/join-our-new-study-on-ai-and-data-driven-computing-in-uk-primary-classrooms/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/join-our-new-study-on-ai-and-data-driven-computing-in-uk-primary-classrooms/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Bobby Whyte]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:39:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data-driven computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new study]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi Computing Education Research Centre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI literacy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=92517</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Are you a primary school teacher in England, Scotland or Wales interested in AI and data science and how students learn about AI and data in computing? The Raspberry Pi Computing Education Research Centre is starting an exciting new research project investigating how to teach about AI and data in the primary computing classroom, and&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/join-our-new-study-on-ai-and-data-driven-computing-in-uk-primary-classrooms/">Join our new study on AI and data-driven computing in UK primary classrooms</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Are you a primary school teacher in England, Scotland or Wales interested in AI and data science and how students learn about AI and data in computing?</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="600" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/01/Young-people-doing-digital-making-1.png" alt="" class="wp-image-86142" style="width:688px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/01/Young-people-doing-digital-making-1.png 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/01/Young-people-doing-digital-making-1-300x180.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/01/Young-people-doing-digital-making-1-500x300.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/01/Young-people-doing-digital-making-1-768x461.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/01/Young-people-doing-digital-making-1-800x480.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/01/Young-people-doing-digital-making-1-450x270.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/01/Young-people-doing-digital-making-1-900x540.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>The <a href="https://computingeducationresearch.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Raspberry Pi Computing Education Research Centre</a> is starting an exciting new research project investigating how to teach about AI and data in the primary computing classroom, and we would like you to get involved.</p>



<p>The study will look at:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>How AI and data-driven computing is currently taught (e.g. using Machine Learning for Kids, Google’s Teachable Machine)</li>



<li>What key ideas about AI and data young people need to understand</li>



<li>How young people make sense of working with data in computing</li>
</ul>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://rpf.io/data-science-study-blog" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Register here</a></div>
</div>



<p>The study involves attending a workshop in Cambridge, co-designing a unit of work, and then teaching it. Where necessary, we can reimburse you for reasonable expenses, such as supply cover, travel, and accommodation.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2560" height="1709" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_030-scaled.jpg" alt="A teacher assisting a young person with a coding project." class="wp-image-89308" style="aspect-ratio:1.4979937583593401;width:690px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_030-scaled.jpg 2560w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_030-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_030-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_030-768x513.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_030-1536x1026.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_030-2048x1367.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_030-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_030-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_030-900x601.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>Our aim for the study is to understand how primary school teachers approach teaching about data-driven technologies, and to find suitable methods for building young people’s confidence in working with data in computing lessons.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What is data-driven computing?</strong></h2>



<p>Research has suggested that new data-driven technologies such as AI and machine learning (or ML) require <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/a-research-led-framework-for-teaching-about-models-in-ai-and-data-science/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a different approach to teaching about problem-solving</a> in the computing classroom. Instead of defining a set of rules (e.g. if-then-else statements, or a <strong>rule-based</strong> approach), learners must instead collect lots of data to train a model (a <strong>data-driven</strong> approach) such as using Google’s Teachable Machine to classify image data.</p>



<p>For educators and resource developers, we still lack a clear understanding of how to teach young people about how rule-based and data-driven systems differ, how we can talk about them, and how we develop young people’ mental models. We hope this study will help us to find practical ways for primary teachers to build young people’s understanding of AI data in the primary computing classroom.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What does the study involve?</strong></h2>



<p>If you teach at primary level (Years 4, 5 and 6 or P5–P7) in England, Scotland or Wales and are keen to shape how we teach young people about data-driven computing, we invite you to join our new study.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://rpf.io/data-science-study-blog" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Register here</a></div>
</div>



<p>As part of the study, you will attend a workshop with us in Cambridge to co-design a series of data-driven computing lessons to teach in your classroom.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="600" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/01/primary-ed.png" alt="A young learners in the classroom" class="wp-image-86110" style="width:724px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/01/primary-ed.png 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/01/primary-ed-300x180.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/01/primary-ed-500x300.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/01/primary-ed-768x461.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/01/primary-ed-800x480.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/01/primary-ed-450x270.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/01/primary-ed-900x540.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>Following the workshop, you will teach the unit of work in your classroom and we will observe one of your lessons and interview you about your experiences.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How can I take part?</strong></h2>



<p>If you are interested in taking part, register your interest by clicking the link below:</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://rpf.io/data-science-study-blog">Register here</a></div>
</div>



<p>If you have any questions about the project, you can email <a href="mailto:bobby.whyte@raspberrypi.org">bobby.whyte@raspberrypi.org</a>.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/join-our-new-study-on-ai-and-data-driven-computing-in-uk-primary-classrooms/">Join our new study on AI and data-driven computing in UK primary classrooms</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/join-our-new-study-on-ai-and-data-driven-computing-in-uk-primary-classrooms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to evaluate your use of classroom technology with the PICRAT framework</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-evaluate-your-use-of-classroom-technology-with-the-picrat-framework/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-evaluate-your-use-of-classroom-technology-with-the-picrat-framework/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Sayers]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 09:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pedagogy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quick reads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PICRAT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=92494</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>There’s always something new to consider when teaching with technology. From the latest advancements in AI, to new software and hardware updates, it can be difficult to know which tools to use and how to incorporate it effectively into your lessons. In today’s blog, we explore the PICRAT framework and how it can help you&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-evaluate-your-use-of-classroom-technology-with-the-picrat-framework/">How to evaluate your use of classroom technology with the PICRAT framework</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>There’s always something new to consider when teaching with technology. From the latest advancements in AI, to new software and hardware updates, it can be difficult to know which tools to use and how to incorporate it effectively into your lessons.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="263" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/PICRAT-QR-500x263.png" alt="" class="wp-image-92495" style="aspect-ratio:1.9011540651037624;width:715px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/PICRAT-QR-500x263.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/PICRAT-QR-300x158.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/PICRAT-QR-768x403.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/PICRAT-QR-800x420.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/PICRAT-QR-450x236.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/PICRAT-QR-900x473.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/PICRAT-QR.png 1200w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>In today’s blog, we explore the PICRAT framework and how it can help you reflect on your use of technology in the classroom.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also share our new <a href="http://the-cc.io/qr29" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PICRAT Quick Read</a>, which you can download for free to: </p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Find practical tips on how to use the PICRAT model when planning your lessons</li>



<li>Read a summary of the research behind the framework</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What is the PICRAT framework?</strong></h2>



<p>Technology is constantly changing, and educators must continually decide what tools to use in their practice. To help with this challenge, researchers started developing theoretical models that teachers (especially student teachers) could use to reflect on how they integrate technology in their classrooms.</p>



<p>You might already be familiar with frameworks like TPACK (Technology, Pedagogy, and Content Knowledge) and SAMR (Substitution, Augmentation, Modification, Redefinition). While these models are useful, the PICRAT framework was created to address gaps in these earlier models, offering a clearer, student-focused approach. Significantly, it encourages you to treat technology as a tool to support learning, rather than the goal itself.</p>



<p>It asks two simple questions: “How are students experiencing the technology?” and “How does this impact your practice?”. The answers to these questions form a matrix as pictured below.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="288" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/PICRAT-Matrix-500x288.png" alt="" class="wp-image-92497" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/PICRAT-Matrix-500x288.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/PICRAT-Matrix-300x173.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/PICRAT-Matrix-450x259.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/PICRAT-Matrix.png 600w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>PIC (which runs along the y-axis) refers to the student&#8217;s relationship to the technology:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Passive – Students receive learning through technology</li>



<li>Interactive – Students interact with the content or other learning through technology </li>



<li>Creative – Students construct knowledge using technology</li>
</ul>



<p>RAT (which runs along the x-axis) refers to how the teacher uses the technology:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Replaces – Using technology but with an existing pedagogy</li>



<li>Amplifies – Using technology to improve pedagogy or outcomes</li>



<li>Transforms – Using technology to create new pedagogical practices</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How can I apply the PICRAT model?</strong></h2>



<p>First choose the lesson you’re planning to deliver. Consider what activities you’ll be running and the technologies involved. You’ll then be able to plot where they sit on the matrix using the PICRAT acronym.</p>



<p>For example, if you are teaching a lesson on Python loops, you might initially plan for students to watch a pre-recorded coding tutorial on their laptops. In this scenario, the student experience is Passive (receiving info via tech), and the teacher&#8217;s use is Replacement because the video simply replaces a live lecture. To move up the matrix, you could instead have students use an online IDE to complete a &#8220;Parson’s Problem&#8221; puzzle where they rearrange blocks of code to fix a loop. This shifts the activity to Interactive and Amplification, as the digital tool provides immediate debugging feedback that a paper-based exercise could not.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="288" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/Educator-Presenting-Clubs-Conference-2023-500x288.png" alt="Educator presenting in a classroom." class="wp-image-92500" style="width:552px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/Educator-Presenting-Clubs-Conference-2023-500x288.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/Educator-Presenting-Clubs-Conference-2023-300x173.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/Educator-Presenting-Clubs-Conference-2023-450x259.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/Educator-Presenting-Clubs-Conference-2023.png 600w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>Next, think about how you might move your practice forwards. Although every position on the matrix has its own value, the framework is hierarchical. The overall goal is to try to move your practice towards the top right of the matrix to be Creative and Transformative.</p>



<p>To help you achieve this, take some time to reflect on your current lessons, activities, and the technologies you use. Ask yourself questions like:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>What does the technology I’m using offer that could be used to amplify my practice?
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>What benefits would this have for students?</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Does the technology present opportunities for students to interact with each other, not just the technology?</li>



<li>What other technological tools might support collaboration? </li>
</ul>



<p>Research highlights that technology is rarely used in ways that allow young people to be creative. By using the PICRAT matrix, teachers can identify missed opportunities and explore ways to transform their lessons, ensuring learners can be creative and thrive.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The benefits of the PICRAT model</strong></h2>



<p>Potential benefits for educators:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>The framework encourages meaningful reflections, allowing teachers to easily evaluate how they’re using technology within their lessons</li>



<li>Reflections and the PICRAT matrix helps teachers to identify missed opportunities and gaps in their practice, ultimately leading to better student experiences</li>
</ul>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2200" height="1467" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AI-research-summit-10.jpg" alt="Photo of educators sharing ideas in a classroom." class="wp-image-92505" style="aspect-ratio:1.5015248128638758;width:539px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AI-research-summit-10.jpg 2200w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AI-research-summit-10-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AI-research-summit-10-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AI-research-summit-10-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AI-research-summit-10-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AI-research-summit-10-2048x1366.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AI-research-summit-10-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AI-research-summit-10-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/AI-research-summit-10-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 2200px) 100vw, 2200px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>You can use the PICRAT framework as part of your own reflections, or as part of a group activity. It’s a great way to spark discussion about technology integration with colleagues and improve best practices.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Want to find out more about the PICRAT framework?</strong></h2>



<p>If you’d like to learn more about the PICRAT model, you can download our Quick Read for free via our new <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/teach/pedagogy/quick-reads?utm_source=rpf_blog&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;utm_campaign=Quick-Reads-promotion-2026&amp;utm_id=Quick-Reads-promotion&amp;utm_content=February">Pedagogy Quick Reads page</a>.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="http://the-cc.io/qr29">Download the PICRAT Pedagogy Quick Read</a></div>
</div>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-evaluate-your-use-of-classroom-technology-with-the-picrat-framework/">How to evaluate your use of classroom technology with the PICRAT framework</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-evaluate-your-use-of-classroom-technology-with-the-picrat-framework/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A day with young creators at Coolest Projects Mzansi 2025</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/a-day-with-young-creators-at-coolest-projects-mzansi-2025/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/a-day-with-young-creators-at-coolest-projects-mzansi-2025/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tanaka Dhliwayo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:06:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Coolest Projects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coolest projects 2026]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coolest Projects South Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[young creators]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=92448</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Coolest Projects is the world’s leading technology showcase for young people, a space where creativity, curiosity, and problem-solving come together through code. Last November, Coolest Projects returned to South Africa, providing another exciting opportunity to celebrate and amplify the voices of young digital creators across Mzansi, a local name for South Africa. Coolest Projects brings&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/a-day-with-young-creators-at-coolest-projects-mzansi-2025/">A day with young creators at Coolest Projects Mzansi 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Coolest Projects is the world’s leading technology showcase for young people, a space where creativity, curiosity, and problem-solving come together through code. Last November, <a href="https://online.coolestprojects.org/">Coolest Projects</a> returned to South Africa, providing another exciting opportunity to celebrate and amplify the voices of young digital creators across Mzansi, a local name for South Africa.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="384" height="512" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/unnamed-4.jpg" alt="A student working on their project." class="wp-image-92466" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/unnamed-4.jpg 384w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/unnamed-4-188x250.jpg 188w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 384px) 100vw, 384px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>Coolest Projects brings young people together to share what excites them the most about creating with technology, whether that&#8217;s making a game, a website, a robot, or a simple Scratch animation. What matters most is not perfection, but participation.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A showcase for young makers</h2>



<p>Coolest Projects, an initiative of the Raspberry Pi Foundation, is brought to South Africa by our long-standing partner <a href="https://coderlevelup.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Coder:LevelUp</a>, giving young people the space to share how they get creative with technology.</p>



<p>I spent the day surrounded by young people explaining their ideas with a mix of excitement, nerves, and confidence — the kind of emotions you get when you build something yourself and someone is finally asking you about it.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="384" height="512" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/unnamed-2.jpg" alt="A group of people standing around a table." class="wp-image-92463" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/unnamed-2.jpg 384w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/unnamed-2-188x250.jpg 188w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 384px) 100vw, 384px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>The event brought together over 250 young people to share the projects they had been working on. Some had been preparing for months, while others had begun exploring their ideas more recently. All of them arrived ready to explain what they made, how it worked, and what they would do differently next time.</p>



<p>There wasn&#8217;t a single kind of project. There was a Scratch animation at one table, a game at the next, and a hardware project across the room. Some projects were polished, others rougher around the edges. But the event isn’t about perfection, it&#8217;s about learning and having the courage to show your work.</p>



<p>For a lot of participants, this was the first time they had presented their work to an audience, and you could see their confidence build as they spoke. By the end of the day, many were already talking about what they wanted to build next! From experience, we know that many of these young people will come back to Coolest Projects in the future, with our <a href="https://static.raspberrypi.org/files/coolestprojects/Coolest_Projects_2025_impact_report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">global impact data</a> showing that over 1 in 10 participants in the <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/coolest-projects-2025-where-11980-young-tech-creators-shared-their-ideas/">Coolest Projects online showcase in 2025</a> had also taken part in Coolest Projects in 2024.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The coolest projects and the coolest people</h2>



<p>One of my favourite things about Coolest Projects is that although you might come for the projects, what stays with you is often the people behind them. Coolest Projects celebrates both what young people build and who they are becoming.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">The coolest projects</h3>



<p>A project that really stood out to me was created by a group of girls who built a language app that translates words from isiZulu, one of South Africa’s official languages, into French and other languages — an ambitious and thoughtful idea.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="375" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/unnamed-5-500x375.jpg" alt="A group of students looking at a computer screen." class="wp-image-92467" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/unnamed-5-500x375.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/unnamed-5-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/unnamed-5-450x338.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/unnamed-5.jpg 512w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>What made this project especially meaningful to me was how well it reflected South Africa’s identity as a rainbow nation, with 12 official languages and countless cultures intersecting everyday. Their work wasn&#8217;t just technical, it was deeply relevant. It showed how young creators are already thinking about inclusion, communication, and using technology to bridge the gap between people in different parts of the country. Seeing these young girls confidently present such a culturally aware solution was incredibly inspiring.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">And the coolest people</h3>



<p>A group of boys arrived with a project that, honestly, fell apart on the day. Things didn’t work the way they had planned. But instead of shutting down or panicking, they laughed it off, explained what should have happened, and kept the energy positive. Their confidence, humour, and teamwork were great to see.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="384" height="512" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/unnamed-3.jpg" alt="A group of students standing around a table." class="wp-image-92460" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/unnamed-3.jpg 384w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/unnamed-3-188x250.jpg 188w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 384px) 100vw, 384px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>They showed that Coolest Projects is not about having everything work perfectly. It’s about showing up, trying something ambitious, and being willing to talk about what went wrong.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why does Coolest Projects matter?</h2>



<p>Coolest Projects goes beyond showcasing technical skills. It helps young people:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li>Build confidence in presenting ideas</li>



<li>Develop problem-solving and communication skills</li>



<li>See themselves as creators, not just consumers, of technology</li>
</ol>



<p>For many young creators in South Africa, participating in Coolest Projects is a powerful way to gain recognition and see that their ideas matter and that they belong in the world of technology.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="384" height="512" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/unnamed-6.jpg" alt="A project on a table." class="wp-image-92468" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/unnamed-6.jpg 384w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/02/unnamed-6-188x250.jpg 188w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 384px) 100vw, 384px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>We look forward to Coolest Projects South Africa returning in 2026 to once again showcase the incredible potential of young tech creators across the country.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Inspired to take part?</h2>



<p>The Coolest Projects 2026 global online showcase is now open for entries. Find all the details on how to enter, as well as details of Coolest Projects in-person events you can look forward to throughout 2026, in our <a href="http://rpf.io/cp-entries-2026" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">recent blog post</a>.</p>



<p>To be the first to hear about events near you, sign up to the <a href="http://rpf.io/coolestprojectsnews">Coolest Projects newsletter</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/a-day-with-young-creators-at-coolest-projects-mzansi-2025/">A day with young creators at Coolest Projects Mzansi 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/a-day-with-young-creators-at-coolest-projects-mzansi-2025/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A new qualification in data science and AI for students in England?</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/a-new-qualification-in-data-science-and-ai-for-students-in-england/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/a-new-qualification-in-data-science-and-ai-for-students-in-england/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Diane Dowling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 15:42:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI literacy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=92405</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>At the end of last year, Professor Becky Francis published her long-awaited Curriculum and Assessment Review for England, accompanied by the UK government’s official response. Buried within that response — and not actually proposed in the Review itself — was a notable commitment: to “explore introducing a new Level 3 qualification* in data science and&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/a-new-qualification-in-data-science-and-ai-for-students-in-england/">A new qualification in data science and AI for students in England?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>At the end of last year, Professor Becky Francis published her long-awaited <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/curriculum-and-assessment-review-final-report" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Curriculum and Assessment Review for England</a>, accompanied by the <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/curriculum-and-assessment-review-final-report-government-response" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">UK government’s official response</a>. Buried within that response — and not actually proposed in the Review itself — was a notable commitment: to “explore introducing a new Level 3 qualification* in data science and AI, to ensure that more young people can secure high-value skills for the future and that we cement the UK’s position as a global leader in AI and technology.”</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1300" height="731" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/11/Ada-CS-event.png" alt="Photo of a class of students at computers, in a computer science classroom." class="wp-image-91975" style="aspect-ratio:1.7794583773563921;width:660px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/11/Ada-CS-event.png 1300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/11/Ada-CS-event-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/11/Ada-CS-event-500x281.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/11/Ada-CS-event-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/11/Ada-CS-event-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/11/Ada-CS-event-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/11/Ada-CS-event-900x506.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1300px) 100vw, 1300px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>This announcement reflects a growing global recognition that young people need more than basic digital literacy — they need a deeper understanding of data, automation, and the rapidly evolving capabilities of AI. Countries around the world, from Singapore to the United States, are already wrestling with how to embed AI education into secondary schooling. England now joins that international conversation.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why AI education matters</h2>



<p>AI is an everyday technology now. Young people interact with AI systems constantly, often without realising it. Whether they pursue careers in medicine, engineering, the creative industries, or public policy, they will need a foundational understanding of how AI systems work, what their limitations are, and the ethical implications around them.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1225" height="816" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/03/image4.png" alt="A teenager learning computer science." class="wp-image-83499" style="aspect-ratio:1.5012566322256353;width:664px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/03/image4.png 1225w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/03/image4-300x200.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/03/image4-500x333.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/03/image4-768x512.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/03/image4-800x533.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/03/image4-450x300.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/03/image4-900x600.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1225px) 100vw, 1225px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>Yet in England — and in many education systems globally — very few students receive formal teaching about AI. The English national curriculum makes no explicit reference to AI, and specifications for exams taken at the end of high school include only scattered mentions. This gap leaves young people navigating one of the most transformative technologies of their generation with limited guidance.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Exploring a qualification: Opportunities and challenges</h2>



<p>In 2025, we joined forces with Professor Lord Lionel Tarassenko, one of the UK’s foremost researchers in AI and machine learning, and Simon Peyton Jones, a world-renowned computer scientist and long-time champion of computing education. Together with teachers, school leaders, universities, industry specialists, and exam boards, we have been exploring how we might begin to close the emerging gap in AI and data science education for 16- to 18-year-olds.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1920" height="1280" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/02/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-22.jpg" alt="A group of young people in a lecture hall." class="wp-image-86380" style="width:688px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/02/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-22.jpg 1920w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/02/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-22-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/02/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-22-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/02/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-22-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/02/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-22-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/02/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-22-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/02/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-22-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/02/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-22-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>Over the past eight months, this collaboration has allowed us to refine our shared thinking and gather insights from a wide network of experts and practitioners. We are delighted that England&#8217;s Department for Education has recognised the potential of this work by appointing us to draft the subject content for a possible new qualification in Data Science and AI.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>We are delighted that England&#8217;s Department for Education has recognised the potential of [the work we&#8217;ve been doing] by appointing us to draft the subject content for a possible new qualification in Data Science and AI.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Designing a qualification of this kind raises important questions — not just for the UK, but for any country considering a similar path.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What knowledge and skills should young people gain from the qualification?</h3>



<p>A meaningful qualification must go beyond the use of tools. It should help students understand data literacy, model behaviour, bias, ethics, and the societal implications of AI. Balancing technical understanding with critical thinking is challenging but essential.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">How do we ensure the qualification is accessible and inclusive?</h3>



<p>AI should not become the preserve of already-advantaged students. Any qualification must be designed with equity in mind, recognising differences in school capacity, teacher expertise, and students’ prior experience.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">How do we support teachers to deliver the qualification?</h3>



<p>Teacher professional development is a major challenge worldwide. Delivering a qualification in AI will require confidence with concepts that are not yet common in teacher training. Sustainable delivery models — supported by high-quality resources and professional development — will be crucial.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What form should the qualification take?</h3>



<p>There is an active debate about whether the best route for students in England is a high-stakes qualification or a supplementary course that broadens a core programme of study:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>An <strong>A level</strong> provides structure, national recognition, and clear progression into higher education or employment.</li>



<li>An <strong>Extended Project Qualification (EPQ)</strong> may offer more flexibility, allowing students to explore AI through research or practical investigation without requiring schools to timetable a full qualification.</li>
</ul>



<p>Different countries will make different choices based on their systems, but the underlying questions are the same: how do we create something rigorous, scalable, and future-proof?</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What we’ve learned so far</h2>



<p>In October, the Foundation hosted a workshop with representatives from schools, industry, universities, exam boards, and the Department for Education. Together, we explored key questions including:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>How do we make a qualification compelling &#8211; both for students who choose it and for schools that offer it?</strong></li>



<li><strong>What delivery models will genuinely support teachers to succeed?</strong></li>
</ol>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1920" height="1280" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-16.jpg" alt="An undergraduate student is raising his hand up during a lecture at a university." class="wp-image-87822" style="width:680px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-16.jpg 1920w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-16-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-16-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-16-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-16-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-16-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-16-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-16-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>The feedback we received has been invaluable and will continue to shape the next stage of development. We believe the UK has a significant opportunity to contribute meaningfully to the global conversation about AI education. You can read the <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/11LEDHgEJLClOeeXScNoypksr1w-1sEXQ/view?usp=sharing" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">latest version of our discussion paper here</a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A global call for insights</h2>



<p>Although the current proposal focuses on England, the underlying challenge is international: <strong>how do we prepare young people everywhere to engage thoughtfully and confidently with AI?</strong></p>



<p>We would love to hear from educators, researchers, and policymakers across the world:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Do you know of any successful qualifications or programmes for 16- to 18-year-olds that centre AI or data science?</strong></li>



<li><strong>What lessons should countries learn from each other?</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>To share your ideas or feedback, please <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/contact/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">get in touch</a>. We’d be delighted to learn from your experience as this important work progresses.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<div style="height:20px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<p>* Level 3 in England is the stage of learning for 16- to 19-year-olds, typically ending in qualifications that pave the way for higher study or advanced apprenticeships.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/a-new-qualification-in-data-science-and-ai-for-students-in-england/">A new qualification in data science and AI for students in England?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/a-new-qualification-in-data-science-and-ai-for-students-in-england/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to strategically plan your computing curriculum</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-strategically-plan-your-computing-curriculum/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-strategically-plan-your-computing-curriculum/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Sayers]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 09:42:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quick reads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Learning Graphs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pedagogy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=92389</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Traditionally, curriculum planning has often looked like a linear list: Topic A leads to Topic B, which leads to Topic C. However, as educators we know that learning rarely happens in such a simple, linear way. Concepts are regularly covered in different overlapping topics, and students can often take different routes to reach the same&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-strategically-plan-your-computing-curriculum/">How to strategically plan your computing curriculum</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Traditionally, curriculum planning has often looked like a linear list: Topic A leads to Topic B, which leads to Topic C. However, as educators we know that learning rarely happens in such a simple, linear way. Concepts are regularly covered in different overlapping topics, and students can often take different routes to reach the same destination.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="261" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image4-1-500x261.png" alt="Image displaying the Learning Graphs Quick Read." class="wp-image-92390" style="width:661px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image4-1-500x261.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image4-1-300x157.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image4-1-768x401.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image4-1-800x418.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image4-1-450x235.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image4-1-900x470.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image4-1.png 1200w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>In today’s blog we’re exploring learning graphs, a helpful tool that you can use to plan your computer science curriculum. We’ll share how they can provide educators with a clear, structured way to visualise students’ non-linear progression in a subject.</p>



<p>We also share our new <a href="https://the-cc.io/qr28" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pedagogy Quick Read about learning graphs</a>, which you can download for free to:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Find practical tips on how you can use learning graphs to design your curriculum</li>



<li>Read a summary of the research behind them</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What is a learning graph?</h2>



<p>A learning graph is a visual tool for curriculum planning that moves beyond simple lists. At its core, a learning graph is a network of ‘nodes’ (specific concepts and skills) and ‘links’ (the connections between them).</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="227" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image2-2-500x227.png" alt="Image from the Learning Graphs Quick Read that showcases an example of a learning graph." class="wp-image-92391" style="width:650px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image2-2-500x227.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image2-2-300x136.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image2-2-768x349.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image2-2-800x364.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image2-2-450x205.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image2-2-900x409.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image2-2.png 1530w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>Learning graphs build on research into ‘<a href="https://www.cpre.org/sites/default/files/researchreport/1220_learningtrajectoriesinmathcciireport.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">learning progressions</a>’ and ‘knowledge maps’. They are a practical tool that educators can use to design and validate different curricula. For example, they can help teachers to:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Visualise and map progression</li>



<li>Identify curriculum gaps, so educators can shape and restructure learning experiences as necessary</li>



<li>Ensure the use of consistent terminology</li>



<li>Sequence learning and manage <a href="https://the-cc.io/qr01" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">cognitive load</a></li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How to create a learning graph</h2>



<p>Building a learning graph is an iterative process that helps you think critically about how different parts of your curriculum relate to each other.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Nodes and links</h3>



<p>The first step in creating a learning graph is often to identify your start and end nodes. First, you consider the key concepts and skills that your learners must acquire by the end of a series of lessons. This gives you some end nodes to work towards. Then, you think about learners’ existing knowledge, to help determine your start point. You then work backwards and forwards between these points to identify the different nodes that learners need to cover to get from the beginning to the end.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image3-500x333.jpg" alt="Educators sharing ideas around a table." class="wp-image-92392" style="width:617px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image3-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image3-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image3-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image3-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image3-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image3-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image3-900x600.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image3.jpg 1999w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>Once you have determined your nodes, you add them to your graph and connect them via ‘links’ until your graph is complete. Where knowledge of particular concepts or skills is essential for learning others, you connect the nodes with solid lines. For prior learning that is helpful but not essential, you use dotted lines.</p>



<p>When developing a learning graph, there isn’t a specific level of granularity that you have to work towards. Progression can be as detailed or as high-level as you need. This makes them a helpful tool in creating bespoke learning experiences and curricula for learners.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Collaboration and development</h3>



<p>It is most effective to design learning graphs collaboratively within a small group. This allows curriculum designers to discuss their ideas and challenge each other’s thinking, which helps hone the designs.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1311" height="874" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image1-1-edited-1.jpg" alt="Educators collaborating using post-it notes, planning currciulum." class="wp-image-92395" style="width:683px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image1-1-edited-1.jpg 1311w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image1-1-edited-1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image1-1-edited-1-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image1-1-edited-1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image1-1-edited-1-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image1-1-edited-1-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image1-1-edited-1-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1311px) 100vw, 1311px" /></figure>



<p>When creating learning graphs, it can be extremely useful to use a tool that is dynamic and allows you to move elements and make changes quickly and easily. At the Raspberry Pi Foundation, our team has experimented with a range of tools, including using editable shapes in Google Slides, collaborating in Figma, and arranging sticky notes on paper. We recommend finding a tool that works for you and the educators you are working with. Although it can work, we suggest avoiding using a pen and paper if possible, as designs can quickly become messy and difficult to navigate after lots of iterations.</p>



<p>The process of designing learning graphs has strong links to <a href="https://the-cc.io/qr25" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ABC learning design</a> and the creation of <a href="https://the-cc.io/qr07" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">concept maps</a>, which can also be used for curriculum planning.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Learning graphs in your teaching</h2>



<p>Once created, learning graphs can support you to design and adapt your curricula and assess your students’ learning.</p>



<p>For example, to help sequence learning, you can track or predict the paths through a topic most commonly taken by learners and use this to inform your curriculum design.</p>



<p>If you are adapting a unit of work for a specific qualification or new context, you can prune nodes that are not relevant and add any further knowledge and skills your learners need, then use the new learning graph to guide you as you develop the unit.</p>



<p>Finally, you can assess which node a learner has completed, and use this to identify the next logical step in their learning, ensuring the difficulty level is always appropriate.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Using learning graphs to support analysis</h2>



<p>Another benefit of learning graphs is that they can be combined with lots of other frameworks, for example, <a href="https://w.wiki/6AK6" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bloom’s taxonomy</a>. This allows you to better assess and validate the learning journeys you have designed, and ensure that they are suitably accessible, challenging, and relevant for your learners.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image5-500x333.jpg" alt="Photo of an educator presenting at the front of a classroom of other teachers." class="wp-image-92396" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image5-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image5-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image5-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image5-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image5-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image5-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image5-900x600.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image5.jpg 1999w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>There are a number of ways that you could link your learning graphs to other frameworks, such as annotating nodes with extra information, or using colour coding.</p>



<p>As well as working with learning graphs for specific learning experiences, you can connect multiple learning graphs together and analyse how they intersect. This can help identify inconsistencies between connected sequences of lessons. It can also help uncover broader themes of progression and highlight alternative learning pathways you might not have considered.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Find out more about learning graphs</h2>



<p>If you’d like to find out more about learning graphs, you can download our Pedagogy Quick Read for free.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://the-cc.io/qr28">Download the learning graphs Pedagogy Quick Read</a></div>
</div>



<p>To find out more about how we use learning graphs when planning curriculum resources at the Raspberry Pi Foundation, take a look at our <a href="https://s3.eu-west-2.amazonaws.com/static.raspberrypi.org/files/curriculum/reports/Teaching+and+learning+design+principles+%E2%80%93%C2%A0Raspberry+Pi+Foundation.pdf">teaching and learning design principles</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-strategically-plan-your-computing-curriculum/">How to strategically plan your computing curriculum</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-strategically-plan-your-computing-curriculum/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fostering Kenya’s computing education ecosystem</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/fostering-kenyas-computing-education-ecosystem/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/fostering-kenyas-computing-education-ecosystem/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sandra Keeru]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:01:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kenya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kenya partner showcase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ecosystem]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=92354</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In November, our first-ever Kenya Partner Showcase brought together all our partners from across the country for two days of collaboration, learning, and shared strategy. What stood out to us most from the event was not just the diversity of work that the Kenyan partners are doing in computing education, but also the clear alignment&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/fostering-kenyas-computing-education-ecosystem/">Fostering Kenya’s computing education ecosystem</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In November, our first-ever Kenya Partner Showcase brought together all our partners from across the country for two days of collaboration, learning, and shared strategy. What stood out to us most from the event was not just the diversity of work that the Kenyan partners are doing in computing education, but also the clear alignment that is emerging across partners, government, and communities.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2000" height="1333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0742.jpg" alt="A speaker at the Raspberry Pi Foundation's Kenya Partner Showcase 2025, smiling and holding a microphone." class="wp-image-92360" style="aspect-ratio:1.500418643594753;width:756px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0742.jpg 2000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0742-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0742-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0742-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0742-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0742-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0742-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0742-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>Partners used the Showcase to present sessions about their journeys implementing the Foundation’s programmes, sharing achievements and insights that strengthened the collective learning space. The conversations during our two days together reflected a maturing ecosystem and demonstrated how structured government buy-in is accelerating adoption of <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-our-computing-curriculum-resources-for-kenya-the-journey-so-far/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our localised Computing Curriculum</a> and influencing national policy spaces.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;Through these programmes, we are equipping young people to become future-ready leaders of integrity and impact.” – Betty Oloo Anderson, National Executive Officer, Kenya Girl Guides Association</p>
</blockquote>



<p>It was encouraging to see how far computing education has evolved since we began working with Kenyan partners in 2023, signalling the collective effort and commitment driving this work forward.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Partner-led sessions to reflect on what works</h2>



<p>The sessions revealed a powerful shift already taking place in classrooms, with partners demonstrating how embedding The Computing Curriculum into Teacher Professional Development frameworks is building teacher confidence and elevating the quality of classroom instruction through stronger digital competencies and culturally relevant pedagogy. The <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/impact-of-experience-ai-in-kenya/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">partner presentation on Experience AI</a>, our <a href="https://experience-ai.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">AI literacy programme</a>, was especially powerful. It reframed the national dialogue from questioning whether AI might take over the classroom to recognising the real capacities and limitations of AI tools, and the central role teachers play in guiding young people to use and create AI tools in safe, ethical ways.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;Running Raspberry Pi Foundation programmes has been a transformative journey. It has challenged us to innovate, document rigorously, and continually place learners at the center of every decision. The structured support, tools, and community of practice have enabled us to deliver programmes with greater impact and accountability.” Joel Kahindi, Programme Coordinator, STEAMLabs Africa</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Hands-on demonstrations, from physical computing with Raspberry Pi Pico to teacher development transitions from Scratch to Python, highlighted how practical computing is taking root in both formal and non-formal learning environments.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-blog-entry"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="800" height="534" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/Kenya_Partner_Showcase_2025-800x534.jpg" alt="Attendees have a conversation at the Raspberry Pi Foundation's Kenya Partner Showcase 2025." class="wp-image-92377" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/Kenya_Partner_Showcase_2025-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/Kenya_Partner_Showcase_2025-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/Kenya_Partner_Showcase_2025-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/Kenya_Partner_Showcase_2025-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/Kenya_Partner_Showcase_2025-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/Kenya_Partner_Showcase_2025-2048x1366.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/Kenya_Partner_Showcase_2025-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/Kenya_Partner_Showcase_2025-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>Partners from remote and underserved regions shared how locally contextualised computing tools and programmes we offer are reaching learners in ASAL (arid and semi-arid land) regions, strengthening literacy and digital confidence even in low-resource settings. Complementing this, curriculum-focused partners highlighted how structured computing resources are being adapted for ASAL contexts, reinforcing foundational skills at scale. Efforts around community-centred connectivity are enabling schools, especially in underserved communities, to finally access reliable high-speed internet.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;Through [our partnership with the Raspberry Pi Foundation], we are not only strengthening our programmes but also expanding our vision for what meaningful learning can look like across underserved communities.” – Joel Kahindi, Programme Coordinator, STEAMLabs Africa</p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2000" height="1333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0822.jpg" alt="A speaker at the Raspberry Pi Foundation's Kenya Partner Showcase 2025, smiling and holding a microphone." class="wp-image-92361" style="aspect-ratio:1.500418643594753;width:734px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0822.jpg 2000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0822-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0822-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0822-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0822-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0822-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0822-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0822-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>A notable pattern that emerged was how existing collaborations are now opening doors to new ones, with partners building on their relationship with us to form additional partnerships for devices, connectivity, and shared learning, creating a more holistic digital ecosystem for learners.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Solving shared problems, sharing real stories</h2>



<p>A major anchor of the Showcase was the <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/celebrating-impact-code-clubs-are-thriving-in-kenya-and-south-africa/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Code Club</a> co-creation sprint. Implementing partners worked through real barriers and opportunities: easier onboarding for educators, continuous training, integrating clubs into school calendars, learner-led ownership, and sustainable models that last beyond donor funding. There was strong interest in forming a unified Code Club Kenya partner network to streamline communication, resource-sharing, and visibility, and our team is now exploring what it would take to bring this to life.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2000" height="1333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0720.jpg" alt="A speaker at the Raspberry Pi Foundation's Kenya Partner Showcase 2025, smiling and holding a microphone." class="wp-image-92356" style="aspect-ratio:1.500418643594753;width:700px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0720.jpg 2000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0720-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0720-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0720-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0720-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0720-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0720-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0720-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>One message echoed across sessions: the power of telling real stories. Partners expressed a shared desire to spotlight creator projects, Code Club leader journeys, and regional experiences more consistently, through social media, case studies and impact stories, and shared platforms, to make progress visible and inspire more schools to adopt computing and digital skills.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">From isolation to coordination</h2>



<p>By the close of the Showcase, the takeaway was clear: Kenya’s digital learning ecosystem is no longer a set of isolated efforts — it is a coordinated network that shares priorities, evidence-based insights, and a commitment to scaling impact together. As one partner reflected, “This Showcase created a space for joint learning and will help us scale our impact across the country.” It felt evident, too, that bringing these voices into one room is itself part of the work. For us at the Foundation, this Showcase reaffirmed the responsibility and privilege of stewarding a network that is shaping what the future of learning computing in Kenya can look like.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2000" height="1333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0908.jpg" alt="Two attendees of the Raspberry Pi Foundation's Kenya Partner Showcase 2025 smile at the camera." class="wp-image-92364" style="aspect-ratio:1.500418643594753;width:708px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0908.jpg 2000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0908-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0908-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0908-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0908-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0908-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0908-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0908-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>The Showcase marks the beginning of a new, aligned chapter for computing education in Kenya, one driven by collaboration, clarity, and a shared belief that we go further when we go together. With shared priorities for 2026, the momentum continues, and we will be continuing to highlight where this collective work is headed next.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Thank you to all partners</h2>



<p>We want to thank you to all our partners — Frontier Counties Development Council (FCDC), STEAMLabs Africa, Young Scientists Kenya, Kenya Girl Guides Association, Oasis Mathare, Futures Infinite, EmpServe Kenya, Kenya Connect, Tech Kidz Africa, Riara University, and M-Lugha — for your leadership, dedication, and unwavering belief in what is possible when we learn and build together.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2000" height="1333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0931.jpg" alt="Attendees mingle among tables and chairs at the Raspberry Pi Foundation's Kenya Partner Showcase 2025." class="wp-image-92367" style="aspect-ratio:1.500418643594753;width:753px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0931.jpg 2000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0931-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0931-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0931-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0931-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0931-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0931-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/IMG_0931-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>This Showcase was a reflection of your work, your commitment to learners, and your vision for a digitally empowered Kenya. We are grateful for your continued partnership and excited for all that lies ahead.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/fostering-kenyas-computing-education-ecosystem/">Fostering Kenya’s computing education ecosystem</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/fostering-kenyas-computing-education-ecosystem/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to put data first in K–12 AI education by using data case studies</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-put-data-first-in-k-12-ai-education-by-using-data-case-studies/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-put-data-first-in-k-12-ai-education-by-using-data-case-studies/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manni Cheung]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 11:35:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research seminar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI literacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research and impact]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=92324</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In Germany, as in many countries, AI topics are rapidly entering formal computer science education. Yet, this haste often risks us focusing on fleeting technological developments rather than fundamental concepts. As computer science educator Viktoriya Olari, from Free University of Berlin, discovered in her research, the fundamental role of data, which powers most modern AI&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-put-data-first-in-k-12-ai-education-by-using-data-case-studies/">How to put data first in K–12 AI education by using data case studies</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In Germany, <a href="https://computingeducationresearch.org/projects/computer-science-education-around-the-world/">as in many countries</a>, AI topics are rapidly entering formal computer science education. Yet, this haste often risks us focusing on fleeting technological developments rather than fundamental concepts. As computer science educator Viktoriya Olari, from Free University of Berlin, discovered in her research, the fundamental role of data, which powers most modern AI systems, is critically underestimated in many existing frameworks. If students are to become responsible designers of such systems, they can&#8217;t afford to treat AI as an opaque box. Rather, they must first master the messy, human process that begins with the data itself.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="1067" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image3.png" alt="Viktoriya Olari, from Free University of Berlin." class="wp-image-92325" style="aspect-ratio:1.4995397617918607;width:672px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image3.png 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image3-300x200.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image3-500x333.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image3-768x512.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image3-1536x1024.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image3-800x534.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image3-450x300.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image3-900x600.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Viktoriya Olari</figcaption></figure>
</div>


<p>In our October research seminar, Viktoriya shared the results of her work over the last four years on how schools can shift the focus from the latest technologies to the underlying data. Her research offers a clear structure for what young people should learn about data and how teachers can make it work inside ordinary classrooms.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why begin with data?</h2>



<p>Viktoriya’s analysis of existing AI education frameworks found the data domain is underrepresented, with essentials such as data cleaning often not addressed at all. She argues that, because modern AI systems are data driven, students need both language and routines for working with data: being able to name concepts like <strong>training vs test data</strong>, <strong>data quality</strong>, and <strong>bias</strong>, and to explain practices such as <strong>collection</strong>, <strong>cleaning</strong>, and <strong>pre-processing</strong>. That’s the rationale for teaching data concepts and practices first, and then placing modelling inside an explicit, staged lifecycle.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image4.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1906" height="1070" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image4.png" alt="Word clouds for two foundational components: data concepts and data practices." class="wp-image-92328" style="aspect-ratio:1.7813121272365806;width:696px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image4.png 1906w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image4-300x168.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image4-500x281.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image4-768x431.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image4-1536x862.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image4-800x449.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image4-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image4-900x505.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1906px) 100vw, 1906px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">A slide from Viktoriya&#8217;s presentation. Click to enlarge.</figcaption></figure>
</div>


<p>Her talk presented this argument in the German school context, where AI topics are entering state curricula quickly. Her critique targets how existing frameworks fail to address data and how that gap undermines responsible evaluation and design. The proposed model centres data by pairing an eight-stage, data-driven lifecycle with a curated set of key concepts and practices, and by making “data-based judgment skills” a key outcome.</p>



<p>Viktoriya&#8217;s work organises this understanding into two foundational components: data concepts (the vocabulary, e.g. training/test data, data quality, overfitting) and data practices (the actions, e.g. collect, clean, train, evaluate).</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A lifecycle for learning</h2>



<p>Viktoriya’s framework is built around an eight-stage data lifecycle, stretching from defining a task through gathering, preparing, modeling, evaluating, and finally sharing or archiving results. Inside that backbone she has identified two layers of learning targets:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Data concepts – roughly a hundred ideas that give teachers and students a common language, from “training vs. test data” and “bias” to “features”, “labels”, and “provenance”.</li>



<li>Data practices – 28 kinds of hands-on work (and 69 subpractices) that materialise those ideas: for instance collecting, cleaning, splitting datasets, checking quality, training and evaluating models, and handling privacy and deletion responsibly.</li>
</ul>



<p>More details are available in her work on data-related <a href="https://computingeducation.de/pub/2024_Olari-Romeike_Computers_Education_Open.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">concepts</a> and <a href="https://computingeducation.de/pub/2024_Olari-Romeike_WiPSCE2024.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">practice</a>.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image1-2.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1914" height="1072" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image1-2.png" alt="Viktoriya’s 8-stage process model of the data-driven lifecycle." class="wp-image-92331" style="aspect-ratio:1.785453337761541;width:760px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image1-2.png 1914w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image1-2-300x168.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image1-2-500x280.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image1-2-768x430.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image1-2-1536x860.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image1-2-800x448.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image1-2-450x252.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image1-2-900x504.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1914px) 100vw, 1914px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">A slide from Viktoriya&#8217;s presentation. Click to enlarge.</figcaption></figure>
</div>


<p>Viktoriya’s 8-stage process model of the data-driven lifecycle. It serves as a guide for curriculum developers and teachers, outlining 28 key data-related practices and providing 69 examples of subpractices for use in K–12 computer science education.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image2-1.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1906" height="1074" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image2-1.png" alt="A collection of 133 key data-related concepts." class="wp-image-92334" style="aspect-ratio:1.774726000264096;width:762px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image2-1.png 1906w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image2-1-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image2-1-500x282.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image2-1-768x433.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image2-1-1536x866.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image2-1-800x451.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image2-1-450x254.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image2-1-900x507.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1906px) 100vw, 1906px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">A slide from Viktoriya&#8217;s presentation. Click to enlarge.</figcaption></figure>
</div>


<p>A collection of 133 key data-related concepts. These concepts are organised according to the eight stages of the data-driven lifecycle and provide the foundational vocabulary for teaching AI education.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Making it teachable</h2>



<p>Viktoriya’s team set out to redesign the format so that real data work could happen within ordinary lessons. They ended up with three “<a href="https://computingeducation.de/pub/2025_Olari-Romeike_CompEd25.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Data Case Study</a>” architectures, each using authentic datasets and domain questions. The materials are supported by <a href="https://orangedatamining.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Orange 3</a>, an unplugged machine learning and data visualisations tool familiar to the teachers participating. Variants emerged across three design cycles to address specific challenges, but teachers choose among them based on learning objectives and class context.</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li>Bottom-up: Students create a workflow step by step (e.g. import, inspect, clean, transform, split, train, evaluate). This approach is excellent for procedural fluency, but teachers reported an over-emphasis on operating <em>Orange</em> and too little reflection on the lifecycle unless explicit reflection is added.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Top-down: Students start from a prepared workflow, read plots, infer the role of each branch, identify issues in the data/practices, and justify changes. This architecture directly counters the reflection gap seen in bottom-up and leans into reasoning rather than routine.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Puzzle-like: Using “widgets,” visualisations of data tables, that stand for parts of a data pipeline, students rebuild a valid flow collaboratively. This encourages discussion, works without devices, and makes thinking visible.</li>
</ol>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1904" height="1070" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image5.png" alt="The school-specific data case study" class="wp-image-92335" style="aspect-ratio:1.7794842938002715;width:698px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image5.png 1904w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image5-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image5-500x281.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image5-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image5-1536x863.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image5-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image5-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/image5-900x506.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1904px) 100vw, 1904px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">A slide from Viktoriya&#8217;s presentation.</figcaption></figure>
</div>


<p>The data case study method uses real-world data and context to help students achieve three key learning outcomes: go through the data-driven lifecycle, reflect on data practices and concepts in a criteria-guided manner, and develop data-based problem-solving and judgment skills.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What happened in the German classrooms</h2>



<p>Viktoriya’s team ran three design cycles with small groups in Germany, with students aged 14 to 15. Each cycle lasted around 48 hours of teaching. Because participating teachers already knew Orange 3, the emphasis was on pedagogy rather than software training.</p>



<p>The projects drew on manageable real-world data: spreadsheets, time-series sets, a few geographical samples. Two examples are:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Forecasting Berlin air quality – Students explored how data quality, feature choice, and evaluation metrics shape predictions, then argued which model best answered the civic question.</li>



<li>Classifying Tasmanian abalone – A deceptively simple dataset that invites talk about imbalance, feature engineering, and what counts as “good enough” accuracy.</li>
</ul>



<p>Some groups experimented with collecting their own sensor data, a plan that occasionally failed when the hardware didn’t cooperate. However, even that became part of the lesson: reliability, risk, and missing data are real features of data science, not mistakes to hide.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1132" height="755" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1058.jpg" alt="A computing classroom filled with learners" class="wp-image-32214" style="aspect-ratio:1.4993724724585134;width:738px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1058.jpg 1132w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1058-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1058-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1058-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1058-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1058-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1058-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1132px) 100vw, 1132px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>Student work reflected the three architectures. In the bottom-up groups, guided builds produced complete workflows and concise reflections, while top-down groups submitted annotated screenshots and critiques, and the puzzle-based lessons ended with posters and verbal presentations. Across them all, assessment focused on reasoning: not whether the “right” model appeared, but whether students could explain the stage they were in and justify their choices.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Teaching resources</h2>



<p>Everything Viktoriya described is open and classroom-ready (currently in German). The <a href="https://computingeducation.de/proj-datacases/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">computingeducation.de/proj-datacases</a> hub hosts teacher guides, student tasks, and sample Orange 3 files. The growing library of data cases covers topics from climate data to air quality analytics.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why it matters now</h2>



<p>In the UK, a <a href="https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/media/690b96bbc22e4ed8b051854d/Curriculum_and_Assessment_Review_final_report_-_Building_a_world-class_curriculum_for_all.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">curriculum review</a> has been recently released and along with the Government’s <a href="https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/media/690b2a4a14b040dfe82922ea/Government_response_to_the_Curriculum_and_Assessment_Review.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">response</a>. Across Europe and beyond, education systems are racing to add AI content to their curricula. Tools will come and go, and benchmarks will keep moving. What endures is the capacity to reason about data: to know what stage of work you’re in, what evidence supports your decisions, and what trade-offs you’re making. That is why Viktoriya&#8217;s contribution is unique — it gives teachers a map, a shared vocabulary, and practical ways to make data visible and the focus of discussion in schools.</p>



<p>You can <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/what-should-be-included-in-a-data-science-curriculum-for-schools/?_thumbnail_id=91767" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">read this blog to see how we&#8217;ve used Viktoriya&#8217;s framework</a> in our work designing a data science curriculum for schools.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Join our next seminar</h2>



<p>Join us at our seminar on Tuesday 27 January from 17:00 to 18:30 GMT to hear Salomey Afua Addo talk about <strong>how to teach about neural networks in Junior High Schools</strong> in Ghana.</p>



<p>To sign up and take part, click the button below. We’ll then send you information about joining.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://form.raspberrypi.org/f/research-seminar-sign-up">I want to sign up for the next seminar</a></div>
</div>



<p>We hope to see you there. This will be the final seminar in <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research-impact/research/seminars/previous/teaching-about-ai" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our series on teaching about AI and data science</a> — the next series focuses on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-can-we-teach-about-ai-in-the-arts-humanities-and-sciences-research-seminar-series-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to teach about applied AI across subjects and disciplines</a>.</p>



<p>You can view the <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research-impact/research/seminars" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">schedule of our upcoming seminars</a>, and catch up on past seminars on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research-impact/research/seminars/previous" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our previous seminars page</a>.</p>



<div style="height:20px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<div style="height:20px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Teachers in England, take part in our new data science study</h3>



<p>WKS2 teachers, participate in our new study!<br>We’re launching a new study to explore how to teach learners aged 9 to 11 about data-driven computing. The study will take place in collaboration with <strong>KS2 teachers (Y4/Y5/Y6) in England, Scotland and Wales </strong>and look at:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>What key ideas pupils need to understand</li>



<li>How teachers currently approach topics related to data-driven computing</li>



<li>How pupils make sense of data and probability</li>
</ul>



<p>Our goal is to find practical ways to help teachers build children’s confidence in working with data in computing lessons. The study will be collaborative, with two workshops held throughout 2026, and we’re inviting KS2 teachers (Y4/Y5/Y6) to take part.<br>You can express your interest in participating by filling in this form: <a href="https://rpf.io/data-science-study-blog" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">rpf.io/data-science-study-blog</a></p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-put-data-first-in-k-12-ai-education-by-using-data-case-studies/">How to put data first in K–12 AI education by using data case studies</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-put-data-first-in-k-12-ai-education-by-using-data-case-studies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Coolest Projects 2026: Opens for entries in January!</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/coolest-projects-2026-opens-for-entries-in-january/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/coolest-projects-2026-opens-for-entries-in-january/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Helen Gardner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 11:19:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Coolest Projects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Our impact]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[STEM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coolest projects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding for kids]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=92292</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Coolest Projects is our global technology showcase for young people up to age 18. It’s a place where young creators share the brilliant things they’ve made using digital technology — from first-ever Scratch projects and coding for fun experiments to ambitious robotics builds — with a global audience. Everyone who takes part receives certificates and&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/coolest-projects-2026-opens-for-entries-in-january/">Coolest Projects 2026: Opens for entries in January!</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Coolest Projects is our global technology showcase for young people up to age 18. It’s a place where young creators share the brilliant things they’ve made using digital technology — from first-ever Scratch projects and coding for fun<strong> </strong>experiments to ambitious robotics builds — with a global audience. Everyone who takes part receives certificates and rewards to celebrate their achievements.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What you need to know about Coolest Projects 2026</h2>



<p>Coolest Projects is open to any young person, anywhere in the world. Creators can submit their tech projects to our online showcase, explore the <a href="https://rpf.io/cp-25-gallery" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">global project gallery</a>, and join our special celebration livestream. There are in-person events in some countries for local creators, too (find out more below).</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="799" height="533" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54576484212_4227041373_c.jpg" alt="Young learner at Coolest Projects UK" class="wp-image-92302" style="aspect-ratio:1.4990765442232712;width:771px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54576484212_4227041373_c.jpg 799w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54576484212_4227041373_c-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54576484212_4227041373_c-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54576484212_4227041373_c-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54576484212_4227041373_c-450x300.jpg 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 799px) 100vw, 799px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>By taking part in Coolest Projects, young people can:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Join an international community of digital makers</li>



<li>Represent their country on a global stage</li>



<li>Receive feedback on their creations</li>



<li>Earn certificates to recognise their achievements</li>



<li>Celebrate their progress at our livestream event on 24 June 2026</li>
</ul>



<p>It is completely free to take part in Coolest Projects, and we welcome all kinds of digital technology projects — from first attempts to an ambitious STEM project or advanced build. Projects don’t need to be finished to be submitted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Creators can enter a project into one of seven categories: Scratch, Games, Hardware, Web, Mobile Apps, Advanced Programming, and the emergent category of AI.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How Coolest Projects makes a difference</h2>



<p>The findings from the <a href="https://rpf.io/cp-impact-2025" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Coolest Projects 2025 Impact report </a>offer clear, evidence-based insights into how Coolest Projects builds confidence, creativity, and a sense of belonging for young people around the world. In 2025, almost 12,000 young people from 41 countries took part in Coolest Projects online, a 57% increase on the previous year.&nbsp;This year, we’re excited to welcome even more creators to the Coolest Projects community.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="799" height="533" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54577531709_a53e2a634e_c.jpg" alt="Young learner with her project at Coolest Projects UK" class="wp-image-92306" style="aspect-ratio:1.4990765442232712;width:739px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54577531709_a53e2a634e_c.jpg 799w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54577531709_a53e2a634e_c-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54577531709_a53e2a634e_c-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54577531709_a53e2a634e_c-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54577531709_a53e2a634e_c-450x300.jpg 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 799px) 100vw, 799px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>Our annual evaluation shows that Coolest Projects continues to have a powerful impact on young digital creators worldwide. In 2025:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>100% of mentors and 72% of young people</strong> taking part in the online showcase said their confidence in digital making increased</li>



<li><strong>83% of young people</strong> felt inspired to continue learning and participating in computing after taking part</li>



<li><strong>74% of young creators</strong> and <strong>100% of mentors</strong> said Coolest Projects helped them or their team feel a sense of belonging in computing</li>



<li><strong>80%</strong> of surveyed young people said seeing projects from around the world made them feel part of a larger community of makers</li>
</ul>



<p>Creators told us how proud they felt sharing their work:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“It feels like I’m being noticed!” – Young creator, UK</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&nbsp;“I enjoyed presenting my project and seeing so many creative ideas from others.” – Young creator, India</p>
</blockquote>



<p>With many early-stage makers joining for the first time, including 55% of young people at in-person events, Coolest Projects continues to be an accessible entry point into the world of digital creativity.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="600" height="800" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54804957735_acc5a69e3e_c.jpg" alt="Young learner at Coolest Projects Ireland" class="wp-image-92309" style="aspect-ratio:0.7496427483777263;width:398px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54804957735_acc5a69e3e_c.jpg 600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54804957735_acc5a69e3e_c-188x250.jpg 188w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54804957735_acc5a69e3e_c-500x667.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54804957735_acc5a69e3e_c-450x600.jpg 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>We’re also proud to see growing participation from girls who code, who tell us they value the chance to share their ideas and be inspired by others. At in-person events, girls made up 63% of creators in India, 50% in the US, 39% in Ireland, and 37% in the UK. </p>



<p>Find out more about the incredible creativity and collaboration from mentors and makers worldwide in the <a href="https://rpf.io/cp-impact-2025">Coolest Projects 2025 impact report</a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How to take part in Coolest Projects</h2>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Come up with an idea</strong> — or choose something you’ve already made for school or a science fair project. Whether it started as a small classroom task or a personal coding challenge, any tech creation can be part of Coolest Projects. Our <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">projects site</a> offers hundreds of free, step-by-step guides — ideal for beginners, mentors, and anyone looking for engaging STEM activities for kids. The <a href="https://rpf.io/cp-25-gallery" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">2025 online gallery</a> is also a great place to find inspiration for your next cool coding project.</li>



<li><strong>Select your category.</strong> Our <a href="https://online.coolestprojects.org/categories" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">category pages</a> break down each of the seven categories, including our AI category.</li>



<li><strong>Work on the project</strong> individually or with friends. Young people can take part individually or in teams of up to five.</li>



<li><strong>Submit it</strong> via the Coolest Projects website by 27 May 2026. We encourage creators to take part in both the online showcase <strong>and</strong> their local in-person event — find the dates below.</li>



<li><strong>See your project showcased</strong> in our online gallery.</li>



<li><strong>Join the celebration livestream</strong> to discover creations from around the world on 24 June 2026.</li>
</ol>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://online.coolestprojects.org/take-part"><strong>I want to take part</strong></a></div>
</div>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="799" height="533" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54576484207_5fdff50913_c.jpg" alt="Presenter: Greg Foot interviewing a young learner at Coolest Projects" class="wp-image-92310" style="aspect-ratio:1.4990765442232712;width:705px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54576484207_5fdff50913_c.jpg 799w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54576484207_5fdff50913_c-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54576484207_5fdff50913_c-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54576484207_5fdff50913_c-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54576484207_5fdff50913_c-450x300.jpg 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 799px) 100vw, 799px" /></figure>
</div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Group codes for mentors entering multiple projects online</h2>



<p>If you’re entering several projects on behalf of your group, you can create a <strong>group code</strong> to link young people’s projects to your account.</p>



<p>Here’s a quick reminder of how it works:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Sign up or log in:</strong> Use your Raspberry Pi account or create a new one.</li>



<li><strong>Create a group:</strong> Add your group details, including name and country.</li>



<li><strong>Share your group code:</strong> Young people enter the code on their project submission form.</li>



<li><strong>Review and submit:</strong> View all linked projects in your group dashboard.</li>
</ul>



<p>There is no limit to the number of young people who can submit through one group code.</p>



<p>If you’d like a full walkthrough, watch our step-by-step group code <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ngYHRTzbDHI" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">‘how-to’ video</a>.</p>



<p>Whether your coders are beginners or experienced digital makers, there are lots of resources to support them. Visit the <a href="https://online.coolestprojects.org/guidance" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Coolest Projects guidance page</a> for mentor guides, session plans, and more.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Coolest Projects in-person events in 2026</h2>



<p>Alongside the global online showcase, Coolest Projects events will take place in several countries again this year. We encourage creators to take part in both their local in-person event and the global showcase.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="799" height="533" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54577678590_bc123bedc2_c.jpg" alt="Two young learner testing out a project at Coolest Projects UK" class="wp-image-92313" style="aspect-ratio:1.4990765442232712;width:741px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54577678590_bc123bedc2_c.jpg 799w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54577678590_bc123bedc2_c-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54577678590_bc123bedc2_c-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54577678590_bc123bedc2_c-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2026/01/54577678590_bc123bedc2_c-450x300.jpg 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 799px) 100vw, 799px" /></figure>
</div>


<p>Save the date for:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Coolest Projects Belgium – 14 March</li>



<li>Coolest Projects Japan – 29 March</li>



<li>Coolest Projects USA (Minnesota) – 11 April</li>



<li>Coolest Projects Ireland – 25 April</li>



<li>Coolest Projects USA (Georgia) – 2 May</li>



<li>Coolest Projects UK – 16 May</li>



<li>Coolest Projects Sudan (held in Egypt) – 12 August</li>



<li>Coolest Projects Nigeria – 29 August</li>
</ul>



<p>More dates coming soon for:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Coolest Projects Canada&nbsp;</li>



<li>Coolest Projects India</li>



<li>Coolest Projects Indonesia</li>



<li>Coolest Projects Malaysia</li>



<li>Coolest Projects South Africa</li>



<li>Coolest Projects Sri Lanka</li>
</ul>



<p>Sign up to the <a href="http://rpf.io/coolestprojectsnews" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Coolest Projects newsletter</a> to be the first to hear about events near you.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">We can’t wait to see what your young people create</h2>



<p>Whether your young people already have something they’re excited to share or they’re ready to start something new, Coolest Projects is the perfect place to celebrate their creativity, problem solving, and imagination.</p>



<p>We can’t wait to see the incredible projects they bring to Coolest Projects 2026.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://online.coolestprojects.org/take-part"><strong>I want to take part</strong></a></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/coolest-projects-2026-opens-for-entries-in-january/">Coolest Projects 2026: Opens for entries in January!</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/coolest-projects-2026-opens-for-entries-in-january/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
