<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Raspberry Pi Foundation</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/</link>
	<description>Teach, learn and make with Raspberry Pi</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 11:09:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/06/cropped-raspberrry_pi_logo-100x100.png</url>
	<title>Raspberry Pi Foundation</title>
	<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Free online course on understanding AI for educators</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/free-online-course-on-understanding-ai-for-educators/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/free-online-course-on-understanding-ai-for-educators/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mac Bowley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 11:09:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Experience AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online course]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teacher training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI education]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=88354</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>To empower every educator to confidently bring AI into their classroom, we&#8217;ve created a new online training course called ‘Understanding AI for educators’ in collaboration with Google DeepMind. By taking this course, you will gain a practical understanding of the crossover between AI tools and education. The course includes a conceptual look at what AI&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/free-online-course-on-understanding-ai-for-educators/">Free online course on understanding AI for educators</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>To empower every educator to confidently bring AI into their classroom, we&#8217;ve created a new online training course called <a href="https://www.edx.org/learn/education-teacher-training/raspberry-pi-foundation-teach-teens-computing-understanding-ai-for-teachers?utm_source=rpf-blog&amp;utm_medium=partner-marketing&amp;utm_campaign=raspberrypifoundation" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">‘Understanding AI for educators’</a> in collaboration with Google DeepMind. By taking this course, you will gain a practical understanding of the crossover between AI tools and education. The course includes a conceptual look at what AI is, how AI systems are built, different approaches to problem-solving with AI, and how to use current AI tools effectively and ethically.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/05/online-3412498_1280-500x333.jpg" alt="Image by Mudassar Iqbal from Pixabay" class="wp-image-58721" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/05/online-3412498_1280-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/05/online-3412498_1280-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/05/online-3412498_1280-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/05/online-3412498_1280-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/05/online-3412498_1280-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/05/online-3412498_1280-900x600.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/05/online-3412498_1280.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>In this post, I will share our approach to designing the course and some of the key considerations behind it — all of which you can apply today to teach your learners about AI systems.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Design decisions: Nurturing knowledge and confidence</h2>



<p>We know educators have different levels of confidence with AI tools — we designed this course to help create a level playing field. Our goal is to uplift every educator, regardless of their prior experience, to a point where they feel comfortable discussing AI in the classroom.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/06/RPi2-045-500x333.jpg" alt="Three computer science educators discuss something at a screen." class="wp-image-79983" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/06/RPi2-045-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/06/RPi2-045-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/06/RPi2-045-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/06/RPi2-045-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/06/RPi2-045-2048x1366.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/06/RPi2-045-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/06/RPi2-045-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/06/RPi2-045-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>AI literacy is key to understanding the implications and opportunities of AI in education. The course provides educators with a solid conceptual foundation, enabling them to ask the right questions and form their own perspectives.</p>



<p>As with all our AI learning materials that are part of <a href="https://experience-ai.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Experience AI</a>, we’ve used specific design principles for the course:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Choosing language carefully:</strong> We <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ai-education-anthropomorphism/">never anthropomorphise AI systems</a>, replacing phrases like “The model understands” with “The model analyses”. We do this to make it clear that AI is just a computer system, not a sentient being with thoughts or feelings.</li>



<li><strong>Accurate terminology</strong>: We avoid using AI as a singular noun, opting instead for the more accurate ‘AI tool’ when talking about applications or ‘AI system’ when talking about underlying component parts.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Ethics:</strong> The social and ethical impacts of AI are not an afterthought but highlighted throughout the learning materials.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Three main takeaways</h2>



<p>The course offers three main takeaways any educator can apply to their teaching about AI systems.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>1. Communicating effectively about AI systems</strong></h3>



<p>Deciding the level of detail to use when talking about AI systems can be difficult — especially if you&#8217;re not very confident about the topic. The <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ai-education-resources-what-to-teach-seame-framework/">SEAME framework</a> offers a solution by breaking down AI into 4 levels: social and ethical, application, model, and engine. Educators can focus on the level most relevant to their lessons and also use the framework as a useful structure for classroom discussions.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-blog-entry"><img decoding="async" width="800" height="416" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/03/Screenshot-2023-03-28-at-10.06.35-800x416.png" alt="The SEAME framework gives you a simple way to group learning objectives and resources related to teaching AI and ML, based on whether they focus on social and ethical aspects (SE), applications (A), models (M), or engines (E, i.e. how AI works)." class="wp-image-83522" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/03/Screenshot-2023-03-28-at-10.06.35-800x416.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/03/Screenshot-2023-03-28-at-10.06.35-300x156.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/03/Screenshot-2023-03-28-at-10.06.35-500x260.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/03/Screenshot-2023-03-28-at-10.06.35-768x399.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/03/Screenshot-2023-03-28-at-10.06.35-1536x798.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/03/Screenshot-2023-03-28-at-10.06.35-450x234.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/03/Screenshot-2023-03-28-at-10.06.35-900x468.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/03/Screenshot-2023-03-28-at-10.06.35.png 1590w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></figure></div>


<p>You might discuss the impact a particular AI system is having on society, without the need to explain to your learners how the model itself has been trained or tested. Equally, you might focus on a specific machine learning model to look at where the data used to create it came from and consider the effect the data source has on the output.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">2. Problem-solving approaches: Predictive vs. generative AI</h3>



<p>AI applications can be broadly separated into two categories: predictive and generative. These two types of AI model represent two vastly different approaches to <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/why-were-taking-a-problem-first-approach-to-the-development-of-ai-systems/">problem-solving</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>People create <strong>predictive AI models</strong> to make predictions about the future. For example, you might create a model to make weather forecasts based on previously recorded weather data, or to recommend new movies to you based on your previous viewing history. In developing predictive AI models, the problem is defined first — then a specific dataset is assembled to help solve it. Therefore, each predictive AI model usually is only useful for a small number of applications.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="241" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/RickPayne-and-team-Aiis.-Banner-1280x618-1-500x241.png" alt="Seventeen multicoloured post-it notes are roughly positioned in a strip shape on a white board. Each one of them has a hand drawn sketch in pen on them, answering the prompt on one of the post-it notes &quot;AI is....&quot; The sketches are all very different, some are patterns representing data, some are cartoons, some show drawings of things like data centres, or stick figure drawings of the people involved." class="wp-image-88362" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/RickPayne-and-team-Aiis.-Banner-1280x618-1-500x241.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/RickPayne-and-team-Aiis.-Banner-1280x618-1-300x145.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/RickPayne-and-team-Aiis.-Banner-1280x618-1-768x371.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/RickPayne-and-team-Aiis.-Banner-1280x618-1-800x386.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/RickPayne-and-team-Aiis.-Banner-1280x618-1-450x217.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/RickPayne-and-team-Aiis.-Banner-1280x618-1-900x435.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/RickPayne-and-team-Aiis.-Banner-1280x618-1.png 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Rick Payne and team / Better Images of AI / Ai is&#8230; Banner / CC-BY 4.0</figcaption></figure></div>


<p><strong>Generative AI models</strong> are used to generate media (such as text, code, images, or audio). The possible applications of these models are much more varied because people can use media in many different kinds of ways. You might say that the outputs of generative AI models could be used to solve — or at least to partially solve — any number of problems, without these problems needing to be defined before the model is created.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">3.&nbsp;Using generative AI tools: The OCEAN process</h3>



<p>Generative AI systems rely on user prompts to generate outputs. The OCEAN process, outlined in the course, offers a simple yet powerful framework for prompting AI tools like Gemini, Stable Diffusion or ChatGPT.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/YasmineBoudiaf-LOTIDataProcessing-1280x719-1-500x281.png" alt="Three groups of icons representing people have shapes travelling between them and a page in the middle of the image. The page is a simple rectangle with straight lines representing data. The shapes traveling towards the page are irregular and in squiggly bands." class="wp-image-88363" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/YasmineBoudiaf-LOTIDataProcessing-1280x719-1-500x281.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/YasmineBoudiaf-LOTIDataProcessing-1280x719-1-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/YasmineBoudiaf-LOTIDataProcessing-1280x719-1-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/YasmineBoudiaf-LOTIDataProcessing-1280x719-1-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/YasmineBoudiaf-LOTIDataProcessing-1280x719-1-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/YasmineBoudiaf-LOTIDataProcessing-1280x719-1-900x506.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/YasmineBoudiaf-LOTIDataProcessing-1280x719-1.png 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Yasmine Boudiaf &amp; LOTI / Better Images of AI / Data Processing / CC-BY 4.0</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>The first three steps of the process help you write better prompts that will result in an output that is as close as possible to what you are looking for, while the last two steps outline how to improve the output:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Objective:</strong> Clearly state what you want the model to generate</li>



<li><strong>Context</strong>: Provide necessary background information</li>



<li><strong>Examples</strong>: Offer specific examples to fine-tune the model’s output</li>



<li><strong>Assess</strong>: Evaluate the output&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Negotiate</strong>: Refine the prompt to correct any errors in the output</li>
</ol>



<p>The final step in using any generative AI tool should be to closely review or edit the output yourself. These tools will very quickly get you started but you&#8217;ll always have to rely on your own human effort to ensure the quality of your work.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Helping educators to be critical users</h2>



<p>We believe the knowledge and skills our ‘Understanding AI for educators’ course teaches will help any educator determine the right AI tools and concepts to bring into their classroom, regardless of their specialisation. Here&#8217;s what one course participant had to say:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;From my inexperienced viewpoint, I kind of viewed AI as a cheat code. I believed that AI in the classroom could possibly be a real detriment to students and eliminate critical thinking skills.<br><br>After learning more about AI [on the course] and getting some hands-on experience with it, my viewpoint has certainly taken a 180-degree turn. AI definitely belongs in schools and in the workplace. It will take time to properly integrate it and know how to ethically use it. Our role as educators is to stay ahead of this trend as opposed to denying AI&#8217;s benefits and falling behind.&#8221; – ‘Understanding AI for educators’ course participant</p>
</blockquote>



<p>All our Experience AI resources — including this online course and <a href="https://experience-ai.org/en/units/experience-ai-lessons" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the teaching materials</a> — are designed to foster a generation of AI-literate educators who can confidently and ethically guide their students in navigating the world of AI.</p>



<p>You can sign up to the course for free here:&nbsp;</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-1 wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-text-align-center wp-element-button" href="https://www.edx.org/learn/education-teacher-training/raspberry-pi-foundation-teach-teens-computing-understanding-ai-for-teachers?utm_source=rpf-blog&amp;utm_medium=partner-marketing&amp;utm_campaign=raspberrypifoundation">I want to sign up</a></div>
</div>



<p><em>A version of this article also appears in&nbsp;<a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hello World</a>&nbsp;issue 25, which will be published on Monday 23 September and will focus on all things generative AI and education.</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/free-online-course-on-understanding-ai-for-educators/">Free online course on understanding AI for educators</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/free-online-course-on-understanding-ai-for-educators/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How useful do teachers find error message explanations generated by AI? Pilot research results</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/error-message-explanations-large-language-models-teachers-views/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/error-message-explanations-large-language-models-teachers-views/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Veronica Cucuiat]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 14:46:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research seminar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming education]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=88171</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As discussions of how artificial intelligence (AI) will impact teaching, learning, and assessment proliferate, I was thrilled to be able to add one of my own research projects to the mix. As a research scientist at the Raspberry Pi Foundation, I’ve been working on a pilot research study in collaboration with Jane Waite to explore&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/error-message-explanations-large-language-models-teachers-views/">How useful do teachers find error message explanations generated by AI? Pilot research results</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As discussions of how artificial intelligence (AI) will impact teaching, learning, and assessment proliferate, I was thrilled to be able to add one of my own research projects to the mix. As a research scientist at the Raspberry Pi Foundation, I’ve been working on a pilot research study in collaboration with Jane Waite to explore the topic of program error messages (PEMs).&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/06/Spencers-Story-12-500x333.jpg" alt="Computer science students at a desktop computer in a classroom." class="wp-image-84335" style="width:637px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/06/Spencers-Story-12-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/06/Spencers-Story-12-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/06/Spencers-Story-12-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/06/Spencers-Story-12-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/06/Spencers-Story-12-2048x1365.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/06/Spencers-Story-12-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/06/Spencers-Story-12-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/06/Spencers-Story-12-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>PEMs can be a significant barrier to learning for novice coders, as they are often confusing and difficult to understand. This can hinder troubleshooting and progress in coding, and lead to frustration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Recently, various teams have been exploring how generative AI, specifically large language models (LLMs), can be used to help learners understand PEMs. My research in this area specifically explores secondary teachers’ views of the explanations of PEMs generated by a LLM, as an aid for learning and teaching programming, and I presented some of my results in our <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research/seminars">ongoing seminar series</a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Understanding program error messages is hard at the start</h2>



<p>I started the seminar by setting the scene and describing the current background of research on novices’ difficulty in using PEMs to fix their code, and the efforts made to date to improve these. The three main points I made were that:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li>PEMs are often difficult to decipher, especially by novices, and there’s a whole research area dedicated to identifying ways to improve them.</li>



<li><a href="https://doi.org/10.1145/3587102.3588785" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Recent studies</a> have employed LLMs as a way of enhancing PEMs. However, the <a href="https://doi.org/10.1145/3344429.3372508" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">evidence</a> on what makes an ‘effective’ PEM for learning is limited, variable, and contradictory.</li>



<li>There is limited research in the context of K–12 programming education, as well as research conducted in collaboration with teachers to better understand the practical and pedagogical implications of integrating LLMs into the classroom more generally.</li>
</ol>



<p>My pilot study aims to fill this gap directly, by reporting K–12 teachers’ views of the potential use of LLM-generated explanations of PEMs in the classroom, and how their views fit into the wider theoretical paradigm of feedback literacy.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What did the teachers say?</h2>



<p>To conduct the study, I interviewed eight expert secondary computing educators. The interviews were semi-structured activity-based interviews, where the educators got to experiment with a prototype version of the Foundation’s <a href="https://editor.raspberrypi.org" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">publicly available Code Editor</a>. This version of the Code Editor was adapted to generate LLM explanations when the question mark next to the standard error message is clicked (see Figure 1 for an example of a LLM-generated explanation). The Code Editor version called the OpenAI GPT-3.5 interface to generate explanations based on the following prompt: “You are a teacher talking to a 12-year-old child. Explain the error {error} in the following Python code: {code}”.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="275" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-500x275.png" alt="The Foundation’s Python Code Editor with LLM feedback prototype." class="wp-image-88178" style="width:633px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-500x275.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-300x165.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-768x422.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-800x440.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-450x247.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-900x495.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image.png 1115w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Figure 1: The Foundation&#8217;s Code Editor with LLM feedback prototype.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Fifteen themes were derived from the educators’ responses and these were split into five groups (Figure 2). Overall, the educators’ views of the LLM feedback were that, for the most part, a sensible explanation of the error messages was produced. However, all educators experienced at least one example of invalid content (LLM &#8220;hallucination&#8221;). Also, despite not being explicitly requested in the LLM prompt, a possible code solution was always included in the explanation.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="357" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-1-500x357.png" alt="Themes and groups derived from teachers’ responses." class="wp-image-88179" style="width:643px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-1-500x357.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-1-300x214.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-1-768x548.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-1-800x571.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-1-450x321.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-1.png 822w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Figure 2: Themes and groups derived from teachers’ responses.<br></figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Matching the themes to PEM guidelines</h2>



<p>Next, I investigated how the teachers’ views correlated to the research conducted to date on enhanced PEMs. I used the guidelines proposed by <a href="https://doi.org/10.1145/3344429.3372508" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Brett Becker and colleagues</a>, which consolidate a lot of the research done in this area into ten design guidelines. The guidelines offer best practices on how to enhance PEMs based on cognitive science and educational theory empirical research. For example, they outline that enhanced PEMs should provide scaffolding for the user, increase readability, reduce cognitive load, use a positive tone, and provide context to the error.</p>



<p>Out of the 15 themes identified in my study, 10 of these correlated closely to the guidelines. However, the 10 themes that correlated well were, for the most part, the themes related to the content of the explanations, presentation, and validity (Figure 3). On the other hand, the themes concerning the teaching and learning process did not fit as well to the guidelines.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="288" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-2-500x288.png" alt="Correlation between teachers’ responses and enhanced PEM design guidelines." class="wp-image-88180" style="width:640px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-2-500x288.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-2-300x173.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-2-768x443.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-2-1536x885.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-2-800x461.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-2-450x259.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-2-900x519.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-2.png 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Figure 3: Correlation between teachers’ responses and enhanced PEM design guidelines.<br></figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Does feedback literacy theory fit better?</h2>



<p>However, when I looked at feedback literacy theory, I was able to correlate all fifteen themes — the theory fits.</p>



<p>Feedback literacy theory positions the feedback process (which includes explanations) as a social interaction, and accounts for the actors involved in the interaction — the student and the teacher — as well as the relationships between the student, the teacher, and the feedback. We can explain feedback literacy theory using three constructs: feedback types, student feedback literacy, and teacher feedback literacy (Figure 4).&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="276" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-3-500x276.png" alt="Feedback literacy at the intersection between feedback types, student feedback literacy, and teacher feedback literacy." class="wp-image-88181" style="width:662px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-3-500x276.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-3-300x166.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-3-768x424.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-3-1536x849.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-3-800x442.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-3-450x249.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-3-900x497.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-3.png 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Figure 4: Feedback literacy at the intersection between feedback types, student feedback literacy, and teacher feedback literacy.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>From the feedback literacy perspective, feedback can be grouped into four types: telling, guiding, developing understanding, and opening up new perspectives. The feedback type depends on the role of the student and teacher when engaging with the feedback (Figure 5).&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="257" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-4-500x257.png" alt="Feedback types as formalised by McLean, Bond, &amp; Nicholson." class="wp-image-88182" style="width:684px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-4-500x257.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-4-300x154.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-4-768x395.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-4-1536x790.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-4-800x412.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-4-450x231.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-4-900x463.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-4.png 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Figure 5: Feedback types as formalised by <a href="https://doi.org/10.1080/03075079.2013.855718" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">McLean, Bond, &amp; Nicholson</a>.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>From the student perspective, the competencies and dispositions students need in order to use feedback effectively can be stated as: appreciating the feedback processes, making judgements, taking action, and managing affect. Finally, from a teacher perspective, teachers apply their feedback literacy skills across three dimensions: design, relational, and pragmatic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In short, according to feedback literacy theory, effective feedback processes entail well-designed feedback with a clear pedagogical purpose, as well as the competencies students and teachers need in order to make sense of the feedback and use it effectively.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="330" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2019/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_028-500x330.jpg" alt="A computing educator with three students at laptops in a classroom." class="wp-image-50374" style="width:648px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2019/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_028-500x330.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2019/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_028-300x198.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2019/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_028-768x507.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2019/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_028-1636x1080.jpg 1636w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>This theory therefore provided a promising lens for analysing the educators&#8217; perspectives in my study. When the educators’ views were correlated to feedback literacy theory, I found that:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li>Educators prefer the LLM explanations to fulfil a <strong>guiding</strong> and <strong>developing understanding</strong> role, rather than <strong>telling</strong>. For example, educators prefer to either remove or delay the code solution from the explanation, and they like the explanations to include keywords based on concepts they are teaching in the classroom to guide and develop students’ understanding rather than tell.</li>
</ol>



<ol start="2" class="wp-block-list">
<li>Related to students’ feedback literacy, educators talked about the ways in which the LLM explanations help or hinder students to <strong>make judgements</strong> and <strong>action the feedback</strong> in the explanations. For example, they talked about how detailed, jargon-free explanations can help students make judgments about the feedback, but invalid explanations can hinder this process. Therefore, teachers talked about the need for ways to manage such invalid instances. However, for the most part, the educators didn’t talk about eradicating them altogether. They talked about ways of flagging them, using them as counter-examples, and having visibility of them to be able to address them with students.</li>
</ol>



<ol start="3" class="wp-block-list">
<li>Finally, from a teacher feedback literacy perspective, educators discussed the need for professional development to manage feedback processes inclusive of LLM feedback (<strong>design</strong>) and address issues resulting from reduced opportunities to interact with students (<strong>relational </strong>and<strong> pragmatic</strong>). For example, if using LLM explanations results in a reduction in the time teachers spend helping students debug syntax errors from a pragmatic time-saving perspective, then what does that mean for the relationship they have with their students?&nbsp;</li>
</ol>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion from the study</h2>



<p>By correlating educators’ views to feedback literacy theory as well as enhanced PEM guidelines, we can take a broader perspective on how LLMs might not only shape the content of the explanations, but the whole social interaction around giving and receiving feedback. Investigating ways of supporting students and teachers to practise their feedback literacy skills matters just as much, if not more, than focusing on the content of PEM explanations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This study was a first-step exploration of eight educators’ views on the potential impact of using LLM explanations of PEMs in the classroom. Exactly what the findings of this study mean for classroom practice remains to be investigated, and we also need to examine students’ views on the feedback and its impact on their journey of learning to program.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you want to hear more, you can watch my seminar:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Explaining programming error messages using AI – V. Cucuiat | Computing education research" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fVD2zpGpcY0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<div style="height:38px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<p>You can also read the <a href="https://assets.ctfassets.net/oshmmv7kdjgm/3awxIv9oVcHrLrYE7Il51P/6ba73f4417e9e961c32dd2a4be8e0db2/Feedback_literacy_-_Holistic_analysis_of_secondary_educators__views_of_LLM_explanations_of_program_error_messages_in_the_cla.pdf">associated paper</a>, or find out more about the research instruments on this <a href="https://computingeducationresearch.org/projects/using-llms-to-explain-programming-error-messages-pilot-study/">project website</a>.</p>



<p>If any of these ideas resonated with you as an educator, student, or researcher, do reach out — we’d love to hear from you. You can contact me directly at <a href="mailto:veronica.cucuiat@raspberrypi.org">veronica.cucuiat@raspberrypi.org</a> or drop us a line in the comments below.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Join our next seminar</h2>



<p>The focus of our ongoing seminar series is on teaching programming with or without AI. Check out the <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research/seminars">schedule of our upcoming seminars</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To take part in the next seminar, click the button below to sign up, and we will send you information about how to join. We hope to see you there.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-2 wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://form.raspberrypi.org/f/research-seminar-sign-up" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">I want to join the next seminar</a></div>
</div>



<p>You can also catch up on past seminars <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research/seminars">on our blog</a> and on the <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research/seminars/previous">previous seminars and recordings page</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/error-message-explanations-large-language-models-teachers-views/">How useful do teachers find error message explanations generated by AI? Pilot research results</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/error-message-explanations-large-language-models-teachers-views/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Impact of Experience AI: Reflections from students and teachers</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/impact-of-experience-ai-reflections-from-students-and-teachers/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/impact-of-experience-ai-reflections-from-students-and-teachers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lou Loxley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 08:20:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Experience AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI literacy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=88341</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Students and teachers share their stories about the impact the Experience AI lessons have had in developing their understanding of artificial intelligence. We're now expanding Experience AI for 16 more countries and creating new resources on AI safety, thanks to funding from Google.org.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/impact-of-experience-ai-reflections-from-students-and-teachers/">Impact of Experience AI: Reflections from students and teachers</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>“I&#8217;ve enjoyed actually learning about what AI is and how it works, because before I thought it was just a scary computer that thinks like a human,” a student learning with Experience AI at King Edward’s School, Bath, UK, told us. </p>



<p>This is the essence of what we aim to do with our <a href="http://experience-ai.org" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Experience AI lessons</a>, which demystify artificial intelligence (AI) and machine learning (ML). Through Experience AI, teachers worldwide are empowered to confidently deliver engaging lessons with a suite of resources that inspire and educate 11- to 14-year-olds about AI and the role it could play in their lives.</p>



<p>“I learned new things and it changed my mindset that AI is going to take over the world.” – <strong>Student, Malaysia</strong></p>



<p></p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="375" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image.jpeg" alt="Experience AI students in Malaysia" class="wp-image-88357" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-300x225.jpeg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-450x338.jpeg 450w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Experience AI students in Malaysia</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Developed by us with <a href="https://deepmind.google/impact/?_gl=1*j0ixqt*_up*MQ..*_ga*MTA2MzY3NTU3Ni4xNzIyMzM0NDQw*_ga_LS8HVHCNQ0*MTcyMjMzNDQzOS4xLjAuMTcyMjMzNDQzOS4wLjAuMA..">Google DeepMind</a>, our first set of Experience AI lesson resources was aimed at a UK audience and launched in April 2023. Next we released tailored versions of the resources for 5 other countries, working in close partnership with organisations in Malaysia, Kenya, Canada, Romania, and India. Thanks to new funding from <a href="http://google.org">Google.org</a>, we&#8217;re now expanding Experience AI for 16 more countries and creating new resources on AI safety, with the aim of providing leading-edge AI education for more than 2 million young people across Europe, the Middle East, and Africa. </p>



<p>In this blog post, you&#8217;ll hear directly from students and teachers about the impact the Experience AI lessons have had so far.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Case study:  Experience AI in Malaysia</h2>



<p><a href="https://www.pscpen.com/?gclid=CjwKCAjwnqK1BhBvEiwAi7o0XwOaDBaQ9Qc6Xj6qE8u3XFBGllunpeKpdneHSshtZQpoVtZH_X9tkBoCHR8QAvD_BwE" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Penang Science Cluster</a> in Malaysia is among the first organisations we&#8217;ve partnered with for Experience AI. Speaking to Malaysian students learning with Experience AI, we found that the lessons were often very different from what they had expected. </p>



<p></p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="375" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/IMG_8078-2-500x375.jpg" alt="Launch of Experience AI in Malaysia " class="wp-image-88348" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/IMG_8078-2-500x375.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/IMG_8078-2-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/IMG_8078-2-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/IMG_8078-2-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/IMG_8078-2-2048x1536.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/IMG_8078-2-800x600.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/IMG_8078-2-450x337.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/IMG_8078-2-900x675.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Launch of Experience AI in Malaysia</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>“I actually thought it was going to be about boring lectures and not much about AI but more on coding, but we actually got to do a lot of hands-on activities, which are pretty fun. I thought AI was just about robots, but after joining this, I found it could be made into chatbots or could be made into personal helpers.” – <strong>Student, Malaysia</strong></p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Actually, I thought AI was mostly related to robots, so I was expecting to learn more about robots when I came to this programme. It widened my perception on AI.” &#8211; <strong>Student, Malaysia.</strong> </p>
</blockquote>



<p>The Malaysian government actively promotes AI literacy among its citizens, and working with local education authorities, Penang Science Cluster is using Experience AI to train teachers and equip thousands of young people in the state of Penang with the understanding and skills to use AI effectively. </p>



<p>“We envision a future where AI education is as fundamental as mathematics education, providing students with the tools they need to thrive in an AI-driven world”, says Aimy Lee, Chief Operating Officer at Penang Science Cluster. “The journey of AI exploration in Malaysia has only just begun, and we’re thrilled to play a part in shaping its trajectory.”</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Giving non-specialist teachers the confidence to introduce AI to students</h2>



<p>Experience AI provides <a href="https://experience-ai.org/en/">lesson plans, classroom resources, worksheets, hands-on activities, and videos</a> to help teachers introduce a wide range of AI applications and help students understand how they work. The resources are <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ai-education-resources-what-to-teach-seame-framework/">based on research</a>, and because we adapt them <a href="https://experience-ai.org/en/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">to each partner&#8217;s country</a>, they are culturally relevant and relatable for students. <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/a-teachers-guide-to-teaching-experience-ai-lessons/">Any teacher</a> can use the resources in their classroom, whether or not they have a background in computing education. </p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Our Key Stage 3 Computing students now feel immensely more knowledgeable about the importance and place that AI has in their wider lives. These lessons and activities are engaging and accessible to students and educators alike, whatever their specialism may be.” &#8211; <strong>Dave Cross,  North Liverpool Academy, UK</strong></p>
</blockquote>



<p>“The feedback we’ve received from both teachers and learners has been overwhelmingly positive. They consistently rave about how accessible, fun, and hands-on these resources are. What’s more, the materials are so comprehensive that even non-specialists can deliver them with confidence.” – <strong>Storm Rae, The National Museum of Computing, UK</strong></p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/IMG_5895-46-500x333.jpg" alt="Experience AI teacher training in Kenya" class="wp-image-88352" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/IMG_5895-46-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/IMG_5895-46-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/IMG_5895-46-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/IMG_5895-46-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/IMG_5895-46-2048x1365.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/IMG_5895-46-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/IMG_5895-46-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/IMG_5895-46-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Experience AI teacher training in Kenya</figcaption></figure></div>


<p><br>“[The lessons] go above and beyond to ensure that students not only grasp the material but also develop a genuine interest and enthusiasm for the subject.” – <strong>Teacher, Changamwe Junior School, Mombasa, Kenya</strong></p>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Sparking debates on bias and the limitations of AI</h2>



<p>When learners gain an understanding of how AI works, it gives them the confidence to discuss areas where the technology doesn&#8217;t work well or its output is incorrect. These classroom debates deepen and consolidate their knowledge, and help them to use AI more critically.</p>



<p>“Students enjoyed the practical aspects of the lessons, like categorising apples and tomatoes. They found it intriguing how AI could sometimes misidentify objects, sparking discussions on its limitations. They also expressed concerns about AI bias, which these lessons helped raise awareness about. I didn&#8217;t always have all the answers, but it was clear they were curious about AI&#8217;s implications for their future.” – <strong>Tracey Mayhead, Arthur Mellows Village College, Peterborough, UK</strong></p>



<p></p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="375" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/group-at-computer-500x375.jpg" alt="Experience AI students in UK " class="wp-image-88353" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/group-at-computer-500x375.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/group-at-computer-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/group-at-computer-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/group-at-computer-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/group-at-computer-2048x1536.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/group-at-computer-800x600.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/group-at-computer-450x338.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/group-at-computer-900x675.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Experience AI students in UK</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>“The lessons that we trialled took some of the ‘magic’ out of AI and started to give the students an understanding that AI is only as good as the data that is used to build it.” – <strong>Jacky Green, Waldegrave School, UK&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>“I have enjoyed learning about how AI is actually programmed, rather than just hearing about how impactful and great it could be.” – <strong>Student, King Edward’s School, Bath, UK&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>“It has changed my outlook on AI because now I&#8217;ve realised how much AI actually needs human intelligence to be able to do anything.” – <strong>Student, Arthur Mellows Village College, Peterborough, UK&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>“I didn’t really know what I wanted to do before this but now knowing more about AI, I probably would consider a future career in AI as I find it really interesting and I really liked learning about it.” – <strong>Student, Arthur Mellows Village College, Peterborough, UK&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>If you’d like to get involved with Experience AI as an educator and use our free lesson resources with your class, you can start by visiting <a href="http://experience-ai.org" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">experience-ai.org</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/impact-of-experience-ai-reflections-from-students-and-teachers/">Impact of Experience AI: Reflections from students and teachers</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/impact-of-experience-ai-reflections-from-students-and-teachers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The European Astro Pi Challenge 2024/25 launches today</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/the-european-astro-pi-challenge-2024-25-launches-today/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/the-european-astro-pi-challenge-2024-25-launches-today/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Fergus Kirkpatrick]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 08:44:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Astro Pi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Programmes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[astro pi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mission Space Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mission Zero]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european astro pi challenge]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=88298</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Registration is now open for the European Astro Pi Challenge 2024/25! The Astro Pi Challenge, an ESA Education project run in collaboration with us here at the Raspberry Pi Foundation, offers young people the incredible opportunity to write computer programs that will run in space. Young people can take part in two exciting missions for&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/the-european-astro-pi-challenge-2024-25-launches-today/">The European Astro Pi Challenge 2024/25 launches today</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Registration is now open for the <a href="https://astro-pi.org/">European Astro Pi Challenge 2024/25</a>! The Astro Pi Challenge, an ESA Education project run in collaboration with us here at the Raspberry Pi Foundation, offers young people the incredible opportunity to write computer programs that will run in space.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-medium"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="222" height="250" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/09/Astro-Pi-2021-1-222x250.png" alt="Logo of the European Astro Pi Challenge." class="wp-image-74456" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/09/Astro-Pi-2021-1-222x250.png 222w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/09/Astro-Pi-2021-1-500x564.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/09/Astro-Pi-2021-1-768x866.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/09/Astro-Pi-2021-1-1361x1536.png 1361w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/09/Astro-Pi-2021-1-800x903.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/09/Astro-Pi-2021-1-450x508.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/09/Astro-Pi-2021-1-900x1015.png 900w" sizes="(max-width: 222px) 100vw, 222px" /></figure></div>


<p>Young people can take part in two exciting missions for beginners and more experienced coders, and send their code to run on special Raspberry Pi computers, called Astro Pis, on board the International Space Station (ISS).</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Meet the new Astro Pi ambassador, Sławosz Uznański</strong></h2>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery aligncenter has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-1 is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-is-layout-flex">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" data-id="88301" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/71578-European-Space-Agency-ESA-500x333.jpg" alt="Sławosz Uznański inside a replica of the Columbus module." class="wp-image-88301" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/71578-European-Space-Agency-ESA-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/71578-European-Space-Agency-ESA-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/71578-European-Space-Agency-ESA-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/71578-European-Space-Agency-ESA-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/71578-European-Space-Agency-ESA-2048x1366.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/71578-European-Space-Agency-ESA-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/71578-European-Space-Agency-ESA-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/71578-European-Space-Agency-ESA-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Sławosz Uznański</figcaption></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" data-id="88308" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/71575-European-Space-Agency-ESA-500x333.jpg" alt="Sławosz Uznański at the European Space Agency." class="wp-image-88308" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/71575-European-Space-Agency-ESA-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/71575-European-Space-Agency-ESA-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/71575-European-Space-Agency-ESA-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/71575-European-Space-Agency-ESA-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/71575-European-Space-Agency-ESA-2048x1366.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/71575-European-Space-Agency-ESA-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/71575-European-Space-Agency-ESA-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/71575-European-Space-Agency-ESA-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Sławosz Uznański at the European Space Agency</figcaption></figure>
</figure>



<div style="height:20px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<p>We are delighted that new ESA project astronaut Sławosz Uznański will be the ambassador for this year’s Astro Pi Challenge. Sławosz, born in Poland in 1984, has a background in space systems engineering and has conducted research in radiation effects. He recently served as the Engineer in Charge of CERN’s largest accelerator, the Large Hadron Collider.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Mission Zero: Send your pixel art into space</strong></h2>



<p>In <a href="https://astro-pi.org/mission-zero" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mission Zero</a>, young people create beautiful pixel art to display on the Astro Pis’ LED screens. This mission requires no prior experience of Python coding, and it can be completed in around an hour.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/24-25_code-examples-500x333.png" alt="A selection of pixel art images by Mission Zero 2023/24 participants. The images  show a variety of plants and animals, such as a cactus, a cat, and an elephant." class="wp-image-88302" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/24-25_code-examples-500x333.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/24-25_code-examples-300x200.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/24-25_code-examples-768x512.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/24-25_code-examples-800x533.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/24-25_code-examples-450x300.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/24-25_code-examples-900x600.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/24-25_code-examples.png 1500w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Pixel art examples by Mission Zero 2023/24 participants</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>To take part, young people design and code pixel art inspired by nature on Earth and beyond, to display on the Astro Pi computers for the astronauts on the ISS to see as they go about their daily tasks.</p>



<p>Using our <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/projects/astro-pi-mission-zero">step-by-step Mission Zero project guide</a>, young people will learn to create simple Python programs in which they will code with variables and use the colour sensors on the Astro Pis to change the background colour in their images. To help your teams create their designs, check out the examples from teams that took part in Mission Zero in 2023/24 in the project guide.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/01/CodeClub_ParkStreet-17-500x333.jpg" alt="A young person smiles while using a laptop." class="wp-image-82998" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/01/CodeClub_ParkStreet-17-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/01/CodeClub_ParkStreet-17-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/01/CodeClub_ParkStreet-17-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/01/CodeClub_ParkStreet-17.jpg 627w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>Young people can create their Mission Zero programs individually or in teams of up to 4 people, and this year, we have added a save function for young people as they code. This will make it easier for mentors to run Mission Zero over more than one session, and also means that young people can finish their projects at home. They will need to use your classroom code and their team name to load their saved projects.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Mission Space Lab: Calculate the speed of the ISS</strong></h2>



<p><a href="https://astro-pi.org/mission-space-lab">Mission Space Lab</a> asks teams to solve a real-world scientific task in space. It is ideally suited to young people who would like to learn more about space science and stretch their programming skills.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="375" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/run_1_gps_image_0-2-500x375.jpg" alt="A photo of Mexico taken by an Astro Pi computer on board the ISS." class="wp-image-88303" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/run_1_gps_image_0-2-500x375.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/run_1_gps_image_0-2-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/run_1_gps_image_0-2-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/run_1_gps_image_0-2-1536x1151.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/run_1_gps_image_0-2-2048x1535.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/run_1_gps_image_0-2-800x600.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/run_1_gps_image_0-2-450x337.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/run_1_gps_image_0-2-900x675.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">&nbsp;A photo of Mexico taken using an Astro Pi computer during a team’s experiment in Mission Space Lab 2023/24</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>In <a href="https://astro-pi.org/mission-space-lab">Mission Space Lab</a> this year, the task for teams of 2 to 6 young people is to calculate the speed at which the International Space Station is travelling — as accurately as possible. Teams need to write a Python program that:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li>Collects data from the Astro Pi computers’ sensors or cameras about the orientation and motion of the ISS as it orbits the Earth, and</li>



<li>Uses this data to calculate the travel speed</li>
</ol>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/05/AstroPi-WORF-LR-iss069e004379-500x333.jpg" alt="The Astro Pi computers inside the International Space Station." class="wp-image-83983" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/05/AstroPi-WORF-LR-iss069e004379-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/05/AstroPi-WORF-LR-iss069e004379-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/05/AstroPi-WORF-LR-iss069e004379-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/05/AstroPi-WORF-LR-iss069e004379-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/05/AstroPi-WORF-LR-iss069e004379-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/05/AstroPi-WORF-LR-iss069e004379-900x600.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/05/AstroPi-WORF-LR-iss069e004379.jpg 1392w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">The Astro Pi computers at the WORF window on the International Space Station. Credit: ESA/NASA</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>This year we have created a new way for teams to test their programs, with an online version of the Astro Pi Replay tool. All teams need to do is select their program and run it in Astro Pi Replay, which will create a real-time simulation of the program running on the ISS, using historical data and images. Astro Pi Replay will also show program outputs and report errors. This means teams can code their program in their preferred code editor, then test with an internet browser. However, if they wish, teams can still run the Astro Pi Replay tool offline with Thonny.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Important dates for your diary</strong></h2>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>16 September 2024: Registration is now open for Mission Zero and Mission Space Lab!</li>



<li>24 February 2025: Mission Space Lab submissions close</li>



<li>24 March 2025: Mission Zero submissions close</li>



<li>April–May 2025: Astro Pi programs run on the International Space Station</li>



<li>June 2025: Astro Pi teams receive their certificates</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Register today</strong></h2>



<p>Both missions are open to young people up to age 19 from eligible countries — all ESA Member States and beyond. To find out more and register, visit <a href="https://astro-pi.org">astro-pi.org</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look out for updates and resources being shared on the <a href="https://astro-pi.org">Astro Pi website</a>, including a Mission Zero video codealong and Mission Space Lab live streams. You can also keep up-to-date with all the Astro Pi news on the <a href="https://x.com/Astro_Pi">Astro Pi X account</a>, our <a href="https://www.facebook.com/RaspberryPiFoundation">Facebook</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/raspberrypifoundation">LinkedIn</a>, and <a href="https://www.instagram.com/raspberrypifoundation">Instagram</a>, or by signing up to the newsletter at <a href="https://astro-pi.org">astro-pi.org</a>.</p>



<p>We can’t wait to see your programs!</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/the-european-astro-pi-challenge-2024-25-launches-today/">The European Astro Pi Challenge 2024/25 launches today</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/the-european-astro-pi-challenge-2024-25-launches-today/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Experience AI: How research continues to shape the resources</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-how-research-continues-to-shape-the-resources/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-how-research-continues-to-shape-the-resources/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lou Loxley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 14:01:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Experience AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI literacy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=88224</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Our free teaching materials aim to boost AI literacy worldwide. This blog post explains how we use research to continue to shape our Experience AI resources, including the new AI safety resources we are developing.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-how-research-continues-to-shape-the-resources/">Experience AI: How research continues to shape the resources</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Since we launched the Experience AI learning programme in the UK in April 2023, educators in 130 countries have downloaded Experience AI lesson resources. They estimate reaching over 630,000 young people with the lessons, helping them to understand how AI works and to build the knowledge and confidence to use AI tools responsibly. Just last week, we announced another <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-expands-to-reach-over-2-million-students/">exciting expansion</a> of Experience AI: thanks to $10 million in funding from <a href="http://google.org" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Google.org</a>, we will be able to work with local partner organisations to provide research-based AI education to an estimated over 2 million young people across Europe, the Middle East and Africa. </p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/img_8806_720-500x333.jpg" alt="Trainer discussing Experience AI at a teacher training event in Kenya." class="wp-image-88225" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/img_8806_720-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/img_8806_720-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/img_8806_720-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/img_8806_720.jpg 720w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Experience AI teacher training in Kenya</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>This blog post explains how we use research to continue to shape our Experience AI resources, including the new AI safety resources we are developing. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The beginning of Experience AI</h2>



<p>Artificial intelligence (AI) and machine learning (ML) applications are part of our everyday lives — we use them every time we scroll through social media feeds organised by recommender systems or unlock an app with facial recognition. For young people, there is more need than ever to gain the skills and understanding to critically engage with AI technologies.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/canva_stock_mobile_phone_image-500x281.png" alt="Someone holding a mobile phone that's open on their social media apps folder. " class="wp-image-88315" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/canva_stock_mobile_phone_image-500x281.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/canva_stock_mobile_phone_image-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/canva_stock_mobile_phone_image-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/canva_stock_mobile_phone_image-1536x864.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/canva_stock_mobile_phone_image-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/canva_stock_mobile_phone_image-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/canva_stock_mobile_phone_image-900x506.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/canva_stock_mobile_phone_image.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>We wanted to design free lesson resources to help teachers in a wide range of subjects confidently introduce AI and ML to students aged 11 to 14 (Key Stage 3). This led us to develop <a href="https://experience-ai.org/?utm_source=rpf_old_ai_blogs&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;utm_campaign=experienceai_april23&amp;utm_id=experienceai_april23" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Experience AI</a>, in collaboration with <a href="https://deepmind.google/impact/?_gl=1*j0ixqt*_up*MQ..*_ga*MTA2MzY3NTU3Ni4xNzIyMzM0NDQw*_ga_LS8HVHCNQ0*MTcyMjMzNDQzOS4xLjAuMTcyMjMzNDQzOS4wLjAuMA.." target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Google DeepMind</a>, offering materials including lesson plans, slide decks, videos (both teacher- and student-facing), student activities, and assessment questions.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">SEAME: The research-based framework behind Experience AI</h2>



<p>The Experience AI resources were built on rigorous research from the <a href="https://computingeducationresearch.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Raspberry Pi Computing Education Research Centre</a> as well as from other researchers, including those we hosted at our <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/tag/ai-education/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">series of seminars on AI and data science education</a>. The Research Centre&#8217;s work involved mapping and categorising over 500 resources used to teach AI and ML, and found that the majority were one-off activities, and that very few resources were tailored to a specific age group.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="284" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/screenshot_2024-08-08_at_17.25.35_720-500x284.png" alt="An example activity slide in the Experience AI lessons where students learn about bias. " class="wp-image-88226" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/screenshot_2024-08-08_at_17.25.35_720-500x284.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/screenshot_2024-08-08_at_17.25.35_720-300x170.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/screenshot_2024-08-08_at_17.25.35_720-450x256.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/screenshot_2024-08-08_at_17.25.35_720.png 720w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">An example activity in the Experience AI lessons where students learn about bias.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>To analyse the content that existing AI education resources covered, the Centre developed a <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/12/RPF-Seminar-Proceedings-Volume-3.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">simple framework called SEAME</a>. The framework gives you an easy way to group concepts, knowledge, and skills related to AI and ML based on whether they focus on social and ethical aspects (SE), applications (A), models (M), or engines (E, i.e. how AI works.)</p>



<p>Through Experience AI, learners also gain an understanding of the models underlying AI applications, and the processes used to train and test ML models.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="282" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image_720-1-500x282.png" alt="An example activity slide in the Experience AI lessons where students learn about classification. " class="wp-image-88228" style="width:528px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image_720-1-500x282.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image_720-1-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image_720-1-450x254.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image_720-1.png 720w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">An example activity in the Experience AI lessons where students learn about classification.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Our Experience AI lessons cover all <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ai-education-resources-what-to-teach-seame-framework/">four levels of SEAME</a> and focus on applications of AI that are relatable for young people. They also introduce learners to AI-related issues such as privacy or bias concerns, and the impact of AI on employment.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The six foundation lessons of Experience AI</h2>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>What is AI?: </strong>Learners explore the current context of AI and how it is used in the world around them. Looking at the differences between rule-based and data-driven approaches to programming, they consider the benefits and challenges that AI could bring to society.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>How computers learn: </strong>Focusing on the role of data-driven models in AI systems, learners are introduced to ML and find out about three common approaches to creating ML models. Finally they explore classification, a specific application of ML.</li>



<li><strong>Bias in, bias out:</strong> Students create their own ML model to classify images of apples and tomatoes. They discover that a limited dataset is likely to lead to a flawed ML model. Then they explore how bias can appear in a dataset, resulting in biased predictions produced by a ML model.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Decision trees: </strong>Learners take their first in-depth look at a specific type of ML model: decision trees. They see how different training datasets result in the creation of different ML models, experiencing first-hand what the term ‘data-driven’ means.</li>



<li><strong>Solving problems with ML models: </strong>Students are introduced to the AI project lifecycle and use it to create a ML model. They apply a human-focused approach to working on their project, train a ML model, and finally test their model to find out its accuracy.</li>



<li><strong>Model cards and careers: </strong>Learners finish the AI project lifecycle by creating a model card to explain their ML model. To complete the unit, they explore a range of AI-related careers, hear from people working in AI research at Google DeepMind, and explore how they might apply AI and ML to their interests.&nbsp;</li>
</ol>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="263" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/09/8792_Exp_AI_Social_1-500x263.png" alt="Experience AI banner." class="wp-image-84757" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/09/8792_Exp_AI_Social_1-500x263.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/09/8792_Exp_AI_Social_1-300x158.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/09/8792_Exp_AI_Social_1-768x404.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/09/8792_Exp_AI_Social_1-800x420.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/09/8792_Exp_AI_Social_1-450x236.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/09/8792_Exp_AI_Social_1-900x473.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/09/8792_Exp_AI_Social_1.png 1201w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>We also offer two additional stand-alone lessons: one on large language models, how they work, and why they’re not always reliable, and the other on the application of AI in ecosystems research, which lets learners explore how AI tools can be used to support animal conservation.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">New AI safety resources: Empowering learners to be critical users of technology </h2>



<p>We have also been developing a set of resources for educator-led sessions on three topics related to AI safety, funded by <a href="http://google.org" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Google.org</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>AI and your data: With the support of this resource, young people reflect on the data they have already provided to AI applications in their daily lives, and think about how the prevalence of AI tools might change the way they protect their data.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li>



<li>Media literacy in the age of AI: This resource highlights the ways AI tools can be used to perpetuate misinformation and how AI applications can help people combat misleading claims.</li>



<li>Using generative AI responsibly: With this resource, young people consider their responsibilities when using generative AI, and their expectations of developers who release Experience AI tools.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Other research principles behind our free teaching resources&nbsp;</h2>



<p>As well as using the SEAME framework, we have incorporated a whole host of other research-based concepts in the design principles for the Experience AI resources. For example, we avoid <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ai-education-anthropomorphism/">anthropomorphism</a> — that is, words or imagery that can lead learners to wrongly believe that AI applications have sentience or intentions like humans do — and we instead promote the understanding that it&#8217;s people who design AI applications and decide how they are used. We also teach about data-driven application design, which is a core concept in <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/machine-learning-education-school-computational-thinking-2-0-research-seminar/">computational thinking 2.0</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Share your feedback</h2>



<p>We’d love to hear your thoughts and feedback about using the Experience AI resources. Your comments help us to improve the current materials, and to develop future resources. You can <a href="https://survey.raspberrypi.org/jfe/form/SV_0ocO2xa81Bq7QPA">tell us what you think using this form</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And if you’d like to start using the Experience AI resources as an educator, you can download them for free at <a href="http://experience-ai.org">experience-ai.org</a>.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-how-research-continues-to-shape-the-resources/">Experience AI: How research continues to shape the resources</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-how-research-continues-to-shape-the-resources/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Adapting primary Computing resources for cultural responsiveness: Bringing in learners&#8217; identity</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-computing-resources-cultural-responsiveness-research-with-primary-k5-teachers/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-computing-resources-cultural-responsiveness-research-with-primary-k5-teachers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katharine Childs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 10:12:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research seminar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culturally relevant teaching]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=88263</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In recent years, the emphasis on creating culturally responsive educational practices has gained significant traction in schools worldwide. This approach aims to tailor teaching and learning experiences to better reflect and respect the diverse cultural backgrounds of students, thereby enhancing their engagement and success in school. In one of our recent research studies, we collaborated&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-computing-resources-cultural-responsiveness-research-with-primary-k5-teachers/">Adapting primary Computing resources for cultural responsiveness: Bringing in learners&#8217; identity</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In recent years, the emphasis on creating culturally responsive educational practices has gained significant traction in schools worldwide. This approach aims to <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/culturally-relevant-computing-curriculum-guidelines-for-teachers/">tailor teaching and learning experiences to better reflect and respect the diverse cultural backgrounds of students</a>, thereby enhancing their engagement and success in school. In one of <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research/">our recent research studies</a>, we collaborated with a small group of primary school Computing teachers to adapt existing resources to be more culturally responsive to their learners.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="355" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image1-500x355.png" alt="Teachers work together to identify adaptations to Computing lessons. " class="wp-image-88271" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image1-500x355.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image1-300x213.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image1-768x545.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image1-800x567.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image1-450x319.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image1-900x638.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image1.png 1210w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">At a workshop for the study, teachers collaborated to identify adaptations to Computing lessons</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>We used a <a href="https://static.raspberrypi.org/files/curriculum/quickreads/20-Pedagogy_Summary_Cultural_Relevance_Areas_of_Opportunity_2024.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">set of ten areas of opportunity</a> to scaffold and prompt teachers to look for ways that Computing resources could be adapted, including making changes to the content or the context of lessons, and using pedagogical techniques such as collaboration and open-ended tasks. </p>



<p>Today&#8217;s blog lays out our findings about how teachers can bring students&#8217; identities into the classroom as an entry point for culturally responsive Computing teaching.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Collaborating with teachers</h2>



<p>A group of twelve primary teachers, from schools spread across England, volunteered to participate in the study. The primary objective was for our research team to collaborate with these teachers to adapt two units of work about creating digital images and vector graphics so that they better aligned with the cultural contexts of their students. The research team facilitated an <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/research-teacher-workshop-culturally-relevant-computing-lessons/">in-person, one-day workshop</a> where the teachers could discuss their experiences and work in small groups to adapt materials that they then taught in their classrooms during the following term.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A shared focus on identity</h2>



<p>As the workshop progressed, an interesting pattern emerged. Despite the diversity of schools and student populations represented by the teachers, each group independently decided to focus on the theme of identity in their adaptations. This was not a directive from the researchers, but rather a spontaneous alignment of priorities among the teachers.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image4-500x281.jpg" alt="An example slide from a culturally adapted activity to create a vector graphic emoji. " class="wp-image-88268" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image4-500x281.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image4-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image4-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image4-800x450.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image4-450x253.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image4-900x506.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image4.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">An example of an adapted Computing activity to create a vector graphic emoji.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>The focus on identity manifested in various ways. For some teachers, it involved adding diverse role models so that students could see themselves represented in computing, while for others, it meant incorporating discussions about students&#8217; own experiences into the lessons. However, the most compelling commonality across all groups was the decision to have students create a digital picture that represented something important about themselves. This digital picture could take many forms — an emoji, a digital collage, an avatar to add to a game, or even <a href="https://computingeducationresearch.org/blog-creating-culturally-relevant-resources/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">creating fantastical animals</a>. The goal of these activities was to provide students with a platform to express aspects of their identity that were significant to them whilst also practising the skills to manipulate vector graphics or digital images.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Funds of identity theory</h2>



<p>After the teachers had returned to their classrooms and taught the adapted lessons to their students, we analysed the digital pictures created by the students using <a href="https://d1wqtxts1xzle7.cloudfront.net/50416384/Funds_of_identity._A_new_concept_based_o20161119-22911-3gzfts-libre.pdf?1479562273=&amp;response-content-disposition=inline%3B+filename%3DFunds_of_Identity_A_new_concept_based_on.pdf&amp;Expires=1724153622&amp;Signature=gIu9G2gOiNBEjpbxnF6t5MbsAXt7eeIjFFIlFWhM5OaYdUKflRTfA-Du39l5vDBR8tOI8LjYUGEx-pIF9EdaE~icmCknxD3-FX7v913ROZBVxPisWvq-W96gw9MzvRx--qeyXfwDyAah7JRaKqIaq0wXtIsuD5OFgMR8lAoSTOl-GLxV6nY-cFpwCpg1BOUS36Nqg-1oI04GrsCI1EKczK3ZOofAQAl9hORQh-t8DVIHRBFiQTmUv8trPb3PtZ2eiJskwgojL-4ZH0zxth78n0cOAhzYGKktfEOLkMlg3aRG1qXRRr8sybUBGyw9~CvNqqyXAkmL37Rrxj2NqLv2sw__&amp;Key-Pair-Id=APKAJLOHF5GGSLRBV4ZA" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>funds of identity theory</strong></a>. This theory explains how our personal experiences and backgrounds shape who we are and what makes us unique and individual, and argues that our identities are not static but are continuously shaped and reshaped through interactions with the world around us. </p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="371" height="311" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image3.png" alt="Keywords for the funds of identity framework, drawing on work by Esteban-Guitart and Moll (2014) and Poole (2017)." class="wp-image-88269" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image3.png 371w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image3-298x250.png 298w" sizes="(max-width: 371px) 100vw, 371px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Funds of identity framework, drawing on work by Esteban-Guitart and Moll (2014) and Poole (2017).</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>In the context of our study, this theory argues that students bring their funds of identity into their Computing classrooms, including their cultural heritage, family traditions, languages, values, and personal interests. Through the image editing and vector graphics activities, students were able to create what the funds of identity theory refers to as <strong>identity artefacts</strong>. This allowed them to explore and highlight the various elements that hold importance in their lives, illuminating different facets of their identities. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Students’ funds of identity</h2>



<p>The use of the funds of identity theory provided a robust framework for understanding the digital artefacts created by the students. We analysed the teachers’ descriptions of the artefacts, paying close attention to how students represented their identities in their creations.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>1. Personal interests and values&nbsp;</strong></h4>



<p>One significant aspect of the analysis centered around the personal interests and values reflected in the artefacts. Some students chose to draw on their <strong>practical</strong> funds of identity and create images about hobbies that were important to them, such as drawing or playing football. Others focused on <strong>existential </strong>&nbsp;funds of identity and represented values that were central to their personalities, such as cool, chatty, or quiet.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>2. Family and community connections</strong></h4>



<p>Many students also chose to include references to their family and community in their artefacts. <strong>Social</strong> funds of identity were displayed when students featured family members in their images. Some students also drew on their <strong>institutional </strong>funds, adding references to their school, or <strong>geographical </strong>funds, by showing places such as the local area or a particular country that held special significance for them. These references highlighted the importance of familial and communal ties in shaping the students&#8217; identities.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>3. Cultural representation</strong></h4>



<p>Another common theme was the way students represented their cultural backgrounds. Some students chose to highlight their <strong>cultural</strong> funds of identity, creating images that included their heritage, including their national flag or traditional clothing. Other students incorporated <strong>ideological </strong>aspects of their identity that were important to them because of their faith, including Catholicism and Islam. This aspect of the artefacts demonstrated how students viewed their cultural heritage as an integral part of their identity.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Implications for culturally responsive Computing teaching</h2>



<p>The findings from this study have several important implications. Firstly, the spontaneous focus on identity by the teachers suggests that identity is a powerful entry point for culturally responsive Computing teaching. Secondly, the application of the funds of identity theory to the analysis of student work demonstrates the diverse cultural resources that students bring to the classroom and highlights ways to adapt Computing lessons in ways that resonate with students&#8217; lived experiences.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="297" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image2-500x297.png" alt="An example of an identity artefact made by one of the students in a culturally adapted lesson on vector graphics. " class="wp-image-88270" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image2-500x297.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image2-300x178.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image2-768x456.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image2-800x475.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image2-450x267.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image2-900x534.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image2.png 1098w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">An example of an identity artefact made by one of the students in the culturally adapted lesson on vector graphics. </figcaption></figure></div>


<p>However, we also found that teachers often had to carefully support students to illuminate their funds of identity. Sometimes students found it difficult to create images about their hobbies, particularly if they were from backgrounds with fewer social and economic opportunities. We also observed that when teachers modelled an identity artefact themselves, perhaps to show an example for students to aim for, students then sometimes copied the funds of identity revealed by the teacher rather than drawing on their own funds. These points need to be taken into consideration when using identity artefact activities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Finally, these findings relate to lessons about image editing and vector graphics that were taught to students aged 8- to 10-years old in England, and it remains to be explored how students in other countries or of different ages might reveal their funds of identity in the Computing classroom.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Moving forward with cultural responsiveness</h2>



<p>The study demonstrated that when Computing teachers are given the opportunity to collaborate and reflect on their practice, they can develop innovative ways to make their teaching more culturally responsive. The focus on identity, as seen in the creation of identity artefacts, provided students with a platform to express themselves and connect their learning to their own lives. By understanding and valuing the funds of identity that students bring to the classroom, teachers can create a more equitable and empowering educational experience for all learners.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/02/Purford-Computing-Kits-15-copy-500x333.jpg" alt="Two learners do physical computing in the primary school classroom." class="wp-image-78257" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/02/Purford-Computing-Kits-15-copy-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/02/Purford-Computing-Kits-15-copy-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/02/Purford-Computing-Kits-15-copy-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/02/Purford-Computing-Kits-15-copy-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/02/Purford-Computing-Kits-15-copy-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/02/Purford-Computing-Kits-15-copy-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/02/Purford-Computing-Kits-15-copy-900x600.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/02/Purford-Computing-Kits-15-copy.jpg 1680w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>We’ve written about this study in more detail in a <a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/3677619.3678106" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">full paper</a> and a <a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/3677619.3678120" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">poster paper</a>, which will be published at the <a href="https://www.wipsce.org/2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">WiPSCE conference</a> next week. </p>



<p>We would like to thank all the researchers who worked on this project, including our collaborations with Lynda Chinaka from the University of Roehampton, and Alex Hadwen-Bennett from King’s College London. Finally, we are grateful to Cognizant for funding this academic research, and to the cohort of primary Computing teachers for their enthusiasm, energy, and creativity, and their commitment to this project.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-computing-resources-cultural-responsiveness-research-with-primary-k5-teachers/">Adapting primary Computing resources for cultural responsiveness: Bringing in learners&#8217; identity</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-computing-resources-cultural-responsiveness-research-with-primary-k5-teachers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Experience AI at UNESCO’s Digital Learning Week</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-unescos-digital-learning-week/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-unescos-digital-learning-week/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben Garside]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 10:50:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Experience AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI literacy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=88222</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Last week, Andrew Csizmadia and I were honoured to attend UNESCO’s Digital Learning Week conference to present our free Experience AI resources and how they can help teachers demystify AI for their learners.   The conference drew a worldwide audience in-person and online to hear about the work educators and policy makers are doing to support&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-unescos-digital-learning-week/">Experience AI at UNESCO’s Digital Learning Week</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Last week, Andrew Csizmadia and I were honoured to attend <a href="https://www.unesco.org/sites/default/files/medias/fichiers/2024/09/DLW_programme_FINAL_2Sept2024_0.pdf?hub=83250">UNESCO’s Digital Learning Week</a> conference to present our free Experience AI resources and how they can help teachers demystify AI for their learners.  </p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="329" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco-500x329.jpg" alt="A group of educators at a UNESCO conference." class="wp-image-88243" style="width:632px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco-500x329.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco-300x197.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco-768x505.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco-800x526.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco-450x296.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco-900x592.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>The conference drew a worldwide audience in-person and <a href="https://webcast.unesco.org/events/2024-09-DLW/#">online</a> to hear about the work educators and policy makers are doing to support teachers&#8217; use of AI tools in their teaching and learning. Speaker after speaker reiterated that the shared goal of our work is to support learners to become critical consumers and responsible creators of AI systems.</p>



<p>In this blog, we share how our conference talk demonstrated the use of Experience AI for pursuing this globally shared goal, and how the Experience AI resources align with UNESCO&#8217;s newly launched AI competency framework for students.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Presenting the design principles behind Experience AI</h2>



<p>Our talk about <a href="https://experience-ai.org/">Experience AI</a>, our learning programme developed with Google DeepMind, focused on the research-informed approach we are taking in our resource development. Specifically, we spoke about three key design principles that we embed in the Experience AI resources:</p>



<p>Firstly, using AI and machine learning to solve problems requires learners and educators to think differently to traditional computational thinking and use a data-driven approach instead, as laid out in the research around <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/machine-learning-education-school-computational-thinking-2-0-research-seminar/">computational thinking 2.0</a>.</p>



<p>Secondly, every word we use in our teaching about AI is important to help young people form accurate mental models about how AI systems work. In particular, we focused our examples around <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ai-education-anthropomorphism/">the need to avoid anthropomorphising language when we describe AI systems</a>. Especially given that some developers produce AI systems with the aim to make them appear human-like in their design and outputs, it’s important that young people understand that <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/why-were-taking-a-problem-first-approach-to-the-development-of-ai-systems/">AI systems are in fact built and designed by humans</a>.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="283" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-5-500x283.png" alt="" class="wp-image-88234" style="width:710px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-5-500x283.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-5-300x170.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-5-768x435.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-5-1536x870.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-5-800x453.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-5-450x255.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-5-900x510.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-5.png 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>Thirdly we described how we used the <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ai-education-resources-what-to-teach-seame-framework/">SEAME framework</a> we adapted from work by Jane Waite (Raspberry Pi Foundation) and Paul Curzon (Queen Mary University, London) to categorise hundreds of AI education resources and inform the design of our Experience AI resources. The framework offers a common language for educators when assessing the content of resources, and when supporting learners to understand the different aspects of AI systems.&nbsp;</p>



<p>By presenting our design principles, we aimed to give educators, policy makers, and attendees from non-governmental organisations practical recommendations and actionable considerations for designing learning materials on AI literacy.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How Experience AI aligns with UNESCO&#8217;s new AI competency framework for students</h2>



<p>At Digital Learning Week, UNESCO launched two AI competency frameworks:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>A <a href="https://unesdoc.unesco.org/ark:/48223/pf0000391105">framework for students</a>, intended to help teachers around the world with integrating AI tools in activities to engage their learners</li>



<li>A <a href="https://unesdoc.unesco.org/search/10c7faad-c984-4e37-add4-3d455d104046">framework for teachers</a>, &#8220;defining the knowledge, skills, and values teachers must master in the age of AI&#8221;</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>AI competency framework for students</strong></p>



<p>We have had the chance to map the Experience AI resources to UNESCO’s AI framework for students at a high level, finding that the resources cover 10 of the 12 areas of the framework (see image below).</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="297" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-6-500x297.png" alt="" class="wp-image-88235" style="width:677px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-6-500x297.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-6-300x178.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-6-450x268.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-6.png 565w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">An adaptation of a summary table from UNESCO&#8217;s new student competency framework (<a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/igo/">CC-BY-SA 3.0 IGO</a>), highlighting the 10 areas covered by our Experience AI resources</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>For instance, throughout the Experience AI resources runs a thread of promoting &#8220;citizenship in the AI era&#8221;: the social and ethical aspects of AI technologies are highlighted in all the lessons and activities. In this way, they provide students with the foundational knowledge of how AI systems work, and where they may work badly. Using the resources, educators can teach their learners core AI and machine learning concepts and make these concepts concrete through practical activities where learners create their own models and critically evaluate their outputs. Importantly, by learning with Experience AI, students not only learn to be responsible users of AI tools, but also to consider fairness, accountability, transparency, and privacy when they create AI models.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Teacher competency framework for AI&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>UNESCO’s <a href="https://unesdoc.unesco.org/ark:/48223/pf0000391104">AI competency framework for teachers</a> outlines 15 competencies across 5 dimensions (see image below).&nbsp; We enjoyed listening to the launch panel members talk about the strong ambitions of the framework as well as the realities of teachers&#8217; global and local challenges. The three key messages of the panel were:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>AI will not replace the expertise of classroom teachers</li>



<li>Supporting educators to build AI competencies is a shared responsibility</li>



<li>Individual countries&#8217; education systems have different needs in terms of educator support</li>
</ul>



<p>All three messages resonate strongly with the work we&#8217;re doing at the Raspberry Pi Foundation. Supporting all educators is a fundamental part of our resource development. For example, Experience AI offers everything a teacher with no technical background needs to deliver the lessons, including lesson plans, videos, worksheets and slide decks. We also provide a free online training course on understanding AI for educators. And in <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-expands-to-reach-over-2-million-students/">our work with partner organisations around the world</a>, we <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/localising-ai-education-adapting-experience-ai-resources/">adapt and translate Experience AI resources</a> so they are culturally relevant, and we organise locally delivered teacher professional development.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="245" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-7-500x245.png" alt="" class="wp-image-88236" style="width:627px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-7-500x245.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-7-300x147.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-7-768x376.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-7-800x392.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-7-450x221.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-7-900x441.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/image-7.png 1306w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">A summary table from UNESCO&#8217;s new teacher competency framework (<a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/igo/">CC-BY-SA 3.0 IGO</a>)</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>&nbsp;The teachers&#8217; competency framework is meant as guidance for educators, policy makers, training providers, and application developers to support teachers in using AI effectively, and in helping their learners gain AI literacy skills. We will certainly consult the document as we develop our training and professional development resources for teachers further.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Towards AI literacy for all young people</h2>



<p>Across this year’s UNESCO’s Digital Learning Week, we saw that the role of AI in education took centre stage across the presentations and the informal conversations among attendees. It was a privilege to present our work and see how well Experience AI was received, with attendees recognising that our design principles align with the values and principles in UNESCO’s new AI competency frameworks.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="377" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco_2-500x377.jpg" alt="A conference table setup with a pair of headphones resting on top of a UNESCO brochure." class="wp-image-88245" style="width:628px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco_2-500x377.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco_2-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco_2-768x578.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco_2-1536x1157.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco_2-800x603.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco_2-450x339.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco_2-900x678.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/unesco_2.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>We look forward to continuing this international conversation about AI literacy and working in aligned ways to support all young people to develop a foundational understanding of AI technologies.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-unescos-digital-learning-week/">Experience AI at UNESCO’s Digital Learning Week</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-unescos-digital-learning-week/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Experience AI expands to reach over 2 million students</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-expands-to-reach-over-2-million-students/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-expands-to-reach-over-2-million-students/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Philip Colligan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 11:29:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Experience AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI literacy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=88144</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Two years ago, we announced Experience AI, a collaboration between the Raspberry Pi Foundation and Google DeepMind to inspire the next generation of AI leaders. Today I am excited to announce that we are expanding the programme with the aim of reaching more than 2 million students over the next 3 years, thanks to a&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-expands-to-reach-over-2-million-students/">Experience AI expands to reach over 2 million students</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Two years ago, we <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-deepmind-ai-education/">announced</a> Experience AI, a collaboration between the Raspberry Pi Foundation and <a href="https://deepmind.google/about/?_gl=1*1dknnl3*_up*MQ..*_ga*OTM4ODUzMjYzLjE3MjM1NDAyNjA.*_ga_LS8HVHCNQ0*MTcyMzU0MDI1OS4xLjAuMTcyMzU0MDI2Mi4wLjAuMA..">Google DeepMind</a> to inspire the next generation of AI leaders.</p>



<p>Today I am excited to announce that we are expanding the programme with the aim of reaching more than 2 million students over the next 3 years, thanks to a generous grant of $10m from Google.org.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="541" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Philip-cropped-1-500x541.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-88292" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Philip-cropped-1-500x541.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Philip-cropped-1-231x250.jpg 231w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Philip-cropped-1-768x831.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Philip-cropped-1-1419x1536.jpg 1419w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Philip-cropped-1-1892x2048.jpg 1892w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Philip-cropped-1-800x866.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Philip-cropped-1-450x487.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Philip-cropped-1-900x974.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Why do kids need to learn about AI</strong></h2>



<p>AI technologies are already changing the world, and we are told that their potential impact is unprecedented in human history. But just like every other wave of technological innovation, along with all of the opportunities, the advancement of AI has the potential to leave people behind, to exacerbate divisions, and to create more problems than it solves.</p>



<p>Part of the answer to this challenge lies in ensuring that all young people develop a foundational understanding of AI technologies and the role that they can play in their lives.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="342" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/04/Experience-AI-classroom-scaled-e1681724472404-500x342.jpg" alt="An educator points to an image on a student's computer screen." class="wp-image-83703" style="width:592px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/04/Experience-AI-classroom-scaled-e1681724472404-500x342.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/04/Experience-AI-classroom-scaled-e1681724472404-300x205.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/04/Experience-AI-classroom-scaled-e1681724472404-768x526.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/04/Experience-AI-classroom-scaled-e1681724472404-1536x1051.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/04/Experience-AI-classroom-scaled-e1681724472404-800x548.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/04/Experience-AI-classroom-scaled-e1681724472404-450x308.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/04/Experience-AI-classroom-scaled-e1681724472404-900x616.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/04/Experience-AI-classroom-scaled-e1681724472404.jpg 1683w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>That&#8217;s why the conversation about AI in education is so important. A lot of the focus of that conversation is on how we harness the power of AI technologies to improve teaching and learning. Enabling young people to use AI to learn is important, but it&#8217;s not enough.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We need to equip young people with the knowledge, skills, and mindsets to use AI technologies to create the world they want. And that means supporting their teachers, who once again are being asked to teach a subject that they didn&#8217;t study.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Experience AI&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p>That&#8217;s the work that we&#8217;re doing through <a href="https://experience-ai.org/en/">Experience AI</a>, an ambitious programme to provide teachers with free classroom resources and professional development, enabling them to teach their students about AI technologies and how they are changing the world. All of our resources are grounded in research defining the concepts that make up AI literacy, they are rooted in real-world examples drawing on the work of Google DeepMind, and they involve hands-on, interactive activities.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9721_XAI_Infographic_Update_V2.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="652" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9721_XAI_Infographic_Update_V2-500x652.png" alt="" class="wp-image-88155" style="width:515px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9721_XAI_Infographic_Update_V2-500x652.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9721_XAI_Infographic_Update_V2-192x250.png 192w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9721_XAI_Infographic_Update_V2-768x1001.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9721_XAI_Infographic_Update_V2-1179x1536.png 1179w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9721_XAI_Infographic_Update_V2-1572x2048.png 1572w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9721_XAI_Infographic_Update_V2-800x1043.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9721_XAI_Infographic_Update_V2-450x586.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9721_XAI_Infographic_Update_V2-900x1173.png 900w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></a></figure></div>


<p>The Experience AI resources have already been downloaded 100,000 times across 130 countries, and we estimate that 750,000 young people have taken part in an Experience AI lesson so far.</p>



<p>In November 2023, we announced that we were building a global network of partners that we would work with to localise and translate the Experience AI resources, ensuring they are culturally relevant, and to organise locally delivered teacher professional development. We&#8217;ve made a fantastic start working with partners in Canada, India, Kenya, Malaysia, and Romania, and it&#8217;s been brilliant to see the enthusiasm and demand for AI literacy from teachers and students across the globe.</p>



<p>Thanks to an incredibly generous donation of $10m from Google.org — announced at Google.org&#8217;s first impact summit — we will shortly be welcoming new partners in 17 countries across Europe, the Middle East, and Africa, with the aim of reaching more than 2 million students in the next three years.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">New resources on AI safety</h2>



<p>Alongside the expansion of the global network of Experience AI partners, we are also launching three new resources that focus on critical issues of AI safety:&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>AI and your data</strong>: Helping young people reflect on the data they are already providing to AI applications in their lives, and on how the prevalence of AI tools might change the way they protect their data.</p>



<p><strong>Media literacy in the age of AI</strong>: Highlighting to young people the ways AI tools can be used to perpetuate misinformation, and how AI applications can help combat misleading claims.</p>



<p><strong>Using generative AI responsibly</strong>: Empowering young people to reflect on their responsibilities when using generative AI, and their expectations of developers who release AI tools.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/aisafetyimage1-500x281.png" alt="A laptop surrounded by various screens displaying images, videos, and a world map." class="wp-image-88156" style="width:593px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/aisafetyimage1-500x281.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/aisafetyimage1-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/aisafetyimage1-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/aisafetyimage1-1536x864.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/aisafetyimage1-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/aisafetyimage1-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/aisafetyimage1-900x506.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/aisafetyimage1.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Get involved</strong></h2>



<p>In many ways, this moment in the development of AI technologies reminds me of the internet in the 1990s (yes, I am that old). We all knew that it had potential, but no-one could really imagine the full scale of what would follow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We failed to rise to the educational challenge of that moment and are still living with the consequences of that failure: a dire shortage of talent; a tech sector that doesn&#8217;t represent all communities and voices; and young people and communities who are still missing out on economic opportunities and unable to use technology to solve the problems that matter to them.</p>



<p>We have an opportunity to do a better job this time. If you&#8217;re interested in getting involved, we&#8217;d love to hear from you.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-3 wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://form.raspberrypi.org/4873612">Contact us</a></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-expands-to-reach-over-2-million-students/">Experience AI expands to reach over 2 million students</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-expands-to-reach-over-2-million-students/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Join the UK Bebras Challenge 2024</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/uk-bebras-challenge-2024/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/uk-bebras-challenge-2024/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Csizmadia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 10:19:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bebras]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computational thinking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UK Bebras Computational Thinking Challenge]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=88087</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The UK Bebras Challenge, the nation&#8217;s largest computing competition, is back and open for entries from schools. This year’s challenge will be open for entries from 4–15 November. Last year, over 400,000 students from across the UK took part. Read on to learn how your school can get involved. What is UK Bebras? UK Bebras&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/uk-bebras-challenge-2024/">Join the UK Bebras Challenge 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9638_Bebras_2024_Assets_V3_4_B-500x281.png" alt="" class="wp-image-88219" style="width:614px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9638_Bebras_2024_Assets_V3_4_B-500x281.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9638_Bebras_2024_Assets_V3_4_B-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9638_Bebras_2024_Assets_V3_4_B-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9638_Bebras_2024_Assets_V3_4_B-1536x864.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9638_Bebras_2024_Assets_V3_4_B-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9638_Bebras_2024_Assets_V3_4_B-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9638_Bebras_2024_Assets_V3_4_B-900x506.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/9638_Bebras_2024_Assets_V3_4_B.png 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>The <a href="https://www.bebras.uk/index.php?action=welcome">UK Bebras Challenge</a>, the nation&#8217;s largest computing competition, is back and open for entries from schools. This year’s challenge will be open for entries from 4–15 November. Last year, over 400,000 students from across the UK took part. Read on to learn how your school can get involved.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-4 wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://www.bebras.uk/admin/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">I want to register my school for Bebras</a></div>
</div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What is UK Bebras?</strong></h2>



<p>UK Bebras is a free-to-enter annual competition that is designed to spark interest in computational thinking among students aged 6 to 19 by providing engaging and thought-provoking activities. The 45-minute challenge is accessible to everyone, offering age-appropriate interactive questions for students at different levels, including a tailored version for students with severe sight impairments.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The questions are designed to give every student the opportunity to showcase their potential, whether they excel in maths or computing, or not. With self-marking questions and no programming required, it’s easy for schools to participate.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Thank you for another fantastic Bebras event! My students have really enjoyed it. This is the first year that one of my leadership team actually did the Bebras to understand what we are preparing the children for — she was very impressed!” Reference 5487</p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2016/01/widcombe-500x333.jpg" alt="A class of primary school students do coding at laptops." class="wp-image-18911" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2016/01/widcombe-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2016/01/widcombe-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2016/01/widcombe.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;I really enjoyed doing the Bebras challenge yesterday. It was the most accessible it’s ever been for me as a braillist/screen reader user.&#8221; Reference 5372</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What does a UK Bebras question look like?</strong></h2>



<p>The questions are inspired by classic computing problems but are presented in a fun, age-appropriate way. For instance, a puzzle for 6- to 8-year-olds might involve guiding a hungry tortoise along the most efficient path across a lawn, while 16- to 19-year-olds could be asked to sort members for quiz teams based on who knows who — a challenging problem relating to graph theory.</p>



<p>Here’s a question we ran in 2023 for the Castors group (ages 8 to 10). Can you solve it?&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Planting carrots</strong></p>



<p>A robotic rabbit is planting carrot seeds in these four earth mounds.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="225" height="43" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-7.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-88100" style="width:293px;height:auto"/></figure>



<p>It can respond to these commands:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table class="has-fixed-layout"><tbody><tr><td><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://lh7-qw.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXe6XQe8OIx6mGtLrZYBxodHqE-sLBjCGpcGCpK3D2AlP9dBkayuUgBRciwiWdMPE9hFVg9ERlzQmeDlcVST_FfiUObCCAZEuFixwIPXO7UXwPVGvSDISshP_F7EJYN-TmCk45Hlo3Y8NDeHCwF_MMclmoau?key=TpmqmkWyz_d1J4QC40Gf-g" width="133" height="101"><strong></strong></td><td>jump left to the next mound<strong><br></strong></td></tr><tr><td><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://lh7-qw.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXcFEXDkECY9nsqWwMkbPbt2SkA3ngByTkIlkCdXyO_wNWlsvOBiNQdgKzIa8PAiA1GubRTMHg_W_z2J_McdtO4mSYKk7cmSiacWeLhyyo8i9mW5c56TT-qpL7x6sZrB5YE2DNEZGf2WsenpC6aiDqNbJ_8?key=TpmqmkWyz_d1J4QC40Gf-g" width="133" height="102"><strong></strong></td><td><strong></strong>jump right to the next mound<br></td></tr><tr><td><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://lh7-qw.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXf6_W_qGu8srmuQWiNSS7yh096xzuFmXxO9cuhkXDCTIw6szGhs0RHZnnZyscrKujYfkU9tCNyDJcV-e2iTJQg7MzlvO6DeLjyN5MlnwLM90pIKoQrLnW-MOdrrZ3yBIIx4W_ARDyklLoJFaxuKT9pwxo1W?key=TpmqmkWyz_d1J4QC40Gf-g" width="132" height="103"><strong></strong></td><td>plant a carrot seed in the mound you are on</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>Here is a sequence of commands for the rabbit:</p>



<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://lh7-qw.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXdsWWjDCqmMltQAx81lB8IpisGRojPADijS1BZ_ylKXvypZTNgGzkCiXY3bSnFfS5CYrsrB0BVBYtL_SjNx4MknFWmZQZVohRkLzjHFXIP5x4IUftsAheOGZiyBQHqmTV35og3iR_ayu3YiRAwUNSWY0Hk1?key=TpmqmkWyz_d1J4QC40Gf-g" width="602" height="81"><br><strong><br></strong>We don&#8217;t know which mound the rabbit started on, but we do know that, when it followed this sequence, it placed each of three carrot seeds on different mounds.</p>



<p><strong>Question:</strong>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Which picture shows how the carrot seeds could have been planted by the robot following the sequence of commands?</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="103" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-7-500x103.png" alt="" class="wp-image-88096" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-7-500x103.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-7-300x62.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-7-450x93.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-7.png 740w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure>



<p><strong>Example puzzle answer</strong></p>



<p>The correct answer is: <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://lh7-qw.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXd1lKmLPIkyPrWKK-4b-nThS3bEOPLee-6fd1b2LsZdbXQ1S7vdEsAJESP0rdvFGgUd6sjekeBwe5jko6GG8thJ62aMYFLUta1NeqRDvTKGe20JfLKKigOK1WsHqtIqVpZ8N_lrJ561Oh3dPEx31Zkd4YcD?key=TpmqmkWyz_d1J4QC40Gf-g" width="253" height="40"></p>



<p>The image below shows the route the robot takes by following the instructions:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="67" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-6-500x67.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-88095" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-6-500x67.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-6-300x40.jpeg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-6-450x60.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-6.jpeg 626w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="258" height="70" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-88088"/></figure>



<p>After executing the first two commands</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="136" height="62" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-1.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-88089"/></figure>



<p>the rabbit places the seed on the mound to the far right:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="258" height="55" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-2.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-88090"/></figure>



<p>It then executes the commands</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="139" height="61" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-3.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-88091"/></figure>



<p>and lays the next seed:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="259" height="56" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-4.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-88092"/></figure>



<p>Then it jumps to the left twice and lays the last seed</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="201" height="64" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-6.png" alt="" class="wp-image-88093"/></figure>



<p>So the carrot seeds will be on the hills in the order:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="253" height="40" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-5.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-88094"/></figure>



<p>Did you get it right?</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How do I get my school involved?</strong></h2>



<p>Visit the <a href="https://www.bebras.uk/">UK Bebras website</a> for more information and to register your school. Once you’ve registered, you&#8217;ll get access to the entire UK Bebras back catalogue of questions, allowing you to create custom quizzes for your students to tackle at any time throughout the year. These quizzes are self-marking, and you can download your students&#8217; results to keep track of their progress. Schools have found these questions perfect for enrichment activities, end-of-term quizzes, lesson starters, and even full lessons to develop computational thinking skills.</p>



<p>Join for free at <a href="https://bebras.uk/admin">bebras.uk/admin</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/uk-bebras-challenge-2024/">Join the UK Bebras Challenge 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/uk-bebras-challenge-2024/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bridging the gap from Scratch to Python: Introducing &#8216;Paint with Python&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/learn-to-code-python/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/learn-to-code-python/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Marc Scott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 09:34:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Python]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[text-based programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding for kids]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=88064</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We have developed an innovative activity to support young people as they transition from visual programming languages like Scratch to text-based programming languages like Python. This activity introduces a unique interface that empowers learners to easily interact with Python while they create a customised painting app. “The kids liked the self-paced learning, it allowed them&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/learn-to-code-python/">Bridging the gap from Scratch to Python: Introducing &#8216;Paint with Python&#8217;</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We have developed an innovative activity to support young people as they transition from visual programming languages like Scratch to text-based programming languages like Python.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="375" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-2-500x375.png" alt="An illustration of a web browser window with colourful tags and labels around it." class="wp-image-88065" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-2-500x375.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-2-300x225.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-2-768x576.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-2-800x600.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-2-450x338.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-2.png 900w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>This activity introduces a unique interface that empowers learners to easily interact with Python while they create a customised painting app.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The kids liked the self-paced learning, it allowed them to work at their own rate. They liked using RGB tables to find their specific colours.” – Code Club mentor</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Why learn to code Python?</strong></h2>



<p>We&#8217;ve long been championing Python as an ideal tool for young people who want to start text-based programming. Python has simple syntax and needs very few lines of code to get started, and there is a vibrant community of supportive programmers surrounding it.</p>



<p>However, we know that starting with Python can be challenging for young people who have never done any text-based coding. They can face obstacles such as software installation issues, getting used to a new syntax, and the need for appropriate typing skills.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How &#8216;Paint with Python&#8217; helps learners get started</strong></h2>



<p>&#8216;Paint with Python&#8217; is an online educational activity that addresses many of these challenges and helps young people learn to code Python for the first time. It’s entirely web-based, requiring no software installation beyond a web browser. Instructions are displayed in a side panel, allowing learners to read and code without needing to switch tabs.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="186" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-4-500x186.png" alt="" class="wp-image-88067" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-4-500x186.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-4-300x112.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-4-768x286.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-4-1536x572.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-4-800x298.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-4-450x168.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-4-900x335.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-4.png 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>To help young people with creating their painting app, much of the initial code is pre-written behind the scenes, which enables learners to focus on experimenting with Python and observing the outcomes. They engage with the code by clicking on suggested options or, in some cases, by typing small snippets of Python. For example, they can select colours from a range of options or, as they grow more confident, type RGB values to create custom colours.</p>



<p>The activity is fully responsive for mobile and tablet devices and provides a final view of the full program on the last page, together with suggested routes to continue learning text-based programming.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>An accessible introduction to text-based programming</strong></h2>



<p>We believe this activity offers an accessible way for young learners to begin their journey with text-based programming and learning to code Python. The code they write is straightforward and the activity is designed to minimise errors. When mistakes do occur, the interface provides clear, constructive feedback, guiding learners to make corrections.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="297" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-5-500x297.png" alt="" class="wp-image-88068" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-5-500x297.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-5-300x178.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-5-768x456.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-5-1536x911.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-5-800x475.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-5-450x267.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-5-900x534.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/image-5.png 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>Try out &#8216;Paint with Python&#8217; at<a href="http://rpf.io/paint-with-python"> rpf.io/paint-with-python</a>. We’d love to hear your feedback! Please send any thoughts you have to uxresearch@raspberrypi.org.&nbsp;</p>



<p><em>This activity was developed with support from the Cisco Foundation. Through our funding partnership with them, we&#8217;ve been able to provide thousands of young people with the inspiration and opportunity to progress their coding skills anywhere, and on any device.</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/learn-to-code-python/">Bridging the gap from Scratch to Python: Introducing &#8216;Paint with Python&#8217;</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/learn-to-code-python/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
