<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Raspberry Pi Foundation</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/</link>
	<description>Teach, learn and make with Raspberry Pi</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 10:51:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/06/cropped-raspberrry_pi_logo-100x100.png</url>
	<title>Raspberry Pi Foundation</title>
	<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Teaching about AI in schools: Take part in our Research and Educator Community Symposium</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teaching-about-ai-in-schools-research-and-educator-community-symposium/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teaching-about-ai-in-schools-research-and-educator-community-symposium/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jane Waite]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 10:51:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research and Educator Community Symposium]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi Computing Education Research Centre]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=88786</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Worldwide, the use of generative AI systems and related technologies is transforming our lives. From marketing and social media to education and industry, these technologies are being used everywhere, even if it isn’t obvious. Yet, despite the growing availability and use of generative AI tools, governments are still working out how and when to regulate&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teaching-about-ai-in-schools-research-and-educator-community-symposium/">Teaching about AI in schools: Take part in our Research and Educator Community Symposium</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Worldwide, the use of generative AI systems and related technologies is transforming our lives. From marketing and social media to education and industry, these technologies are being used everywhere, even if it isn’t obvious. Yet, despite the growing availability and use of generative AI tools, governments are still working out how and when to regulate such technologies to ensure they don’t cause unforeseen negative consequences. </p>



<p>How, then, do we equip our young people to deal with the <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/why-were-taking-a-problem-first-approach-to-the-development-of-ai-systems/">opportunities and challenges that they are faced with from generative AI applications and associated systems</a>? Teaching them <strong>about</strong> AI technologies seems an important first step. But what should we teach, when, and how?</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="500" height="334" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2017/11/DSC_6056-500x334.jpg" alt="A teacher aids children in the classroom" class="wp-image-38319" style="width:676px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2017/11/DSC_6056-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2017/11/DSC_6056-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2017/11/DSC_6056-768x513.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2017/11/DSC_6056-1618x1080.jpg 1618w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Researching AI curriculum design</strong></h2>



<p>The researchers at the Raspberry Pi Foundation have been looking at research that will help inform curriculum design and resource development to teach about AI in school. As part of this work, a number of research themes have been established, which we would like to explore with educators at a face-to-face symposium.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These research themes include the SEAME model, a simple way to analyse learning experiences about AI technology, as well as anthropomorphisation and how this might influence the formation of mental models about AI products. These research themes have become the cornerstone of the Experience AI resources we’ve co-developed with Google DeepMind. We will be using these materials to exemplify how the research themes can be used in practice as we review the recently published UNESCO AI competencies.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="500" height="334" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/IMG_0018-500x334.jpg" alt="A group of educators at a workshop." class="wp-image-88796" style="width:674px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/IMG_0018-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/IMG_0018-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/IMG_0018-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/IMG_0018-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/IMG_0018-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/IMG_0018-900x600.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/IMG_0018.jpg 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>Most importantly, we will also review how we can help teachers and learners move from a rule-based view of problem solving to a data-driven view, from computational thinking 1.0 to <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/machine-learning-education-school-computational-thinking-2-0-research-seminar/">computational thinking 2.0</a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>A call for teacher input on the AI curriculum</strong></h2>



<p>Over ten years ago, teachers in England experienced a large-scale change in what they needed to teach in computing lessons when programming was more formally added to the curriculum. As we enter a similar period of change — this time to introduce teaching about AI technologies — we want to hear from teachers as we collectively start to rethink our subject and curricula.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We think it is imperative that educators’ voices are heard as we reimagine computer science and add data-driven technologies into an already densely packed learning context.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="500" height="349" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/CC_WORKSHOP230819-126-500x349.jpg" alt="Educators at a workshop." class="wp-image-88809" style="width:690px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/CC_WORKSHOP230819-126-500x349.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/CC_WORKSHOP230819-126-300x209.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/CC_WORKSHOP230819-126-768x535.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/CC_WORKSHOP230819-126-800x558.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/CC_WORKSHOP230819-126-450x314.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/CC_WORKSHOP230819-126-900x627.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/CC_WORKSHOP230819-126-216x150.jpg 216w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/CC_WORKSHOP230819-126.jpg 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Join our Research and Educator Community Symposium</strong></h2>



<p>On <strong>Saturday, 1 February 2025</strong>, we are running a <strong>Research and Educator Community Symposium</strong> in collaboration with the <a href="https://computingeducationresearch.org/">Raspberry Pi Computing Education Research Centre</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In this symposium, we will bring together UK educators and researchers to review research themes, competency frameworks, and early international AI curricula and to reflect on how to advance approaches to teaching about AI. This will be a practical day of collaboration to produce suggested key concepts and pedagogical approaches and highlight research needs.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="334" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/Research-Centre_Launch_low-res-24-500x334.jpg" alt="Educators and researchers at an event. " class="wp-image-88800" style="width:684px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/Research-Centre_Launch_low-res-24-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/Research-Centre_Launch_low-res-24-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/Research-Centre_Launch_low-res-24-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/Research-Centre_Launch_low-res-24-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/Research-Centre_Launch_low-res-24-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/Research-Centre_Launch_low-res-24-900x600.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/Research-Centre_Launch_low-res-24.jpg 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>This symposium focuses on<strong> teaching about AI technologies</strong>, so we will <strong>not </strong>be looking at which AI tools might be used in general teaching and learning or how they may change teacher productivity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is vitally important for young people to learn how to use AI technologies in their daily lives so they can become discerning consumers of AI applications. But how should we teach them? Please help us start to consider the best approach by signing up for our Research and Educator Community Symposium by 9 December 2024.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Information at a glance</strong></h2>



<p><strong>When:</strong>  Saturday, 1 February 2025 (10am to 5pm) </p>



<p><strong>Where:</strong> Raspberry Pi Foundation Offices, Cambridge</p>



<p><strong>Who:</strong> If you have started teaching about AI, are creating related resources, are providing professional development about AI technologies, or if you are planning to do so, please apply to attend our symposium. Travel funding is available for teachers in England.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-1 wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://cambridge.eu.qualtrics.com/jfe/form/SV_9LZiHyJjn6UPGm2">Apply by 9 December 2024</a></div>
</div>



<p>Please note we expect to be oversubscribed, so book early and tell us about why you are interested in taking part. We will notify all applicants of the outcome of their application by 11 December.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teaching-about-ai-in-schools-research-and-educator-community-symposium/">Teaching about AI in schools: Take part in our Research and Educator Community Symposium</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teaching-about-ai-in-schools-research-and-educator-community-symposium/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Introducing new artificial intelligence and machine learning projects for Code Clubs</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/artificial-intelligence-projects-for-kids/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/artificial-intelligence-projects-for-kids/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pete Bell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 09:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Project paths]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Projects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding projects]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=88639</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We’re pleased to share a new collection of Code Club projects designed to introduce creators to the fascinating world of artificial intelligence (AI) and machine learning (ML). These projects bring the latest technology to your Code Club in fun and inspiring ways, making AI and ML engaging and accessible for young people. We’d like to&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/artificial-intelligence-projects-for-kids/">Introducing new artificial intelligence and machine learning projects for Code Clubs</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We’re pleased to share <a href="http://rpf.io/ai">a new collection of Code Club projects</a> designed to introduce creators to the fascinating world of artificial intelligence (AI) and machine learning (ML). These projects bring the latest technology to your Code Club in fun and inspiring ways, making AI and ML engaging and accessible for young people. We’d like to thank <strong>Amazon Future Engineer</strong> for supporting the development of this collection.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="263" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-13-500x263.png" alt="A man on a blue background, with question marks over his head, surrounded by various objects and animals, such as apples, planets, mice, a dinosaur and a shark." class="wp-image-88749" style="width:673px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-13-500x263.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-13-300x158.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-13-768x403.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-13-1536x806.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-13-800x420.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-13-450x236.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-13-900x473.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-13.png 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The value of learning about AI and ML</strong></h2>



<p>By engaging with AI and ML at a young age, creators gain a clearer understanding of the capabilities and limitations of these technologies, helping them to challenge misconceptions. This early exposure also builds foundational skills that are increasingly important in various fields, preparing creators for future educational and career opportunities. Additionally, as AI and ML become more integrated into educational standards, having a strong base in these concepts will make it easier for creators to grasp more advanced topics later on.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What’s included in this collection</strong></h2>



<p>We’re excited to offer a range of AI and ML projects that feature both video tutorials and step-by-step written guides. The video tutorials are designed to guide creators through each activity at their own pace and are captioned to improve accessibility. The step-by-step written guides support creators who prefer learning through reading.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The projects are crafted to be flexible and engaging. The main part of each project can be completed in just a few minutes, leaving lots of time for customisation and exploration. This setup allows for short, enjoyable sessions that can easily be incorporated into Code Club activities.</p>



<p>The collection is organised into two distinct paths, each offering a unique approach to learning about AI and ML:</p>



<p><a href="http://rpf.io/mlws"><strong>Machine learning with Scratch</strong></a> introduces foundational concepts of ML through creative and interactive projects. Creators will train models to recognise patterns and make predictions, and explore how these models can be improved with additional data.</p>



<p><a href="http://rpf.io/ai-toolkit"><strong>The AI Toolkit</strong></a> introduces various AI applications and technologies through hands-on projects using different platforms and tools. Creators will work with voice recognition, facial recognition, and other AI technologies, gaining a broad understanding of how AI can be applied in different contexts.</p>



<p>Inclusivity is a key aspect of this collection. The projects cater to various skill levels and are offered alongside an unplugged activity, ensuring that everyone can participate, regardless of available resources. Creators will also have the opportunity to stretch themselves — they can explore advanced technologies like Adobe Firefly and practical tools for managing Ollama and Stable Diffusion models on Raspberry Pi computers.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Project examples</strong></h2>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="263" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-14-500x263.png" alt="A piece of cheese is displayed on a screen. There are multiple mice around the screen. " class="wp-image-88750" style="width:672px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-14-500x263.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-14-300x158.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-14-768x403.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-14-1536x806.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-14-800x420.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-14-450x236.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-14-900x473.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-14.png 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>One of the highlights of our new collection is <a href="http://rpf.io/chomp"><strong>Chomp the </strong><strong>c</strong><strong>heese</strong></a>, which uses Scratch Lab&#8217;s experimental face recognition technology to create a game students can play with their mouth! This project offers a playful introduction to facial recognition while keeping the experience interactive and fun.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="263" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-15-500x263.png" alt="A big orange fish on a dark blue background, with green leaves surrounding the fish. " class="wp-image-88751" style="width:674px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-15-500x263.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-15-300x158.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-15-768x403.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-15-1536x806.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-15-800x420.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-15-450x236.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-15-900x473.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-15.png 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p><a href="http://rpf.io/fish"><strong>Fish </strong><strong>f</strong><strong>ood</strong></a> uses <a href="https://machinelearningforkids.co.uk/#!/about">Machine Learning for Kids</a>, with creators training a model to control a fish using voice commands.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="263" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-16-500x263.png" alt="An illustration of a pink brain is displayed on a screen. There are two hands next to the screen playing the 'Rock paper scissors' game. " class="wp-image-88752" style="width:678px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-16-500x263.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-16-300x158.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-16-768x403.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-16-1536x806.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-16-800x420.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-16-450x236.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-16-900x473.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-16.png 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>In <a href="http://rpf.io/tam"><strong>Teach a </strong><strong>m</strong><strong>achine</strong></a>, creators train a computer to recognise different objects such as fingers or food items. This project introduces classification in a straightforward way using the <a href="https://teachablemachine.withgoogle.com/">Teachable Machine</a> platform, making the concept easy to grasp.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="263" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-17-500x263.png" alt="Two men on a blue background, surrounded by question marks, a big green apple and a red tomato. " class="wp-image-88753" style="width:682px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-17-500x263.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-17-300x158.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-17-768x403.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-17-1536x806.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-17-800x420.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-17-450x236.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-17-900x473.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-17.png 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p><a href="http://rpf.io/avt"><strong>Apple vs </strong><strong>t</strong><strong>omato</strong></a> also uses Teachable Machine, but this time creators are challenged to train a model to differentiate between apples and tomatoes. Initially, the model exhibits bias due to limited data, prompting discussions on the importance of data diversity and ethical AI practices.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="263" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-18-500x263.png" alt="Three people on a light blue background, surrounded by music notes and a microbit. " class="wp-image-88754" style="width:680px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-18-500x263.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-18-300x158.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-18-768x403.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-18-1536x806.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-18-800x420.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-18-450x236.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-18-900x473.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-18.png 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p><a href="http://rpf.io/dance"><strong>Dance </strong><strong>d</strong><strong>etector</strong></a> allows creators to use accelerometer data from a micro:bit to train a model to recognise dance moves like Floss or Disco. This project combines physical computing with AI, helping creators explore movement recognition technology they may have experienced in familiar contexts such as video games.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="263" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-19-500x263.png" alt="A green dinosaur in a forest is being observed by a person hiding in the bush holding the binoculars. " class="wp-image-88755" style="width:682px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-19-500x263.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-19-300x158.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-19-768x403.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-19-1536x806.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-19-800x420.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-19-450x236.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-19-900x473.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-19.png 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p><a href="http://rpf.io/dinodecisions"><strong>Dinosaur </strong><strong>d</strong><strong>ecision </strong><strong>t</strong><strong>ree</strong></a> is an unplugged activity where creators use a paper-based branching chart to classify different types of dinosaurs. This hands-on project introduces the concept of decision-making structures, where each branch of the chart represents a choice or question leading to a different outcome. By constructing their own decision tree, creators gain a tactile understanding of how these models are used in ML to analyse data and make predictions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These AI projects are designed to support young people to get hands-on with AI technologies in Code Clubs and other non-formal learning environments. Creators can also enter one of their projects into <a href="https://online.coolestprojects.org">Coolest Projects</a> by taking a short video showing their project and any code used to make it. Their creation will then be showcased in the online gallery for people all over the world to see.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/artificial-intelligence-projects-for-kids/">Introducing new artificial intelligence and machine learning projects for Code Clubs</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/artificial-intelligence-projects-for-kids/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Implementing a computing curriculum in Telangana</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/implementing-a-computing-curriculum-in-telangana/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/implementing-a-computing-curriculum-in-telangana/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Fiona Coventry]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 09:09:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Impact of our work]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=88723</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Last year we launched a partnership with the Government of Telangana Social Welfare Residential Educational Institutions Society (TGSWREIS) in Telangana, India to develop and implement a computing curriculum at their Coding Academy School and Coding Academy College. Our impact team is conducting an evaluation. Read on to find out more about the partnership and what&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/implementing-a-computing-curriculum-in-telangana/">Implementing a computing curriculum in Telangana</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Last year we <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/tswreis-coding-academy-computing-education-partnership-telangana/">launched a partnership with the Government of Telangana Social Welfare Residential Educational Institutions Society (TGSWREIS) </a>in Telangana, India to develop and implement a computing curriculum at their Coding Academy School and Coding Academy College. Our impact team is conducting an evaluation. Read on to find out more about the partnership and what we’ve learned so far.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Aim of the partnership&nbsp;</h2>



<p>The aim of our partnership is to enable students in the school and undergraduate college to learn about coding and computing by providing the best possible curriculum, resources, and training for teachers.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/india-school-500x333.png" alt="Students sit in a classroom and watch the lecture slides. " class="wp-image-88734" style="width:670px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/india-school-500x333.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/india-school-300x200.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/india-school-768x512.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/india-school-800x533.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/india-school-450x300.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/india-school.png 900w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>As both institutions are government institutions, education is provided for free, with&nbsp;approximately 800 high-performing students from disadvantaged backgrounds currently benefiting. The school is co-educational up to grade 10 and the college is for female undergraduate students only.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The partnership is strategically important for us at the Raspberry Pi Foundation because it helps us to test curriculum content in an Indian context, and specifically with learners from historically marginalised communities with limited resources.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Adapting our curriculum content for use in Telangana</h2>



<p>Since our partnership began, we’ve developed curriculum content for students in grades 6–12 in the school, which is in line with India’s national education policy requiring coding to be introduced from grade 6. We’ve also developed curriculum content for the undergraduate students at the college.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="367" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/DSC00893-500x367.jpg" alt="Students and educators engage in digital making. " class="wp-image-88731" style="width:644px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/DSC00893-500x367.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/DSC00893-300x220.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/DSC00893-768x564.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/DSC00893-800x587.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/DSC00893-450x330.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/DSC00893-900x661.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/DSC00893.jpg 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>In both cases, the content was developed based on an initial needs assessment — we used the assessment to adapt content from our previous work on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/curriculum">The Computing Curriculum</a>. Local examples were integrated to make the content relatable and culturally relevant for students in Telangana. Additionally, we tailored the content for different lesson durations and to allow a higher frequency of lessons. We captured impact and learning data through assessments, lesson observations, educator interviews, student surveys, and student focus groups.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Curriculum well received by educators and students</h2>



<p>We have found that the partnership is succeeding in meeting many of its objectives. The curriculum resources have received lots of positive feedback from students, educators, and observers.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="282" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/IMG_4811-500x282.jpg" alt="Students and educators engage in digital making. " class="wp-image-88728" style="width:666px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/IMG_4811-500x282.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/IMG_4811-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/IMG_4811-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/IMG_4811-800x450.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/IMG_4811-450x253.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/IMG_4811-900x507.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/IMG_4811.jpg 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>In our recent survey, 96% of school students and 85% of college students reported that they’ve learned new things in their computing classes. This was backed up by assessment marks, with students scoring an average of 70% in the school and 69% in the college for each assessment, compared to a pass mark of 40%. Students were also positive about their experiences of the computing and coding classes, and particularly enjoyed the practical components.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“My favourite thing in this computing classes [sic] is doing practical projects. By doing [things] practically we learnt a lot.” &#8211; Third year undergraduate student, Coding Academy College</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Since their last SA [summative assessment] exam, students have learnt spreadsheet [concepts] and have enjoyed applying them in activities. Their favourite part has been example codes, programming, and web-designing activities.” &#8211; Student focus group facilitator, grade 9 students, Coding Academy School</p>
</blockquote>



<p>However, we also found some variation in outcomes for different groups of students and identified some improvements that are needed to ensure the content is appropriate for all. For example, educators and students felt improvements were needed to the content for undergraduates specialising in data science — there was a wish for the content to be more challenging and to more effectively prepare students for the workplace. Some amendments have been made to this content and we will continue to keep this under review.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In addition, we faced some challenges with the equipment and infrastructure available. For example, there were instances of power cuts and unstable internet connections. These issues have been addressed as far as possible with Wi-Fi dongles and educators adapting their delivery to work with the equipment available.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Our ambition for India</h2>



<p>Our team has already made some improvements to our curriculum content in preparation for the new academic year. We will also make further improvements based on the feedback received.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="282" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/DSC00942-500x282.jpg" alt="Students and educators engage in digital making. " class="wp-image-88729" style="width:647px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/DSC00942-500x282.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/DSC00942-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/DSC00942-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/DSC00942-800x450.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/DSC00942-450x253.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/DSC00942-900x507.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/DSC00942.jpg 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>The long-term vision for our work in India is to enable any school in India to teach students about computing and creating with digital technologies. Over our five-year partnership, we plan to work with TGSWREIS to roll out a computing curriculum to other government schools within the state.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Through our work in Telangana and <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/introducing-a-computing-curriculum-in-odisha/">Odisha</a>, we are learning about the unique challenges faced by government schools. We&#8217;re designing our curriculum to address these challenges and ensure that every student in India has the opportunity to thrive in the 21st century. If you would like to know more about our work and impact in India, please reach out to us at <a href="mailto:india@raspberrypi.org">india@raspberrypi.org</a>.</p>



<p>We take the evaluation of our work seriously and are always looking to understand how we can improve and increase the impact we have on the lives of young people. To find out more about <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/our-focus-on-impact/">our approach to impact</a>, you can read about our recently updated <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/theory-of-change-2024/">theory of change</a>, which supports how we evaluate what we do.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/implementing-a-computing-curriculum-in-telangana/">Implementing a computing curriculum in Telangana</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/implementing-a-computing-curriculum-in-telangana/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Introducing picamzero: Simplifying Raspberry Pi Camera projects for beginners</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/picamzero-raspberry-pi-camera-projects-for-beginners/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/picamzero-raspberry-pi-camera-projects-for-beginners/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Laura Sach]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 10:23:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Python]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[picamzero]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[raspberry pi camera]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi Camera Module]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=88672</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Thousands of learners worldwide take their first steps into text-based programming using the Python programming language. Python is not only beginner-friendly, but is also used extensively in industry. In 2015, Python developer Daniel Pope, who has a keen interest in education, noticed that beginners often have great ideas for creating projects but struggle because the&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/picamzero-raspberry-pi-camera-projects-for-beginners/">Introducing picamzero: Simplifying Raspberry Pi Camera projects for beginners</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Thousands of learners worldwide take their first steps into text-based programming using the Python programming language. Python is not only beginner-friendly, but is also used extensively in industry.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/CodeClub_ParkStreet-22-500x333.jpg" alt="An educator helps two young learners with a coding project in a classroom." class="wp-image-88307" style="width:562px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/CodeClub_ParkStreet-22-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/CodeClub_ParkStreet-22-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/CodeClub_ParkStreet-22-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/CodeClub_ParkStreet-22-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/CodeClub_ParkStreet-22-2048x1366.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/CodeClub_ParkStreet-22-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/CodeClub_ParkStreet-22-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/CodeClub_ParkStreet-22-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>In 2015, Python developer Daniel Pope, who has a keen interest in education, noticed that beginners often have great ideas for creating projects but struggle because the software libraries they need to use are aimed at more confident programmers. To address this, he created <a href="https://pygame-zero.readthedocs.io/en/stable/#">Pygame Zero</a> — a simplified version of the popular PyGame software. Since then, various developers have expanded the range of &#8216;zero&#8217; libraries for Python.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How Python zero libraries help beginner programmers</strong></h2>



<p>The Raspberry Pi Foundation has a long history of supporting Python zero libraries. <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.com/news/gpio-zero-a-friendly-python-api-for-physical-computing/">GPIO Zero</a> was launched back in 2015, followed by <a href="https://lawsie.github.io/guizero/">guizero</a> and then <a href="https://picozero.readthedocs.io/en/latest/">picozero</a>. The goal of all &#8216;zero&#8217; libraries is the same: to help beginner programmers create amazing projects using simple, understandable code, supported by useful documentation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Picamera2 library is a powerful tool for advanced users, but beginners — such as <a href="https://astro-pi.org/mission-space-lab">Astro Pi: Mission Space Lab</a> programme participants — would benefit from a zero library to allow them to use the Raspberry Pi Camera module.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-11-500x281.png" alt="The Astro Pi Mark II units." class="wp-image-88673" style="width:580px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-11-500x281.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-11-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-11-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-11.png 720w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">The Astro Pi Mark II units</figcaption></figure></div>

<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="375" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/astro-pi-1-500x375.png" alt="" class="wp-image-88701" style="width:585px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/astro-pi-1-500x375.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/astro-pi-1-300x225.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/astro-pi-1-768x575.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/astro-pi-1-800x599.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/astro-pi-1-450x337.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/astro-pi-1-900x674.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/astro-pi-1.png 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Image taken by Astro Pi: Mission Space Lab programme participants</figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Picamzero: how to get started</strong></h2>



<p>The Code Club Projects and Youth Programmes teams at the Raspberry Pi Foundation have joined forces to create<strong> <code>picamzero</code></strong>: a new library that makes it simple for beginners to use the Raspberry Pi Camera board.</p>



<p>As with the other &#8216;zero&#8217; libraries, it’s straightforward to get started. You can install picamzero by typing two commands in your Raspberry Pi&#8217;s terminal:</p>



<p><code>sudo apt update</code></p>



<p><code>sudo apt install python3-picamzero</code></p>



<p>Once it&#8217;s installed, setting up your program to communicate with your camera is easy:</p>



<p><code>from picamzero import Camera</code></p>



<p><code>cam = Camera()</code></p>



<p>You can ask picamzero to take a time-lapse sequence and make a video of your images using a single line of code.</p>



<p><code>cam.capture_sequence("mysequence.jpg", make_video=True)</code></p>



<p>Picamzero also makes it easy to add text and image overlays to your images.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="403" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-12-500x403.png" alt="A Lego scene captured using picamzero." class="wp-image-88674" style="width:596px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-12-500x403.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-12-300x242.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-12-768x618.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-12-800x644.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-12-450x362.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-12-900x725.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-12.png 1274w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">A Lego scene captured using picamzero</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>We&#8217;ve written beginner-friendly <a href="https://raspberrypifoundation.github.io/picamera-zero/">documentation</a> for the new library so that you can explore what you can create using just a few lines of code. We&#8217;ve also updated our resources so that you can start making exciting projects using picamzero straight away:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/projects/getting-started-with-picamera">Getting started with Picamera</a></li>



<li><a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/projects/cress-egg-heads/">Cress Egg Heads</a></li>



<li><a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/projects/parent-detector">Parent Detector</a></li>



<li><a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/projects/push-button-stop-motion">Push button stop motion</a></li>
</ul>



<p>We hope you enjoy using picamzero. Please get in touch if you have any feedback or suggestions. Happy coding!</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/picamzero-raspberry-pi-camera-projects-for-beginners/">Introducing picamzero: Simplifying Raspberry Pi Camera projects for beginners</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/picamzero-raspberry-pi-camera-projects-for-beginners/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to make debugging a positive experience for secondary school students</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/debugging-positive-experience-secondary-school-students/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/debugging-positive-experience-secondary-school-students/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Bonnie Sheppard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 08:48:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research seminar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=88650</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Artificial intelligence (AI) continues to change many areas of our lives, with new AI technologies and software having the potential to significantly impact the way programming is taught at schools. In our seminar series this year, we’ve already heard about new AI code generators that can support and motivate young people when learning to code,&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/debugging-positive-experience-secondary-school-students/">How to make debugging a positive experience for secondary school students</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Artificial intelligence (AI) continues to change many areas of our lives, with new AI technologies and software having the potential to significantly impact the way programming is taught at schools. In our seminar series this year, we’ve already heard about <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/using-an-ai-code-generator-with-school-age-beginner-programmers/">new AI code generators</a> that can support and motivate young people when learning to code, AI tools that can create <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/supporting-learners-with-programming-tasks-through-ai-generated-parsons-problems/">personalised Parson’s Problems</a>, and research into <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/error-message-explanations-large-language-models-teachers-views/">how generative AI could improve young people’s understanding of program error messages</a>.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="334" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/08/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_016-500x334.jpg" alt="Two teenage girls do coding activities at their laptops in a classroom." class="wp-image-73546" style="width:574px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/08/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_016-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/08/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_016-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/08/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_016-768x513.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/08/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_016-1536x1025.jpg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>At times, it can seem like everything is being automated with AI. However, there are some parts of learning to program that cannot (and probably should not) be automated, such as understanding errors in code and how to fix them. Manually typing code might not be necessary in the future, but it will still be crucial to understand the code that is being generated and how to improve and develop it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As important as debugging might be for the future of programming, it’s still often the task most disliked by novice programmers. Even if program error messages can be explained in the future or tools like LitterBox can flag bugs in an engaging way, actually <strong>fixing</strong> the issues involves time, effort, and resilience — which can be hard to come by at the end of a computing lesson in the late afternoon with 30 students crammed into an IT room.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="195" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-7-500x195.png" alt="" class="wp-image-88651" style="width:605px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-7-500x195.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-7-300x117.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-7-768x299.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-7-800x311.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-7-450x175.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-7.png 897w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Debugging can be challenging in many different ways and it is important to understand why students struggle to be able to support them better.</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>But what is it about debugging that young people find so hard, even when they’re given enough time to do it? And how can we make debugging a more motivating experience for young people? These are two of the questions that Laurie Gale, a PhD student at the Raspberry Pi Computing Education Research Centre, focused on in our July seminar.</p>



<h1 class="wp-block-heading">Why do students find debugging hard?</h1>



<p>Laurie has spent the past two years talking to teachers and students and developing tools (a <a href="https://github.com/LaurieGale10/program-logs-viewer">visualiser of students&#8217; programming behaviour</a> and <a href="https://primmdebug.web.app/">PRIMMDebug</a>, a teaching process and tool for debugging) to understand why many secondary school students struggle with debugging. It has quickly become clear through his research that most issues are due to problematic debugging strategies and students’ negative experiences and attitudes.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="426" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-500x426.jpeg" alt="A photograph of Laurie Gale. " class="wp-image-88652" style="width:628px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-500x426.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-294x250.jpeg 294w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-768x654.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-1536x1308.jpeg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-800x681.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-450x383.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-900x766.jpeg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image.jpeg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>When Laurie Gale started looking into debugging research for his PhD, he noticed that the majority of studies had been with college students, so he decided to change that and find out what would make debugging easier for novice programmers at secondary school.</em><br></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>When students first start learning how to program, they have to remember a vast amount of new information, such as different variables, concepts, and program designs. Utilising this knowledge is often challenging because they’re already busy juggling all the content they’ve previously learnt and the challenges of the programming task at hand. When error messages inevitably appear that are confusing or misunderstood, it can become extremely difficult to debug effectively.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="156" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-8-500x156.png" alt="" class="wp-image-88653" style="width:630px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-8-500x156.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-8-300x94.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-8-768x240.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-8-800x250.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-8-450x141.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-8-900x281.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-8.png 1422w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Program error messages are usually not tailored to the age of the programmers and can be hard to understand and overwhelming for novices.</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Given this information overload, students often don’t develop efficient strategies for debugging. When Laurie analysed the debugging efforts of 12- to 14-year-old secondary school students, he noticed some interesting differences between students who were more and less successful at debugging. While successful students generally seemed to make less frequent and more intentional changes, less successful students tinkered frequently with their broken programs, making one- or two-character edits before running the program again. In addition, the less successful students often ran the program soon after beginning the debugging exercise without allowing enough time to actually read the code and understand what it was meant to do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The issue with these behaviours was that they often resulted in students <strong>adding errors</strong> when changing the program, which then compounded and made debugging increasingly difficult with each run. 74% of students also resorted to spamming, pressing ‘run’ again and again without changing anything. This strategy resonated with many of our seminar attendees, who reported doing the same thing after becoming frustrated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Educators need to be aware of the negative consequences of students’ exasperating and often overwhelming experiences with debugging, especially if students are less confident in their programming skills to begin with. Even though spending 15 minutes on an exercise shows a remarkable level of tenaciousness and resilience, students’ attitudes to programming — and computing as a whole — can quickly go downhill if their strategies for identifying errors prove ineffective. Debugging becomes a vicious circle: if a student has negative experiences, they are less confident when having to bug-fix again in the future, which can lead to another set of unsuccessful attempts, which can further damage their confidence, and so on. Avoiding this downward spiral is essential.&nbsp;</p>



<h1 class="wp-block-heading">Approaches to help students engage with debugging</h1>



<p>Laurie stresses the importance of understanding the cognitive challenges of debugging and using the right tools and techniques to empower students and support them in developing effective strategies.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="282" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-9-500x282.png" alt="" class="wp-image-88654" style="width:594px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-9-500x282.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-9-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-9-768x434.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-9-800x452.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-9-450x254.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-9-900x508.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-9.png 1071w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>To make debugging a less cognitively demanding activity, Laurie recommends using a range of tools and strategies in the classroom.</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Some ideas of how to improve debugging skills that were mentioned by Laurie and our attendees included:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Using frame-based editing tools for novice programmers</strong> because such tools encourage students to focus on logical errors rather than accidental syntax errors, which can distract them from understanding the issues with the program. Teaching debugging should also go hand in hand with understanding programming syntax and using simple language. As one of our attendees put it, “You wouldn’t give novice readers a huge essay and ask them to find errors.”</li>



<li><strong>Making error messages more understandable</strong>, for example, by <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/error-message-explanations-large-language-models-teachers-views/">explaining them to students using Large Language Models</a>.</li>



<li><strong>Teaching systematic debugging processes</strong>. There are several different approaches to doing this. One of our participants suggested using the scientific method (forming a hypothesis about what is going wrong, devising an experiment that will provide information to see whether the hypothesis is right, and iterating this process) to methodically understand the program and its bugs. </li>
</ul>



<p>Most importantly, debugging should not be a daunting or stressful experience. Everyone in the seminar agreed that creating a positive error culture is essential.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="218" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-10-500x218.png" alt="" class="wp-image-88655" style="width:588px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-10-500x218.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-10-300x131.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-10-768x334.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-10-1536x668.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-10-800x348.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-10-450x196.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-10-900x392.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image-10.png 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Teachers in Laurie’s study have stressed the importance of positive debugging experiences.</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Some ideas you could explore in your classroom include:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Normalising errors</strong>: Stress how normal and important program errors are. Everyone encounters them — a professional software developer in our audience said that they spend about half of their time debugging. </li>



<li><strong>Rewarding perseverance</strong>: Celebrate the effort, not just the outcome.</li>



<li><strong>Modelling how to fix errors</strong>: Let your students write buggy programs and attempt to debug them in front of the class.</li>
</ul>



<p>In a welcoming classroom where students are given support and encouragement, debugging can be a rewarding experience. What may at first appear to be a failure — even a spectacular one — can be embraced as a valuable opportunity for learning. As a teacher in Laurie’s study said, “If something should have gone right and went badly wrong but somebody found something interesting on the way… you celebrate it. Take the fear out of it.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Watch the recording of Laurie&#8217;s presentation:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Teaching debugging in secondary school – L. Gale | Computing education research" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MKD5GuteMC0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<div style="height:38px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h1 class="wp-block-heading">Join our next seminar</h1>



<p>In our current seminar series, we are exploring how to teach programming with and without AI.</p>



<p>Join us at our next seminar on Tuesday, 12 November at 17:00–18:30 GMT to hear Nicholas Gardella (University of Virginia) discuss the effects of using tools like GitHub Copilot on the motivation, workload, emotion, and self-efficacy of novice programmers. To sign up and take part in the seminar, click the button below — we’ll then send you information about joining. We hope to see you there.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-2 wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://form.raspberrypi.org/f/research-seminar-sign-up" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">I want to join the next seminar</a></div>
</div>



<p>The <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/computing-education-research-online-seminars/">schedule of our upcoming seminars</a> is online. You can catch up on past seminars on our <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research/seminars/previous">previous seminars and recordings page</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/debugging-positive-experience-secondary-school-students/">How to make debugging a positive experience for secondary school students</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/debugging-positive-experience-secondary-school-students/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ada Computer Science: A year in review</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ada-computer-science-a-year-in-review/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ada-computer-science-a-year-in-review/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dan Fisher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 08:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ada Computer Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[students]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teachers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=88558</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>With the new academic year fully under way in many parts of the world, it&#8217;s the perfect time to reflect on the growth and innovations we&#8217;ve achieved with the Ada Computer Science platform. Your feedback has helped us make improvements to better support teachers and students — here&#8217;s a look back at some of the&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ada-computer-science-a-year-in-review/">Ada Computer Science: A year in review</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>With the new academic year fully under way in many parts of the world, it&#8217;s the perfect time to reflect on the growth and innovations we&#8217;ve achieved with <a href="https://adacomputerscience.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the Ada Computer Science platform</a>. Your feedback has helped us make improvements to better support teachers and students — here&#8217;s a look back at some of the key developments for Ada from the past 12 months.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ada-event-23-500x333.jpg" alt="Teachers in discussion at a table." class="wp-image-87837" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ada-event-23-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ada-event-23-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ada-event-23-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ada-event-23-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ada-event-23-2048x1366.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ada-event-23-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ada-event-23-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ada-event-23-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Teachers in discussion at a Raspberry Pi Foundation teacher training event.</figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Supporting students through personalised learning, new resources, and new questions</strong></h2>



<p>We made significant improvements throughout the year to support students with exam preparation and personalised learning. We introduced over 145 new self-marking questions and updated 50 existing ones, bringing the total to <a href="https://adacomputerscience.org/questions?examBoard=ada&amp;examBoards=ada&amp;stage=all" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">more than 1000</a>. A new type of question was also launched to help students practise writing longer responses: they label parts of a sample answer and apply a mark scheme, simulating a peer review process. You can read more about this work in the AI section below.</p>



<p>We updated the question finder tool with an intuitive new design. Instead of seeing ten questions at random, students can now see all the questions we have on any given topic, and can use the filters to refine their searches by qualification and difficulty level. This enables students to better personalise their revision and progress tracking</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;Ada Computer Science has been very effective for my revision. I like how it provides hints and pointers if you answer a question incorrectly.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>– Ada Computer Science student</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The <a href="https://adacomputerscience.org/topics/sound_representation?examBoard=ada&amp;stage=all" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">‘Representation of sound’</a> topic received a major update, with clearer explanations, new diagrams, and improved feedback to support students as they tackle common misconceptions in sound physics. We also refreshed the <a href="https://adacomputerscience.org/topics/number_representation?examBoard=ada&amp;stage=all" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">‘Representation of numbers’</a> topic, adding new content and interactive quizzes to support teachers in assessing students&#8217; understanding more effectively.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We introduced a new database scenario titled <a href="https://adacomputerscience.org/topics/projdb_repair_and_reform?examBoard=ada&amp;stage=all" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">‘Repair &amp; Reform’</a>, offering an entity relationship diagram, a data dictionary, and a new SQL editor and question set to help students prepare for project-based assessments. We&#8217;ve further expanded this scenario into a <a href="https://adacomputerscience.org/topics/projdb_repair_and_reform?examBoard=ada&amp;stage=all" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">full project</a> covering all stages of development, including requirements analysis and evaluation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>April was dedicated to gearing up for the exam season, with the introduction of revision flashcards and ready-made quizzes on key topics like bitmapped graphics and sorting algorithms. We also launched <a href="https://adacomputerscience.org/pages/student_challenges?examBoard=all&amp;stage=all" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a student revision challenge</a>, which ran from April to June and attracted over 600 participants.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;Ada Computer Science is an excellent resource to help support teachers and students. The explanations are clear and relevant, and the questions help students test their knowledge and understanding in a structured way, providing links to help them reconcile any discrepancies or misunderstandings.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>– Patrick Kennedy, Computer Science teacher</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Supporting teachers</strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</h2>



<p>We expanded our efforts to support new computer science teachers with the launch of <a href="https://adacomputerscience.org/pages/teacher_mentoring_2024?examBoard=ada&amp;stage=all" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a teacher mentoring programme</a> that offers free online drop-in sessions. We also hosted a teacher training event at the Raspberry Pi Foundation office in Cambridge (as seen in the picture below), where educators saw previews of upcoming content on AI and machine learning and contributed their own questions to the platform.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/ada-event-13-500x333.jpg" alt="Group photo featuring computer science teachers and colleagues from the Raspberry PI Foundation." class="wp-image-88014" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/ada-event-13-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/ada-event-13-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/ada-event-13-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/ada-event-13-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/ada-event-13-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/08/ada-event-13.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>AI content and AI features</strong></h2>



<p>We continued our focus on AI and machine learning, <a href="https://adacomputerscience.org/topics?examBoard=ada&amp;stage=all" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">releasing new learning resources</a> that explore the ethical and social implications of AI alongside the practical applications of AI and machine learning models.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To expand the Ada platform&#8217;s features, we also made considerable progress in integrating a large language model (LLM) to mark free-text responses. Our research showed that, as of June, LLM marks matched real teachers&#8217; marks 82% of the time. In July, we received ethics approval from the University of Cambridge to add LLM-marked questions to the Ada platform.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Computer science education in Scotland</strong></h2>



<p>We made significant strides towards supporting Scottish teachers and students with <a href="https://adacomputerscience.org/exam_specifications_scotland?examBoard=ada&amp;stage=all#scotland_national_5/sqa" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">resources tailored to the SQA Computing Science curriculum</a>. From September to November last year, we piloted a new set of materials specifically designed for Scottish teachers, receiving valuable feedback that we&#8217;ve used in 2024 to develop new content. More than half of the theory content for the National 5 and Higher specifications is now available on the platform.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="332" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image2-500x332.png" alt="Teacher, in the middle of a computing lesson." class="wp-image-88585" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image2-500x332.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image2-300x199.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image2-768x509.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image2-800x531.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image2-450x298.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image2-900x597.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image2.png 1191w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>Our ‘Reform &amp; Repair’ database scenario and project align with both SQA Higher and A level standards, providing a comprehensive resource for students preparing for project-based assessments.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Looking ahead: New resources for September and beyond</strong></h2>



<p>We have big plans for Ada for the next 12 months. Our focus will remain on continuously improving our resources and supporting the needs of both educators and students.&nbsp;</p>



<p>After the positive response to our ‘Repair &amp; Reform’ database project, our content experts are planning additional practical projects to support students and teachers. The next one will be a web project that covers HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP, supporting students taking SQA qualifications in Scotland or undertaking the non-examined assessment (NEA) at A level.</p>



<p>We’ll be working on a number of teacher-focused improvements to the platform, which you’ll also see on Ada&#8217;s sibling site, <a href="https://isaacphysics.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Isaac Physics</a>. These will include an overhaul of the markbook to make it more user-friendly, and updates to the ‘Assignments’ tool so assignments better meet the needs of teachers in schools.</p>



<p>We’ll be welcoming the next cohort of computer science students to the STEM SMART programme in January 2025 where, in partnership with the University of Cambridge, we’ll offer free, complementary teaching and support to UK students at state schools. <a href="https://www.undergraduate.study.cam.ac.uk/stem-smart">Applications are now open</a>.</p>



<p>Thank you to every teacher and student who has given their time in the last year to share feedback about <a href="https://adacomputerscience.org/">Ada Computer Science</a> — your insights are invaluable as we work to make high-quality computer science materials easily accessible. Here&#8217;s to another fantastic year of learning and growth!</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ada-computer-science-a-year-in-review/">Ada Computer Science: A year in review</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ada-computer-science-a-year-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How fun-filled Code Clubs drive learning: New evidence</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-fun-filled-code-clubs-drive-learning-new-evidence/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-fun-filled-code-clubs-drive-learning-new-evidence/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben Durbin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 12:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Code Club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Impact of our work]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=88608</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>When you walk into a vibrant Code Club, it is easy to see that the young creators are having fun with digital making. But are they actually learning anything? Our recent evaluation has shown that not only are they developing their coding skills, but there are many other benefits. Code Club is a network of&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-fun-filled-code-clubs-drive-learning-new-evidence/">How fun-filled Code Clubs drive learning: New evidence</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>When you walk into a vibrant Code Club, it is easy to see that the young creators are having fun with digital making. But are they actually learning anything? Our recent evaluation has shown that not only are they developing their coding skills, but there are many other benefits.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="283" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/07/CC_TESCO_005-500x283.jpg" alt="Young person sitting at a laptop with an adult mentor helping them with their code. " class="wp-image-72924" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/07/CC_TESCO_005-500x283.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/07/CC_TESCO_005-300x170.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/07/CC_TESCO_005-768x434.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/07/CC_TESCO_005-1536x869.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/07/CC_TESCO_005-2048x1158.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/07/CC_TESCO_005-800x453.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/07/CC_TESCO_005-450x255.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/07/CC_TESCO_005-900x509.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p><a href="https://codeclub.org">Code Club</a> is a network of free coding clubs where young people learn how to create with technology. The Raspberry Pi Foundation supports Code Clubs through training and guidance for mentors, and by providing learning resources that lead to meaningful and lasting learning outcomes for the young people attending the clubs.</p>



<p>Founded in the UK in 2012, Code Club has grown into a global movement and has already inspired more than 2 million young people to learn how to build their own apps, games, animations, websites, and so much more. We are incredibly proud of the impact Code Club has already achieved and we want many more young people to benefit. Our ambitious goal for the next decade is to reach 10 million more young people through Code Club.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>New impact insights about Code Club</strong></h2>



<p>We&#8217;re ambitious about Code Club because we know it works. Over the last year, the <a href="https://www.durham.ac.uk/research/institutes-and-centres/evidence-centre-education/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Durham University Evidence Centre for Education (DECE)</a> conducted an independent evaluation of the programme that confirmed <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2017/03/Randomised-Controlled-Trial-and-Process-Evaluation-of-Code-Clubs.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">earlier evidence</a>: attending Code Club leads to positive outcomes for young people.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/CodeClub_ParkStreet-04-500x333.jpg" alt="Two young people smiling whilst working on their laptop with an adult mentor by their side." class="wp-image-88616" style="width:500px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/CodeClub_ParkStreet-04-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/CodeClub_ParkStreet-04-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/CodeClub_ParkStreet-04-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/CodeClub_ParkStreet-04-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/CodeClub_ParkStreet-04-2048x1366.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/CodeClub_ParkStreet-04-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/CodeClub_ParkStreet-04-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/CodeClub_ParkStreet-04-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>The DECE evaluation showed that young people who attend Code Club build their coding skills. They also become more confident in learning coding, grow their interest in it, and develop a sense of belonging. Researchers observed how each young person has their individual projects to work on, which promote a sense of ownership and personalised learning, but that there are also opportunities for collaboration and celebrating their achievements with other creators in the club.</p>



<p>Young people also develop positive attitudes to coding and a range of life skills such as problem solving and communication. These skills and mindsets prepare young people to confidently engage with emerging technologies and with learning in a broader context.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>“Coding is really fun when I know what to do, but sometimes it is hard. But I always keep trying.”</em> </p>



<p>– Code Club creator.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Another finding was that Code Clubs are a place where young people who experience difficulties in formal classroom settings can thrive. This suggests Code Clubs can help educators engage a more diverse group of young people in creating with technology than formal education alone could.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>“We see pupils in completely different roles when they are doing these Code Club activities. They enjoy more, and you can see they have skills to do things that we otherwise don’t notice.”</em> </p>



<p>– Code Club mentor.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>None of the benefits for young people would be possible without the volunteers who give their time and make Code Clubs the positive learning environments they are. Their support is crucial to young people’s engagement and skill development. The evaluation showed that mentors find the experience of volunteering rewarding, and pointed us towards areas where we can offer further support to help them run engaging, impactful Code Clubs.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>“…volunteering with Code Club has helped me feel I’m a useful member of society in my old age, so the benefits have been good for me too.”</em></p>



<p> – Code Club mentor.</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How we&#8217;re building on our support for clubs</strong></h2>



<p>With AI already transforming so many parts of our lives, learning how to create with technology has never been more important. Generative AI is changing how humans give instructions to computers, and at Code Club, young people can experiment with new technologies such as AI in a safe environment. New projects that support young people to learn about AI technologies will be added to the <a href="https://codeclub.org/en/learn-to-code">Code Club Projects site</a> later this month, alongside support for club leaders and mentors on this topic.</p>



<p>The evaluation methods used by the DECE will help us hone our ongoing impact measurement work for Code Clubs running in communities all over the world. As we continue to support Code Clubs, we are taking into account that the independent evaluation ran in school-based Code Clubs in the UK only. In our work to grow the Code Club network across the globe, we are adapting our support and resources for local contexts in collaboration with partners who share their expertise.</p>



<p>This will ensure that Code Clubs can provide a fun, welcoming space for all young people. And while they’re having fun, they will also gain relevant learning experiences that empower them to engage confidently with a world that is being transformed by digital technologies.</p>



<p>If you&#8217;re interested in the DECE evaluation&#8217;s results, we&#8217;ve put together a <a href="https://static.raspberrypi.org/files/about/Code_Club_Summary_Report_Durham-Oct_2024.pdf">summary</a> for you to download.</p>



<p>To get involved in <a href="https://codeclub.org/en/">Code Club</a>, visit <a href="https://codeclub.org">codeclub.org</a>.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-fun-filled-code-clubs-drive-learning-new-evidence/">How fun-filled Code Clubs drive learning: New evidence</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-fun-filled-code-clubs-drive-learning-new-evidence/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Introduce the Code Editor into your school</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-editor-for-education/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-editor-for-education/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joanne Vincent]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 11:40:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Code Editor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=88582</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Since we first launched the Code Editor, a free online tool designed to support young people&#160;as they learn text-based programming, we’ve been excited to hear how educators have been trying it out in their classrooms.&#160; “I used the Code Editor with my computer science students yesterday and it worked a dream! Students were able to&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-editor-for-education/">Introduce the Code Editor into your school</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Since we <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-editor-beta-testing/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">first launched the Code Editor</a>, a free online tool designed to support young people&nbsp;as they learn text-based programming, we’ve been excited to hear how educators have been trying it out in their classrooms.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I used the Code Editor with my computer science students yesterday and it worked a dream! Students were able to write and run code without any issues.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>&#8211; Head of Computer Science</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The Code Editor is designed for learning, rather than for professional use, and is informed by our understanding of pedagogy and computing education. It can be accessed from a web browser without installing any additional software.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Earlier this year, we announced that we’d be <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-editor-classroom-management/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">introducing classroom management features</a> and we’re now pleased to confirm that we’ve launched the beta version of <a href="https://editor.raspberrypi.org/en/education" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Code Editor for Education</a> with school accounts.<strong> </strong>You can be the first to try out the new features, together with the many schools who have chosen to pre-register their school accounts.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Simple and easy classroom management</strong></h2>



<p>We’ve kept the educator interface clean, simple, and easy to use. School owners can invite other teachers to join, add students, organise students into classes, and help students reset their passwords quickly. Educators can create coding projects to share with students and view their work.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="500" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image1-500x500.jpg" alt="A digital image showcasing the classroom management features of the Code Editor for Education." class="wp-image-88594" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image1-500x500.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image1-250x250.jpg 250w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image1-150x150.jpg 150w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image1-768x768.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image1-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image1-800x800.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image1-100x100.jpg 100w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image1-300x300.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image1-450x450.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image1-900x900.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/image1.jpg 1999w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>All features, totally free</strong></h2>



<p>We’ve added these classroom management features because one of the key problems we’ve seen educators face over the past months has been the lack of an affordable tool to teach text-based coding in the classroom. We will always provide the Code Editor and all of its features to educators and students for free.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Safe and private by design</strong></h2>



<p>We take safeguarding seriously, providing visibility of student work at all times, as well as features such as the ability to report a concern. In line with best practices protecting children online, we minimise data capture so that we have just enough to keep students safe.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Future developments&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p>As the platform is currently in beta, we’d love to hear what you think of the new classroom management features — please <a href="https://form.raspberrypi.org/f/code-editor-for-education-feedback">send us your feedback</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’ll be actively looking to develop new features over the coming months. Such features are set to include an extended set of Python libraries,<strong> </strong>custom instructions that sit alongside starter code projects and teacher-to-student feedback capabilities. All new developments will be informed by ongoing educator feedback.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Find out more and </strong><a href="https://editor.raspberrypi.org/en/education"><strong>register for a free school account</strong>.</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-editor-for-education/">Introduce the Code Editor into your school</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-editor-for-education/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Celebrating Coolest Projects 2024, plus dates for 2025</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/coolest-projects-2024-impact-2025-dates/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/coolest-projects-2024-impact-2025-dates/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vicky Fisher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 10:02:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Coolest Projects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coolest projects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding for kids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Impact of our work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coolest projects 2024]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=88543</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Coolest Projects celebrates young digital creators and the amazing things they make with technology. Today, we&#8217;re sharing the impact that taking part in Coolest Projects showcases has on young people&#8217;s motivation and confidence, as well as announcing dates for Coolest Projects 2025. Coolest Projects in 2024 This year, 7197 young people across 4678 projects took&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/coolest-projects-2024-impact-2025-dates/">Celebrating Coolest Projects 2024, plus dates for 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Coolest Projects celebrates young digital creators and the amazing things they make with technology. Today, we&#8217;re sharing the impact that taking part in Coolest Projects showcases has on young people&#8217;s motivation and confidence, as well as announcing dates for Coolest Projects 2025.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="263" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Facebook-14-500x263.png" alt="Coolest Projects will be back in 2025." class="wp-image-88544" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Facebook-14-500x263.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Facebook-14-300x158.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Facebook-14-768x403.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Facebook-14-1536x807.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Facebook-14-800x420.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Facebook-14-450x236.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Facebook-14-900x473.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Facebook-14.png 1750w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Coolest Projects in 2024</h2>



<p>This year, 7197 young people across 4678 projects took part in our global Coolest Projects online showcase, with participants from 43 countries. All of these projects were shared in our <a href="https://online.coolestprojects.org/events/cp-2024/gallery" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">online showcase gallery</a>, and we hosted a <a href="https://youtu.be/1ln4S0jYaok" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">live-streamed event</a> celebrating <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/coolest-projects-2024-young-tech-creators-showcase-their-projects-online/">the judges’ favourites</a> watched by over 1000 people.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/53720701373_6646826b7b_k-500x333.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-88548" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/53720701373_6646826b7b_k-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/53720701373_6646826b7b_k-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/53720701373_6646826b7b_k-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/53720701373_6646826b7b_k-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/53720701373_6646826b7b_k-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/53720701373_6646826b7b_k-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/53720701373_6646826b7b_k-900x600.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/53720701373_6646826b7b_k.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>At the 2024 in-person Coolest Projects events in Ireland and the UK, 171 young people shared projects. At these events, the young creators presented their projects to other attendees and our team of judges. They also took part in other activities, including a digital escape room.</p>



<p>We wanted to understand how Coolest Projects impacts young people, and so we collected the following data:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>For the online showcase, mentors and tech creators filled in a survey when they completed their project registration, and we ran focus groups with mentors, who are adults that support the tech creators</li>



<li>At the UK and Ireland in-person events, creators completed a survey, other event attendees completed feedback cards, and we also interviewed creators.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Online showcase: Impact on skills and confidence</h2>



<p>In the survey, mentors and young people told us that taking part in the Coolest Projects online showcase had a positive impact:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>91% of young people and 87% of mentors agreed or strongly agreed that taking part in Coolest Projects online inspired them or their team to continue to participate in computing and technology</li>



<li>89% of young people and 86% of mentors agreed or strongly agreed that taking part in Coolest Projects online increased their or their team&#8217;s confidence in coding and digital making</li>
</ul>



<p>Mentors told us that the community built by the online showcase gallery played an important role in making young people want to participate,&nbsp; and improving their confidence. One mentor said that “[being part of the online showcase] motivates them actually to do something innovative and&#8230; [the] global community motivates them to think out of the box.”</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/06/Web-500x281.png" alt="The favourites in the web category for Coolest Projects 2024." class="wp-image-87659" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/06/Web-500x281.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/06/Web-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/06/Web-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/06/Web-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/06/Web-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/06/Web-900x506.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/06/Web.png 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>They also reported that the online community inspired young people to solve real-world problems. One mentor said, “the wonderful thing is the kids create so many things which are solutions to world problems.” Others told us that young people feel a great deal of pride that their solutions are available for others to see online and that they get ideas from other projects on how to solve problems. One mentor from India told us about a young person who created a boat to clean rivers and then was inspired to learn to program micro:bit devices, having seen similar projects in the gallery.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Focus on ‘growth, not competition’</h2>



<p>The phrase ‘growth, not competition’ came from the mentors in the focus group, and we love this description.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“[With] Coolest Projects… the only agenda is to grow. Grow with the coding, nurture your skills, creativity.” – Focus group attendee.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In the focus group, mentors told us they really valued the way the Coolest Projects online showcase allows all young people to participate, including those who were less experienced tech creators. One mentor told us that because everyone’s project is displayed in the gallery the <em>“</em>beauty is that everybody is encouraged individually… regarding the experience. … They can start with very small things. And they have [the] opportunity to upload it on the platform.”</p>



<p>One mentor who supports young people in remote locations in India spoke about the way Coolest Projects offers a level playing field where his students can be included and participate to the same extent as less remote places: “students never feel left behind.”</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="551" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/12/CPUK19_PHOTO4010-500x551.jpg" alt="Three young people working together on a tech project." class="wp-image-82384" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/12/CPUK19_PHOTO4010-500x551.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/12/CPUK19_PHOTO4010-227x250.jpg 227w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/12/CPUK19_PHOTO4010-768x846.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/12/CPUK19_PHOTO4010-800x881.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/12/CPUK19_PHOTO4010-450x496.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/12/CPUK19_PHOTO4010-900x991.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/12/CPUK19_PHOTO4010.jpg 1025w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>The in-person events also reflected the diversity of young people’s experience of digital making. Of those creators who answered surveys, 35% said it was their first time making this kind of project, while 37% said they had made similar projects before. This mix of experience was also reflected in the interviews, with some young people creating something for the first time and having only started learning coding recently, while others had been developing their projects for a long time. Many creators told us they felt inspired by the opportunity to show their projects to others, regardless of their experience level.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">In-person events: Building a community of digital creators</h2>



<p>Attendees at both Coolest Projects UK and Ireland commented on the sense of community and the excitement that was generated by being around other young people. One young person spoke about how much they enjoyed being “surrounded by people who like coding too”. They really valued seeing other creators’ projects and speaking with their peers.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/09/53103950367_666a2ce548_k-500x333.jpg" alt="The exhibition hall at Coolest Projects Ireland 2023." class="wp-image-84885" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/09/53103950367_666a2ce548_k-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/09/53103950367_666a2ce548_k-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/09/53103950367_666a2ce548_k-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/09/53103950367_666a2ce548_k-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/09/53103950367_666a2ce548_k-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/09/53103950367_666a2ce548_k-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/09/53103950367_666a2ce548_k-900x600.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/09/53103950367_666a2ce548_k.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>The young people we spoke to reflected on the positive impact of this sense of community and belonging. They told us that seeing others’ projects inspired them to develop their ideas and learn new skills. One young person described how the in-person event allowed them to <em>“</em>get inspired and socialise.” A second said, “that’s why I’m here — to get inspired.”</p>



<p>Another clear theme was how much young people valued the opportunity to show their projects to others. This gave them confidence in their own ability to build things. One creator at Coolest Projects UK spoke about the sense of achievement they felt after building something themselves and then being able to present it to others.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="355" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Coolest-Projects_2024_10-500x355.jpg" alt="Two young people share a project on their laptop with a judge at Coolest Projects." class="wp-image-88545" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Coolest-Projects_2024_10-500x355.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Coolest-Projects_2024_10-300x213.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Coolest-Projects_2024_10-768x545.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Coolest-Projects_2024_10-1536x1090.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Coolest-Projects_2024_10-800x567.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Coolest-Projects_2024_10-450x319.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Coolest-Projects_2024_10-900x638.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Coolest-Projects_2024_10.jpg 1906w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>Young people at both events spoke about their plans for what they wanted to do next, talking about trying new technology such as building games, learning Python, and creating mobile apps. At both events, creators described how they wanted to continue to develop and build on their existing ideas with the possibility of showcasing them again.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What we want to learn next</h2>



<p>We are continuing to look for ways to improve the Coolest Projects experience for young people and their mentors. As part of this, we are conducting user experience research to understand how we can improve the registration process for the online Coolest Projects showcase.</p>



<p>We were delighted to hear from mentors in this year’s focus group how much they valued the online showcase gallery, and we want to understand the impact of this resource better as part of Coolest Projects 2025. If you want to find out more about Coolest Projects, we highly recommend taking a look at <a href="https://online.coolestprojects.org/events/cp-2024/gallery">the amazing projects made by young people around the world</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Dates for Coolest Projects 2025</h2>



<p>We’re so pleased that so many young people around the world loved taking part in Coolest Projects this year. And we’re very excited that Coolest Projects will be back and bigger than ever before in 2025!&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Coolest Projects online showcase is open to any young person up to age 18, based anywhere in the world. <strong>Registration opens 14 January</strong>, and we’ll host a celebratory livestream on <strong>25 June</strong>.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="344" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/coolest-projects-500x344.jpg" alt="A Coolest Projects sign with two people doing handstands in front of it." class="wp-image-85383" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/coolest-projects-500x344.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/coolest-projects-300x206.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/coolest-projects-768x528.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/coolest-projects-1536x1056.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/coolest-projects-2048x1409.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/coolest-projects-800x550.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/coolest-projects-450x310.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/coolest-projects-900x619.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/coolest-projects-216x150.jpg 216w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>Coolest Projects in-person events will also be popping up around the world. In-person events are open to everyone up to age 18 in the host country. Family and friends are very welcome to come along too.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Save the date for:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Coolest Projects Ireland, 1 March 2025</li>



<li>Coolest Projects USA, 5 April 2025</li>



<li>Coolest Projects Belgium, 26 April 2025</li>



<li>Coolest Projects UK, 17 May 2025</li>



<li>Coolest Projects Ghana, date TBC</li>



<li>Coolest Projects India, date TBC</li>



<li>Coolest Projects Malaysia, date TBC</li>



<li>Coolest Projects South Africa, date TBC</li>
</ul>



<p>Keep an eye on the <a href="https://online.coolestprojects.org/take-part">Coolest Projects website</a> for more event dates and details coming soon.</p>



<p>It’s never too early to start making and saving digital projects to showcase next year. We can’t wait to see what the world&#8217;s young tech creators will make!</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/coolest-projects-2024-impact-2025-dates/">Celebrating Coolest Projects 2024, plus dates for 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/coolest-projects-2024-impact-2025-dates/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Computing Curriculum: Three global perspectives</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/the-computing-curriculum-global-perspectives/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/the-computing-curriculum-global-perspectives/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dan Fisher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 09:22:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Computing Curriculum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Impact of our work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[curriculum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=88473</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Across continents and cultural contexts, our free Computing Curriculum serves as a common thread that connects educators. Read the stories of 3 educators who share their thoughts on the curriculum’s application, adaptability, and the impact it’s had on their educational settings.  I’m Freda, and I co-founded a non-profit organisation called Waloyo in South Africa. Coming&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/the-computing-curriculum-global-perspectives/">The Computing Curriculum: Three global perspectives</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Across continents and cultural contexts, our free <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/curriculum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Computing Curriculum</a> serves as a common thread that connects educators. Read the stories of 3 educators who share their thoughts on the curriculum’s application, adaptability, and the impact it’s had on their educational settings. </p>



<p><strong>I’m Freda, and I co-founded a non-profit organisation called Waloyo in South Africa.</strong></p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" class="wp-image-88479" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Freda_TCC-500x333.png" alt="Photo of Freda, co-founder of the non-profit organisation called Waloyo." srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Freda_TCC-500x333.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Freda_TCC-300x200.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Freda_TCC-768x512.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Freda_TCC-800x533.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Freda_TCC-450x300.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Freda_TCC.png 900w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>Coming from a background of technology consulting, I know the value of computing education. I have a real drive to teach young kids coding so they can get ahead and find jobs in our digital economy.</p>



<p>Our role at Waloyo is to work with non-profit organisations that work with young people and want to expand their services to include computing skills training. Waloyo trains non-profit facilitators, who in turn teach computing skills to youth between the ages of 6 and 18. A unique challenge is that the majority of facilitators we train don&#8217;t have any previous computing experience. The resources we use need to be clear and easy to follow.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>What I really love about The Computing Curriculum resources is the facilitator guides.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Our initial plan was to run the training programmes after school and outside the school curriculum, but we were getting requests from schools to support them too. South Africa doesn’t have a national computing curriculum, so there aren’t many subject specialist teachers. So we looked for curriculum resources from other countries to support our work and that’s how we found The Computing Curriculum.<strong> </strong></p>



<p>In rural Africa where we work, students have low levels of exposure to computers and computing. So whether they are 6 or 18 years old, we usually start with Scratch. The younger kids then continue with Scratch and the older kids move quickly on to Python as they build confidence.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="321" class="wp-image-48960" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2019/01/scratch3-500x321.png" alt="Screenshot of Scratch 3 interface" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2019/01/scratch3-500x321.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2019/01/scratch3-300x193.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2019/01/scratch3-768x493.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2019/01/scratch3.png 1213w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>What I really love about The Computing Curriculum resources is the facilitator guides. They fit in well with our process of training NGO facilitators to work directly with the kids. I love the comprehensiveness and flexibility of what your curriculum provides to enable this method of delivery.</p>



<p>So far we&#8217;ve launched 3 programmes in communities in South Africa, impacting around 150 young people, and it’s worked beautifully. It&#8217;s phenomenal to see how excited the kids get when the computer does what they want it to do!</p>



<p><strong>I’m Al</strong>, <strong>and I’ve been a secondary science teacher since 1991.</strong></p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="281" class="wp-image-88480" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Al_TCC-500x281.jpg" alt="Photo of Al out hiking in rocky terrain." srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Al_TCC-500x281.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Al_TCC-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Al_TCC-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Al_TCC-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Al_TCC-800x450.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Al_TCC-450x253.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Al_TCC-900x506.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Al_TCC.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>For the past 13 years, I’ve taught in international schools. Two years ago, I decided to retrain in teaching computing. My wife and I are currently teaching in Kazakhstan. I now teach at primary level but still handle some secondary classes. For primary, there&#8217;s significant time pressure, especially with extra lessons for the local language, making it challenging to fit computing into the schedule.</p>



<p>The private schools where I work are starting to implement the UK computer science curriculum. At one of the schools, they have a robotics course which has given rise to a misconception that everything in computing is about robotics! My role, therefore, involves expanding the concept of robotics to include a broader range of computing activities and finding efficient ways to integrate these new materials into the curriculum with minimal effort from the staff. I focus on selecting appropriate units to fit into what the schools are already doing rather than implementing a comprehensive new program.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery aligncenter has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-1 is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-is-layout-flex">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" data-id="82467" class="wp-image-82467" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/12/SCRATCH_CONF240819-916-1024x683-1-500x333.jpeg" alt="Workshop attendees at a table." srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/12/SCRATCH_CONF240819-916-1024x683-1-500x333.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/12/SCRATCH_CONF240819-916-1024x683-1-300x200.jpeg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/12/SCRATCH_CONF240819-916-1024x683-1-768x512.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/12/SCRATCH_CONF240819-916-1024x683-1-800x534.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/12/SCRATCH_CONF240819-916-1024x683-1-450x300.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/12/SCRATCH_CONF240819-916-1024x683-1-900x600.jpeg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/12/SCRATCH_CONF240819-916-1024x683-1.jpeg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" data-id="88519" class="wp-image-88519" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Clubs-conference_2_HD-72-500x333.jpg" alt="Photo of educators collaborating on various projects at a desk, with laptops open displaying the Scratch Editor." srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Clubs-conference_2_HD-72-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Clubs-conference_2_HD-72-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Clubs-conference_2_HD-72-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Clubs-conference_2_HD-72-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Clubs-conference_2_HD-72-2048x1366.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Clubs-conference_2_HD-72-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Clubs-conference_2_HD-72-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/Clubs-conference_2_HD-72-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure>
</figure>



<div style="height:20px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<p>The Raspberry Pi Foundation’s curriculum resources are valuable because they provide comprehensive lists of programs and ideas that I can adapt for my colleagues. I adapt resources to make them more accessible for primary teachers, simplifying and customising them for ease of use.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>The Raspberry Pi Foundation’s curriculum resources are valuable because they provide comprehensive lists of programs and ideas that I can adapt for my colleagues.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Once students understand that computing is a tool for developing skills rather than just passive consumption, they take ownership of their learning which boosts their confidence. Culturally relevant materials are particularly effective, especially in diverse international classrooms. Adapting resources to be culturally relevant and incorporating students&#8217; examples enhances their usefulness and impact. The resources are excellent, but by tailoring them, they can be even more effective, particularly in an international context with diverse nationalities and learning concepts.</p>



<p><strong>Head of ICT at an international school in Egypt</strong></p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" class="wp-image-81196" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/09/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-22-500x333.jpg" alt="In a computing classroom, a boy looks down at a keyboard." srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/09/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-22-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/09/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-22-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/09/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-22-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/09/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-22-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/09/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-22-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/09/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-22-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/09/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-22-900x600.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/09/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-22.jpg 1728w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>As Head of Department, I am responsible for what all the different age groups learn, from year 1 to year 12. We use the Cambridge International (CIE) curriculum, so I was looking for supplementary resources that build from the basics, have a clear progression map, and complement the resources we already had.</p>



<p>With The Computing Curriculum, it is easy to pick out individual lesson resources to use. I love that it doesn’t need a licence and that the students don’t face any problems when they download it to practise at home. I’m covering curriculums for both computing and digital literacy, so I use resources that are relevant to my curriculum maps.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>With The Computing Curriculum, it is easy to pick out individual lesson resources to use.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In some schools, their idea of an ICT lesson is getting students to play games, use Word documents, make PowerPoint presentations, and that’s it. But this generation of students love coding and making their own games. So instead of playing the game, we teach them how to develop a game and how to add the characters themselves.</p>



<p>From year 1 to year 2, students take part in a wide range of computing activities and develop a lot of new skills. They find these skills amazing. It makes them feel engaged, excited, and that they are doing something valuable.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Using The Computing Curriculum </h2>



<p>These educators’ stories show how easy it is to adapt our Computing Curriculum to your unique context, enhancing students&#8217; technical skills and inspiring creativity, critical thinking, and a passion for problem-solving. We look forward to continuing this journey with these and other educators as they transform computing education for their learners.</p>



<p>If you&#8217;re looking for new computing resources to teach with, why not give <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/curriculum/">The Computing Curriculum</a> a try? You can also read our <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/culturally-responsive-pedagogy-for-computing-education/">culturally relevant pedagogy research</a> that Al mentions in his interview.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/the-computing-curriculum-global-perspectives/">The Computing Curriculum: Three global perspectives</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/the-computing-curriculum-global-perspectives/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
