<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Raspberry Pi Foundation</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/</link>
	<description>Teach, learn and make with Raspberry Pi</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 10:45:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/06/cropped-raspberrry_pi_logo-100x100.png</url>
	<title>Raspberry Pi Foundation</title>
	<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Beyond phone bans: Empowering students to critically navigate and reimagine technology</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/beyond-phone-bans-empowering-students-to-critically-navigate-and-reimagine-technology/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/beyond-phone-bans-empowering-students-to-critically-navigate-and-reimagine-technology/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Laura Kirsop]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 10:45:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hello World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital literacy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=90250</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Amidst heated discussion of smartphones and their impacts on young people&#8217;s lives, it&#8217;s become a frequent recommendation to ban phones in schools. Below I summarise the research evidence on smartphone bans (it&#8217;s mixed) and share tips for computing educators on how to constructively address the topic with their learners and empower them to think critically&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/beyond-phone-bans-empowering-students-to-critically-navigate-and-reimagine-technology/">Beyond phone bans: Empowering students to critically navigate and reimagine technology</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Amidst heated discussion of smartphones and their impacts on young people&#8217;s lives, it&#8217;s become a frequent recommendation to ban phones in schools. Below I summarise the research evidence on smartphone bans (it&#8217;s mixed) and share tips for computing educators on how to constructively address the topic with their learners and empower them to think critically about technology design.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="2560" height="1707" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/Copy-of-pexels-katerina-holmes-5905506-scaled.jpg" alt="Photo of a young person showing their mobile phone to a peer." class="wp-image-90242" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/Copy-of-pexels-katerina-holmes-5905506-scaled.jpg 2560w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/Copy-of-pexels-katerina-holmes-5905506-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/Copy-of-pexels-katerina-holmes-5905506-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/Copy-of-pexels-katerina-holmes-5905506-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/Copy-of-pexels-katerina-holmes-5905506-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/Copy-of-pexels-katerina-holmes-5905506-2048x1365.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/Copy-of-pexels-katerina-holmes-5905506-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/Copy-of-pexels-katerina-holmes-5905506-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/Copy-of-pexels-katerina-holmes-5905506-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A turning tide</h2>



<p>2024 was the year the tide turned against smartphones. Across the world, parents, teachers, and governments highlighted the risks of excessive phone use among young people. In the UK, the ‘Smartphone Free Childhood’ movement emerged, quickly growing to 100,000 members who advocate for keeping smartphones away from children due to concerns about addiction, harmful content, and mental health. Jonathan Haidt’s global bestseller <em>The Anxious Generation</em> has further fuelled the movement, linking smartphone use to adolescent mental health issues and recommending phonefree schools. Meanwhile, countries including England, France, and Finland have urged schools to adopt strict phone bans, hoping to reduce classroom distractions and enhance student safety.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="2500" height="1667" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-max-fischer-5212669.jpg" alt="Photo of a young person in a classroom showing their phone screen to their friends." class="wp-image-90243" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-max-fischer-5212669.jpg 2500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-max-fischer-5212669-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-max-fischer-5212669-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-max-fischer-5212669-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-max-fischer-5212669-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-max-fischer-5212669-2048x1366.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-max-fischer-5212669-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-max-fischer-5212669-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-max-fischer-5212669-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 2500px) 100vw, 2500px" /></figure></div>


<p>Despite widespread support, academic research on phone bans remains limited and inconclusive. Given this situation, computing educators are uniquely positioned to offer an alternative approach.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Evaluating evidence on phone bans&nbsp;</h2>



<p>The rapid spread of school smartphone bans is a straightforward response to complex issues around personal technology use in education. Teachers and parents frequently view phones as inherently disruptive, a perspective supported by studies that show phones can impair students’ focus and engagement in lessons. Concerns about cyberbullying and addiction contribute to this view, with many educators seeing bans as a practical solution to mitigate risks. Surveys in England reveal that nearly half of all secondary schools now enforce all-day bans. This trend was supported by teachers participating in my master’s degree research, who see these policies as necessary to reduce distractions and maintain control in the classroom.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;Calls for outright bans may oversimplify the conversation.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Yet calls for outright bans may oversimplify the conversation, limiting opportunities to examine both the benefits and the risks of smartphone use in schools. <a href="http://helloworld.cc/smartphone-evidence" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Evidence on the impact of phone restrictions is mixed</a>: while some studies suggest restrictions may benefit learning, especially for students who struggle the most, others indicate no significant impact on academic outcomes. Additionally, recent findings show that cyberbullying is not directly linked to time spent online, with traditional bullying still more prevalent in schools. Even the narrative around smartphone addiction is contested, with some researchers suggesting that concerns about addiction may be overstated. And some places <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teaching-digital-literacy-without-devices/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">schools do not have access to digital devices</a> for learners and then smartphones may play a crucial role in teaching and learning digital literacy skills.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="2560" height="1706" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-rdne-6936147-scaled.jpg" alt="Photo of four young people sitting at their desks, on their mobile phones." class="wp-image-90246" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-rdne-6936147-scaled.jpg 2560w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-rdne-6936147-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-rdne-6936147-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-rdne-6936147-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-rdne-6936147-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-rdne-6936147-2048x1365.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-rdne-6936147-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-rdne-6936147-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-rdne-6936147-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /></figure></div>


<p>As the debate over smartphone bans continues, educators have an opportunity to move beyond restrictions and engage students in understanding the technology that shapes their lives. This is where computing educators can really make a difference. How can they guide students to understand why technology is designed to capture attention and what lies behind these design choices?</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Understanding and questioning the design of technology&nbsp;</h2>



<p>School smartphone bans can feel like a hopeless act that suggests phones and social media are inherently incompatible with learning and student well-being. This approach assumes the only solution is to remove them, rather than considering how these technologies might be better managed or reimagined to support young people. What if, instead of banning phones, educators worked with students to explore why they are so captivating and how they could be designed differently? Computing educators can lead this exploration. With digital literacy as part of their curriculum, computing teachers can help students question the motives behind their devices, fostering a critical understanding of the forces shaping their digital world.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;With digital literacy as part of their curriculum, computing teachers can help students question the motives behind their devices, fostering a critical understanding of the forces shaping their digital world.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>At the heart of how social media platforms are designed is their business models. Tech companies rely on features such as notifications, autoplay, and infinite scrolling to maximise user engagement and revenue. This is part of what the writer Shoshana Zuboff calls <a href="https://www.hbs.edu/faculty/Pages/item.aspx?num=56791" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">“surveillance capitalism”</a>, where companies gather vast amounts of behavioural data by keeping users engaged on their platforms for as long as possible.</p>



<p>In the classroom, educators can open discussions with students on the motives behind technology design, exploring questions such as why platforms want users to stay engaged, and what data they are collecting. Activities might include analysing popular apps to identify which features encourage prolonged use, or debating how social media could be designed to prioritise user wellbeing. By critically examining these design choices, students can better understand the forces driving their digital interactions and consider ways in which technology could be reimagined to serve them, rather than just profiting from them.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Collaborative policymaking&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Once young people understand why phones and social media are designed the way they are, educators can work with students to create phone policies that reflect shared values and goals. This collaborative approach encourages students to take ownership of their technology use, and computing teachers, drawing on their knowledge of technology design and digital literacy, are ideally positioned to facilitate these discussions.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2560" height="1707" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-rdne-8500344-scaled.jpg" alt="Photo of three school pupils together looking at a mobile phone." class="wp-image-90247" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-rdne-8500344-scaled.jpg 2560w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-rdne-8500344-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-rdne-8500344-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-rdne-8500344-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-rdne-8500344-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-rdne-8500344-2048x1365.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-rdne-8500344-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-rdne-8500344-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-rdne-8500344-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /></figure></div>


<p><a href="https://www.renniecenter.org/sites/default/files/2019-01/2019%20Condition%20of%20Education%20Action%20Guide_Student%20Voice.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Research suggests that policies developed with student input are more effective</a>, as they foster responsibility and engagement. By involving students in policymaking, educators can encourage them to consider how phones could support rather than hinder learning. For example, students might agree that phones should stay off during certain times, or in certain spaces, but that they might be useful in other scenarios where access benefits learning. This kind of flexibility ensures that phones are used thoughtfully, allowing for both practical boundaries and opportunities for educational use.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Critical skills for navigating the digital world</h2>



<p>As debate around smartphone use in schools continues, academic research remains inconclusive on the effectiveness of phone bans. This uncertainty presents computing educators with an opportunity to move beyond restrictive policies and foster deeper understanding. By guiding students to explore why phones and social media are designed to capture attention, we can help to equip them with the critical skills needed to navigate their digital world thoughtfully. Involving students in crafting flexible, meaningful phone policies reinforces this understanding, giving them a sense of agency in shaping technology’s role in their lives.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2560" height="1707" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-karolina-grabowska-5311395-scaled.jpg" alt="Close up photo of a desk with school books, various coloured pens and a mobile phone in shot." class="wp-image-90248" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-karolina-grabowska-5311395-scaled.jpg 2560w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-karolina-grabowska-5311395-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-karolina-grabowska-5311395-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-karolina-grabowska-5311395-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-karolina-grabowska-5311395-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-karolina-grabowska-5311395-2048x1365.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-karolina-grabowska-5311395-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-karolina-grabowska-5311395-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/pexels-karolina-grabowska-5311395-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /></figure></div>


<p>Computing educators are uniquely positioned to empower students, not just as users, but as active challengers of technology design norms. Embracing a collaborative approach allows computing educators to inspire students to envision a future where technology genuinely serves their growth and their learning, rather than commercial interests.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">More on digital literacy for young people</h2>



<p><em>A version of this article appears in the newest issue of </em><a href="http://rpf.io/hw-26-laurakirsop" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Hello World magazine</em></a><em>, which is all about teaching digital literacy. </em><a href="http://rpf.io/hw-26-lk-phonebans" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Explore issue 26</em></a><em> and download your free PDF copy today.</em></p>



<p><em>You can also listen to our recent </em><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/podcast" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Hello World podcast</em></a><em> episode discussing the myth of the &#8216;digital native&#8217; and </em><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/podcast/digital-natives-are-young-people-tech-savy-or-dependent" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>whether today&#8217;s young people are tech-savvy or tech-dependent</em></a><em>.</em></p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/beyond-phone-bans-empowering-students-to-critically-navigate-and-reimagine-technology/">Beyond phone bans: Empowering students to critically navigate and reimagine technology</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/beyond-phone-bans-empowering-students-to-critically-navigate-and-reimagine-technology/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Teaching digital literacy without devices</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teaching-digital-literacy-without-devices/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teaching-digital-literacy-without-devices/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 12:43:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hello World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital literacy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=90217</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Lack of access to devices presents teachers with challenges in any setting. In schools, money is often limited and digital technology may not be the priority when buildings need maintenance or libraries need replenishing. This issue is particularly important when the very subject you teach relies on and relates to devices that you may have&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teaching-digital-literacy-without-devices/">Teaching digital literacy without devices</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Lack of access to devices presents teachers with challenges in any setting. In schools, money is often limited and digital technology may not be the priority when buildings need maintenance or libraries need replenishing. This issue is particularly important when the very subject you teach relies on and relates to devices that you may have limited or no access to.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="667" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/IMG_9645.jpg" alt="An educator helps students with a coding task in a classroom." class="wp-image-90229" style="width:762px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/IMG_9645.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/IMG_9645-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/IMG_9645-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/IMG_9645-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/IMG_9645-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/IMG_9645-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/IMG_9645-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>It must be frustrating for teachers in this situation to see marketing campaigns from companies showing how their curriculum offering will use the very latest in robotics, AI, or media production, when the teachers&#8217; reality is that they don’t have anything like the means or resources to deliver this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Fortunately there are approaches that can help. Below I outline some of the ways we are working with teachers to make the teaching of computing and digital literacy less resource-heavy and more accessible and equitable.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Schools in Kenya: A case study&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Our work with Kenyan teachers has brought the access issue into sharp focus for us. We are currently developing free resources to deliver the Kenyan curriculum to schools in Mombasa and the Frontier Counties. There are big contrasts both between and within these two areas of the country. Some schools are well equipped with digital technology, while others have very little access to any computing devices; in these schools, smartphones play a crucial role.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="667" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/IMG_9976.jpg" alt="Students code in Scratch on a computer." class="wp-image-90231" style="width:762px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/IMG_9976.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/IMG_9976-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/IMG_9976-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/IMG_9976-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/IMG_9976-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/IMG_9976-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/IMG_9976-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>With that in mind, the curriculum resources we develop suggest class activities that make the most of limited devices, such as the use of projected demonstrations. We also provide a step-by-step guide to computing tasks, with screenshots, to guide learners through the tasks conceptually. This ensures learners understand the process and can apply their new knowledge once they gain access to the necessary devices.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We make these resources available online and in downloadable documents. This means the resources can be taken offline and taught in places without stable internet connection. We are also careful to limit file sizes, to make downloads more accessible. Wherever possible, our resources are device-agnostic, so that they can be accessed on a wide range of devices, including personal devices such as mobile phones.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="668" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/20221025_Kenya_Connect_RPF_Training_07925.jpg" alt="A close-up shot shows a person's hand holding a small red LED light, which is illuminated. " class="wp-image-90232" style="width:762px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/20221025_Kenya_Connect_RPF_Training_07925.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/20221025_Kenya_Connect_RPF_Training_07925-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/20221025_Kenya_Connect_RPF_Training_07925-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/20221025_Kenya_Connect_RPF_Training_07925-768x513.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/20221025_Kenya_Connect_RPF_Training_07925-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/20221025_Kenya_Connect_RPF_Training_07925-450x301.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/20221025_Kenya_Connect_RPF_Training_07925-900x601.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>As well as tailoring curriculum resources, we have also adapted our teacher training to make it more accessible for people with less experience of using computing devices. For example, during a recent project coaching community trainers in Mombasa, we emphasised activities that improve digital skills on various devices. This meant that when passing the training on to other teachers, the community trainers had a broader set of skills across a wider range of devices.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="667" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/IMG_9984.jpg" alt="An educator delivers a lesson to students in a classroom. " class="wp-image-90233" style="width:762px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/IMG_9984.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/IMG_9984-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/IMG_9984-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/IMG_9984-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/IMG_9984-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/IMG_9984-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/IMG_9984-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">You&#8217;ll be able to read more about the impact of our work with Kenyan schools in an upcoming blog post.</figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Unplugged activities</h2>



<p>Even computing-specific concepts such as a programming construct can, to a degree, be taught with very limited access to devices. Unplugged activities, where no digital technology is required, can be used to introduce fundamental concepts such as sequencing and repetition.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="668" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/Copy-of-20221025_Kenya_Connect_RPF_Training_07755.jpg" alt="A group of men holding a string." class="wp-image-90234" style="width:762px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/Copy-of-20221025_Kenya_Connect_RPF_Training_07755.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/Copy-of-20221025_Kenya_Connect_RPF_Training_07755-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/Copy-of-20221025_Kenya_Connect_RPF_Training_07755-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/Copy-of-20221025_Kenya_Connect_RPF_Training_07755-768x513.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/Copy-of-20221025_Kenya_Connect_RPF_Training_07755-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/Copy-of-20221025_Kenya_Connect_RPF_Training_07755-450x301.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/Copy-of-20221025_Kenya_Connect_RPF_Training_07755-900x601.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>For example, you can ask learners to recognise patterns in repeating sequences of colours and identify how to describe the sequences without repeating the colours many times. While it is good practice to link the learning from an unplugged activity back to a plugged activity, students will still benefit when that is not possible.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Emulators&nbsp;</h2>



<p>There are also a significant number of devices which offer online emulator apps that mirror the functions of the physical device. Consider <a href="https://www.tts-group.co.uk/bee-bot-programmable-floor-robot/1015268.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Bee-Bot floor robots</a>, which can be relatively expensive to purchase and may get damaged in a classroom. If you don&#8217;t have the physical device, its <a href="http://helloworld.cc/beebot-emulator" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">emulator app</a> provides a similar experience.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="666" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/Copyright_©-Ministerio-de-Educacion-Chile_45409780321_78f48e2510_o.jpg" alt="Three young learners present their coding project." class="wp-image-90235" style="width:762px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/Copyright_©-Ministerio-de-Educacion-Chile_45409780321_78f48e2510_o.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/Copyright_©-Ministerio-de-Educacion-Chile_45409780321_78f48e2510_o-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/Copyright_©-Ministerio-de-Educacion-Chile_45409780321_78f48e2510_o-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/Copyright_©-Ministerio-de-Educacion-Chile_45409780321_78f48e2510_o-768x511.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/Copyright_©-Ministerio-de-Educacion-Chile_45409780321_78f48e2510_o-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/Copyright_©-Ministerio-de-Educacion-Chile_45409780321_78f48e2510_o-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/Copyright_©-Ministerio-de-Educacion-Chile_45409780321_78f48e2510_o-900x599.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>Similarly, the <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/collections/microbit" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">micro:bit</a>, a versatile microcontroller for young people, can be emulated in the MakeCode programming environment, including all its buttons and sensors. There are also numerous emulators which enable you to make and test your own circuits using a variety of hardware platforms. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What do you actually need?&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Sometimes it can be helpful to look up what devices you actually need — they might not be as expensive as you think. General-purpose, single-board computers such as <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.com/products/raspberry-pi-zero-2-w/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Raspberry Pi</a> can be bought new for less than £25, and more powerful models still under £50.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="772" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/46444116075_1e50b044f3_b.jpg" alt="A young learner is building his project at a Coolest Projects event." class="wp-image-90236" style="width:762px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/46444116075_1e50b044f3_b.jpg 1024w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/46444116075_1e50b044f3_b-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/46444116075_1e50b044f3_b-500x377.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/46444116075_1e50b044f3_b-768x579.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/46444116075_1e50b044f3_b-800x603.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/46444116075_1e50b044f3_b-450x339.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/46444116075_1e50b044f3_b-900x679.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure></div>


<p>Similarly, microcontrollers such as <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.com/products/raspberry-pi-pico-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Raspberry Pi Pico</a>, <a href="https://microbit.org/buy/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">micro:bit</a>, or <a href="https://redfernelectronics.co.uk/crumble/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Crumble</a>, range from about £5 to £20 per device. Accessories such as LEDs, jumper leads, motors, and buzzers are also reasonably priced. They can be a relatively low-cost entry into physical computing and robotics, especially if you pair them with craft materials or share devices between students.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Make the most of it&nbsp;</h2>



<p>However limited your access to devices is, I encourage you to:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Look out for partners or solution providers that prioritise inclusivity and accessibility in their resources</li>



<li>Consider whether you can make activities accessible on a wider range of devices and use what students may already have (check out <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/octostudio-app/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the OctoStudio app</a> for smartphones for example)</li>



<li>Use unplugged activities, and relate them back to plugged devices when possible</li>



<li>Look up devices which might be more affordable than you realised</li>
</ul>



<p>If you have your own tips to share with fellow teachers, please comment below.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">More on digital literacy</h2>



<p><em>You can discover our free </em><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/courses/learn-python" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>teacher training</em></a><em> and </em><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/curriculum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>classroom resources</em></a><em>, and read about how we&#8217;ve integrated </em><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/pedagogy/resources" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>digital literacy in The Computing Curriculum</em></a><em>.</em></p>



<p><em>A version of this article appears in the newest issue of </em><a href="http://rpf.io/hw-26-benhall" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Hello World magazine</em></a><em>, which is all about digital literacy. </em><a href="http://rpf.io/hw-26-bh-nd" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Explore issue 26</em></a><em> and download your free PDF copy today.</em><br><em>You can also listen to our recent </em><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/podcast" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Hello World podcast</em></a><em> episode exploring </em><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/podcast/teacher-tips-how-to-improve-digital-literacy-in-your-classroom" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>three teachers&#8217; digital literacy tips for the classroom</em></a><em>.</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teaching-digital-literacy-without-devices/">Teaching digital literacy without devices</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teaching-digital-literacy-without-devices/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Experience CS: A safe, creative way to teach computing</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-cs-a-safe-creative-way-to-teach-computing/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-cs-a-safe-creative-way-to-teach-computing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Laura Kirsop]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 13:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Experience CS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=90201</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Experience CS is our new free curriculum that helps elementary and middle school educators (working with students aged 8 to 14) teach computer science with confidence through creative, cross-curricular lessons and projects. Designed for teachers, by teachers, Experience CS is built to be easy to use in classrooms, with everything you need integrated into one&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-cs-a-safe-creative-way-to-teach-computing/">Experience CS: A safe, creative way to teach computing</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Experience CS is <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-cs-a-new-way-to-teach-computer-science/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our new free curriculum</a> that helps elementary and middle school educators (working with students aged 8 to 14) teach computer science with confidence through creative, cross-curricular lessons and projects. Designed for teachers, by teachers, <a href="https://experience-cs.org/?utm_source=rpf&amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;utm_campaign=exp-cs-blog-scratch" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Experience CS</a> is built to be easy to use in classrooms, with everything you need integrated into one safe, school-friendly platform.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2560" height="1709" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_029-scaled.jpg" alt="A group of young people and educators smiling while engaging with a computer" class="wp-image-63316" style="width:775px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_029-scaled.jpg 2560w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_029-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_029-768x513.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_029-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_029-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_029-2048x1367.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_029-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_029-scaled-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_029-scaled-900x601.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /></figure></div>


<p>In this blog post, we will share more about the safety features of Experience CS, and the steps we’ve taken to make the platform a great fit for your school.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A safe, teacher-managed environment</h2>



<p>Experience CS supports young people to develop their understanding of computer science through engaging, interactive projects using the programming language Scratch. Scratch is a popular block-based language that helps young people get started with coding, and Experience CS includes a version of Scratch that we have built especially for schools. With our version, which is fully integrated into the Experience CS platform, students can explore coding in a teacher-managed, closed environment that aligns with schools’ safeguarding policies and gives you full control over what your students see and do.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="609" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/scratch_experience_cs.jpg" alt="Scratch coding within Experience CS. If you've used our Code Editor, you'll recognise this interface." class="wp-image-90202" style="width:824px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/scratch_experience_cs.jpg 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/scratch_experience_cs-300x114.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/scratch_experience_cs-500x190.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/scratch_experience_cs-768x292.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/scratch_experience_cs-1536x585.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/scratch_experience_cs-800x305.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/scratch_experience_cs-450x171.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/scratch_experience_cs-900x343.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Scratch coding within Experience CS. If you&#8217;ve used our Code Editor, you&#8217;ll recognise this interface.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Student safety and privacy are at the forefront in Experience CS, which means:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>A private, closed environment</strong>. Projects are kept within the classroom and cannot be published to a public gallery.<br></li>



<li><strong>Teacher-controlled access</strong>. Students don’t need to create or manage their own accounts. Teachers manage their students’ access, with no student email addresses required.<br></li>



<li><strong>No social features</strong>. Students don’t create public profiles or follow other users, and there are no chat or comment features for young people.<br></li>



<li><strong>Curated content</strong>. Students can only access the projects and materials you share with them, not content from other users.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Tailor-made for schools</h2>



<p>We have designed every part of the Experience CS platform with school environments in mind, making it easier for teachers to manage and for students to use.</p>



<p>Here’s how:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Fully integrated platform.</strong> Everything students need is built into the Experience CS platform, including Scratch, lesson resources, student materials, and project templates. There is no need to visit other websites.<br></li>



<li><strong>Simple access. </strong>Teachers generate class codes so learners can jump straight into activities, with no student email address required.<br></li>



<li><strong>Automatic progress saving.</strong> Students’ projects are saved in the platform and linked to their class. Teachers can see students’ progress at a glance.<br></li>



<li><strong>Teacher control.</strong> Teachers have full visibility of students’ activity, and what students see and do stays within the classroom environment.</li>
</ul>



<p>Experience CS gives you the tools and peace of mind to deliver creative, engaging computer science lessons and activities in a way that works for your school. You will be able to effortlessly manage students’ work, with everything you and your students need provided within a simple, intuitive interface.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="5980" height="3947" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2019/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_028.jpg" alt="A computing educator with three students at laptops in a classroom." class="wp-image-50374" style="width:774px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2019/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_028.jpg 5980w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2019/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_028-300x198.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2019/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_028-768x507.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2019/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_028-500x330.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2019/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_028-1636x1080.jpg 1636w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 5980px) 100vw, 5980px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Be the first to try Experience CS</h2>



<p>Experience CS is launching soon, and we can’t wait to see what you and your students create with it.</p>



<p>If you would like early access, want to stay up to date, or are interested in trying Experience CS out in your classroom, <a href="https://experience-cs.org/?utm_source=rpf&amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;utm_campaign=exp-cs-blog-scratch" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for updates</a> and we’ll keep you in the loop.</p>



<p>We’re also planning ahead: in the coming months, we’ll make our version of Scratch available to all schools and clubs via our <a href="https://editor.raspberrypi.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Code Editor</a>. That means whether or not you use the Experience CS curriculum, you’ll be able to run safe, creative coding sessions using Scratch in a school-friendly environment.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-cs-a-safe-creative-way-to-teach-computing/">Experience CS: A safe, creative way to teach computing</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-cs-a-safe-creative-way-to-teach-computing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ready, set, Scratch: A beginner&#8217;s guide to creative coding</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ready-set-scratch-a-beginners-guide-to-creative-coding/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ready-set-scratch-a-beginners-guide-to-creative-coding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Calleja]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 10:01:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Scratch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding for kids]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=90164</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What is Scratch? Scratch is a free, beginner-friendly coding platform that allows young people to create animations, games, and interactive stories using simple visual blocks. Scratch removes some of the complexity of coding by replacing syntax-heavy programming languages with intuitive drag-and-drop blocks. This lets creativity take centre stage and makes it the perfect first step&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ready-set-scratch-a-beginners-guide-to-creative-coding/">Ready, set, Scratch: A beginner&#8217;s guide to creative coding</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What is Scratch?</strong></h2>



<p>Scratch is a free, beginner-friendly coding platform that allows young people to create animations, games, and interactive stories using simple visual blocks. Scratch removes some of the complexity of coding by replacing syntax-heavy programming languages with intuitive drag-and-drop blocks. This lets creativity take centre stage and makes it the perfect first step for young coders.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2560" height="1707" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/CodeClub_ParkStreet-04-scaled.jpg" alt="Two young people smiling whilst working on their laptop with an adult mentor by their side." class="wp-image-88616" style="width:658px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/CodeClub_ParkStreet-04-scaled.jpg 2560w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/CodeClub_ParkStreet-04-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/CodeClub_ParkStreet-04-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/CodeClub_ParkStreet-04-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/CodeClub_ParkStreet-04-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/CodeClub_ParkStreet-04-2048x1366.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/CodeClub_ParkStreet-04-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/CodeClub_ParkStreet-04-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/10/CodeClub_ParkStreet-04-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Why Scratch is the ideal starting point</strong></h2>



<p>Every coding journey begins with a single step. Scratch delivers this first step in a way that is playful, approachable, and empowering. Scratch immediately delivers tangible results that new coders can feel proud of by linking coding to storytelling, design, and play. It also cultivates curiosity, confidence, and resilience — qualities crucial to long-term success in both coding and problem solving.</p>



<p>Most importantly, Scratch emphasises exploration over perfection. It invites young learners to experiment freely, troubleshoot confidently, and express themselves creatively without fear of making mistakes. This exploratory mindset provides the foundation for future technical proficiency and innovation.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Get started with our free projects</strong></h2>



<p>Starting with structured projects helps young learners build solid coding skills while maintaining enthusiasm and enjoyment.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/projects/catch-the-bus"><strong>Catch the bus (animation)</strong></a></h3>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="688" height="361" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-9.png" alt="" class="wp-image-90175" style="width:662px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-9.png 688w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-9-300x157.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-9-500x262.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-9-450x236.png 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 688px) 100vw, 688px" /></figure></div>


<p>In ‘Catch the bus’, coders create an animation featuring a character (called a sprite in Scratch) attempting to catch a departing bus. They learn how to sequence events, switch costumes to simulate movement, and synchronise actions to tell a simple story. This introduces fundamental storytelling and animation skills in Scratch.</p>



<p><strong>What you&#8217;ll learn:</strong></p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Timing and sequencing actions</li>



<li>Using costume changes to simulate movement</li>



<li>Creating narrative animations</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/projects/chomp-the-cheese"><strong>Chomp the cheese (interactive)</strong></a></h3>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2560" height="1344" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-10-scaled.png" alt="" class="wp-image-90176" style="width:664px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-10-scaled.png 2560w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-10-300x157.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-10-500x262.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-10-768x403.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-10-1536x806.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-10-2048x1075.png 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-10-800x420.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-10-450x236.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-10-900x472.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /></figure></div>


<p>In ‘Chomp the cheese’, learners use facial recognition tools in Scratch Lab to build an interactive game controlled by mouth movements. Using a webcam, players physically open their mouths to &#8220;chomp&#8221; virtual cheese snacks on screen. This playful and engaging activity introduces machine learning concepts in a tangible and enjoyable way.</p>



<p><strong>What you&#8217;ll learn:</strong></p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Using facial recognition in Scratch</li>



<li>Creating interactive games with webcam input</li>



<li>Basic concepts of machine learning and interactivity</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/projects/boat-race"><strong>Boat race (game)</strong></a></h3>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="688" height="361" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-11.png" alt="" class="wp-image-90177" style="width:664px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-11.png 688w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-11-300x157.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-11-500x262.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-11-450x236.png 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 688px) 100vw, 688px" /></figure></div>


<p>In ‘Boat race’, young coders create a game where players navigate a boat around obstacles, steering using mouse controls. They learn to handle player input, detect collisions, and define conditions for winning. This foundational game-making experience sets the stage for more complex creations in the future.</p>



<p><strong>What you&#8217;ll learn:</strong></p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Controlling sprites with mouse clicks</li>



<li>Collision detection between sprites</li>



<li>Defining goals and win conditions</li>
</ul>



<p>&#8220;The key to sparking a lifelong interest in coding is excitement. When young people are building something they genuinely care about, they&#8217;re not worried about getting everything perfect on the first try. They&#8217;re chasing their ideas and learning as they go. Scratch creates the ideal environment for this type of messy, brilliant exploration. It provides young coders with the freedom to experiment, persevere, and express themselves — all while enjoying the process,&#8221; or so says my amazing colleague Pete Bell, Learning Manager and creator of some of our most engaging content at the Raspberry Pi Foundation. I have to say, I agree with him!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Level up and build momentum</strong></h2>



<p>After completing their first projects, young coders can continue to build momentum through several exciting avenues:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ready-to-remix-favourite-projects-to-tinker-with/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Personalise projects</a>:</strong> Encourage learners to remix existing projects by altering characters, backgrounds, and rules. Personalisation deepens learning and fosters ownership of the coding experience.</li>



<li><strong><a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/collections/python" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Explore Python</a>:</strong> Scratch&#8217;s block-based coding naturally leads to curiosity about text-based languages like Python, which many learners find an exciting next step.</li>



<li><strong><a href="https://codeclub.org/en/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Join a Code Club</a>:</strong> Coding alongside peers transforms individual learning into a social experience. Code Clubs offer a collaborative environment where learners solve problems together, share creations, and build lasting friendships.</li>
</ul>



<p>Encouraging personalisation, curiosity, and community involvement keeps learners motivated and engaged on their coding journey.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2374" height="1220" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/05/CODE_CLUB_UDAIPUR_00011.jpg" alt="Children in a Code Club in India." class="wp-image-84055" style="width:664px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/05/CODE_CLUB_UDAIPUR_00011.jpg 2374w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/05/CODE_CLUB_UDAIPUR_00011-300x154.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/05/CODE_CLUB_UDAIPUR_00011-500x257.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/05/CODE_CLUB_UDAIPUR_00011-768x395.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/05/CODE_CLUB_UDAIPUR_00011-1536x789.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/05/CODE_CLUB_UDAIPUR_00011-2048x1052.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/05/CODE_CLUB_UDAIPUR_00011-800x411.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/05/CODE_CLUB_UDAIPUR_00011-450x231.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/05/CODE_CLUB_UDAIPUR_00011-900x463.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 2374px) 100vw, 2374px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Conclusion</strong></h2>



<p>Scratch is more than just an introductory tool — it&#8217;s a creative playground that nurtures curiosity, resilience, and technical skills in equal measure. By guiding young coders through their first steps with engaging projects and supportive encouragement, you lay the foundation for a lifetime of innovation, problem-solving, and creative expression. Ready, set, <a href="https://scratch.mit.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Scratch</em></a>! Let’s get started!</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ready-set-scratch-a-beginners-guide-to-creative-coding/">Ready, set, Scratch: A beginner&#8217;s guide to creative coding</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ready-set-scratch-a-beginners-guide-to-creative-coding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Insights from a teacher trainer: Schools are ready to engage in AI — what they need is support</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/insights-from-a-teacher-trainer-experience-ai/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/insights-from-a-teacher-trainer-experience-ai/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dan Shilling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 10:15:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Experience AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=90140</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Today’s blog post is written by Dan Shilling, Programmes Manager at Parent Zone, one of our global partners for Experience AI. “Educators have been struggling to find resources and support to teach young people about AI.” This is something I’ve heard a lot when delivering Experience AI teacher training through Parent Zone’s partnership with the&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/insights-from-a-teacher-trainer-experience-ai/">Insights from a teacher trainer: Schools are ready to engage in AI — what they need is support</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>Today’s blog post is written by Dan Shilling, Programmes Manager at Parent Zone, one of our global partners for Experience AI.</em></p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Educators have been struggling to find resources and support to teach young people about AI.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>This is something I’ve heard a lot when delivering <a href="https://parentzone.org.uk/ExperienceAI">Experience AI teacher training</a> through Parent Zone’s partnership with the Raspberry Pi Foundation.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="686" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-8.png" alt="An educator is delivering a presentation during a workshop." class="wp-image-90141" style="width:798px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-8.png 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-8-300x129.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-8-500x214.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-8-768x329.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-8-1536x659.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-8-800x343.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-8-450x193.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-8-900x386.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Our partnership with the Raspberry Pi Foundation</strong></h2>



<p>Experience AI is an artificial intelligence (AI) literacy programme, co-developed by the Raspberry Pi Foundation and Google DeepMind, that teaches students aged 11 to 14 about AI and machine learning. Thanks to funding from <a href="http://google.org">Google.org</a>, Parent Zone has partnered with the Raspberry Pi Foundation to provide free training to UK educators, equipping them with the skills they need to effectively deliver the programme in their settings.<br><br>The Experience AI <a href="http://rpf.io/expai-blog-parentzone1">resources </a>help educators, including those from non-technical backgrounds, to deliver impactful lessons on AI and machine learning. Lesson resources span technical elements (e.g. data-driven models, bias) and practical elements (e.g. careers, safety).</p>



<p>Our face-to-face and virtual training sessions show teachers how to use the programme resources, as well as helping them feel more confident in the subject matter.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The sessions also give me an opportunity to hear from teachers about how AI is being used and taught in classrooms,&nbsp;and the opportunities and challenges it’s creating.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="584" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/experience-ai.jpg" alt="A group of educators at a workshop." class="wp-image-90148" style="width:802px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/experience-ai.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/experience-ai-300x175.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/experience-ai-500x292.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/experience-ai-768x449.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/experience-ai-800x467.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/experience-ai-450x263.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/experience-ai-900x526.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Curiosity and experimentation</strong></h2>



<p>AI has a major presence in many schools now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Teachers tell me they’re seeing students use AI to support their homework. One teacher spoke about a student using a chatbot to help break down a maths problem, describing it like “having a tutor at home.”</p>



<p>Teachers are also using AI themselves to assist in their work — for example, to plan lessons, generate activities, and get ideas on how to explain complex topics more clearly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Openness to experimentation is clearly there.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="667" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/experience-ai-1.jpg" alt="Educators at a workshop." class="wp-image-90150" style="width:800px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/experience-ai-1.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/experience-ai-1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/experience-ai-1-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/experience-ai-1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/experience-ai-1-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/experience-ai-1-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/experience-ai-1-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Addressing concerns</strong></h2>



<p>For all the benefits of AI, teachers also have concerns about it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Some have told me their students have no idea how easily these tools can be used to mislead or manipulate, through disinformation and deepfakes, for example.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is why Experience AI resources are meeting educator needs. Not only do they explain how AI and machine learning actually work, but they also address many pressing concerns around AI, from responsible usage and media literacy, to how data bias can affect the final output.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Positive changes</strong></h2>



<p>In all the workshops, what stands out to me most is how ready teachers are to engage. They want to understand more. They want to help their students make sense of AI, and use it positively.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They’re grateful for practical, grounded training and support that doesn’t assume they’ve all got computer science degrees. After one of our sessions, a teacher said:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>“The better we educate ourselves, the better we&#8217;re able to help young people. It’s important because it&#8217;s affecting their day-to-day lives. We can help them navigate AI platforms, but in a safe way.”</em></p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="1067" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/experience-ai-2.jpg" alt="Educators at a workshop." class="wp-image-90151" style="width:806px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/experience-ai-2.jpg 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/experience-ai-2-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/experience-ai-2-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/experience-ai-2-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/experience-ai-2-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/experience-ai-2-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/experience-ai-2-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/experience-ai-2-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Join a network of AI-ready educators</strong></h2>



<p>If you’re a UK secondary school teacher, you can sign up for free training from Parent Zone, with dates available until November 2025. You can choose from:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><a href="https://parentzone.org.uk/ExperienceAI/Campus">Full-day sessions at the Google AI Campus in London</a>&nbsp;</li>



<li><a href="https://parentzone.org.uk/ExperienceAI/Schools">In school full-day sessions</a></li>



<li><a href="https://parentzone.org.uk/ExperienceAI/remote">Remote, online workshops (full and half-days)</a></li>
</ul>



<p><em>For more information about Experience AI, <a href="http://rpf.io/expai-blog-parentzone1">visit our website</a>.</em></p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/insights-from-a-teacher-trainer-experience-ai/">Insights from a teacher trainer: Schools are ready to engage in AI — what they need is support</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/insights-from-a-teacher-trainer-experience-ai/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What do we even mean by digital literacy?</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/what-do-we-even-mean-by-digital-literacy/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/what-do-we-even-mean-by-digital-literacy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rachel Arthur]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 10:05:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital literacy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=90111</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>’Digital literacy’ is a term that seems to pop up everywhere. In the early 2000s, it was the next big thing; some even suggested it might replace traditional literacy and numeracy. But, like many educational trends, it soon faded from the spotlight, and became something that schools &#8216;should&#8217; do, or something left to the lone&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/what-do-we-even-mean-by-digital-literacy/">What do we even mean by digital literacy?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>’Digital literacy’ is a term that seems to pop up everywhere. In the early 2000s, it was the next big thing; some even suggested it might replace traditional literacy and numeracy. But, like many educational trends, it soon faded from the spotlight, and became something that schools &#8216;should&#8217; do, or something left to the lone teacher who had been handed the role of IT coordinator.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1500" height="1012" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/BARROWHILL_CC4282.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-89026" style="width:649px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/BARROWHILL_CC4282.jpg 1500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/BARROWHILL_CC4282-300x202.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/BARROWHILL_CC4282-500x337.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/BARROWHILL_CC4282-768x518.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/BARROWHILL_CC4282-800x540.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/BARROWHILL_CC4282-450x304.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/BARROWHILL_CC4282-900x607.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1500px) 100vw, 1500px" /></figure></div>


<p>For many teachers, at least in the UK, digital literacy meant booking a set of laptops (and hoping the last class had remembered to charge them) and ticking off history learning objectives by making a PowerPoint about Henry VIII’s wives. It became a bit of an afterthought.&nbsp;</p>



<p>More recently, digital literacy seems to have been rebranded as ‘digital skills’, often framed as the capabilities young people need for the workplace of tomorrow. But I don’t think that tells the full story.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Digital literacy beyond employability</h2>



<p>Digital literacy isn’t just about employability; it’s about fairness and access. It’s about more than just learning to use spreadsheets (though my love for Excel remains strong); it’s about ensuring that all young people have the knowledge and confidence to navigate the digital world we live in today.</p>



<p>Digital literacy is about understanding the digital tools we rely on every day, securely accessing online services, making informed decisions about sharing personal information, and critically evaluating the endless stream of news and misinformation online.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s also <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/teach/ai-education">about artificial intelligence</a>: not just playing with the latest tools, but <a href="http://rpf.io/expai-hw-blogra" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">understanding how they work</a>, the biases built into them, and the ways they shape our lives.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2560" height="1707" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/CoderDojo-CCW-07-scaled.jpg" alt="Three ways to help students learn about the impact of technology" class="wp-image-90006" style="width:652px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/CoderDojo-CCW-07-scaled.jpg 2560w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/CoderDojo-CCW-07-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/CoderDojo-CCW-07-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/CoderDojo-CCW-07-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/CoderDojo-CCW-07-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/CoderDojo-CCW-07-2048x1366.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/CoderDojo-CCW-07-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/CoderDojo-CCW-07-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/CoderDojo-CCW-07-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /></figure></div>


<p>True digital literacy empowers young people to engage with technology thoughtfully, critically, and confidently. And that’s something worth making space for. To truly ensure that young people have fair access to the digitally enabled world we live in, we must equip them with the skills to <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/should-we-ditch-the-term-digital-native-the-latest-conversation-on-the-podcast/">understand and use technology effectively</a>. This means making space for digital literacy <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/curriculum/">within the curriculum</a> and ensuring that all teachers feel confident in delivering it.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Digital literacy as a core part of teaching</h2>



<p>Every teacher has a role to play in helping students develop these essential skills. This requires high-quality curriculum resources that integrate digital tools meaningfully into different subjects, as well as <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/courses/learn-python">comprehensive teacher training</a> to ensure every educator feels empowered to teach digital literacy as part of their everyday practice.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, let’s not treat digital literacy like that forgotten box of tangled charging cables in the staffroom (important, but nobody is quite sure what to do with it). Instead, let’s make it a core part of teaching, just like reading, writing, and knowing how to keep a straight face when a student asks if they really need to save their work.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2560" height="1379" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/CODE_CLUB_CHENNAI_0002-scaled.jpg" alt="Two girls code at a desktop computer while a female mentor observes them." class="wp-image-63420" style="width:654px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/CODE_CLUB_CHENNAI_0002-scaled.jpg 2560w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/CODE_CLUB_CHENNAI_0002-300x162.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/CODE_CLUB_CHENNAI_0002-768x414.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/CODE_CLUB_CHENNAI_0002-500x269.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/CODE_CLUB_CHENNAI_0002-1536x827.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/CODE_CLUB_CHENNAI_0002-2048x1103.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/CODE_CLUB_CHENNAI_0002-800x431.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/CODE_CLUB_CHENNAI_0002-scaled-450x242.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/CODE_CLUB_CHENNAI_0002-scaled-900x485.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /></figure></div>


<p>If we get this right, we’re not just preparing young people for the jobs of tomorrow, we’re making sure they can navigate today’s digital world safely, confidently, and with the critical thinking skills to tell fact from fiction (because let’s face it, the internet isn’t exactly short on absolute nonsense).&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, who’s up for making a PowerPoint about Henry VIII’s wives?&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">More on digital literacy</h2>



<p><em>You can discover our free </em><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/courses/learn-python"><em>teacher training</em></a><em> and </em><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/curriculum/"><em>classroom resources</em></a><em>, and read about how we&#8217;ve integrated </em><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/pedagogy/resources"><em>digital literacy in The Computing Curriculum</em></a><em>.</em></p>



<p><em>A version of this article appears in the newest issue of <a href="http://rpf.io/hw-26-rachelarthur" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hello World magazine</a>, which is all about digital literacy. <a href="http://rpf.io/hw-26-ra-dl" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Explore issue 26 and download your free PDF copy</a> today.</em></p>



<p><em>You can also listen to our recent Hello World podcast episode exploring </em><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/podcast/teacher-tips-how-to-improve-digital-literacy-in-your-classroom"><em>three teachers&#8217; digital literacy tips for the classroom</em></a><em>.</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/what-do-we-even-mean-by-digital-literacy/">What do we even mean by digital literacy?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/what-do-we-even-mean-by-digital-literacy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pedagogy Quick Reads: turning abstract ideas into classroom practice</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/pedagogy-quick-reads-turning-abstract-ideas-into-classroom-practice/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/pedagogy-quick-reads-turning-abstract-ideas-into-classroom-practice/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[James Robinson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 10:56:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pedagogy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quick reads]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=90081</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What does outstanding computing education look like in the age of AI? We&#8217;ve just released a new series of Pedagogy Quick Reads exploring this vital question. Focusing on three aspects of AI in computing education, these short guides offer practical insights and new strategies for your classroom practice. Each Pedagogy Quick Read is designed to&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/pedagogy-quick-reads-turning-abstract-ideas-into-classroom-practice/">Pedagogy Quick Reads: turning abstract ideas into classroom practice</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>What does outstanding computing education look like in the age of AI?</strong> We&#8217;ve just released a new series of <em>Pedagogy Quick Reads</em> exploring this vital question. Focusing on three aspects of AI in computing education, these short guides offer practical insights and new strategies for your classroom practice.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1920" height="1280" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/03/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-5.jpg" alt="In a computing classroom, a smiling girl raises her hand." class="wp-image-78791" style="width:580px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/03/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-5.jpg 1920w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/03/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-5-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/03/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-5-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/03/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-5-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/03/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-5-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/03/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-5-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/03/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-5-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/03/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-5-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /></figure></div>


<p>Each Pedagogy Quick Read is designed to help educators explore, understand, and apply one area of research evidence.</p>



<p>You get:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>An introduction to the topic or idea, putting it into context</li>



<li>A summary of the key concepts and takeaways for educators</li>



<li>Sections elaborating on each key concept and relevant research</li>



<li>A diagram presenting the same ideas in visual form</li>



<li>Links to referenced resources for further reading</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Introducing our AI Pedagogy Quick Reads</strong></h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Computational Thinking 2.0</strong></h3>



<p>This Quick Read explores how the concept of computational thinking is evolving, particularly in the context of AI. It offers guidance on how to teach computational thinking skills that are relevant to and enhanced by AI technologies.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="http://the-cc.io/qr21" target="_blank" rel=" noreferrer noopener"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="1281" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-5.png" alt="" class="wp-image-90082" style="width:450px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-5.png 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-5-300x240.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-5-500x400.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-5-768x615.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-5-1536x1230.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-5-800x641.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-5-450x360.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-5-900x721.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></figure></div>


<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>&#8220;Without CT2.0, today&#8217;s learners will remain passive consumers rather than informed participants in a world increasingly shaped by data-driven AI technologies.&#8221;</em></p>
</blockquote>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="http://the-cc.io/qr21" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Download</strong></a></div>
</div>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Anthropomorphism</strong></h3>



<p>As AI becomes widely used, it&#8217;s important to consider how students understand and view these technologies. This Quick Read discusses anthropomorphism (attributing human-like qualities to AI) and provides strategies for teaching about AI in a way that avoids common misconceptions.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="http://the-cc.io/qr22" target="_blank" rel=" noreferrer noopener"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="1281" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-6.png" alt="" class="wp-image-90084" style="width:452px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-6.png 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-6-300x240.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-6-500x400.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-6-768x615.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-6-1536x1230.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-6-800x641.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-6-450x360.png 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></figure></div>


<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>&#8220;If young people see this technology as innately human-like, we run the risk of impacting their&#8230;sense of agency&#8230;safety&#8230;social connection&#8230;curiosity.&#8221;</em></p>
</blockquote>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="http://the-cc.io/qr22" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Download</strong></a></div>
</div>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Feedback Literacy</strong></h3>



<p>Effective feedback is important for student learning, especially in a rapidly changing field like AI. This Quick Read examines how to develop &#8220;feedback literacy&#8221; in both educators and students, enabling them to give, receive, and use feedback more effectively.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="http://the-cc.io/qr23" target="_blank" rel=" noreferrer noopener"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="1281" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-7.png" alt="" class="wp-image-90086" style="width:450px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-7.png 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-7-300x240.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-7-500x400.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-7-768x615.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-7-1536x1230.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-7-800x641.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-7-450x360.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-7-900x721.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></figure></div>


<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>“How do we ensure that all students get the most out of AI system-produced feedback? Feedback literacy is a theory-driven framework that can help&#8230;answer this question.&#8221;</em></p>
</blockquote>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="http://the-cc.io/qr23" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Download</strong></a></div>
</div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Browse our library of pedagogy resources</strong></h2>



<p>The new AI-themed reads join our bank of other Pedagogy Quick Reads, which cover a wide range of topics related to computing education. You can find these resources and more on our <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/pedagogy">pedagogy page</a>, all organised around our <a href="http://the-cc.io/pedagogy_poster">12 pedagogy principles</a> for computing education.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="342" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/11/NCCE_SW_003-500x342.jpg" alt="a teenage boy does coding during a computer science lesson." class="wp-image-77410" style="width:584px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/11/NCCE_SW_003-500x342.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/11/NCCE_SW_003-300x205.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/11/NCCE_SW_003-768x526.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/11/NCCE_SW_003-1536x1051.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/11/NCCE_SW_003-2048x1402.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/11/NCCE_SW_003-800x548.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/11/NCCE_SW_003-450x308.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2021/11/NCCE_SW_003-900x616.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Other resources&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p>As well as our Pedagogy Quick Reads, we also offer lots of other resources to support computing educators:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>The <a href="http://rpf.io/hw-quickreads-pedagogy">Hello World</a> Big Book of Computing Pedagogy is an in-depth guide to research-backed computing education pedagogy, covering a wide range of topics and offering practical advice for teachers.</li>



<li>The <a href="http://rpf.io/hw-quickread-general">Hello World magazine and podcast</a> feature insights from educators in computing education, exploring current research, best classroom practices, and innovative teaching strategies.</li>



<li>Our AI literacy programme, <a href="http://rpf.io/expai-blog-quickreads" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Experience AI</a>, provides teachers with cutting-edge resources on AI and machine learning, based on proven pedagogical principles to support effective learning and teaching.</li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/pedagogy-quick-reads-turning-abstract-ideas-into-classroom-practice/">Pedagogy Quick Reads: turning abstract ideas into classroom practice</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/pedagogy-quick-reads-turning-abstract-ideas-into-classroom-practice/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Celebrating young innovators at Coolest Projects USA</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/celebrating-young-innovators-at-coolest-projects-usa/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/celebrating-young-innovators-at-coolest-projects-usa/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sophie Ashford]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 12:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Coolest Projects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coolest projects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coolest projects 2025]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coolest Projects USA]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=90040</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Last month, the Science Museum of Minnesota buzzed with excitement as young tech creators from across the country came together for Coolest Projects USA in a celebration of creativity, curiosity, and coding. Around 40 young people showcased their projects on the day, sharing their work with friends, family, and the wider coding community. With hands-on&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/celebrating-young-innovators-at-coolest-projects-usa/">Celebrating young innovators at Coolest Projects USA</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Last month, the Science Museum of Minnesota buzzed with excitement as young tech creators from across the country came together for Coolest Projects USA in a celebration of creativity, curiosity, and coding.</p>



<p>Around 40 young people showcased their projects on the day, sharing their work with friends, family, and the wider coding community. With hands-on tech activities, project demonstrations, fun swag, and certificates of achievement, the day was packed with energy and enthusiasm.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="667" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54474541522_7b3c7e72d4_k.jpg" alt="Young creators at the Coolest Project USA event." class="wp-image-90054" style="width:714px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54474541522_7b3c7e72d4_k.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54474541522_7b3c7e72d4_k-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54474541522_7b3c7e72d4_k-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54474541522_7b3c7e72d4_k-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54474541522_7b3c7e72d4_k-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54474541522_7b3c7e72d4_k-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54474541522_7b3c7e72d4_k-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>Coolest Projects is all about empowering young people to show off what they&#8217;ve built, no matter their skill level or experience. From first-time coders to budding engineers, everyone was welcomed and learnt something from the day.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Celebrating impact: Broadcom Foundation Coding with Commitment®&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p>One of the standout moments was the presentation of the Broadcom Foundation Coding with Commitment® special recognition, which highlights a project that uses code to solve real-world problems.</p>



<p>The award went to Kaila for her project, Car vs Road, a self-driving car simulation designed to explore how natural disasters like hurricanes, floods, and tornadoes might impact autonomous vehicle technology.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="667" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475743575_d45064ddd1_k.jpg" alt="Kaila presenting her project at Coolest Projects USA." class="wp-image-90055" style="width:716px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475743575_d45064ddd1_k.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475743575_d45064ddd1_k-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475743575_d45064ddd1_k-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475743575_d45064ddd1_k-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475743575_d45064ddd1_k-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475743575_d45064ddd1_k-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475743575_d45064ddd1_k-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“My project was inspired by Waymo. After hearing about Coolest Projects through the Minnesota State Science and Engineering Fair, I decided to attend — and absolutely loved it! The atmosphere was welcoming, the judges were so involved, and the entire experience was truly unforgettable.” &#8211; Kaila, 2025 Coding with Commitment® recipient </p>
</blockquote>



<p>Broadcom Foundation’s partnership with Coolest Projects USA highlights how coding can be a powerful tool for tackling global challenges, from health to climate change, and champions digital literacy for all youth.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Celebrating creativity across categories</strong></h2>



<p>With seven categories available for entries, the judges had their work cut out for them choosing their favourite projects. Here are some that captured their attention on the day:</p>



<p><strong>Mila | Sports Compilation, Scratch</strong></p>



<p>Mila’s project, Sports Compilation, tells a story through animated sports scenes that inspire people to try new things and embrace their rebellious side.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p class="is-style-plain">“I wanted to show my mom that I could code — even though I’m not a ‘full-time coder’. I kept working on my original sports scene and added more to create something bigger.”</p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="667" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475580714_237a7638ac_k.jpg" alt="Mila presenting her project at Coolest Projects USA." class="wp-image-90057" style="width:720px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475580714_237a7638ac_k.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475580714_237a7638ac_k-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475580714_237a7638ac_k-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475580714_237a7638ac_k-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475580714_237a7638ac_k-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475580714_237a7638ac_k-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475580714_237a7638ac_k-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“My biggest challenge was making it reset automatically. At first, I didn’t understand the instructions I found online, but then I figured out how to use timing and broadcasts to make it work.&#8221;</p>



<p>&#8220;Coolest Projects was so fun, my teacher hyped it up, and it lived up to the excitement!”</p>
</blockquote>



<p><strong>Ethan | Coding AI to Enhance Speech Therapy</strong></p>



<p>Ethan’s project was inspired by his experience with speech therapy. He used machine learning to help people identify and correct different types of incorrect pronunciations of the /s/ sound. Ethan shared his motivations behind attending:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I went to Coolest Projects USA to get the opportunity to present my work and receive feedback from a large audience of judges, participants, and other viewers on how to improve my project and the presentation of it.”</p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="667" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475744440_4d4bc85f00_k.jpg" alt="Participants at Coolest Projects USA." class="wp-image-90065" style="width:722px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475744440_4d4bc85f00_k.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475744440_4d4bc85f00_k-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475744440_4d4bc85f00_k-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475744440_4d4bc85f00_k-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475744440_4d4bc85f00_k-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475744440_4d4bc85f00_k-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475744440_4d4bc85f00_k-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I had fun at Coolest Projects USA, seeing the different ways that young people like me are taking advantage of technology to try and help the lives of others, and also seeing the creativity and determination that we have.”</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>A big thank you</strong></h2>



<p>We want to say a huge thank you to every young creator who presented a project, to the families who cheered them on, and to our amazing volunteers and partners. We also want to give a special shoutout to our sponsors, Broadcom Foundation and Best Buy Inc., for their incredible support. We couldn’t have done it without you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you for making Coolest Projects USA 2025 such a special day!</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="667" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475386306_ced29ee009_k.jpg" alt="Participants at Coolest Projects USA." class="wp-image-90067" style="width:722px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475386306_ced29ee009_k.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475386306_ced29ee009_k-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475386306_ced29ee009_k-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475386306_ced29ee009_k-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475386306_ced29ee009_k-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475386306_ced29ee009_k-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/54475386306_ced29ee009_k-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>There’s still time to get involved with Coolest Projects this year…</strong></h2>



<p>If you missed the event or are feeling inspired, there are still ways to join the Coolest Projects global community!</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>The online Coolest Projects showcase is open for entries from young people anywhere in the world. Entries close 28 May.</li>



<li>Coolest Projects UK takes place in Bradford on 17 May. Come along and discover what young people are creating.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<p>Partner events are held around the world — head to the <a href="https://online.coolestprojects.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Coolest Projects website</a> to find out more.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/celebrating-young-innovators-at-coolest-projects-usa/">Celebrating young innovators at Coolest Projects USA</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/celebrating-young-innovators-at-coolest-projects-usa/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Impact of Experience AI in Kenya</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/impact-of-experience-ai-in-kenya/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/impact-of-experience-ai-in-kenya/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Paul Akwabi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 12:03:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Experience AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kenya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Impact of our work]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=90017</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Today’s blog post is written by Paul Akwabi, Executive Director at Tech Kidz Africa, part of our global partner network for Experience AI. As artificial intelligence (AI) continues to reshape industries and redefine how we work and learn, it is essential that Kenyan educators are equipped with the knowledge and skills to introduce AI concepts&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/impact-of-experience-ai-in-kenya/">Impact of Experience AI in Kenya</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>Today’s blog post is written by Paul Akwabi, Executive Director at <a href="https://techkidzafrica.co.ke/">Tech Kidz Africa</a>, part of our global partner network for <a href="http://rpf.io/tka-blogpost" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Experience AI</a>.</em></p>



<p>As artificial intelligence (AI) continues to reshape industries and redefine how we work and learn, it is essential that Kenyan educators are equipped with the knowledge and skills to introduce AI concepts to their learners.</p>



<p>In Kenya, the education system has taken significant steps towards digital literacy through the Competency Based Curriculum (CBC), which has introduced young learners to coding using Scratch and laid a foundation for tech skills. However, AI is yet to be formally integrated into the curriculum. This has presented an opportunity to prepare teachers to integrate AI into their lessons and inspire the next generation of innovators.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="1066" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-4.jpeg" alt="An educator with students at the Experience AI workshop." class="wp-image-90023" style="width:718px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-4.jpeg 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-4-300x200.jpeg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-4-500x333.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-4-768x512.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-4-1536x1023.jpeg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-4-800x533.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-4-450x300.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-4-900x600.jpeg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How Experience AI has increased digital literacy</h2>



<p>Our partnership with the Raspberry Pi Foundation has been a vital element in the retooling of Kenyan educators. Using the Foundation’s <a href="http://rpf.io/tka-blogpost">Experience AI resources</a>, which they co-developed with Google DeepMind, we have equipped 441 teachers with practical AI and machine learning skills through hands-on training sessions in five counties: Mombasa, Nairobi, Taita Taveta, Meru, and Nakuru.</p>



<p>Our work to empower young learners with coding, robotics, and AI skills has positioned us as a key driver of digital literacy in Kenya. The Experience AI materials have helped us take key next steps — we’ve scaled up AI education, reached more teachers, and further democratised access to emerging technologies, supporting our goal of ensuring that no child is left behind in the digital revolution.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To make the delivery of our training sessions as smooth as possible, we’ve joined hands with county governments and local education authorities like the Teachers Service Commission (TSC). In all the counties we’ve been working in, the TSC are actively promoting digital literacy among teachers and have made sure we equip teachers with the understanding and skills to use AI effectively.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="956" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image.jpeg" alt="Learners using laptops during the Experience AI session. " class="wp-image-90019" style="width:722px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image.jpeg 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-300x179.jpeg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-500x299.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-768x459.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-1536x918.jpeg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-800x478.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-450x269.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-900x538.jpeg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure></div>


<p>Through our expert trainers, we’ve been able to offer hands-on introductions to AI concepts, provide opportunities for practical problem-solving with machine learning models, and expose participants to real-world AI applications. A great example of the work we’ve done is the training we gave to teachers in Meru County, where they learned to create an AI model that recognises certain food types in supermarkets. Later, in group sessions, participants developed their own diverse and innovative AI models. One group, for instance, designed an AI model for dishwashing that detects dirty dishes and automates the water removal process.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="1066" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-1.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-90020" style="width:728px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-1.jpeg 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-1-300x200.jpeg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-1-500x333.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-1-768x512.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-1-1536x1023.jpeg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-1-800x533.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-1-450x300.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-1-900x600.jpeg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Feedback from training</h2>



<p>Through the Experience AI training sessions, many educators gained new confidence and skills, and have already started to integrate AI into their classrooms.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;I am grateful for the invaluable skills gained through the Experience AI training. The knowledge I’ve acquired will not only enhance my ability to conduct research but also empower me to teach my students how to effectively use AI. This is just the beginning. I look forward to building on this foundation and exploring even greater possibilities with AI.&#8221; — <strong>Mr. Githinji, Meru, Kenya</strong></p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="1066" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-5.jpeg" alt="An educator with students at the Experience AI workshop." class="wp-image-90024" style="width:732px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-5.jpeg 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-5-300x200.jpeg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-5-500x333.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-5-768x512.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-5-1536x1023.jpeg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-5-800x533.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-5-450x300.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-5-900x600.jpeg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure></div>


<p>In any aspect of life, learning is about shifting perspectives, nurturing curiosity, and embracing new possibilities — this is what drives innovation. The Experience AI training in Kenya has exemplified this, transforming how we think and approach technology.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I am glad that my county has been considered in this training. I challenge the teachers here to make use of these useful resources to spice up learning in the classroom. I was once a mathematics teacher and I wish I had technology to teach. Thank you Tech Kidz Africa, Raspberry Pi Foundation and Google DeepMind for empowering these teachers.” <strong>— His Excellency Andrew Mwadime, Governor Taita Taveta County</strong></p>
</blockquote>



<p>The overwhelming enthusiasm from educators and learners is evidence that the Experience AI lessons have been highly impactful. Teachers have expressed a strong desire for more training opportunities to support them in equipping students for the future. Many of the teachers have also expressed how the training has demystified AI, enhancing accessibility and giving their daily teaching added relevance. In addition, there is a clear call to scale up these efforts to reach more teachers across the counties in Kenya to ensure that AI education is widespread and inclusive.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="1066" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-3.jpeg" alt="A group of students holding the Experience AI certificates." class="wp-image-90022" style="width:734px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-3.jpeg 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-3-300x200.jpeg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-3-500x333.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-3-768x512.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-3-1536x1023.jpeg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-3-800x533.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-3-450x300.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/05/image-3-900x600.jpeg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure></div>


<p>Experience AI is bringing a unique AI experience to teachers, helping ease fears that AI might render them obsolete or take away their jobs. Educators are excited to explore how AI algorithms work and how they can train them for the benefit of both themselves and their students. They recognise that AI can help create an equal playing field, offering tools worldwide that can showcase and accentuate their talents, capabilities, and skill sets.</p>



<p><em>If you’re interested in finding out more about the Experience AI resources, <a href="http://rpf.io/tka-blogpost" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">visit the  Experience AI  website</a>.</em></p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/impact-of-experience-ai-in-kenya/">Impact of Experience AI in Kenya</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/impact-of-experience-ai-in-kenya/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Should we ditch the term ‘digital native’? The latest conversation on the podcast</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/should-we-ditch-the-term-digital-native-the-latest-conversation-on-the-podcast/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/should-we-ditch-the-term-digital-native-the-latest-conversation-on-the-podcast/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Meg Wang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 11:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hello World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital native]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89993</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The term ‘digital native’ was coined in 2001 to describe young people who grew up surrounded by technology, implying they possess an almost instinctive understanding of digital tools. But how accurate is that label today? Are they truly tech-savvy, or are they simply fluent in using user-friendly devices without a deeper understanding of how they&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/should-we-ditch-the-term-digital-native-the-latest-conversation-on-the-podcast/">Should we ditch the term ‘digital native’? The latest conversation on the podcast</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The term ‘digital native’ was coined in 2001 to describe young people who grew up surrounded by technology, implying they possess an almost instinctive understanding of digital tools. But how accurate is that label today? Are they truly tech-savvy, or are they simply fluent in using user-friendly devices without a deeper understanding of how they work?&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/26.4a-Digital-natives-black-background-2-500x281.png" alt="Thumbnail titled 'Are young people really tech-savvy?'" class="wp-image-90000" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/26.4a-Digital-natives-black-background-2-500x281.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/26.4a-Digital-natives-black-background-2-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/26.4a-Digital-natives-black-background-2-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/26.4a-Digital-natives-black-background-2-1536x864.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/26.4a-Digital-natives-black-background-2-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/26.4a-Digital-natives-black-background-2-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/26.4a-Digital-natives-black-background-2-900x506.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/26.4a-Digital-natives-black-background-2.png 1920w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>In our <a href="http://rpf.io/hwp-digitalnative-podcastlinkblog" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">latest podcast episode</a>, we explore this crucial question: does growing up with technology automatically make someone digitally literate, or just digitally dependent?</p>



<p>Host James Robinson (Raspberry Pi Foundation) is joined by colleague Sway Grantham, Anna Lahtinen (Haaga-Helia University), and Nicole O’Connor (Digi Know This) to unpack the complexities of digital skills, access, and education, and to explore how the label of digital native can sometimes hide broader challenges.</p>



<p>This episode wraps up our three-part mini-series on digital literacy. Each episode builds on the conversations from the latest issue of <em>Hello World</em> magazine, offering expert insight and practical ideas from educators driving real change.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Who are the guests on the podcast, and what will I learn?</h2>



<p>We’ve assembled a panel of expert guests to discuss and debate the concept of the digital native.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="500" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-6-500x500.png" alt="Square headshot of Anna Lahtinen who featured on the Hello World podcast." class="wp-image-89994" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-6-500x500.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-6-250x250.png 250w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-6-150x150.png 150w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-6-768x768.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-6-800x800.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-6-100x100.png 100w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-6-300x300.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-6-450x450.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-6-900x900.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-6.png 1080w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><strong>Anna Lahtinen, Haaga-Helia University of Applied Sciences</strong></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Anna is an internationally recognised scholar who specialises in the transformative effects of artificial intelligence (AI) on working life, businesses, and careers. <strong>In the latest issue of <em><a href="http://rpf.io/blog-hwp-digital-native" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hello World</a></em>, Anna and her colleague Antonia O’Connell write about assumptions regarding high digital literacy among youth in the setting of a work environment.</strong></p>



<p><a href="http://rpf.io/hwp-digitalnative-podcastlinkblog" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">In the podcast</a>, Anna explains that the term <em>‘digital native&#8217;</em> can be useful for starting conversations about the skills, access, and confidence people need to navigate technology, particularly in the workplace. However, she warns that the term can be misleading, as it often assumes that young people have strong digital skills, when many struggle with the practical demands of using technology at work.</p>



<p>Anna also highlights the importance of supporting young people to use technology responsibly and develop a healthy relationship with it. As she puts it: </p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>“If we instil the right values in students, that will eventually lead to a healthy relationship with technology and ethical use of new tools in both their work and their lives.”</em></p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="500" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-7-500x500.png" alt="Square headshot of Nicole O'Connor who featured on the Hello World podcast." class="wp-image-89995" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-7-500x500.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-7-250x250.png 250w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-7-150x150.png 150w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-7-768x768.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-7-800x800.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-7-100x100.png 100w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-7-300x300.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-7-450x450.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-7-900x900.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-7.png 1080w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><strong>Nicole O’Connor, Digi Know This</strong></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Nicole O’Connor is a two-time female founder who brings her expertise to improving teaching and learning through innovative EdTech, digital literacy, and accessibility.</p>



<p><a href="http://rpf.io/hwp-digitalnative-podcastlinkblog" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">In the podcast</a>, Nicole challenges the idea of the<em> </em>digital native<em>,</em> calling it both problematic and overly simplistic. She explains that the term overlooks important differences, like access, privilege, and levels of exposure to technology, which all shape a person’s digital skills. For Nicole, it’s a <em>“grey area”</em> that proves we can’t assume young people are automatically tech-savvy just because they grew up with devices.</p>



<p>Nicole sees digital literacy as a journey, not something people are born with. She compares it to learning a language: while young people may be familiar with technology, they still need to develop deeper skills to become critical thinkers, careful users, and aware of issues like data privacy and online safety. As she puts it:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>“They might have had some exposure, but over time they need to learn the skills to be digitally literate… They’re not even close to that.”</em></p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Listen or watch now</strong></h2>



<p>To hear more, listen to or watch the full episode.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="http://rpf.io/hwp-digitalnatives-listenbuttonblog" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Listen or watch here</a></div>
</div>



<p>You can watch or listen to each episode of our podcast on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLxyaWvsfmq49s-6lJKH1sNcYAeBUizoMr">YouTube</a>, or listen via your preferred audio streaming service, whether that’s <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/hello-world/id1564031383">Apple Podcasts</a>, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/1CagYUqVlkJK9zRN6yaQwG">Spotify</a>, or <a href="https://music.amazon.com/podcasts/7954c4f7-884c-4a91-90e3-1fbd3fdc4ff3/hello-world">Amazon Music</a>. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>You’ve listened to the podcast, now subscribe to the magazine</strong></h2>



<p>We hope this episode, along with the others in the series, inspires you and helps you to engage your students more in computing. In the comments section below, we’d love to hear your thoughts and experience around digital literacy.</p>



<p>The latest issue of Hello World magazine features more insightful articles on digital literacy. Don’t miss out on this discussion — <a href="http://rpf.io/hwp-digitalnatives-subscribeblog" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to Hello World</a> today to ensure you never miss a podcast episode or issue of the magazine.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="http://rpf.io/hwp-digitalnatives-subscribeblog" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Subscribe</a></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/should-we-ditch-the-term-digital-native-the-latest-conversation-on-the-podcast/">Should we ditch the term ‘digital native’? The latest conversation on the podcast</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/should-we-ditch-the-term-digital-native-the-latest-conversation-on-the-podcast/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
