<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Raspberry Pi Foundation</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/</link>
	<description>Teach, learn and make with Raspberry Pi</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 13:28:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/06/cropped-raspberrry_pi_logo-100x100.png</url>
	<title>Raspberry Pi Foundation</title>
	<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Teaching about AI &#8211; Teacher symposium</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teaching-about-ai-teacher-symposium/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teaching-about-ai-teacher-symposium/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jane Waite]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 13:28:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[event]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teaching]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89514</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>AI has become a pervasive term that is heard with trepidation, excitement, and often a furrowed brow in school staffrooms. For educators, there is pressure to use AI applications for productivity — to save time, to help create lesson plans, to write reports, to answer emails, etc. There is also a lot of interest in&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teaching-about-ai-teacher-symposium/">Teaching about AI &#8211; Teacher symposium</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>AI has become a pervasive term that is heard with trepidation, excitement, and often a furrowed brow in school staffrooms. For educators, there is pressure to use AI applications for productivity — to save time, to help create lesson plans, to write reports, to answer emails, etc. There is also a lot of interest in using AI tools in the classroom, for example, to personalise or augment teaching and learning. However, without understanding AI technology, neither productivity nor personalisation are likely to be successful as teachers and students alike must be critical consumers of these new ways of working to be able to use them productively.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-45-500x333.jpg" alt="Fifty teachers and researchers posing for a photo at the AI Symposium, held at the Raspberry Pi Foundation office." class="wp-image-89515" style="width:500px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-45-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-45-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-45-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-45-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-45-2048x1366.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-45-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-45-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-45-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Fifty teachers and researchers share knowledge about teaching about AI.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>In both England and globally, there are few new AI-based curricula being introduced and the drive for teachers and students to learn about AI in schools is lagging, with limited initiatives supporting teachers in what to teach and how to teach it. At the Raspberry Pi Foundation and Raspberry Pi Computing Education Research Centre, we decided it was time to investigate this missing link of teaching about AI, and specifically to discover what the teachers who are leading the way in this topic are doing in their classrooms.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>A day of sharing and activities in Cambridge</strong></h2>



<p>We organised a day-long, face-to-face symposium with educators who have already started to think deeply about teaching about AI, have started to create teaching resources, and are starting to teach about AI in their classrooms. The event was held in Cambridge, England, on 1 February 2025, at the head office of the Raspberry Pi Foundation.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-32-500x333.jpg" alt="Photo of educators and researchers collaborating at the AI symposium." class="wp-image-89521" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-32-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-32-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-32-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-32-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-32-2048x1366.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-32-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-32-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-32-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Teachers collaborated and shared their knowledge about teaching about AI.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Over 150 educators and researchers applied to take part in the symposium. With only 50 places available, we followed a detailed protocol, whereby those who had the most experience teaching about AI in schools were selected. We also made sure that educators and researchers from different teaching contexts were selected so that there was a good mix of primary to further education phases represented. Educators and researchers from England, Scotland, and the Republic of Ireland were invited and gathered to share about their experiences. One of our main aims was to build a community of early adopters who have started along the road of classroom-based AI curriculum design and delivery.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Inspiration, examples, and expertise</strong></h2>



<p>To inspire the attendees with an international perspective of the topics being discussed, Professor Matti Tedre, a visiting academic from Finland, gave a brief overview of the approach to teaching about AI and resources that his research team have developed. In Finland, there is no compulsory distinct computing topic taught, so AI is taught about in other subjects, such as history. Matti showcased tools and approaches developed from the <a href="https://generation-ai.eu/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Generation AI research</a> programme in Finland. You can read about the Finnish research programme and Matti’s two month visit to the Raspberry Pi Computing Education Research Centre in our <a href="https://computingeducationresearch.org/blog-developing-a-new-ai-generation-in-finland/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">blog</a>. </p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-04-500x333.jpg" alt="Photo of a researcher presenting at the AI Symposium." class="wp-image-89516" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-04-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-04-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-04-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-04-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-04-2048x1366.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-04-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-04-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-04-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">A Finnish perspective to teaching about AI.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Attendees were asked to talk about, share, and analyse their teaching materials. To model how to analyse resources, Ben Garside from the Raspberry Pi Foundation modelled how to complete the activities using the <a href="https://experience-ai.org/en/units/ai-safety/?utm_source=partner-marketing&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;utm_campaign=expai-safety&amp;utm_id=Experience+AI&amp;utm_content=CC" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Experience AI resources</a> as an example. The Experience AI materials have been co-created with Google DeepMind and are a suite of free classroom resources, teacher professional development, and hands-on activities designed to help teachers confidently deliver AI lessons. Aimed at learners aged 11 to 14, the materials are informed by the AI education framework developed at the Raspberry Pi Computing Education Research Centre and are grounded in real-world contexts. We’ve recently released new lessons on AI safety, and we’ve <a href="https://experience-ai.org/en/partners/?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;utm_campaign=expai-Q1&amp;utm_id=Experience+AI&amp;utm_content=AI-symposium" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">localised the resources for use in many countries</a> including Africa, Asia, Europe, and North America.</p>



<p>In the morning session, Ben exemplified how to talk about and share learning objectives, concepts, and research underpinning materials using the Experience AI resources and in the afternoon he discussed how he had mapped the <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-unesco-ai-competency-framework/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Experience AI materials to the UNESCO AI competency framework for students</a>.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-47-500x333.jpg" alt="Photo of an adult presenting at the AI Symposium." class="wp-image-89517" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-47-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-47-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-47-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-47-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-47-2048x1366.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-47-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-47-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-47-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">UNESCO provide important expertise.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Kelly Shiohira, from UNESCO, kindly attended our session, and gave an invaluable insight into the <a href="https://www.unesco.org/en/articles/ai-competency-framework-students" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">UNESCO AI competency framework for students</a>. Kelly is one of the framework&#8217;s authors and her presentation helped teachers understand how the materials had been developed. The attendees then used the framework to analyse their resources, to identify gaps and to explore what progression might look like in the teaching of AI.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-29-500x333.jpg" alt="Photo of a whiteboard featuring different coloured post-it notes displayed featuring teachers' and researchers' ideas." class="wp-image-89518" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-29-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-29-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-29-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-29-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-29-2048x1366.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-29-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-29-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/AI-research-summit-29-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Teachers shared their knowledge about teaching about AI.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p><br>Throughout the day, the teachers worked together to share their experience of teaching about AI. They considered the concepts and learning objectives taught, what progression might look like, what the challenges and opportunities were of teaching about AI, what research informed the resources and what research needs to be done to help improve the teaching and learning of AI.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What next?</strong></h2>



<p>We are now analysing the vast amount of data that we gathered from the day and we will share this with the symposium participants before we share it with a wider audience. What is clear from our symposium is that teachers have crucial insights into what should be taught to students about AI, and how, and we are greatly looking forward to continuing this journey with them.</p>



<p>As well as the symposium, we are also conducting academic research in this area, you can read more about this in our <a href="https://computingeducationresearch.org/blog-annual-report-24/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Annual Report</a> and on our <a href="https://computingeducationresearch.org/projects/?project_categories=ai-education-for-young-people" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">research webpages</a>. We will also be consulting with teachers and AI experts. If you’d like to ensure you are sent links to these blog posts, then <a href="https://computingeducationresearch.org/stayintouch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up to our newsletter</a>. If you’d like to take part in our research and potentially be interviewed about your perspectives on curriculum in AI, then contact us at: <a href="mailto:rpcerc-enquiries@cst.cam.ac.uk">rpcerc-enquiries@cst.cam.ac.uk</a> </p>



<p>We also are sharing the research being done by ourselves and other researchers in the field at our research seminars. This year, our seminar series is on teaching about AI and data science in schools. Please do <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research/seminars">sign up</a> and come along, or watch some of the presentations that have already been delivered by the amazing research teams who are endeavouring to discover what we should be teaching about AI and how in schools</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teaching-about-ai-teacher-symposium/">Teaching about AI &#8211; Teacher symposium</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teaching-about-ai-teacher-symposium/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Code Club: Empowering the Next Generation of Digital Creators</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-club-empowering-the-next-generation-of-digital-creators/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-club-empowering-the-next-generation-of-digital-creators/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sophie Ashford]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 11:25:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Code Club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding for kids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mentorship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89484</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Code Club is more than just a place to learn coding — it’s a thriving global community where young minds discover, create, and grow with technology. With a refreshed look and ambitious goals for 2025, Code Club is set to connect an even larger network of mentors and reach millions more young people worldwide. Since&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-club-empowering-the-next-generation-of-digital-creators/">Code Club: Empowering the Next Generation of Digital Creators</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Code Club is more than just a place to learn coding — it’s a thriving global community where young minds discover, create, and grow with technology. With a refreshed look and ambitious goals for 2025, Code Club is set to connect an even larger network of mentors and reach millions more young people worldwide.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="800" height="533" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/CC-_-Primary-school-image.jpg" alt="Code Club at RPF HQ, Cambridge" class="wp-image-89485" style="width:736px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/CC-_-Primary-school-image.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/CC-_-Primary-school-image-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/CC-_-Primary-school-image-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/CC-_-Primary-school-image-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/CC-_-Primary-school-image-450x300.jpg 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Code Club at RPF HQ, Cambridge</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Since it was founded in the UK in 2012, <a href="https://codeclub.org/">Code Club</a> has grown into a global movement, inspiring over two million young people to build apps, games, animations, websites, and more. Supported by the Raspberry Pi Foundation, Code Club provides free training and resources to mentors, ensuring creators achieve meaningful and lasting skills. Our vision for the next decade? To empower ten million more young people to have confidence in their coding.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>A proven impact</strong></h2>



<p>A <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-fun-filled-code-clubs-drive-learning-new-evidence/">recent independent evaluation</a> by the Durham University Evidence Centre for Education (DECE) confirmed what we’ve always believed: Code Club makes a real difference. Young people who attend gain valuable coding skills, grow in confidence, develop a strong interest in technology, and find a sense of belonging in the digital world.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="800" height="450" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Sahibjots-story-13.jpg" alt="Mentor Rajan at his Code Club in India" class="wp-image-89486" style="width:740px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Sahibjots-story-13.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Sahibjots-story-13-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Sahibjots-story-13-500x281.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Sahibjots-story-13-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Sahibjots-story-13-450x253.jpg 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Mentor Rajan at his Code Club in India</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The power of mentorship</strong></h2>



<p>At the heart of Code Club are passionate volunteers who bring coding to life. Whether it’s the thrill of overcoming a challenge or the excitement of seeing an idea come to life on screen, mentors make a lasting impact while learning coding skills alongside their club’s creators.</p>



<p>Bob Bilsland, a dedicated volunteer since 2012, runs one of the world&#8217;s longest-running Code Clubs at Malvern CofE Primary School, Worcestershire, England. His motivation?</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“What brings me back week after week is the sharing of what I enjoy doing. It’s so much fun to help others explore this space themselves, to see what they can personally create. I see that giving others the opportunity to explore and familiarise themselves with computing as something that could open up a world of possibilities for them in the future.”&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>For Yang, a mentor at the EY office clubs, representation in tech is key:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“If there are some female role models, I think for a little girl growing up, that means so much. Because if they can see somebody thrive in this industry, they will see themselves there one day. And that’s the inspiration.”&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="800" height="450" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/YANG-EY-04.jpg" alt="Mentor Yang at her Code Club in London" class="wp-image-89487" style="width:740px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/YANG-EY-04.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/YANG-EY-04-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/YANG-EY-04-500x281.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/YANG-EY-04-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/YANG-EY-04-450x253.jpg 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Mentor Yang at her Code Club in London</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Across the world, volunteers like Nadia in Iraq and Solomon in The Gambia are using Code Club to bridge the digital divide, create opportunities, and empower communities.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“[Code Club] added to my skills. And at the same time, I was able to share my expertise with the young children and to learn from them as well.” &#8211; Nadia Al-Aboody, Iraq.</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“We strongly believe in the transformative power of digital skills and their potential to create opportunities for young people. Witnessing the lack of access to computer knowledge among high school graduates in The Gambia and other sub-Saharan African countries inspired us to take action. By bridging the digital skills gap, we aim to empower young individuals to thrive in the 21st century.” &#8211; Solomon, Gambia&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>A community that inspires</strong></h2>



<p>Code Club isn’t just loved by mentors; it’s so important to the young people who participate.</p>



<p>Eoghan, a young creator from Ireland, values the collaboration and support he receives:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“It’s really fun to meet and talk about ideas with other creators, and the mentors are very helpful in fixing any coding problems.”&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="800" height="450" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Jayantika-Bidkar-Photo-1.jpg" alt="Mentor Jayantika at her Code Club in Pune, India" class="wp-image-89506" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Jayantika-Bidkar-Photo-1.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Jayantika-Bidkar-Photo-1-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Jayantika-Bidkar-Photo-1-500x281.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Jayantika-Bidkar-Photo-1-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Jayantika-Bidkar-Photo-1-450x253.jpg 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Mentor Jayantika at her Code Club in Pune, India</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Jayantika, a 15-year-old from rural Pune, India, started as a creator and is now a peer mentor. For her, Code Club is about giving back:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I believe coding opens doors and helps young children express their creativity. By mentoring, I hope to prepare them for a future that is increasingly driven by AI and technology.”&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Join the movement</strong></h2>



<p>Along with the incredible community, Code Club is supported by sponsors and funders who share our mission. We would like to extend a thank you to Cognizant, who have committed their support to the Code Club mission in the UK and Ireland for 2025.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="800" height="600" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/IMG_1122-1.jpg" alt="Mentors gathering at Clubs Con 2024" class="wp-image-89488" style="width:744px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/IMG_1122-1.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/IMG_1122-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/IMG_1122-1-500x375.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/IMG_1122-1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/IMG_1122-1-450x338.jpg 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Mentors gathering at Clubs Con 2024</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Code Club is more than just learning to code; it’s about creating opportunities, encouraging confidence, and building a global network of digital creators. Whether you&#8217;re a mentor, educator, or young digital maker, there’s a place for you in our community.&nbsp;<a href="https://codeclub.org/">Start your Code Club</a> journey today and join a global community of digital creators.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-club-empowering-the-next-generation-of-digital-creators/">Code Club: Empowering the Next Generation of Digital Creators</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-club-empowering-the-next-generation-of-digital-creators/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Teaching about AI in K–12 education: Thoughts from the USA</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teaching-about-ai-in-k-12-education-thoughts-from-the-usa/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teaching-about-ai-in-k-12-education-thoughts-from-the-usa/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katharine Childs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 11:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research seminar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI in education]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89462</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As artificial intelligence continues to shape our world, understanding how to teach about AI has never been more important. Our new research seminar series brings together educators and researchers to explore approaches to AI and data science education. In the first seminar, we welcomed Shuchi Grover, Director of AI and Education Research at Looking Glass&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teaching-about-ai-in-k-12-education-thoughts-from-the-usa/">Teaching about AI in K–12 education: Thoughts from the USA</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As artificial intelligence continues to shape our world, understanding how to teach <strong>about</strong> AI has never been more important. Our <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-can-we-teach-students-about-ai-and-data-science-2025-seminar-series/">new research seminar series</a> brings together educators and researchers to explore approaches to AI and data science education. In the first seminar, we welcomed <a href="https://www.shuchigrover.com/">Shuchi Grover</a>, Director of AI and Education Research at Looking Glass Ventures. Shuchi began by exploring the theme of teaching using AI, then moved on to discussing teaching about AI in K–12 (primary and secondary) education. She emphasised that it is crucial to teach about AI before using it in the classroom, and this blog post will focus on her insights in this area.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="784" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image.png" alt="Shuchi Grover gave an insightful talk discussing how to teach about AI in K–12 education." class="wp-image-89463" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image.png 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-300x147.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-500x245.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-768x376.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-1536x753.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-800x392.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-450x221.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-900x441.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Shuchi Grover gave an insightful talk discussing how to teach about AI in K–12 education.</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading">An AI literacy framework</h2>



<p>From her research, Shuchi has developed a framework for teaching about AI that is structured as four interlocking components, each representing a key area of understanding:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Basic understanding of AI</strong>, which refers to foundational knowledge such as what AI is, types of AI systems, and the capabilities of AI technologies</li>



<li><strong>Ethics and human–AI relationship</strong>, which includes the role of humans in regard to AI, ethical considerations, and public perceptions of AI</li>



<li><strong>Computational thinking/literacy</strong>, which relates to how AI works, including building AI applications and training machine learning models</li>



<li><strong>Data literacy</strong>, which addresses the importance of data, including examining data features, data visualisation, and biases</li>
</ul>



<p>This framework shows the multifaceted nature of AI literacy, which involves an understanding of both technical aspects and ethical and societal considerations.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1366" height="776" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-1.png" alt="Shuchi’s framework for teaching about AI includes four broad areas." class="wp-image-89464" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-1.png 1366w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-1-300x170.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-1-500x284.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-1-768x436.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-1-800x454.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-1-450x256.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-1-900x511.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1366px) 100vw, 1366px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Shuchi’s framework for teaching about AI includes four broad areas.</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Shuchi emphasised the importance of learning about AI ethics, highlighting the topic of bias. There are many ways that <a href="https://www.weforum.org/stories/2021/07/ai-machine-learning-bias-discrimination/">bias can be embedded in applications of AI and machine learning</a>, including through the data sets that are used and the design of machine learning models. Shuchi discussed supporting learners to engage with the topic through exploring bias in facial recognition software, sharing activities and resources to use in the classroom that can prompt meaningful discussion, such as <a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/joy_buolamwini_how_i_m_fighting_bias_in_algorithms">this talk by Joy Buolamwini</a>. She also highlighted the Kapor Foundation’s <a href="https://kaporfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/Responsible-AI-Guide-Kapor-Foundation.pdf"><em>Responsible AI and Tech Justice: A Guide for K–12 Education</em></a>, which contains questions that educators can use with learners to help them to carefully consider the ethical implications of AI for themselves and for society.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Computational thinking and AI</h2>



<p>In computer science education, <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/computational-thinking-skills-in-our-free-learning-resources/">computational thinking</a> is generally associated with traditional rule-based programming — it has often been used to describe the problem-solving approaches and processes associated with writing computer programs following rule-based principles in a structured and logical way. However, with the emergence of machine learning, Shuchi described a need for computational thinking frameworks to be expanded to also encompass data-driven, probabilistic approaches, which are foundational for machine learning. This would support learners’ understanding and ability to work with the models that increasingly influence modern technology.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2560" height="1709" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_029-scaled.jpg" alt="A group of young people and educators smiling while engaging with a computer." class="wp-image-63316" style="width:719px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_029-scaled.jpg 2560w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_029-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_029-768x513.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_029-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_029-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_029-2048x1367.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_029-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_029-scaled-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_029-scaled-900x601.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Example activities from research studies</h2>



<p>Shuchi shared that a variety of pedagogies have been used in recent research projects on AI education, ranging from hands-on experiences, such as using APIs for classification, to discussions focusing on ethical aspects. You can find out more about these pedagogies in her award-winning paper <a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/abs/10.1145/3626252.3630937"><em>Teaching AI to K-12 Learners: Lessons, Issues and Guidance</em></a>. This plurality of approaches ensures that learners can engage with AI and machine learning in ways that are both accessible and meaningful to them.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1386" height="764" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-2.png" alt="Research projects exploring teaching about AI and machine learning have involved a range of different approaches." class="wp-image-89465" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-2.png 1386w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-2-300x165.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-2-500x276.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-2-768x423.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-2-800x441.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-2-450x248.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-2-900x496.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1386px) 100vw, 1386px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Research projects exploring teaching about AI and machine learning have involved a range of different approaches.</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Shuchi shared examples of activities from two research projects that she has led:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><a href="https://csfrontiers.org/">CS Frontiers</a> engaged high school students in a number of activities involving using <a href="https://netsblox.org/">NetsBlox</a> and accessing real-world data sets. For example, in one activity, students participated in data science activities such as creating data visualisations to answer questions about climate change.&nbsp;</li>



<li><a href="https://cyberai4k12.org/resources/">AI &amp; Cybersecurity for Teens</a> explored approaches to teaching AI and machine learning to 13- to 15-year-olds through the use of cybersecurity scenarios. The project aimed to provide learners with insights into how machine learning models are designed, how they work, and how human decisions influence their development. An example activity guided students through building a classification model to analyse social media accounts to determine whether they may be bot accounts or accounts run by a human.</li>
</ul>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1398" height="766" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-3.png" alt="A screenshot from an activity to classify social media accounts " class="wp-image-89466" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-3.png 1398w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-3-300x164.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-3-500x274.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-3-768x421.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-3-800x438.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-3-450x247.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-3-900x493.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1398px) 100vw, 1398px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>A screenshot from an activity to classify social media accounts&nbsp;</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Closing thoughts</h2>



<p>At the end of her talk, Shuchi shared some final thoughts addressing teaching about AI to K–12 learners:&nbsp;</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>AI learning requires contextualisation:</strong> Think about the data sets, ethical issues, and examples of AI tools and systems you use to ensure that they are relatable to learners in your context.</li>



<li><strong>AI should not be a solution in search of a problem: </strong>Both teachers and learners need to be educated about AI before they start to use it in the classroom, so that they are informed consumers.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Join our next seminar</h2>



<p>In our current seminar series, we are exploring teaching about AI and data science. Join us at our next seminar on Tuesday 11 March at 17:00–18:30 GMT to hear Lukas Höper and Carsten Schulte from Paderborn University discuss supporting middle school students to develop their data awareness.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To sign up and take part in the seminar, click the button below — we will then send you information about joining. We hope to see you there.</p>



<p><a href="https://form.raspberrypi.org/f/research-seminar-sign-up">I want to join the next seminar</a>The <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research/seminars">schedule of our upcoming seminars</a> is online. You can catch up on past seminars on our <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research/seminars/previous">previous seminars and recordings page</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teaching-about-ai-in-k-12-education-thoughts-from-the-usa/">Teaching about AI in K–12 education: Thoughts from the USA</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teaching-about-ai-in-k-12-education-thoughts-from-the-usa/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Teaching AI safety: Lessons from Romanian educators</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teaching-ai-safety-lessons-from-romanian-educators/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teaching-ai-safety-lessons-from-romanian-educators/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elena Coman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 11:23:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Experience AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Romania]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital literacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI Safety]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89420</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This blog post has been written by our Experience AI partners in Romania, Asociatia Techsoup, who piloted our new AI safety resources with Romanian teachers at the end of 2024. Last year, we had the opportunity to pedagogically test the new three resources on AI safety and see first-hand the transformative effect they have on&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teaching-ai-safety-lessons-from-romanian-educators/">Teaching AI safety: Lessons from Romanian educators</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>This blog post has been written by our Experience AI partners in Romania, Asociatia Techsoup, who piloted our new AI safety resources with Romanian teachers at the end of 2024.</em></p>



<p>Last year, we had the opportunity to pedagogically test the <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://rpf.io/aisafetyromania&amp;sa=D&amp;source=docs&amp;ust=1739266952603847&amp;usg=AOvVaw3uHdSrHQWZpneWSErmfHME" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new three resources on AI safety</a> and see first-hand the transformative effect they have on teachers and students. Here’s what we found.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="900" height="600" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/18-IMG_5575-Enhanced-NR.jpg" alt="Students in class." class="wp-image-89432" style="width:753px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/18-IMG_5575-Enhanced-NR.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/18-IMG_5575-Enhanced-NR-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/18-IMG_5575-Enhanced-NR-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/18-IMG_5575-Enhanced-NR-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/18-IMG_5575-Enhanced-NR-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/18-IMG_5575-Enhanced-NR-450x300.jpg 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 900px) 100vw, 900px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Romania struggles with the digital skills gap</strong></h2>



<p>To say the internet is ubiquitous in Romania is an understatement: Romania has one of the fastest internets in the world (<a href="https://www.speedtest.net/global-index">11th place</a>), an impressive mobile internet penetration (<a href="https://www.statista.com/forecasts/1168913/mobile-internet-penetration-in-europe-by-country">86% of the population</a>), and Romania is leading Central and Eastern Europe in terms of percentage of population that is online (89% of the entire population). Unsurprisingly, most of Romania’s internet users are also social media users.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When you combine that with recent national initiatives, such as</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>The introduction of Information Technology and Informatics in the middle-school curriculum in 2017 as a compulsory subject</li>



<li>A Digital Agenda as a national strategy since 2015&nbsp;</li>



<li>Allocation of over 20% of its most recent National Recovery and Resilience Fund for digital transition</li>
</ul>



<p>one might expect a similar lead in digital skills, both basic and advanced.</p>



<p>But only 28% of the population, well below the 56% EU average, and just 47% of young people between 16 and 24 have basic digital skills — the lowest percentage in the European Union.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Findings from the latest International Computer and Information Literacy Study (<a href="https://www.iea.nl/sites/default/files/2024-11/ICILS_2023_International_Report_0.pdf">ICILS, 2023</a>)&nbsp; underscore the urgent need to improve young people&#8217;s digital skills. Just 4% of students in Romania were scored at level 3 of 4, meaning they can demonstrate the capacity to work independently when using computers as information gathering and management tools, and are able, for example, to recognise that the credibility of web‐based information can be influenced by the identity, expertise, and motives of the people who create, publish, and share it.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="900" height="600" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/72-IMG_5648-Enhanced-NR.jpg" alt="Students use a computer in class." class="wp-image-89436" style="width:755px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/72-IMG_5648-Enhanced-NR.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/72-IMG_5648-Enhanced-NR-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/72-IMG_5648-Enhanced-NR-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/72-IMG_5648-Enhanced-NR-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/72-IMG_5648-Enhanced-NR-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/72-IMG_5648-Enhanced-NR-450x300.jpg 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 900px) 100vw, 900px" /></figure></div>


<p>Furthermore, 33% of students were assessed as level 1, while a further 40% of students did not even reach the minimum level set out in the ICILS, which means that they are unable to demonstrate even basic operational skills with computers or an understanding of computers as tools for completing simple tasks. For example, they can’t use computers to perform routine research and communication tasks under explicit instruction, and can’t manage simple content creation, such as entering text or images into pre‐existing templates.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Why we wanted to pilot the Experience AI safety resources</strong></h2>



<p>Add AI — and particularly generative AI — to this mix, and it spells huge trouble for educational systems unprepared for the fast rate of AI adoption by their students. Teachers need to be given the right pedagogical tools and support to address these new disruptions and the AI-related challenges that are adding to the existing post-pandemic ones.</p>



<p>This is why we at <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.asociatiatechsoup.ro/&amp;sa=D&amp;source=docs&amp;ust=1739266952604023&amp;usg=AOvVaw0Ff6FeyWcEeeLgIau7RsN0" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Asociația Techsoup</a> have been enthusiastically supporting Romanian teachers to deliver the Experience AI curriculum created by the Raspberry Pi Foundation and Google DeepMind. We have found it to be the best pedagogical support that prepares students to fully understand AI and to learn how to use machine learning to solve real-world problems.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Testing the resources</strong></h2>



<p>Last year, we had the opportunity to pedagogically test the new three resources on AI Safety and see first-hand the transformative effect they have on teachers and students.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="900" height="600" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/297-IMG_5959.jpg" alt="Students in class." class="wp-image-89439" style="width:756px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/297-IMG_5959.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/297-IMG_5959-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/297-IMG_5959-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/297-IMG_5959-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/297-IMG_5959-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/297-IMG_5959-450x300.jpg 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 900px) 100vw, 900px" /></figure></div>


<p>We worked closely with 8 computer science teachers in 8 Romanian schools from rural and small urban areas, reaching approximately 340 students between the ages of 13 and 18.</p>



<p>Before the teachers used the resources in the classroom, we worked with them in online community meetings and one-to-one phone conversations to help them review the available lesson plans, videos, and activity guides, to familiarise themselves with the structure, and to plan how to adapt the sessions to their classroom context.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In December 2024, the teachers delivered the resources to their students. They guided students through key topics in AI safety, including understanding how to protect their data, critically evaluating data to spot fake news, and how to use AI tools responsibly. Each session incorporated a dynamic mix of teaching methods, including short videos and presentations delivering core messages, unplugged activities to reinforce understanding, and structured discussions to encourage critical thinking and reflection.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Gathering feedback from users</strong></h2>



<p>We then interviewed all the teachers to understand their challenges in delivering such a new curriculum and we also observed two of the lessons. We took time to discuss with students and gather in-depth feedback on their learning experiences, perspectives on AI safety, and their overall engagement with the activities, in focus groups and surveys.</p>



<p>Feedback gathered in this pilot was then incorporated into the resources and recommendations given to teachers as part of the AI safety materials.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Teachers’ perspectives on the resources</strong></h2>



<p>It became obvious quite fast for both us and our teachers that the AI safety resources cover a growing and unaddressed need: to prepare our students for the ubiquitous presence of AI tools, which are on the road to becoming as ubiquitous as the internet itself.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="900" height="600" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/241-IMG_5875-Enhanced-NR.jpg" alt="A teacher and students in class." class="wp-image-89441" style="width:760px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/241-IMG_5875-Enhanced-NR.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/241-IMG_5875-Enhanced-NR-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/241-IMG_5875-Enhanced-NR-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/241-IMG_5875-Enhanced-NR-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/241-IMG_5875-Enhanced-NR-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/241-IMG_5875-Enhanced-NR-450x300.jpg 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 900px) 100vw, 900px" /></figure></div>


<p>Teachers evaluated the resources as very effective, giving them the opportunity to have authentic and meaningful conversations with their students about the world we live in. The format of the lessons was engaging — one of the teachers was so enthusiastic that she actually managed to keep students away from their phones for the whole lesson.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They also appreciated the pedagogical quality of the resources, especially the fact that everything is ready to use in class and that they could access them for free. In interviews, they also appreciated that they themselves also learnt a lot from the lessons:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“For me it was a wake-up call. I was living in my bubble, in which I don&#8217;t really use these tools that much. But the world we live in is no longer the world I knew. … So such a lesson also helps us to learn and to discover the children in another context, &#8211; Carmen Melinte, a computer science teacher at the Colegiul Național Grigore Moisil in the small city of Onești, in north-east Romania, one of the EU regions with the greatest poverty risk.</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What our students think about the resources</strong></h2>



<p>Students enjoyed discussing real-world scenarios and admitted that they don’t really have adults around whom they can talk to about the AI tools they use. They appreciated the interactive activities where they worked in pairs or groups and the games where they pretended to be creators of AI apps, thinking about safety features they could implement:</p>



<p>“I had never questioned AI, as long as it did my homework,” said one student in our focus groups, where the majority of students admitted that they are already using large language models (LLMs) for most of their homework.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;I really liked that I found out what is behind that ‘Accept all’ and now I think twice before giving my data,&#8221; &#8211;&nbsp;Student at the end of the ‘Your data and AI’ activities.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>“Activities put me in a situation where I had to think from the other person&#8217;s shoes and think twice before sharing my personal data,” commented another student.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Good starting point</strong></h2>



<p>This is a good first step: there is an acute need for conversations between young people and adults around AI tools, how to think about them critically, and how to use them safely. School is the right place to start these conversations and activities, as teachers are still trusted by most Romanian students to help them understand the world.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="900" height="600" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/141-IMG_5760.jpg" alt="Students use a computer in class." class="wp-image-89444" style="width:774px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/141-IMG_5760.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/141-IMG_5760-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/141-IMG_5760-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/141-IMG_5760-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/141-IMG_5760-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/141-IMG_5760-450x300.jpg 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 900px) 100vw, 900px" /></figure></div>


<p>But to be able to do that, we need to be serious about equipping teachers with pedagogically sound resources that they can use in class, as well as training them, supporting them, and making sure that most of their time is dedicated to teaching, and not administration. It might seem a slow process, but it is the best way to help our students become responsible, ethical and accountable digital citizens.</p>



<p>We are deeply grateful to the brave, passionate teachers in our community who gave the AI safety resources a try and of course to our partners at the Raspberry Pi Foundation for giving us the opportunity to lead this pilot.</p>



<p>If you are a teacher anywhere in the world, give them a try today to celebrate Safer Internet Day: <a href="http://rpf.io/aisafetyromania">rpf.io/aisafetyromania</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teaching-ai-safety-lessons-from-romanian-educators/">Teaching AI safety: Lessons from Romanian educators</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teaching-ai-safety-lessons-from-romanian-educators/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UNESCO’s International Day of Education 2025: AI and the future of education</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/unescos-international-day-of-education-2025/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/unescos-international-day-of-education-2025/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben Garside]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 09:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI literacy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89400</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Recently, our Chief Learning Officer Rachel Arthur and I had the opportunity to attend UNESCO’s International Day of Education 2025, which focused on the role of education in helping people “understand and steer AI to better ensure that they retain control over this new class of technology and are able to direct it towards desired&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/unescos-international-day-of-education-2025/">UNESCO’s International Day of Education 2025: AI and the future of education</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Recently, our Chief Learning Officer Rachel Arthur and I had the opportunity to attend <a href="https://articles.unesco.org/sites/default/files/medias/fichiers/2025/01/education-day-2025-global-event-paris-cn-en.pdf">UNESCO’s International Day of Education 2025</a>, which focused on the role of education in helping people “understand and steer AI to better ensure that they retain control over this new class of technology and are able to direct it towards desired objectives that respect human rights and advance progress toward the Sustainable Development Goals”.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="1200" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-89401" style="width:635px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image.jpeg 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-300x225.jpeg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-500x375.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-768x576.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-1536x1152.jpeg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-800x600.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-450x338.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-900x675.jpeg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How teachers continue to play a vital role in the future of education</strong></h2>



<p>Throughout the event, a clear message from UNESCO was that teachers have a very important role to play in the future of education systems, regardless of the advances in technology — a message I find very reassuring. However, as with any good-quality debate, the sessions also reflected a range of other opinions and approaches, which should be listened to and discussed too.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With this in mind, I was interested to hear a talk by a school leader from England who is piloting the first “teacherless” classroom. They are trialling a programme with twenty Year 10 students (ages 14–15), using an AI tool developed in-house. This tool is trained on eight existing learning platforms, pulling content and tailoring the learning experience based on regular assessments. The students work independently using an AI tool in the morning, supported by a learning mentor in the classroom, while afternoons focus on developing “softer skills”. The school believes this approach will allow students to complete their GCSE exams in just one year instead of two, seeing it as a solution to the years of lost learning caused by lockdowns during the coronavirus pandemic.</p>



<p>Whilst they were reporting early success in this approach, what occurred to me during the talk was the question of how we can decide if this approach is the right one. The results might sound attractive to school leaders, but do we need a more rounded view of what education should look like? Whatever your views on the purpose of schools, I suspect most people would agree that they serve a much greater purpose than just achieving the top results.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Whilst AI tools may be able to provide personalised learning experiences, it is crucial to consider the role of teachers in young people’s education. If we listed the skills required for a teacher to do their job effectively, I believe we would all reach the same conclusion: teachers play a pivotal role in a young person’s life — one that definitely goes beyond getting the best exam results. According to the Educational Endowment Foundation, <a href="https://educationendowmentfoundation.org.uk/support-for-schools/school-planning-support/1-high-quality-teaching">high-quality teaching is the most important lever schools have on pupil outcomes</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Quality education demands quality educators” – Farida Shaheed, United Nations Special Rapporteur on the Right to Education</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Also, at this stage in AI adoption, can we be sure that this use of AI tools isn’t disadvantageous to any students? We know that machine learning models generate biased results, but I’m not aware of research showing that these systems are fair to all students and do not disadvantage any demographic. An argument levelled against this point is that teachers can also be biased. Aside from the fact that systems have a potentially much larger impact on more students than any individual teacher, I worry that this argument leads to us accepting machine bias, rather than expecting the highest of standards. It is essential that providers of any educational software that processes student data adhere to the principles of <a href="https://www.turing.ac.uk/research/interest-groups/fairness-transparency-privacy">fairness, accountability, transparency, privacy, and security (FATPS)</a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How can the agency of teachers be cultivated in AI adoption?</strong></h2>



<p>We are undeniably at a very early stage of a changing education landscape because of AI, and an important question is how teachers can be supported.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Education has a foundational role to play in helping individuals and groups determine what tasks should be outsourced to AI and what tasks need to remain firmly in human hands.” – <a href="https://articles.unesco.org/sites/default/files/medias/fichiers/2025/01/education-day-2025-global-event-paris-cn-en.pdf">UNESCO</a>&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>I was delighted to have been invited to be part of a panel at the event discussing how the agency of teachers can be cultivated in AI adoption. The panel consisted of people with different views and expertise, but importantly, included a classroom teacher, emphasising the importance of listening to educators and not making decisions on their behalf without them. As someone who works primarily on <a href="https://experience-ai.org/">AI literacy education</a>, my talk was centred around my belief that <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/free-online-course-on-understanding-ai-for-educators/">AI literacy education for teachers</a> is of paramount importance.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="597" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-1-e1738854286993-500x597.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-89403" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-1-e1738854286993-500x597.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-1-e1738854286993-209x250.jpeg 209w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-1-e1738854286993-768x917.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-1-e1738854286993-800x956.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-1-e1738854286993-450x538.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-1-e1738854286993-168x202.jpeg 168w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-1-e1738854286993.jpeg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>Having a basic understanding of how data-driven systems work will empower teachers to think critically and become discerning users, making conscious choices about which tools to use and for what purpose.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For example, while attending the Bett education technology exhibition recently, I was struck by the prevalence of education products that included the use of AI. With ever more options available, we need teachers to be able to make informed choices about which products will benefit and not harm their students.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Teachers urgently need to be empowered to better understand the technical, ethical and pedagogical dimensions of AI.” – Stefania Giannini, Assistant Director-General for Education, UNESCO, <a href="https://www.unesco.org/en/articles/ai-competency-framework-teachers">AI competency framework for teachers</a></p>
</blockquote>



<p>A <a href="https://osf.io/preprints/psyarxiv/t9u8g_v1">very interesting paper</a> released recently showed that individuals with lower AI literacy levels are more receptive towards AI-powered products and services. In short, people with higher literacy levels are more aware of the capabilities and limitations of AI systems. Perhaps this doesn’t mean that people with higher AI literacy levels see all AI tools as ‘bad’, but maybe that they are more able to think critically about the tools and make informed choices about their use.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>UN Special Rapporteur highlights urgent education challenges</strong></h2>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="1205" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-2.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-89404" style="width:562px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-2.jpeg 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-2-300x225.jpeg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-2-500x377.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-2-768x578.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-2-1536x1157.jpeg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-2-800x603.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-2-450x339.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/image-2-900x678.jpeg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure></div>


<p>For me, the most powerful talk of the day came from Farida Shaheed, the United Nations Special Rapporteur on the Right to Education. I would urge anyone to listen to it (<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7BUM-srCwtM">a recording is available on YouTube</a> — the talk begins around 2:16:00).&nbsp;</p>



<p>The talk included many facts that helped to frame some of the challenges we are facing. Ms Shaheed stated that “29% of all schools lack access to basic drinking water, without which education is not possible”. This is a sobering thought, particularly when there is a growing narrative that AI systems have the potential to democratise education.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When speaking about the AI tools being developed for education, Ms Shaheed questioned who the tools are for: “It’s telling that [so very few edtech tools] are developed for teachers. [&#8230;] Is this just because teachers are a far smaller client base or is it a desire to automate teachers out of the equation?”</p>



<p>I’m not sure if I know the answer to this question, but it speaks to my worry that the motivation for tech development does not prioritise taking a human-centred approach. We have to remember that as consumers, we do have more power than we think. If we do not want a future where AI tools are replacing teachers, then we need to make sure that there is not a demand for those tools.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The conference was a fantastic event to be part of, as it was an opportunity to listen to such a diverse range of perspectives. Certainly, we are facing challenges, but equally, it is both reassuring and exciting to know that so many people across the globe are working together to achieve the best possible outcomes for future generations. Ms Shaheed’s concluding message resonated strongly with me:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“[Share good practices], so we can all move together in a co-creative process that is inclusive of everybody and does not leave anyone behind.”&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>As always, we’d love to hear your views — you can contact us <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/contact/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/unescos-international-day-of-education-2025/">UNESCO’s International Day of Education 2025: AI and the future of education</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/unescos-international-day-of-education-2025/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Community Story &#124; Daniela, Thetford Library</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/community-story-daniela-thetford-library/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/community-story-daniela-thetford-library/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sophie Ashford]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 09:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Code Club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[astro pi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89374</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We love hearing from members of the community and sharing the stories of amazing young people, volunteers, and educators who are using their passion for technology to create positive change in the world around them. When Daniela made the transition from working in retail to joining the team at Thetford Library, she never imagined that&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/community-story-daniela-thetford-library/">Community Story | Daniela, Thetford Library</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We love hearing from members of the community and sharing the stories of amazing young people, volunteers, and educators who are using their passion for technology to create positive change in the world around them.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="667" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Daniela-500x667.jpg" alt="Daniela in a Code Club." class="wp-image-89383" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Daniela-500x667.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Daniela-188x250.jpg 188w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Daniela-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Daniela-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Daniela-800x1067.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Daniela-450x600.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Daniela-900x1200.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Daniela.jpg 1500w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>When Daniela made the transition from working in retail to joining the team at Thetford Library, she never imagined that she would one day be leading a Code Club. Her manager, who had previously run the club, asked if Daniela would be interested in taking over, and although she was nervous, she was also eager to embrace the challenge and learn new skills.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;At first, I was nervous about teaching coding, but seeing the children’s excitement made me realise it was so important, and I was learning just as much as they were.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The Code Club was designed to run in eight-week blocks, with a new group of children joining for each term. However, the kids loved it so much that they didn&#8217;t want to leave. Daniela, with her growing passion for coding and mentoring, welcomed the children to attend as often as they wanted, with some children, including one particularly enthusiastic young creator, attending every session. This continuity allowed the children to delve deeper into the world of coding, learning in a different way to what they were used to at school.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Inspiring young coders through creativity</strong></h2>



<p>One of the key things that Daniela has found resonates most with the children is the combination of creativity and coding. She encourages the kids to draw and plan their projects first, which makes the process more engaging and accessible to all of the young people who want to attend. The freedom to be creative is something that she feels is crucial, especially when compared to the more structured and rigid environment of school curriculums. This approach has been particularly rewarding for one young girl in the club who insists on planning and drawing her own characters and backgrounds for all of her projects.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;Coding isn’t just about writing lines of code — it’s about storytelling, problem solving, and imagining what’s possible.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="800" height="596" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/code-club-pic.jpg" alt="Students in a Code Club." class="wp-image-89387" style="width:564px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/code-club-pic.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/code-club-pic-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/code-club-pic-500x373.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/code-club-pic-768x572.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/code-club-pic-450x335.jpg 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Astro Pi: giving young people the confidence to dream big</strong></h2>



<p>Daniela&#8217;s journey into coding took a significant leap when she decided to explore the Astro Pi challenge, a project that involves writing code to run on Astro Pi computers aboard the International Space Station. Despite her initial nerves about diving into Python, a more advanced programming language than she had tried at the club previously, she was blown away by the possibilities it opened up. When telling the children, she almost felt that she was more excited at the prospect of them trying out real space science than them. But once she showed them some examples, the buzz was infectious and the sessions ran far smoother than she could have hoped. Daniela’s tip for trying Astro Pi for the first time? Find a fellow mentor to help you along the way and dream big.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;I never imagined we’d be working on space science at our library. Introducing children to coding early isn’t just about technology; it’s about giving them the confidence to dream big and think differently.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="800" height="1076" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Thetford-Library.jpg" alt="Thetford Library" class="wp-image-89395" style="width:492px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Thetford-Library.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Thetford-Library-186x250.jpg 186w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Thetford-Library-500x673.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Thetford-Library-768x1033.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Thetford-Library-450x605.jpg 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></figure></div>


<p>The success of the Code Club at Thetford Library is part of a broader initiative by Norfolk Libraries to provide digital skills to the community. They are committed to offering resources and opportunities for people of all ages to engage with technology. From their Digital Week, which focuses on improving digital literacy, to offering mentorship for adults learning to navigate the digital world, Norfolk Libraries is working hard to bridge the digital divide.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Benefits of volunteering at a Code Club&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p>For Daniela, the importance of introducing children to coding at an early age is not something she thought would become a passion for her when moving careers. She sees firsthand how these skills empower the children, giving them confidence and opening up future career opportunities.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;Code Club has shown me that stepping outside your comfort zone is where the real growth happens. Both for me and the kids!&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1500" height="2000" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Daniela-mentoring.jpg" alt="A mentor is helping a student in class." class="wp-image-89386" style="width:480px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Daniela-mentoring.jpg 1500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Daniela-mentoring-188x250.jpg 188w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Daniela-mentoring-500x667.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Daniela-mentoring-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Daniela-mentoring-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Daniela-mentoring-800x1067.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Daniela-mentoring-450x600.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/02/Daniela-mentoring-900x1200.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1500px) 100vw, 1500px" /></figure></div>


<p>It’s this combination of creativity, learning, and the sheer joy of discovery that keeps Daniela passionate about running the Code Club, and why she continues to welcome every eager child who walks through the door.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Inspire young people in your community</h2>



<p>If you are interested in encouraging your child to explore coding, take a look at the <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/">free coding project resources</a> we have available to support you. If you would like to set up a <a href="https://codeclub.org/en/">Code Club</a> for young people in your community, or attend one, head to codeclub.org for information and support.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/community-story-daniela-thetford-library/">Community Story | Daniela, Thetford Library</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/community-story-daniela-thetford-library/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Translating educational content: four key principles</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/translating-educational-content-four-key-principles/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/translating-educational-content-four-key-principles/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vicente Forcada]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 13:08:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[translation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hello World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[localisation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89349</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As an organisation with global reach, translation and localisation have been part of the Raspberry Pi Foundation’s activities from the start. Code Clubs and educational partners all over the world are helping young people learn about computing in their own language. We’ve already published over 1,900 translated learning resources, covering up to 32 languages, thanks&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/translating-educational-content-four-key-principles/">Translating educational content: four key principles</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As an organisation with global reach, translation and localisation have been part of the Raspberry Pi Foundation’s activities from the start. Code Clubs and educational partners all over the world are helping young people learn about computing in their own language. We’ve already published over 1,900 translated learning resources, covering up to 32 languages, thanks to the work of our talented localisation team and our amazing community of volunteer translators.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How our approach to translation considers design, process and people</strong></h2>



<p>English is seen by many as the language of computing, and in many countries, it’s also either the language of education or a language that young people aspire to learn. However, English is, in some instances, a barrier to learning: young people in many communities don’t have enough knowledge of English to use it to learn about digital technologies, or even if they do, the language of communication with other students, teachers, or volunteers may not be English.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="353" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Translation-Graphic-500x353.png" alt="Our ‘Space Talk’ project in Latin American Spanish" class="wp-image-89350" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Translation-Graphic-500x353.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Translation-Graphic-300x212.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Translation-Graphic-768x541.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Translation-Graphic-1536x1083.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Translation-Graphic-800x564.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Translation-Graphic-450x317.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Translation-Graphic-900x635.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Translation-Graphic.png 1600w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Our ‘Space Talk’ project in Latin American Spanish</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>In a world where browsers can instantly translate web pages and large language models can power seemingly perfect conversations in virtually any language, it’s easy to assume that translation just happens and that somehow, technology takes care of it. Unfortunately, that’s not the case. Technology is certainly crucial to translation, but there’s much more to it than that. Our approach to translation involves considering design, process, and people to ensure that localised materials truly help young people with their learning journey.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Localisation or translation?</strong></h2>



<p>Localisation and translation are similar terms that are often used interchangeably. Localisation normally refers to adapting a product to suit a local market, whereas translation is a subset of localisation that involves changing the language of the text. For instance, localisation includes currencies, measurements, formatting dates and numbers, and contextual references. Meanwhile, translation involves only changing the language of the text, such as from English to French.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/07/Hills-Road-Dojo_Low-res_22-01-23-24-500x333.jpg" alt="Learners at a Code Club." class="wp-image-84606" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/07/Hills-Road-Dojo_Low-res_22-01-23-24-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/07/Hills-Road-Dojo_Low-res_22-01-23-24-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/07/Hills-Road-Dojo_Low-res_22-01-23-24-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/07/Hills-Road-Dojo_Low-res_22-01-23-24.jpg 560w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>At the Raspberry Pi Foundation, we see translation as an enabler. It enables volunteers to reach learners, learners to succeed in their educational goals, and the Foundation to achieve its mission all over the world.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><br><strong>Four key ways the Foundation maximises the impact and reach of our translated materials</strong></h2>



<p><strong>1. Create with localisation in mind</strong></p>



<p>Regardless of whether learning materials are intended for English-speaking or global audiences, it’s important to create and design them with localisation in mind. That way, they can be used in a variety of places, and any piece of content (text, graphics, or illustrations) can be modified to meet the needs of the target audience. Keeping localisation in mind might include allowing space for text expansion, being mindful of any text embedded in graphic elements, and even making sure the context is understandable for a variety of audiences. Making a piece of content localisable at the creation stage is virtually cost-free. Modifying fully built assets to translate them or to use them in other markets can be expensive and extremely time-consuming!</p>



<p><strong>2. Always have user needs and priorities upfront</strong></p>



<p>Before investing in localising or translating any materials, we seek to understand the needs and priorities of our users. In many countries where English is not the usual language of communication, materials in English are a barrier, even if some of the users have a working knowledge of English. Making materials available in local languages directly results in additional reach and enhanced learning outcomes. In other communities where English has a certain status, a more selective approach may be more appropriate. A full translation may not be expected, but translating or adapting elements within them, such as introductions, videos, infographics, or glossaries, can help engage new learners.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="308" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CODE_CLUB_CHENNAI_0003-500x308.jpg" alt="Photo of a young person coding on a desktop computer." class="wp-image-89354" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CODE_CLUB_CHENNAI_0003-500x308.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CODE_CLUB_CHENNAI_0003-300x185.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CODE_CLUB_CHENNAI_0003-768x473.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CODE_CLUB_CHENNAI_0003-1536x946.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CODE_CLUB_CHENNAI_0003-2048x1261.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CODE_CLUB_CHENNAI_0003-800x493.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CODE_CLUB_CHENNAI_0003-450x277.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CODE_CLUB_CHENNAI_0003-900x554.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p><strong>3. Maximise the use of technology</strong></p>



<p>While it’s possible to translate with pen and paper, translation is only scalable with the use of technology. Computer-assisted translation tools, translation memories, terminology databases, machine translation, large language models, and so on are all technologies that play their part in making the translation process more efficient and scalable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the Foundation, we make use of a variety of translation technologies and also, crucially, work very closely with our content and development teams to integrate their tools and processes into the overall localisation workflow.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>4. Take great care of the people</strong></p>



<p>Even with the best technology and the smoothest integrations, there is a human element that is absolutely essential. Our amazing community of volunteers and partners work very closely with learners in their communities. They understand the needs of those learners and have a wealth of information and insights. We work with them to prioritise, translate, review and test the learning materials. They are key to ensuring that our learning materials help our users reach their learning goals.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>In summary</strong></h2>



<p>Thinking about localisation from the moment we start creating learning materials, understanding the needs of users when creating our end goals, maximising the use of technology, and taking good care of our people and partners are the key principles that drive our translation effort.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you’d like to find out more about translation at the Raspberry Pi Foundation or would like to contribute to the translation of our learning materials, feel free to contact us at <strong>translation@raspberrypi.org</strong>.  <br></p>



<p><em>A version of this article also appears in </em><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Hello World</em></a><em> issue 23.</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/translating-educational-content-four-key-principles/">Translating educational content: four key principles</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/translating-educational-content-four-key-principles/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Addressing the digital skills gap</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/addressing-the-digital-skills-gap/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/addressing-the-digital-skills-gap/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rachel Arthur]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 15:31:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Applied Certificate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Manchester]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital skills]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89344</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The digital skills gap is one of the biggest challenges for today’s workforce. It’s a growing concern for educators, employers, and anyone passionate about helping young people succeed. Digital literacy is essential in today’s world, whether or not you’re aiming for a tech career — yet too many young people are entering adulthood without the&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/addressing-the-digital-skills-gap/">Addressing the digital skills gap</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The digital skills gap is one of the biggest challenges for today’s workforce. It’s a growing concern for educators, employers, and anyone passionate about helping young people succeed.</p>



<p>Digital literacy is essential in today’s world, whether or not you’re aiming for a tech career — yet too many young people are entering adulthood without the skills to navigate it confidently and recent <a href="https://www.kcl.ac.uk/ecs/assets/kcl-scari-computing.pdf">research</a> shows that many young people finish school without formal digital qualifications.</p>



<p>Whilst this challenge is a global one, we’re exploring solutions in England where computing has been part of the national curriculum for a decade and the option of studying for a qualification (GCSE) in computer science is available to many 14-year-olds.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="373" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/06/Screenshot-2024-06-13-at-4.22.52 PM-500x373.png" alt="" class="wp-image-87528" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/06/Screenshot-2024-06-13-at-4.22.52 PM-500x373.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/06/Screenshot-2024-06-13-at-4.22.52 PM-300x225.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/06/Screenshot-2024-06-13-at-4.22.52 PM-768x573.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/06/Screenshot-2024-06-13-at-4.22.52 PM-800x597.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/06/Screenshot-2024-06-13-at-4.22.52 PM-450x336.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/06/Screenshot-2024-06-13-at-4.22.52 PM-900x672.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/06/Screenshot-2024-06-13-at-4.22.52 PM.png 1136w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>The <a href="https://www.kcl.ac.uk/ecs/assets/kcl-scari-computing.pdf">SCARI report</a> shows that GCSE computer science isn’t available in every school in England, and even where it is available, only a fraction of students opt to study it. Where GCSE computer science is offered, the focus is not on broader digital skills, but more on programming and theoretical knowledge which, while important, doesn’t support young people with the knowledge they need to succeed in the modern workplace.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How the Manchester Baccalaureate will help tackle the digital divide</strong></h2>



<p>At the Raspberry Pi Foundation, we’re working with the Greater Manchester Combined Authority to tackle this challenge head-on. Together, as part of their <a href="https://greatermanchester-ca.gov.uk/what-we-do/work-and-skills/technical-education-city-region/the-greater-manchester-baccalaureate/">Manchester Baccalaureate</a> initiative, we’re developing a self-paced course and certification to tackle the digital skills gap directly.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="667" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/img_9427_720-500x667.jpg" alt="Teachers listening to a presentation at a recent workshop the Raspberry Pi Foundation held in Manchester." class="wp-image-89054" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/img_9427_720-500x667.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/img_9427_720-188x250.jpg 188w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/img_9427_720-450x600.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/img_9427_720.jpg 540w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/curriculum/applied-certificate">The Raspberry Pi Foundation Certificate in Applied Computing</a> is designed to be accessed by any pupil, anywhere. It includes a series of flexible modules that students can work through at their own pace. Targeted at young people ages 14 and up, the certificate covers three stages:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Stage 1 – Students gain essential digital skills, preparing them for a wide range of careers</li>



<li>Stages 2 and 3 – Students dive into specialisations in key tech areas, building expertise aligned with in-demand roles</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What we’ve learnt in Manchester so far</strong></h2>



<p>We recently visited Oasis Academy Media City to hold a workshop on digital skills and get input on the certificate. We welcomed educators and industry experts to share their insights, and their feedback has been invaluable.</p>



<p>Teachers pointed out a common challenge: while they see the importance of digital skills, they often lack the time and resources to add new material to an already packed curriculum. By offering the certification as bite-sized modules that focus on specific skills, it makes it easier to slot the content into the timetable, and helps students with limited access to school (due to illness, for example) engage with the course.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="545" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/img_9424_720-1-500x545.jpg" alt="Teachers listening to a presentation at a recent workshop the Raspberry Pi Foundation held in Manchester." class="wp-image-89063" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/img_9424_720-1-500x545.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/img_9424_720-1-229x250.jpg 229w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/img_9424_720-1-450x491.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/img_9424_720-1.jpg 533w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>Educators were particularly excited about the opportunity for students to specialise in areas tied to in-demand roles that are currently being recruited for and our goal is to make the qualification engaging and relevant, helping students see how their learning applies in the real world.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Next steps</strong></h2>



<p>We are currently piloting this qualification in schools throughout Manchester, gathering invaluable feedback from young people as they embark on this learning experience, which will help us refine the course.<br>Stages 1 and 2 of the qualification will launch later this year, and we can’t wait to help students approach their futures with curiosity and confidence.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/addressing-the-digital-skills-gap/">Addressing the digital skills gap</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/addressing-the-digital-skills-gap/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Helping young people navigate AI safely</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/helping-young-people-navigate-ai-safely/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/helping-young-people-navigate-ai-safely/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mac Bowley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 09:46:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Experience AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI Safety]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89321</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>AI safety and Experience AI As our lives become increasingly intertwined with AI-powered tools and systems, it’s more important than ever to equip young people with the skills and knowledge they need to engage with AI safely and responsibly. AI literacy isn’t just about understanding the technology — it’s about fostering critical conversations on how&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/helping-young-people-navigate-ai-safely/">Helping young people navigate AI safely</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">AI safety and Experience AI</h2>



<p>As our lives become increasingly intertwined with AI-powered tools and systems, it’s more important than ever to equip young people with the skills and knowledge they need to engage with AI safely and responsibly. AI literacy isn’t just about understanding the technology — it’s about fostering critical conversations on how to integrate AI tools into our lives while minimising potential harm — otherwise known as ‘AI safety’.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage1-1-500x281.png" alt="" class="wp-image-89322" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage1-1-500x281.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage1-1-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage1-1-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage1-1-1536x864.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage1-1-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage1-1-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage1-1-900x506.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage1-1.png 1920w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p><a href="https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/media/65438d159e05fd0014be7bd9/introducing-ai-safety-institute-web-accessible.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The UK AI Safety Institute defines AI safety as</a>: “The understanding, prevention, and mitigation of harms from AI. These harms could be deliberate or accidental; caused to individuals, groups, organisations, nations or globally; and of many types, including but not limited to physical, psychological, social, or economic harms.”</p>



<p>As a result of this growing need, we’re thrilled to announce the latest addition to our AI literacy programme, Experience AI —&nbsp; ‘AI safety: responsibility, privacy, and security’. Co-developed with Google DeepMind, this comprehensive suite of free resources is designed to empower 11- to 14-year-olds to understand and address the challenges of AI technologies. Whether you’re a teacher, youth leader, or parent, these resources provide everything you need to start the conversation.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Linking old and new topics</h2>



<p>AI technologies are providing huge benefits to society, but as they become more prevalent we cannot ignore the challenges AI tools bring with them. Many of the challenges aren’t new, such as concerns over data privacy or misinformation, but AI systems have the potential to amplify these issues.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage4-1-500x281.png" alt="Digital image depicting computer science related elements." class="wp-image-89325" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage4-1-500x281.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage4-1-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage4-1-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage4-1-1536x864.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage4-1-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage4-1-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage4-1-900x506.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage4-1.png 1920w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>Our resources use familiar online safety themes — like data privacy and media literacy — and apply AI concepts to start the conversation about how AI systems might change the way we approach our digital lives.</p>



<p>Each session explores a specific area:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Your data and AI:</strong> How data-driven AI systems use data differently to traditional software and why that changes data privacy concerns</li>



<li><strong>Media literacy in the age of AI:</strong> The ease of creating believable, AI-generated content and the importance of verifying information</li>



<li><strong>Using AI tools responsibly:</strong> Encouraging critical thinking about how AI is marketed and understanding personal and developer responsibilities</li>
</ul>



<p>Each topic is designed to engage young people to consider both their own interactions with AI systems and the ethical responsibilities of developers.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Designed to be flexible</h2>



<p>Our AI safety resources have flexibility and ease of delivery at their core, and each session is built around three key components:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Animations:</strong> Each session begins with a concise, engaging video introducing the key AI concept using sound pedagogy — making it easy to deliver and effective. The video then links the AI concept to the online safety topic and opens threads for thought and conversation, which the learners explore through the rest of the activities. </li>



<li><strong>Unplugged activities:</strong> These hands-on, screen-free activities — ranging from role-playing games to thought-provoking challenges — allow learners to engage directly with the topics.</li>



<li><strong>Discussion questions:</strong> Tailored for various settings, these questions help spark meaningful conversations in classrooms, clubs, or at home.</li>
</ol>



<p><a href="https://experience-ai.org" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Experience AI</a> has always been about allowing everyone — including those without a technical background or specialism in computer science — to deliver high-quality AI learning experiences, which is why we often use videos to support conceptual learning. </p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage3-1-500x281.png" alt="Digital image featuring two computer screens. One screen seems to represent errors, or misinformation. The other depicts a person potentially plotting something." class="wp-image-89324" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage3-1-500x281.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage3-1-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage3-1-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage3-1-1536x864.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage3-1-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage3-1-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage3-1-900x506.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage3-1.png 1920w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>In addition, we want these sessions to be impactful in many different contexts, so we included unplugged activities so that you don’t need a computer room to run them! There is also advice on shortening the activities or splitting them so you can deliver them over two sessions if you want.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The discussion topics provide a time-efficient way of exploring some key implications with learners, which we think will be more effective in smaller groups or more informal settings. They also highlight topics that we feel are important but may not be appropriate for every learner, for example, the rise of inappropriate deepfake images, which you might discuss with a 14-year-old but not an 11-year-old.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A modular approach for all contexts</h2>



<p>Our previous resources have all followed a format suitable for delivery in a classroom, but for these resources, we wanted to widen the potential contexts in which they could be used. Instead of prescribing the exact order to deliver them, educators are encouraged to mix and match activities that they feel would be effective for their context.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage2-1-500x281.png" alt="Digital image depicting computer science related elements." class="wp-image-89323" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage2-1-500x281.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage2-1-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage2-1-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage2-1-1536x864.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage2-1-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage2-1-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage2-1-900x506.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage2-1.png 1920w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>We hope this will empower anyone, no matter their surroundings, to have meaningful conversations about AI safety with young people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The modular design ensures maximum flexibility. For example:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>A teacher might combine the video with an unplugged activity and follow-up discussion for a 60-minute lesson</li>



<li>A club leader could show the video and run a quick activity in a 30-minute session</li>



<li>A parent might watch the video and use the discussion questions during dinner to explore how generative AI shapes the content their children encounter</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The importance of AI safety education</h2>



<p>With AI becoming a larger part of daily life, young people need the tools to think critically about its use. From understanding how their data is used to spotting misinformation, these resources are designed to build confidence and critical thinking in an AI-powered world.</p>



<p>AI safety is about empowering young people to be informed consumers of AI tools. By using these resources, you’ll help the next generation not only navigate AI, but shape its future. Dive into our materials, start a conversation, and inspire young minds to think critically about the role of AI in their lives.</p>



<p>Ready to get started? Explore our AI safety resources today: <a href="https://rpf.io/aisafetyblog">rpf.io/aisafetyblog</a>. Together, we can empower every child to thrive in a digital world.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/helping-young-people-navigate-ai-safely/">Helping young people navigate AI safely</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/helping-young-people-navigate-ai-safely/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The need to invest in AI skills in schools</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/the-need-to-invest-in-ai-skills-in-schools/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/the-need-to-invest-in-ai-skills-in-schools/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Philip Colligan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 15:07:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Experience AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI in education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI literacy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89294</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Earlier this week, the UK Government published its AI Opportunities Action Plan, which sets out an ambitious vision to maintain the UK&#8217;s position as a global leader in artificial intelligence.&#160; Whether you&#8217;re from the UK or not, it&#8217;s a good read, setting out the opportunities and challenges facing any country that aspires to lead the&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/the-need-to-invest-in-ai-skills-in-schools/">The need to invest in AI skills in schools</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Earlier this week, the UK Government published its <a href="https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/media/67851771f0528401055d2329/ai_opportunities_action_plan.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">AI Opportunities Action Plan</a>, which sets out an ambitious vision to maintain the UK&#8217;s position as a global leader in artificial intelligence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Whether you&#8217;re from the UK or not, it&#8217;s a good read, setting out the opportunities and challenges facing any country that aspires to lead the world in the development and application of AI technologies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of skills, the Action Plan highlights the need for the UK to train tens of thousands more AI professionals by 2030 and sets out important goals to expand education pathways into AI, invest in new undergraduate and master&#8217;s scholarships, tackle the lack of diversity in the sector, and ensure that the lifelong skills agenda focuses on AI skills.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-2-500x281.jpg" alt="Photo of a group of young people working through some Experience AI content." class="wp-image-89305" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-2-500x281.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-2-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-2-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-2-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-2-800x450.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-2-450x253.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-2-900x506.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-2.jpg 1920w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>This is all very important, but the Action Plan fails to mention what I think is one of the most important investments we need to make, which is in schools.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;Most people overestimate what they can achieve in a year and underestimate what they can achieve in ten years.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>While reading the section of the Action Plan that dealt with AI skills, I was reminded of this quote attributed to Bill Gates, which was adapted from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roy_Amara" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Roy Amara&#8217;s law of technology</a>. We tend to overestimate what we can achieve in the short term and underestimate what we can achieve in the long term.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In focusing on the immediate AI gold rush, there is a risk that the government overlooks the investments we need to make right now in schools, which will yield huge returns — for individuals, communities, and economies — over the long term. Realising the full potential of a future where AI technologies are ubiquitous requires genuinely long-term thinking, which isn&#8217;t always easy for political systems that are designed around short-term results.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="500" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-500x500.png" alt="Photo focused on a young person working on a computer in a classroom." class="wp-image-89304" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-500x500.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-250x250.png 250w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-150x150.png 150w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-768x768.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-800x800.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-100x100.png 100w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-300x300.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-450x450.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-900x900.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-400x400.png 400w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-600x600.png 600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36.png 1080w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>But what are those investments? The Action Plan rightly points out that the first step for the government is to accurately assess the size of the skills gap. As part of that work, we need to figure out what needs to change in the school system to build a genuinely diverse and broad pipeline of young people with AI skills. The good news is that we&#8217;ve already made a lot of progress.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">AI literacy</h2>



<p>Over the past three years, the Raspberry Pi Foundation and our colleagues in the <a href="https://computingeducationresearch.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Raspberry Pi Computing Education Research Centre</a> at the University of Cambridge have been working to understand and define what AI literacy means. That led us to create a research-informed <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ai-education-resources-what-to-teach-seame-framework/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">model for AI literacy</a> that unpacks the concepts and knowledge that constitute a foundational understanding of AI.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In partnership with one of the leading UK-based AI companies, Google DeepMind, we used that model to create <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-deepmind-ai-education/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Experience AI</a>. This suite of classroom resources, teacher professional development, and hands-on practical activities enables non-specialist teachers to deliver engaging lessons that help young people build that foundational understanding of AI technologies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve seen huge demand from UK schools already, with thousands of lessons taught in UK schools, and we&#8217;re delighted to be working with <a href="https://parentzone.org.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Parent Zone</a> to support a wider roll out in the UK, along with free teacher professional development.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Experience-AI-Blog-Asset-500x333.jpg" alt="CEO Philip Colligan and  Prime Minister Keir Starmer at the UK launch of Experience AI." class="wp-image-89295" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Experience-AI-Blog-Asset-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Experience-AI-Blog-Asset-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Experience-AI-Blog-Asset-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Experience-AI-Blog-Asset.jpg 512w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">CEO Philip Colligan and Prime Minister Keir Starmer at the UK launch of Experience AI.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>With the generous support of Google.org, we are working with a global network of education partners — from Nigeria to Nepal — to localise and translate these resources, and deliver locally organised teacher professional development. With over 1 million young people reached already, Experience AI can plausibly claim to be the most widely used AI literacy curriculum in the world, and we&#8217;re improving it all the time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All of the materials are available for anyone to use and can be found on the <a href="https://experience-ai.org/en/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Experience AI website</a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">There is no AI without CS</h2>



<p>With the CEO of GitHub claiming that it won&#8217;t be long before <a href="https://www.freethink.com/robots-ai/github-copilot" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">80% of code is written by AI</a>, it&#8217;s perhaps not surprising that some people are questioning whether we still need to teach kids how to code.</p>



<p>I&#8217;ll have much more to say on this in a future blog post, but the short answer is that computer science and programming is set to become more — not less — important in the age of AI. This is particularly important if we want to tackle the lack of diversity in the tech sector and ensure that young people from all backgrounds have the opportunity to shape the AI-enabled future that they will be living in.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Hills-Road-Dojo__22-01-23-36-1-500x333.jpg" alt="Close up of two young people working at a computer." class="wp-image-89303" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Hills-Road-Dojo__22-01-23-36-1-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Hills-Road-Dojo__22-01-23-36-1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Hills-Road-Dojo__22-01-23-36-1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Hills-Road-Dojo__22-01-23-36-1-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Hills-Road-Dojo__22-01-23-36-1-2048x1365.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Hills-Road-Dojo__22-01-23-36-1-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Hills-Road-Dojo__22-01-23-36-1-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Hills-Road-Dojo__22-01-23-36-1-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>The simple truth is that there is no artificial intelligence without computer science. The rapid advances in AI are likely to increase the range of problems that can be solved by technology, creating demand for more complex software, which in turn will create demand for more programmers with increasingly sophisticated and complex skills.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why we&#8217;ve set ourselves the ambition that we will inspire <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/introducing-the-new-code-club/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">10 million more young people</a> to learn how to get creative with technology over the next 10 years through Code Club.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Curriculum reform&nbsp;</h2>



<p>But we also need to think about what needs to change in the curriculum to ensure that schools are equipping young people with the skills and knowledge they need to thrive in an AI-powered world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That will mean changes to the computer science curriculum, providing different pathways that reflect young people&#8217;s interests and passions, but ensuring that every child leaves school with a qualification in computer science or applied digital skills.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s not just computer science courses. We need to modernise mathematics and figure out what a data science curriculum looks like (and where it fits). We also need to recognise that AI skills are just as relevant to biology, geography, and languages as they are to computer science.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="334" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_030-500x334.jpg" alt="A teacher assisting a young person with a coding project." class="wp-image-89308" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_030-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_030-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_030-768x513.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_030-1536x1026.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_030-2048x1367.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_030-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_030-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_030-900x601.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>To be clear, I am not talking about how AI technologies will save teachers time, transform assessments, or be used by students to write essays. I am talking about the fundamentals of the subjects themselves and how AI technologies are revolutionising the sciences and humanities in practice in the real world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These are all areas where the Raspberry Pi Foundation is engaged in original research and experimentation. Stay tuned.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Supporting teachers</h2>



<p>All of this needs to be underpinned by a commitment to supporting teachers, including through funding and time to engage in meaningful professional development. This is probably the biggest challenge for policy makers at a time when budgets are under so much pressure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For any nation to plausibly claim that it has an Action Plan to be an AI superpower, it needs to recognise the importance of making the long-term investment in supporting our teachers to develop the skills and confidence to teach students about AI and the role that it will play in their lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;d love to hear what you think and if you want to get involved, please <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/contact/">get in touch</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/the-need-to-invest-in-ai-skills-in-schools/">The need to invest in AI skills in schools</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/the-need-to-invest-in-ai-skills-in-schools/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
