<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Raspberry Pi Foundation</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/</link>
	<description>Teach, learn and make with Raspberry Pi</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 10:58:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.8.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/06/cropped-raspberrry_pi_logo-100x100.png</url>
	<title>Raspberry Pi Foundation</title>
	<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Adapting our computing curriculum resources for Telangana — the journey so far</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-our-computing-curriculum-resources-for-telangana-the-journey-so-far/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-our-computing-curriculum-resources-for-telangana-the-journey-so-far/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jaskaran Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 10:57:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Computing Curriculum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Impact of our work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Telangana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research and impact]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=91392</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This blog is the third and final in our mini-series about the things we’ve learnt from adapting The Computing Curriculum resources, and from training teachers to use them in schools. In the first two blogs, we wrote about our experiences in Kenya and Odisha, India. Here, we focus on our work in Telangana, India.&#160; This&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-our-computing-curriculum-resources-for-telangana-the-journey-so-far/">Adapting our computing curriculum resources for Telangana — the journey so far</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>This blog is the third and final in our mini-series about the things we’ve learnt from adapting <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/curriculum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Computing Curriculum</a> resources, and from training teachers to use them in schools. In the first two blogs, we wrote about our experiences in <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-our-computing-curriculum-resources-for-kenya-the-journey-so-far/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kenya</a> and <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-our-computing-curriculum-resources-for-odisha-the-journey-so-far/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Odisha, India</a>. Here, we focus on our work in Telangana, India.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="2560" height="1707" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1949-scaled.jpg" alt="Three female students at the Coding Academy in Telangana." class="wp-image-85245" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1949-scaled.jpg 2560w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1949-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1949-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1949-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1949-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1949-2048x1365.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1949-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1949-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1949-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /></figure></div>


<p>This blog was written by Jaskaran Singh, Impact Manager, and Mamta Manaktala, Senior Learning Manager.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Adapting for unique needs</h2>



<p>Every country and region has unique opportunities, challenges, and needs. In a vast country like India, every state is different — <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-our-computing-curriculum-resources-for-odisha-the-journey-so-far/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">what works in Odisha</a> may not work in other locations. Thus, to meet the needs of students in the state of Telangana, <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/computing-curriculum-framework-adapting-to-indias-diverse-landscapes/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">we’ve been working on adapting The Computing Curriculum</a> specifically for them.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="2560" height="1707" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1940-scaled.jpg" alt="A group of female students at the Coding Academy in Telangana." class="wp-image-85251" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1940-scaled.jpg 2560w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1940-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1940-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1940-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1940-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1940-2048x1365.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1940-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1940-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1940-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /></figure></div>


<p>Our work in Telangana began in 2023, when we kickstarted <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/tswreis-coding-academy-computing-education-partnership-telangana/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a five-year partnership with the Telangana Social Welfare Residential Educational Institutions Society (TGSWREIS)</a>, a society under the Government of Telangana. Through the partnership, we’ve developed an adapted curriculum, along with training for educators working in educational institutions with limited resources. The adapted curriculum includes localised examples and activities, and teaching approaches to make the learning experience feel relevant and meaningful for students in Telangana, while keeping the core learning outcomes aligned with global standards.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Testing and iterating</h3>



<p>Since the start of the partnership, we’ve been testing the curriculum at the Coding Academy School, a co-educational school at Moinabad, and the Coding Academy College, a degree college for women in Shamirpet.</p>



<p>Our work delivering the curriculum in Telangana was our first time using a direct-to-learners model. The Coding Academy School and College gave us unique opportunities to work with students directly and observe first-hand the difference the programme made in their learning journeys.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="2560" height="1707" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/YP7_1945-scaled.jpg" alt="A group of students and a teacher at the Coding Academy in Telangana." class="wp-image-85669" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/YP7_1945-scaled.jpg 2560w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/YP7_1945-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/YP7_1945-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/YP7_1945-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/YP7_1945-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/YP7_1945-2048x1365.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/YP7_1945-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/YP7_1945-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/11/YP7_1945-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /></figure></div>


<p>During the first year of implementation, we gathered useful feedback from students and teachers. Check out one of <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/implementing-a-computing-curriculum-in-telangana/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our earlier blogs where we share some of the findings</a>. We used these inputs to further develop the curriculum.</p>



<p>This updated version of the curriculum was implemented in the 2024/25 academic year. At the school, our educators worked with 210 students in grades 7–9, while at the college, our educators worked with 382 undergraduate students. As in the first year, we used data from assessments, lesson observations, educator interviews, student surveys, and student focus groups to understand what’s working well and what could be improved. So what did we learn?</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What we learnt over the past year</h2>



<p>Our evaluation findings show that the updated curriculum worked well and positive outcomes are being achieved for most students. Educators felt prepared to teach the curriculum in this second year and found the ongoing support and spaces for discussion really useful. Moreover, we found that there are potential positive ripple effects beyond the school as well.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Learning outcomes are being achieved to a high degree</h3>



<p>In surveys, 91% of students in the school and 96% of students in the college responded that the lessons helped them get better at computing and coding. Students feel they are not just learning new skills but also finding the content enjoyable: 88% of students in the school and 98% of students in the college responded that they are enjoying their classes. Educators and observers also reported that students were engaged during lessons, and often completed activities without needing any support.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="819" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/image.png" alt="Students' reflections on the computing curriculum." class="wp-image-91393" style="width:720px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/image.png 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/image-300x154.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/image-500x256.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/image-768x393.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/image-1536x786.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/image-800x410.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/image-450x230.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/image-900x461.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure></div>


<p>Students’ assessment scores further confirmed positive learning outcomes. 4 out of every 5 scores in the school and 9 out of every 10 scores in the college were 60% or above, <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/empowering-indias-digital-future-our-computing-curriculums-impact/." target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">which was higher than in the first year of the adapted curriculum’s implementation.</a></p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">The updated curriculum is more aligned to student needs</h3>



<p>The changes we made to the curriculum included:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Adding more localised examples</li>



<li>Simplifying the language&nbsp;</li>



<li>Restructuring the flow of the content</li>
</ul>



<p>Educators were highly positive about the updates to the curriculum.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The students are able to [better] understand the examples because we updated [to] the India context examples.” — Educator, Coding Academy School&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Students are receiving it very well because we have modified the content this year, and [that includes] the placements of the unit and the connectivity of the lessons and units.” — Educator, Coding Academy School</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Additionally, for the college curriculum, we aligned the content more closely with the learning objectives set by Osmania University — with which the college is affiliated. We also included more advanced topics for students specialising in data science. During interviews, educators reported that the content was now much better aligned to student expectations.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“[The curriculum] we have designed is based as per [the] Osmania University curriculum. [The lessons] are definitely meeting the students&#8217; needs because whatever discussions we are taking in classes, they are [successfully] participating in those discussions and they are doing whatever activities we give them.” — Educator, Coding Academy College</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Outside of knowledge and skills in computing, the curriculum is also helping students develop wider life skills. In our survey, college students shared that working on projects gives them a sense of accomplishment and the confidence to solve real-world problems. Many students also reported that through the curriculum they are developing higher-order thinking skills, which will support their future careers.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The thrill lies the creativity and problem-solving aspects. I get to turn ideas into reality pieces, and there is something incredible satisfying about debugging code and watching it run flawlessly. It&#8217;s like slow, challenging puzzles, frustrating at times but rewarding when everything clicks.” — Student, Coding Academy College</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“My favourite thing [about] the computing and coding classes [is the] Scratch programme. I have learnt it [for the] first time. By learning I have enjoyed a lot. During the coding process, it trains our brain to think deeply, identify trouble, and break things up and put pieces together [as] a solution.” — Student, Coding Academy College</p>
</blockquote>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Students are inspired to continue engaging&nbsp;</h3>



<p>Students are showing high interest in applying their skills outside of their classes. Almost all students — 100% in the school and 99% in the college — reported that they would like to participate in coding-related competitions.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="750" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/IMG_0255.jpg" alt="A group of female students working on a coding project." class="wp-image-91401" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/IMG_0255.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/IMG_0255-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/IMG_0255-500x375.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/IMG_0255-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/IMG_0255-800x600.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/IMG_0255-450x338.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/IMG_0255-900x675.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>Educators also told us that many students are exploring future job opportunities in the computing and digital technology fields, and are curious about topics outside the curriculum. Interestingly, 93% of the college students who were studying courses not traditionally associated with jobs in computing and digital technology reported that they would like to pursue a job in computing.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">The positive benefits go beyond the school</h3>



<p>We have also learnt that a high-quality computing education for young people has potentially wider benefits for the community. One educator described how students are helping their families, many of whom have limited experiences, engage more confidently with digital technologies.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Families don&#8217;t know how to use smartphones and laptop computers, but our students know very well so I can say they do teach to their elders how to use these platforms.” — Educator, Coding Academy School</p>
</blockquote>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Ongoing support for educators was important</h3>



<p>To help educators feel confident and prepared, individualised learning resources were provided throughout the year. These were well received by educators. Educators also found the weekly meetings with our India-based team members useful to discuss ongoing challenges regarding delivery and assessments.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What could still be improved</h3>



<p>There were improvements this year in the availability of equipment, and the use of Wi-Fi dongles addressed internet connectivity issues to some degree. However, educators still faced some challenges. For example, educators in the school faced issues accessing printed worksheets and educators in the college faced issues accessing projectors during their lessons. We are working closely with our delivery partner to address these issues for the new academic year.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1536" height="1024" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/YP7_1955-1536x1024-1.jpg" alt="A group of male students working on a coding project." class="wp-image-91402" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/YP7_1955-1536x1024-1.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/YP7_1955-1536x1024-1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/YP7_1955-1536x1024-1-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/YP7_1955-1536x1024-1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/YP7_1955-1536x1024-1-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/YP7_1955-1536x1024-1-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/YP7_1955-1536x1024-1-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1536px) 100vw, 1536px" /></figure></div>


<p>With regard to the content, educators felt the curriculum could benefit from some further amendments. For the school curriculum, these include easing the transition from block-based to text-based coding. For the college curriculum, there were suggestions for more focus on real-world applications of coding and including advanced topics, like machine learning, for undergraduates specialising in computing-related subjects. We have considered all these suggestions and made necessary revisions to the curriculum.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Next steps in Telangana: Scaling up impact</h2>



<p>With the success of the pilot, we’re excited to announce that the adapted curriculum will now be implemented at over 350 schools and junior colleges in the state of Telangana. A majority of schools will be with the same partner, TGSWREIS, while some schools and junior colleges will be with other partners. The Coding Academy School will become our hub for trialling new curriculum content and strategies, and conducting research studies and teacher training and support. Additionally, the school will also host inter-school events.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="750" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/IMG_0267.jpg" alt="A group of female students working on a coding project." class="wp-image-91404" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/IMG_0267.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/IMG_0267-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/IMG_0267-500x375.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/IMG_0267-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/IMG_0267-800x600.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/IMG_0267-450x338.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/09/IMG_0267-900x675.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>The progress we&#8217;ve seen so far in Telangana is very encouraging. We look forward to continuing these partnerships and helping more young people realise their potential through the power of computing and digital technologies.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What we learnt about adapting curriculum resources for different regions</h2>



<p>From our work in Telangana, <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-our-computing-curriculum-resources-for-odisha-the-journey-so-far/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Odisha</a>, and <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-our-computing-curriculum-resources-for-kenya-the-journey-so-far/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kenya</a>, we’ve learnt that a curriculum isn’t a one-size-fits-all product. The local context, culture, and educational provisions are important considerations when adapting learning resources for different regions. We’ve also learnt that building long-term partnerships with organisations who have local expertise is key to understanding these considerations and effectively reaching communities where we can make the biggest difference. Finally, we’ve learnt that adaptation isn’t a one-time activity. It’s a cycle of continuous refinement; listening closely to feedback from the ground is important to ensure that our support for educators and learning experiences for young people have the best possible impact.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Want to learn more about our curriculum resources?</h2>



<p>You can access our <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/curriculum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">free Computing Curriculum resources on our website</a> — we are currently working to make the materials for India and Kenya downloadable there.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-our-computing-curriculum-resources-for-telangana-the-journey-so-far/">Adapting our computing curriculum resources for Telangana — the journey so far</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-our-computing-curriculum-resources-for-telangana-the-journey-so-far/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Improvements to the Code Club Projects website</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/improvements-to-the-code-club-projects-website/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/improvements-to-the-code-club-projects-website/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Divya Mahadevan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 14:09:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Code Club Projects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Code Club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Projects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[projects site]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=91350</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Getting creative with technology is now easier than ever on the Code Club Projects website. If you’ve visited Code Club Projects recently, you may have noticed that the site has changed over the last few months. In the spring, we launched an initiative to make it easier to find a project. I’m excited to share&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/improvements-to-the-code-club-projects-website/">Improvements to the Code Club Projects website</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Getting creative with technology is now easier than ever on the <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Code Club Projects</a> website. If you’ve visited Code Club Projects recently, you may have noticed that the site has changed over the last few months. In the spring, we launched an initiative to make it easier to <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/projects" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">find a project</a>. I’m excited to share some of the changes we’ve made based on feedback from young people and mentors.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="667" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/CodeClub_CamMS_24-008.jpg" alt="A mentor with a young coder in a Code Club session. " class="wp-image-91353" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/CodeClub_CamMS_24-008.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/CodeClub_CamMS_24-008-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/CodeClub_CamMS_24-008-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/CodeClub_CamMS_24-008-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/CodeClub_CamMS_24-008-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/CodeClub_CamMS_24-008-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/CodeClub_CamMS_24-008-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Finding projects based on difficulty</h2>



<p>Being able to filter projects by skill level (beginner, intermediate, advanced) has been the feature most requested by mentors. A survey we ran in the spring confirmed that young people find levels helpful when trying to find a project on their own. While our project paths have always had levels, our expert educators have now reviewed every single project on the site and categorised them as a Level 1, Level 2, or Level 3 project. These difficulty levels are easily available as filters on the side of the search page.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“[The Code Club] resources are extremely helpful, particularly for mentors with limited experience; step-by-step guidance is very useful and effective.” – Code Club mentor, Tunisia</p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1463" height="1185" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Screenshot-2025-08-28-at-12.37.37-edited.png" alt="Screenshot of level on project card and filters" class="wp-image-91370" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Screenshot-2025-08-28-at-12.37.37-edited.png 1463w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Screenshot-2025-08-28-at-12.37.37-edited-300x243.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Screenshot-2025-08-28-at-12.37.37-edited-500x405.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Screenshot-2025-08-28-at-12.37.37-edited-768x622.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Screenshot-2025-08-28-at-12.37.37-edited-800x648.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Screenshot-2025-08-28-at-12.37.37-edited-450x364.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Screenshot-2025-08-28-at-12.37.37-edited-900x729.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1463px) 100vw, 1463px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Finding projects based on interest</h2>



<p>For young people and mentors who aren’t sure where to get started with coding, an easy question to ask is “What do you like to do”? With over 200+ projects on the site, there is a wide variety of projects that span a number of young people’s passions, such as games, art, or nature. In fact, in the same spring survey, young people largely preferred finding projects by interest over technology (e.g., Scratch, Python).&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s why we’ve created a brand-new set of pages dedicated to helping young people find projects by interest. We believe making it easy to find a project by an existing interest will help young people get excited about coding.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“[Attending Code Club] … combined with watching peers make cool things seems to be a great encouragement to go build rather than just consume.” – Code club mentor, Japan</p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="599" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-5.png" alt="Screenshot of different Interest categories on the Code Club Projects site." class="wp-image-91351" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-5.png 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-5-300x112.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-5-500x187.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-5-768x288.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-5-1536x575.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-5-800x300.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-5-450x168.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-5-900x337.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure></div>


<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Check out our new interest pages</a></div>
</div>



<p>Code Clubs projects are designed to appeal to creators’ interests, including creating their own games.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Finding projects based on technology</h2>



<p>Through the Clubs annual survey, we know that some young people enjoy following our project pathways and others enjoy finding an individual project to work on during club time. We also know that some of our top search terms are “Scratch” and “Python”, which allow users to see all Scratch projects that are available on the site. We’ve redesigned our technology pages so it’s easy to see paths and projects per technology in the same place.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I think [Raspberry Pi Foundation projects are] really easy to understand and encourage young people to learn more and more.” – Code Club leader, Brazil</p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2016" height="1395" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Screenshot-2025-08-28-at-12.40.19-edited.png" alt="Screenshot of different Technology categories on the Code Club Projects site." class="wp-image-91372" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Screenshot-2025-08-28-at-12.40.19-edited.png 2016w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Screenshot-2025-08-28-at-12.40.19-edited-300x208.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Screenshot-2025-08-28-at-12.40.19-edited-500x346.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Screenshot-2025-08-28-at-12.40.19-edited-768x531.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Screenshot-2025-08-28-at-12.40.19-edited-1536x1063.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Screenshot-2025-08-28-at-12.40.19-edited-800x554.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Screenshot-2025-08-28-at-12.40.19-edited-450x311.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Screenshot-2025-08-28-at-12.40.19-edited-900x623.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Screenshot-2025-08-28-at-12.40.19-edited-216x150.png 216w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 2016px) 100vw, 2016px" /></figure></div>


<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Check out our technology pages</a></div>
</div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What’s next?</h2>



<p>We’ve heard from mentors that our projects are too long to print out. We’re working to improve that, starting with brand-new short PDFs for the Intro to Scratch path projects. Each PDF is no more than six pages, double-sided.</p>



<p>Are there other projects you’d like to see PDF versions of? <a href="https://form.raspberrypi.org/4874134">Let us know.</a>&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re currently working on an idea tentatively titled “project challenges”. If you’re interested in helping us develop the idea, <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://form.raspberrypi.org/4874134&amp;sa=D&amp;source=docs&amp;ust=1756380196157806&amp;usg=AOvVaw1yzxl1eNoY29z2_1-pZW8R">please get in touch</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>If you have not started a club yet but are interested in supporting the young people in your community to explore coding, you can find out more on the <a href="https://codeclub.org/en/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Code Club</a> website. The team will support you every step of the way with resources, training, and a collaborative community.</strong></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/improvements-to-the-code-club-projects-website/">Improvements to the Code Club Projects website</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/improvements-to-the-code-club-projects-website/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Code, confidence, and community: A look back at Astro Pi 2024–25</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-confidence-and-community-a-look-back-at-astro-pi-2024-25/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-confidence-and-community-a-look-back-at-astro-pi-2024-25/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jaskaran Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 11:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Astro Pi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mission Space Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mission Zero]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european astro pi challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Impact of our work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[astro pi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=91323</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Taking part in the European Astro Pi Challenge builds young people’s confidence and motivates them to try further digital making and programming activities, according to their mentors. The challenge, a European Space Agency (ESA) Education project run in collaboration with the Raspberry Pi Foundation, offers young people the amazing opportunity to write a short computer&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-confidence-and-community-a-look-back-at-astro-pi-2024-25/">Code, confidence, and community: A look back at Astro Pi 2024–25</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Taking part in the European Astro Pi Challenge builds young people’s confidence and motivates them to try further digital making and programming activities, according to their mentors. The challenge, a European Space Agency (ESA) Education project run in collaboration with the Raspberry Pi Foundation, offers young people the amazing opportunity to write a short computer program to run on Raspberry Pi computers on board the International Space Station (ISS).</p>



<p>An incredible 27,304 young people from 27 countries got involved in Astro Pi 2024–25, with 26,294 succeeding in having their code run in space across the two challenge activities, Mission Zero and Mission Space Lab. As in past years, we’ve asked mentors and their teams about their experience and the impact participating had on them. So what did they say?</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How we listened to feedback</h2>



<p>To find out what worked well, what we could improve, and the impact Astro Pi has had on young people&#8217;s lives this year, we encouraged mentors to complete a survey after teams submitted their computer programs. We also ran focus group discussions to deepen our understanding. A huge thank you to the 99 Mission Zero and 26 Mission Space Lab mentors who completed our surveys, and the five mentors who participated in our focus groups.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="940" height="788" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/MSL-Earth-observation-images-24-25.png" alt="A selection of earth observation images captured by MSL teams." class="wp-image-91335" style="width:620px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/MSL-Earth-observation-images-24-25.png 940w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/MSL-Earth-observation-images-24-25-298x250.png 298w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/MSL-Earth-observation-images-24-25-500x419.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/MSL-Earth-observation-images-24-25-768x644.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/MSL-Earth-observation-images-24-25-800x671.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/MSL-Earth-observation-images-24-25-450x377.png 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">A selection of earth observation images captured by MSL teams</figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What is working well</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Low stakes but high impact</h3>



<p>Mentors believe that Astro Pi is a great opportunity for young people to build their coding skills and knowledge of STEM concepts. Close to 80% of mentors for Mission Zero and 90% for Mission Space Lab agreed that these outcomes were being achieved for the young people in their teams. Mentors also appreciated that while the programme had real-world application, the learning experience was relaxed and low pressure.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="603" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-4.png" alt="" class="wp-image-91324" style="width:720px" title="Chart" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-4.png 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-4-300x113.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-4-500x188.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-4-768x289.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-4-1536x579.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-4-800x302.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-4-450x170.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-4-900x339.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure></div>


<p>Many of our young participants come from areas of educational disadvantage or traditionally underrepresented groups where confidence with technology and STEM subjects can be low. Mentors reported that the programme empowers young people, increasing their confidence with computing and digital making, and helping them connect with a wider community of learners from around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“They [young people] come from complicated environments and sometimes their confidence is very low. They don&#8217;t believe in themselves and this [Mission Zero challenge] really empowers them.” — Mission Zero mentor</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;I think having a space mission, having Mission Zero is a way of connecting not only to a worldwide group of learners, but also explorers, future scientists, future astronauts. To see them as part of a larger community, not just an activity or assignment that they have to do in class. They discover their own abilities and potential, and exercise their creativity in a very low stakes environment… and then to see it come to life in that global way I think is extremely valuable.” — Mission Zero mentor</p>
</blockquote>



<p>This increased confidence also encourages young people to take on other opportunities. 78% of Mission Zero mentors and 96% of Mission Space Lab mentors believe that it is likely that their students will participate in other coding and digital making challenges in the future.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="753" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/IMG_20241030_153035_HDR.jpg" alt="A group of students at a Mission Space Lab hackathon event." class="wp-image-91328" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/IMG_20241030_153035_HDR.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/IMG_20241030_153035_HDR-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/IMG_20241030_153035_HDR-500x377.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/IMG_20241030_153035_HDR-768x578.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/IMG_20241030_153035_HDR-800x602.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/IMG_20241030_153035_HDR-450x339.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/IMG_20241030_153035_HDR-900x678.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">A group of students at a Mission Space Lab hackathon event</figcaption></figure></div>


<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Space is cool!</h3>



<p>The connection to space and the ISS continues to be a strong motivator, not just for young people but also mentors and other peers. In our survey, 90% of mentors in Mission Zero and 92% in Mission Space Lab reported that the young people participating were highly motivated by the possibility of having their code run on the ISS. In focus groups, mentors highlighted how the excitement of working on a space project extended to them and other adults too.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“They&#8217;ve always really enjoyed the sheer fact that you get to send stuff into space because it is really cool.” — Mission Zero mentor</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“You know, even the adults I tell about this say, ‘oh, that sounds amazing. Can I do it?’ I go, ‘No, you&#8217;re too old. I&#8217;m too old.’” — Mission Zero mentor</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;We want our code to run in space! We are fascinated by discovery and the opportunity to contribute to a real science experiment on the ISS.&#8221; — Mission Space Lab mentor</p>
</blockquote>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">The resources and guidance are useful</h3>



<p>We know how crucial mentors are to the success of Astro Pi. Mentors come from diverse backgrounds and we are committed to making sure they feel prepared and supported. We were thrilled to hear that over 90% of Mission Zero mentors and 80% of Mission Space Lab mentors found the Astro Pi resources useful.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I had no skills but the support proved to be excellent” — Mission Zero mentor</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Step-by-step instructions were excellent and really clear. Very easy to follow.” — Mission Zero mentor</p>
</blockquote>



<p>For Mission Space Lab, the more technical activity, we’ve been working on providing additional support. In 2024–25 we introduced a new online simulator tool for teams to test their programs with historical ISS data. Mentors found the tool to be helpful, allowing them to troubleshoot their code.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1200" height="1200" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Astro_Pi_Submissions_Closed_V2-03.png" alt="An illustration of the ISS sending files back to a satellite on Earth." class="wp-image-91341" style="width:620px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Astro_Pi_Submissions_Closed_V2-03.png 1200w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Astro_Pi_Submissions_Closed_V2-03-250x250.png 250w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Astro_Pi_Submissions_Closed_V2-03-500x500.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Astro_Pi_Submissions_Closed_V2-03-150x150.png 150w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Astro_Pi_Submissions_Closed_V2-03-768x768.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Astro_Pi_Submissions_Closed_V2-03-800x800.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Astro_Pi_Submissions_Closed_V2-03-100x100.png 100w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Astro_Pi_Submissions_Closed_V2-03-300x300.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Astro_Pi_Submissions_Closed_V2-03-450x450.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Astro_Pi_Submissions_Closed_V2-03-900x900.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">An illustration of the ISS sending files back to a satellite on Earth</figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What could be improved?</h2>



<p>While we celebrate the successes, we’re always keen to understand how we can improve the programme.</p>



<p>As in previous years, mentors reported that young people whose computer programs passed the eligibility criteria and ran on the ISS (or “achieved flight status&#8221;, as we call it) benefited most from the experience. While 12% more Mission Space Lab teams achieved flight status this year compared to last year, some registered teams still did not submit programs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To understand why, we surveyed mentors who had registered but who did not then submit computer programs. In the 55 responses, the main reasons given were a shortage of time due to other school commitments, and their teams finding the challenge difficult.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Some survey respondents suggested a need for more simplified, step-by-step instructions for less experienced learners. Additionally, a few teams faced technical issues with the online portal and the testing tool.</p>



<p>Thank you to all the mentors who provided their honest feedback. We’ve read and considered all of it and will use it to make Astro Pi even better in the future.</p>



<p>Astro Pi will be launching for its 10th year on Monday, 8 September 2025. We’ve been working on making it easier than ever to take part in both missions and are looking forward to supporting you and your teams in getting your code into space. If you’re interested in taking part, <a href="https://astro-pi.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up to our newsletter</a> and get the latest news and information about our resources for this year’s missions. </p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Important dates:</strong></h3>



<p>8 September 2025: The Astro Pi Challenge opens for registration</p>



<p>16 February 2026: Closing date for Mission Space Lab</p>



<p>23 March 2026: Closing date for Mission Zero</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-confidence-and-community-a-look-back-at-astro-pi-2024-25/">Code, confidence, and community: A look back at Astro Pi 2024–25</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-confidence-and-community-a-look-back-at-astro-pi-2024-25/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dedication to digital education in Bangladesh: Meet Shajan</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/dedication-to-digital-education-in-bangladesh-meet-shajan/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/dedication-to-digital-education-in-bangladesh-meet-shajan/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sophie Ashford]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 10:50:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Code Club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=91292</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We love hearing from members of the community and sharing stories of amazing young people, volunteers, and educators who are using their passion for technology to create positive change in the world around them. Today, we introduce Shajan, a digital storyteller and senior business advisor at the BBC, whose extraordinary personal and professional journey has&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/dedication-to-digital-education-in-bangladesh-meet-shajan/">Dedication to digital education in Bangladesh: Meet Shajan</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We love hearing from members of the community and sharing stories of amazing young people, volunteers, and educators who are using their passion for technology to create positive change in the world around them.</p>



<p>Today, we introduce Shajan, a digital storyteller and senior business advisor at the BBC, whose extraordinary personal and professional journey has led him to champion digital literacy for young people in Bangladesh.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1200" height="1600" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/CCBD-me-1.jpeg" alt="Shajan at a computer." class="wp-image-91298" style="width:520px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/CCBD-me-1.jpeg 1200w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/CCBD-me-1-188x250.jpeg 188w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/CCBD-me-1-500x667.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/CCBD-me-1-768x1024.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/CCBD-me-1-1152x1536.jpeg 1152w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/CCBD-me-1-800x1067.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/CCBD-me-1-450x600.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/CCBD-me-1-900x1200.jpeg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Family roots in Bangladesh</strong></h2>



<p>Shajan is British-born, but his roots deeply connect him to Bangladesh. This connection was instilled by childhood holidays to Bangladesh, as well as his late father, who emigrated to the UK in the 1960s but always encouraged Shajan to maintain ties with the community he left behind. Shajan&#8217;s pull towards Bangladesh intensified after his father&#8217;s passing fifteen years ago.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;I always thought I&#8217;d like to do something, carry on the work he left behind with efforts in building schools and supporting his local community.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The memory of his sister Khela, who passed away at just 12 years old while in Bangladesh, also motivates Shajan. He says, &#8220;She was a really creative person, really into her arts and crafts and learning.&#8221;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Khela&#8217;s loss fuels Shajan&#8217;s desire to do something specifically for the young people of Bangladesh, connecting with their potential for creativity and learning.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Setting off on a new path</strong></h2>



<p>Shajan&#8217;s 15 years of working for the BBC led him to discover the power of digital education. In 2015, he project-managed the BBC&#8217;s &#8220;Make It Digital&#8221; campaign, a UK-wide initiative addressing the National Digital Skills Gap.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As part of this, he led partnerships with organisations like <a href="https://codeclub.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Code Club</a>. </p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“That experience showed me how digital tools could unlock creativity in young people and build their confidence.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>During his visits to Bangladesh, Shajan observed a widening digital divide. Young people, especially in rural areas, lacked access to basic internet and computers. Teachers faced heavy workloads, and many students needed to pause their education to support their families. Seeing no equivalent to Code Club in Bangladesh to inspire young people, Shajan felt he had to act. Before he knew it, he was requesting a six-month career break.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;I said, &#8216;This is what I always wanted to do. If I don&#8217;t do it now, I will miss the opportunity.'&#8221;&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>With the support of both the BBC and Code Club, Shajan packed his bags and moved to Dhaka, the capital city of Bangladesh.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Creating a movement</strong></h2>



<p>Shajan&#8217;s initial goal was to raise awareness and build a sustainable model for Code Club in Bangladesh. Recognising that teachers needed support to run clubs, Shajan’s strategy was to engage university students as volunteers. He organised a national coding festival, leveraging these student volunteers to connect with schools and prepare young participants for a Scratch-based project challenge. The event received lots of media attention, encouraging interest and inspiring a new generation of coders.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2048" height="1365" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Code-Club-Bangladesh-National-Childrens-Coding-Festival-pic-1.jpg" alt="Students at Code Club Bangladesh." class="wp-image-91305" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Code-Club-Bangladesh-National-Childrens-Coding-Festival-pic-1.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Code-Club-Bangladesh-National-Childrens-Coding-Festival-pic-1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Code-Club-Bangladesh-National-Childrens-Coding-Festival-pic-1-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Code-Club-Bangladesh-National-Childrens-Coding-Festival-pic-1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Code-Club-Bangladesh-National-Childrens-Coding-Festival-pic-1-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Code-Club-Bangladesh-National-Childrens-Coding-Festival-pic-1-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Code-Club-Bangladesh-National-Childrens-Coding-Festival-pic-1-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/Code-Club-Bangladesh-National-Childrens-Coding-Festival-pic-1-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 2048px) 100vw, 2048px" /></figure></div>


<p>However, there were some hurdles that had to be worked around, including unreliable internet connections, limited access to computers, and unstable electricity supply. Beyond practical challenges, Shajan faced a crucial mindset shift.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Not everybody&#8217;s convinced yet that their children should be doing coding. For many families, generating immediate income takes precedence over digital education. Balancing the need to put food on the table with the long-term benefits of coding remains a constant battle.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Despite these obstacles, Shajan&#8217;s efforts proved successful. Some of the creators from the 2016–2017 classes, now in their twenties, have pursued computer science and now share how Code Club helped them on their paths. He also organised an incredible exchange program, bringing creators and mentors from Code Club South Korea to Bangladesh for a seven-day visit. Despite not sharing a language, creators connected through the language of code, an experience Shajan describes as inspiring for the young people and adults alike.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1200" height="1600" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/CC-South-KoreaV-isit-2017.jpg" alt="Students from South Korea visiting Code Club Bangladesh." class="wp-image-91303" style="width:520px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/CC-South-KoreaV-isit-2017.jpg 1200w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/CC-South-KoreaV-isit-2017-188x250.jpg 188w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/CC-South-KoreaV-isit-2017-500x667.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/CC-South-KoreaV-isit-2017-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/CC-South-KoreaV-isit-2017-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/CC-South-KoreaV-isit-2017-800x1067.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/CC-South-KoreaV-isit-2017-450x600.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/CC-South-KoreaV-isit-2017-900x1200.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>A new chapter</strong></h2>



<p>Shajan’s focus now is to launch a <a href="https://online.coolestprojects.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Coolest Projects</a> event in Sylhet, the place his father was born and a region he wants to focus on before taking Coolest Projects national as well.</p>



<p>He is actively engaging with teachers and student volunteers across the city, with strong support from Nooraiya Khan, an ICT Lecturer with a background in computer science. Nooraiya is working hard with Shajan to co-lead all Code Club activities in Bangladesh, bringing valuable expertise and shared passion to the movement.</p>



<p>Shajan believes the current digital landscape offers new opportunities. He is a strong advocate for the role of artificial intelligence (AI) in education, viewing it as a way to help bring opportunities to all young people. He plans to introduce <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/technology/ai_and_data" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">AI-focused Code Club projects</a> to Bangladesh, ensuring the next generation is prepared for a future driven by technology.</p>



<p>For Shajan, Code Club Bangladesh is &#8220;for everybody&#8221;. He wants to ensure that no child, especially girls and those from underserved communities, is left behind. He would welcome anyone interested in helping the young people of Bangladesh, including teachers, educators, tech professionals, and government bodies, to join Code Club Bangladesh’s journey.</p>



<p>If you’d like to support young people in your community to explore coding, why not start a Code Club? The team will support you every step of the way with resources, training, and a collaborative community.</p>



<p>Find out more on <a href="https://codeclub.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the Code Club website</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/dedication-to-digital-education-in-bangladesh-meet-shajan/">Dedication to digital education in Bangladesh: Meet Shajan</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/dedication-to-digital-education-in-bangladesh-meet-shajan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How social learning can lead to better outcomes in your computing classroom</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-social-learning-can-lead-to-better-outcomes-in-your-computing-classroom/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-social-learning-can-lead-to-better-outcomes-in-your-computing-classroom/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Sayers]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 12:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quick reads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research and impact]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pedagogy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=91283</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Throughout our lives, we’re constantly learning from others. Whether we’re interacting with teachers or trainers, or observing friends or strangers, we’re learning either deliberately or inadvertently. This process is known as ‘social learning’.&#160; In today’s blog, you&#8217;ll dive into what social learning is and how you can use it to create more engaging and effective&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-social-learning-can-lead-to-better-outcomes-in-your-computing-classroom/">How social learning can lead to better outcomes in your computing classroom</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Throughout our lives, we’re constantly learning from others. Whether we’re interacting with teachers or trainers, or observing friends or strangers, we’re learning either deliberately or inadvertently. This process is known as ‘social learning’.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In today’s blog, you&#8217;ll dive into what social learning is and how you can use it to create more engaging and effective learning experiences in your computing classroom.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="https://the-cc.io/qr27"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1200" height="630" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-3.png" alt="Image of our latest Pedagogy Quick Read" class="wp-image-91269" style="width:710px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-3.png 1200w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-3-300x158.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-3-500x263.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-3-768x403.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-3-800x420.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-3-450x236.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-3-900x473.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></a></figure></div>


<p>You&#8217;ll also find our latest <a href="https://the-cc.io/qr27" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pedagogy Quick Read, which explores social learning</a>. It’s free to download and includes:&nbsp;</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Practical tips for how to use social learning and related approaches with your learners</li>



<li>A summary of the research behind social learning</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What is social learning?</strong></h2>



<p>Social learning is simply any learning that involves other people. It can take any form, from watching a video, to taking part in a classroom discussion. It can take place in person or online, and it can happen without people realising they’re learning something.</p>



<p>Social learning is based on modelling and involves people observing and imitating the behaviours that others model. Albert Bandura, the acknowledged originator of social learning theory, suggested that social learning is guided by four related processes:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Attention: Recognising and focusing on someone’s behaviour and its vital elements</li>



<li>Retention: Creating a mental image and description to help you recall what you observed; practising responses (mentally or actively)</li>



<li>Reproduction: Translating the mental image back into actions</li>



<li>Motivation: Having a good reason to repeat (or avoid) the behaviours, depending on the rewards or punishments involved</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How can I enable social learning?</strong></h2>



<p>There’s lots of ways you can involve social learning in your computing classroom, including through other teaching approaches and frameworks.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-qw.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXddQBuLVR9P43LCtWyMpFQsUJK__lDxbEaWKlYnfMlxS7SPNSxQzw_37A5yoMqLYazKfKIDYCbgE-ODC-jvdUUzJRaGWvMLHB5HqBChxVu7jQFnd4bq0HyPQ5hKw9pqOxTDfXTMgA?key=1qFGVc53lQ3hqwvNuD6hiw" alt="4 children social learning in the classroom" style="width:652px;height:auto"/></figure></div>


<p>To help your learners get the most out of social learning, it&#8217;s best to:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Create a safe environment for learners to share learnings, ask questions, and actively engage in the learning process</li>



<li>Include a mix of resources and activities to ensure inclusion and accessibility</li>



<li>Set clear expectations and instructions, and ensure that social learning is key to achieve learning objectives</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Applying social learning: Some teaching approaches</strong></h3>



<p>Among our <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/teach/pedagogy/resources" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">pedagogy resources</a>, you&#8217;ll find lots of practical advice for teaching approaches that promote social learning. The approaches we recommend for the pedagogy principles &#8216;Work together&#8217; and &#8216;Model everything&#8217; are especially suitable.</p>



<p>Work together:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><a href="https://the-cc.io/qr03" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pair programming</a> (PDF)</li>



<li><a href="https://the-cc.io/qr04" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Peer instruction</a> (PDF)</li>



<li><a href="https://the-cc.io/qr15" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Project-based learning</a> (PDF)</li>



<li><a href="https://the-cc.io/qr16" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Physical computing</a> (PDF)</li>
</ul>



<p>Model everything:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><a href="https://the-cc.io/qr02" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Worked examples</a> (PDF)</li>



<li><a href="https://the-cc.io/qr05" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Live coding</a> (PDF)</li>



<li><a href="https://the-cc.io/qr24" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Levels of abstraction in programming</a> (PDF)</li>



<li><a href="https://the-cc.io/qr14" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Code tracing</a> (PDF)</li>
</ul>



<p>Using a <a href="https://the-cc.io/qr11" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PRIMM</a> (PDF) approach for structuring programming lessons, and encouraging students to talk about code as part of these, also works well for social learning.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Applying social learning: Practical examples</strong></h3>



<p>Let&#8217;s look at <a href="https://the-cc.io/qr03" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>pair programming</strong></a> as an example. In this activity, pairs of learners work together to create a computer program, taking on distinct roles that they swap regularly. One learner acts as the &#8216;driver&#8217;, writing the code, while the other is the &#8216;navigator&#8217;, guiding the process, reviewing the code, and identifying potential issues.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As they work, each learner is able to observe the other person’s approach, learning with and from their partner throughout the activity. This constant interaction and shared problem solving can help them to understand programming concepts better and to build stronger teamwork skills.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-qw.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXcQUJ_ygoMT3sPQEgUDhQ5JuciWnZFnDe70GykCegEG-HTjzWypO_Kw19RTtvpGdADPqmLNzJ7JsCXElnd8Bc9XsoE7gXn98Cup6uO4g-8I8fDemSrdhm_kN3dRjs5ZiQWOmNtWlA?key=1qFGVc53lQ3hqwvNuD6hiw" alt="Children in the classroom social learning" style="width:650px;height:auto"/></figure></div>


<p>Another example is setting your class the task to <strong>create shared digital resources</strong> on several topics everyone needs to learn about. In this activity, you split learners into small groups or pairs, and assign them a topic to later explain to the whole group. Grouped learners work together to create a resource explaining their topic. As the facilitator, you can either provide the information they need, or let them conduct their own research. At the end of the activity, each group presents their resource to the wider class.</p>



<p>An activity like this helps learners develop their knowledge through working together and talking to each other, and also provides the class with resources they can keep using.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The benefits of social learning</strong></h2>



<p>Potential benefits for teachers:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Improved student engagement and learning</li>



<li>Enhanced professional development experiences, leading to more confident teaching</li>
</ul>



<p>Potential benefits for students:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Improved social skills</li>



<li>Opportunities to build higher-level thinking skills</li>



<li>Deeper understanding and a greater ability to remember knowledge in the long term</li>
</ul>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://the-cc.io/qr27" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Download the Quick Read on social learning</a></div>
</div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>A social approach to shaping the future</strong></h2>



<p>In a world filled with complex challenges, there&#8217;s more need than ever for people to work together. By using social learning approaches in your classroom, you help your students to engage more deeply with your teaching and to develop the skills to succeed in collaboration with others. In this way, you&#8217;ll prepare them for navigating technological change as well as for shaping a common future where everyone can thrive.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-social-learning-can-lead-to-better-outcomes-in-your-computing-classroom/">How social learning can lead to better outcomes in your computing classroom</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-social-learning-can-lead-to-better-outcomes-in-your-computing-classroom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Celebrating impact: Code Clubs are thriving in Kenya and South Africa</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/celebrating-impact-code-clubs-are-thriving-in-kenya-and-south-africa/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/celebrating-impact-code-clubs-are-thriving-in-kenya-and-south-africa/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vicky Fisher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 09:02:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Code Club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[non-formal learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global clubs partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Impact of our work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research and impact]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=91237</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Across Kenya and South Africa, Code Clubs are going from strength to strength. We’re excited to share their incredible progress and positive impact with you and shine a spotlight on our fantastic partner organisations, whose support makes it all possible! Partnering up to increase our reach Code Club is a thriving global community of clubs&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/celebrating-impact-code-clubs-are-thriving-in-kenya-and-south-africa/">Celebrating impact: Code Clubs are thriving in Kenya and South Africa</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Across Kenya and South Africa, Code Clubs are <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/global-impact-empowering-young-people-in-kenya-and-south-africa/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">going from strength to strength</a>. We’re excited to share their incredible progress and positive impact with you and shine a spotlight on our fantastic partner organisations, whose support makes it all possible!</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="668" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6563.jpg" alt="Young people use laptops to do their coding tasks." class="wp-image-91250" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6563.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6563-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6563-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6563-768x513.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6563-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6563-450x301.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6563-900x601.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Partnering up to increase our reach</strong></h2>



<p>Code Club is a thriving global community of clubs where young people can develop the confidence to create with digital technologies in a fun and supportive space. In Kenya we’ve been working closely with <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/giving-back-through-code-club-meet-douglas/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Oasis Mathare</a>, Young Scientists Kenya, <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/computing-education-machakos-kenya-edtech-hub-launch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kenya Connect</a>, Tech Kidz Africa, STEAM Labs Africa, and Futures Infinite, while in South Africa we’ve teamed up with Keep a Child Alive and <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/highlights-from-coolest-projects-south-africa-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Coder:Level Up</a>.</p>



<p>We used a train-the-trainer model to help our partners in Kenya and South Africa train Code Club mentors. We began by training community trainers from each partner, who then went on to deliver training to club mentors. This has allowed us to reach 1,498 mentors across both countries. Club mentors told us how grateful they have been to these partners for their ongoing support, including providing training and visiting the clubs.</p>



<p>As part of our ongoing evaluation of the Code Club programme in Kenya and South Africa, we’ve collected feedback from our partners, club mentors, and creators via feedback surveys, club visits, and focus groups to help us understand the impact of our work.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="668" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6622.jpg" alt="Douglas from Oasis Mathare (second from left) with members of the Raspberry Pi Foundation team." class="wp-image-91253" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6622.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6622-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6622-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6622-768x513.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6622-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6622-450x301.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6622-900x601.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Reaching areas of disadvantage</strong></h2>



<p>There are 397 Code Clubs running in Kenya and 622 in South Africa — we estimate we’re reaching over 42,000 young people through Code Clubs and nearly 20,000 through related one-off events such as summer programmes.</p>



<p>This broad reach means that young people who might otherwise have had limited or no access to computing are now engaging with coding, and doing so in truly exciting ways.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One Kenyan Code Club leader, working in a particularly disadvantaged and marginalised area, said Code Club was so important to young people as it means &#8220;you don&#8217;t have to be left behind&#8221;.<em> </em>They shared that such a large number are attending the club — and that many more are wanting to join — because young people are&nbsp; eager to be<em> </em>&#8220;part of the digital future&#8221;.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Impact on young people</strong></h2>



<p>89% of surveyed mentors reported an increase in their young people’s skills in coding and confidence to engage with emerging technology.&nbsp;</p>



<p>According to one South African Code Club mentor, taking part in Code Club “changes your perception and thinking…. it&#8217;s possible to do things… it becomes a reality because it&#8217;s not a really difficult thing. It&#8217;s something that you can do step by step and it really changes the mindset. It really redefines how someone thinks.”</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="668" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6594.jpg" alt="Young people work together on a coding task." class="wp-image-91258" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6594.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6594-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6594-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6594-768x513.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6594-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6594-450x301.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6594-900x601.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>Mentors consistently told us that young people are collaborating more, and supporting each other in their learning journeys. One South African young person perfectly captured this spirit:<em> </em>&#8220;if they don&#8217;t know something, we can teach it to them.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mentors also shared that young people are inspired to continue developing their coding and computing skills beyond club sessions. They&#8217;re actively seeking opportunities to deepen their knowledge and are already thinking about how they could use their newfound skills in their future careers.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Empowering Code Club mentors</strong></h2>



<p>Overall, club mentors felt well prepared to run clubs and found the training high quality and useful. This is reflected in the high percentage of mentors who agreed that the training increased their skills, confidence, and knowledge, with some partners showing an agreement rate as high as 91%.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Partners have also worked hard delivering extra training on requested topics such as additional computer skills and mentorship to help mentors feel more confident running Code Clubs.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="667" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6604.jpg" alt="A mentor running a Code Club." class="wp-image-91260" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6604.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6604-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6604-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6604-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6604-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6604-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/DSC_6604-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Continuing to improve</strong></h2>



<p>We recognise the unique challenges that can arise when running clubs in areas of Kenya and South Africa where access to technology and the internet isn’t always consistent. We’re continuing to develop resources and support for these clubs, as well as working with partners to better understand what their clubs need.</p>



<p>We’re also continually reflecting on and refining our train-the-trainer model to understand how best to equip community trainers with the confidence and skills they need to train others.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Next steps</strong></h2>



<p>The dedication and hard work of our partners have been instrumental in allowing us to significantly expand our reach and impact in Kenya and South Africa. Alongside this incredible growth, we&#8217;ve strengthened our commitment by increasing the size of our teams operating directly from both countries. This means we can continue to grow our support for our thriving Code Club communities.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re excited to have a number of new partners setting up Code Clubs over the next year. We look forward to sharing the invaluable insights and feedback we&#8217;ve received from our existing partners to ensure our new partners are fully supported and feel empowered to deliver transformative Code Clubs in their areas.</p>



<p>Watch this space!</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/celebrating-impact-code-clubs-are-thriving-in-kenya-and-south-africa/">Celebrating impact: Code Clubs are thriving in Kenya and South Africa</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/celebrating-impact-code-clubs-are-thriving-in-kenya-and-south-africa/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Opening the box: Tools to teach young people about AI</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/opening-the-box-tools-to-teach-young-people-about-ai/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/opening-the-box-tools-to-teach-young-people-about-ai/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Bonnie Sheppard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 11:09:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research seminar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI literacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research and impact]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=91216</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>New research by the Alan Turing Institute, published in June, shows that in the UK nearly one in four children aged 8 to 12 is using artificial intelligence (AI) tools like ChatGPT. With learners exploring these tools at such young ages, it’s more urgent than ever to develop teaching resources that help them understand how&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/opening-the-box-tools-to-teach-young-people-about-ai/">Opening the box: Tools to teach young people about AI</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>New research by the <a href="https://www.turing.ac.uk/news/experts-call-greater-focus-childrens-ai-use-research-shows-nearly-1-4-children-use-ai-learning" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Alan Turing Institute</a>, published in June, shows that in the UK nearly one in four children aged 8 to 12 is using artificial intelligence (AI) tools like ChatGPT. With learners exploring these tools at such young ages, it’s more urgent than ever to develop teaching resources that help them understand how AI works.</p>



<p>One of the biggest challenges with AI is that it’s hard to tell how these tools function. With a chatbot, you enter a prompt and the tool returns a response, but what happens in between is invisible. For educators, that’s a problem: how can we help young people become thoughtful, creative users of AI tools if the technology feels like a closed box?</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-1 is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-is-layout-flex">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="650" data-id="91217" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-500x650.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-91217" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-500x650.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-192x250.jpeg 192w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-768x998.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-800x1040.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-450x585.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-900x1170.jpeg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image.jpeg 950w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="650" data-id="91218" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1-500x650.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-91218" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1-500x650.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1-192x250.jpeg 192w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1-768x998.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1-800x1040.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1-450x585.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1-900x1170.jpeg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1.jpeg 950w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure>
</figure>



<p>In our May research seminar, we welcomed <strong>Matti Tedre</strong> and <strong>Henriikka Vartiainen</strong> from the University of Eastern Finland. They’ve been <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/machine-learning-education-school-computational-thinking-2-0-research-seminar/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">working on how to teach about AI for years</a> and were frustrated with existing educational platforms: many of these are either too complex, raise privacy concerns, or rely on coding skills that not all students (or teachers) have. In response, they created an <a href="https://tm.gen-ai.fi/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">award-winning, classroom-friendly tool</a> designed to make AI technology more transparent and more hands-on.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>A practical way to teach AI in schools</strong></h2>



<p>Matti and Henriikka began by discussing the unique challenges of teaching young learners about AI technology. Many students start with “folk theories”, for example, thinking that computers understand language like humans do. These misconceptions can be surprisingly hard to shake.</p>



<p>They also pointed out broader issues:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>The abstract nature of AI means there are very few research-based approaches to teaching it effectively</li>



<li>Mastery of AI concepts requires sustained practice and curricular change, not just a few one-off interventions</li>



<li>In countries like Finland, where programming isn’t part of the curriculum, any teaching tool must be no-code to be accessible</li>
</ul>



<p>To address these challenges, Matti and Henriikka have spent three years co-designing tools and approaches with local schools, teachers, and over 200 students. Their approach is grounded in educational theory and a set of core AI learning principles:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>No-code for inclusivity:</strong> Removing the need for programming lowers the barrier to entry for both teachers and students</li>



<li><strong>Learner-centred co-design:</strong> Every part of the experience is developed in collaboration with schools to make sure it’s engaging and relevant</li>



<li><strong>Working with personal data:</strong> Learners create and work with their own data sets, which makes the experience more engaging and personally relevant</li>



<li><strong>Integration with school subjects:</strong> Integrating AI concepts into other subjects helps to make the uses of AI tools more concrete for learners</li>



<li><strong>Focus on specific applications:</strong> Rather than teaching about generic ‘AI’, the focus is on specific and understandable applications, such as facial recognition</li>



<li><strong>Hands-on experimentation:</strong> Practical projects help students understand tricky ideas like bias, fairness, and social impact</li>



<li><strong>Collaborative learning:</strong> Working together helps students reflect, question, and learn from each other</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>GenAI Teachable Machine: Opening the box</strong></h2>



<p>Frustrated by existing platforms that require programming skills, raise privacy concerns, or don’t allow collaboration, Matti and Henriikka’s team developed <a href="https://tm.gen-ai.fi/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GenAI Teachable Machine</a>: a no-code, browser-based tool designed to make key AI concepts tangible. In <a href="https://infedu.vu.lt/journal/INFEDU/article/779/info" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the central research study</a>, the team used the tool with Finnish students in grade 4–7 (10 to 14 years of age). It&#8217;s a great introductory tool that could also be used with younger and older students.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1285" height="482" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image.png" alt="GenAI Teachable Machine is freely available online and maintains a “line of sight”: All important steps are visible to the learner." class="wp-image-91219" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image.png 1285w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-300x113.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-500x188.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-768x288.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-800x300.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-450x169.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-900x338.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1285px) 100vw, 1285px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>GenAI Teachable Machine is freely available online and maintains a “line of sight”: All important steps are visible to the learner</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Matti demonstrated how the tool addresses their core AI learning principles with a simple, creative project. Using hand puppets, he trained a model to recognise four distinct classes: a background, a bunny, a calm wolf, and an angry wolf. For each class, he assigned a specific action: a sound, an image, or both. This hands-on process gives students a direct line of sight from the data they might create (visuals of hand puppets) to the final behaviour of the model (outputted sounds and images). They learn about classifiers, training, and confidence levels not as abstract definitions, but as creative tools they can control.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="823" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1.png" alt="Matti Tedre demonstrating a bunny and wolf recognition model." class="wp-image-91220" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1.png 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1-300x154.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1-500x257.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1-768x395.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1-1536x790.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1-800x412.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1-450x231.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1-900x463.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Matti Tedre demonstrating a bunny and wolf recognition model</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>But the learning really starts when things don’t work as expected. Students can easily open their models on their phones with an automatically created QR code and then move around the classroom to test their models. At this point, they quickly notice how fragile AI technology can be. For example, in the case of a simple recognition model trained on specific colours or features, with a change of lighting or a different shirt, the model might fail. These “failures” turn into powerful lessons. For instance, a face-recognition app trained mostly on students with blonde hair might not work well for someone with brown hair — sparking immediate conversations about bias. As Matti put it, students very quickly start asking deep questions.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1728" height="1152" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/03/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-8.jpg" alt="In a computing classroom, two girls concentrate on their programming task." class="wp-image-78793" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/03/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-8.jpg 1728w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/03/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-8-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/03/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-8-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/03/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-8-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/03/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-8-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/03/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-8-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/03/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-8-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/03/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-8-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1728px) 100vw, 1728px" /></figure></div>


<p>GenAI Teachable Machine also allows students to apply their AI models to the physical world. By connecting to a simple, low-cost robotics kit, students can use their models to control motors, lights, and other actuators. This step into the physical world teaches fundamental concepts that are difficult to grasp in a purely virtual environment. Students learn about causality, as their model&#8217;s classifications trigger real, physical actions. They also learn about the need for a world model — an understanding of how the physical world works — and see that they must take responsibility for what happens when their abstract models have real-world consequences.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1128" height="602" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-2.png" alt="Examples of students’ robot creations." class="wp-image-91221" style="width:720px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-2.png 1128w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-2-300x160.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-2-500x267.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-2-768x410.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-2-800x427.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-2-450x240.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-2-900x480.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1128px) 100vw, 1128px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Examples of students’ robot creations</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>By combining a no-code platform with practical, well-designed learning experiences, Matti, Henriikka, and their team are showing what AI education can look like: hands-on, accessible, and grounded in real understanding. Their work is helping students see inside the box, and giving them the tools to think critically about the AI technologies that are becoming part of their everyday lives.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Find out more</strong></h2>



<p>If you&#8217;re an educator interested in including the topic of AI in your teaching, <a href="http://tm.gen-ai.fi" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">you can try GenAI Teachable Machine on its official website</a>.</p>



<p>You may also be interested in our own <a href="https://experience-ai.org/en/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Experience AI</a> resources, which are designed to help you and your learners navigate the fast-moving world of AI and machine learning technologies.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Join us at our next seminar</strong></h2>



<p>In September, Matti and his team are returning to discuss other ways to teach young people about AI technologies.</p>



<p>To sign up and take part in the Matti&#8217;s seminar on Tues 9 Sept at 17:00–18:30 BST, click the button below. We&#8217;ll then send you information about joining. We hope to see you there.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research-impact/research/seminars" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">I want to join the next seminar</a></div>
</div>



<p>The <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research-impact/research/seminars" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">schedule of our upcoming seminars is online</a>. You can catch up on past seminars on our <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research-impact/research/seminars/previous" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">previous seminars page</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/opening-the-box-tools-to-teach-young-people-about-ai/">Opening the box: Tools to teach young people about AI</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/opening-the-box-tools-to-teach-young-people-about-ai/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Adapting our computing curriculum resources for Odisha — the journey so far</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-our-computing-curriculum-resources-for-odisha-the-journey-so-far/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-our-computing-curriculum-resources-for-odisha-the-journey-so-far/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Fiona Coventry]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 10:56:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Computing Curriculum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Impact of our work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Odisha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research and impact]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=91177</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Today&#8217;s blog is the second in a mini-series of three sharing our experiences of adapting computing curriculum resources for different contexts, and of training teachers to use them in schools. Last month we wrote about our collaboration with partners in Kenya. Here we discuss our work in Odisha, India. This article has been written by&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-our-computing-curriculum-resources-for-odisha-the-journey-so-far/">Adapting our computing curriculum resources for Odisha — the journey so far</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Today&#8217;s blog is the second in a mini-series of three sharing our experiences of adapting computing curriculum resources for different contexts, and of training teachers to use them in schools. <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-our-computing-curriculum-resources-for-kenya-the-journey-so-far/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Last month we wrote about our collaboration with partners in Kenya</a>. Here we discuss our work in Odisha, India.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="750" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3118-1.jpg" alt="Teachers at a teacher training in Odisha." class="wp-image-91193" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3118-1.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3118-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3118-1-500x375.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3118-1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3118-1-800x600.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3118-1-450x338.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3118-1-900x675.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>This article has been written by Fiona Coventry, Impact Manager, and Mamta Manaktala, Senior Learning Manager.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A long-term partnership in Odisha</h2>



<p>We know that building long-term partnerships with organisations that have local expertise is key to making a real impact for young people. This fact was echoed by people involved in education initiatives worldwide who spoke at the <a href="https://www.wwhge.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">What Works Hub for Global Education</a> 2024 annual conference, which Fiona followed online. Our work in Odisha is an example of this.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="750" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3569-1.jpg" alt="Teachers at a teacher training in Odisha." class="wp-image-91197" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3569-1.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3569-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3569-1-500x375.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3569-1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3569-1-800x600.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3569-1-450x338.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3569-1-900x675.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>We have now been working with our government partner in Odisha, Panchasakha Shikhya Setu (formerly Mo School Abhiyan), for four years. Our journey began in 2021, when we worked together to <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-club-eastern-india-computer-science-education/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">establish a network of Code Clubs in government and government-aided schools</a> in the state. In 2023, our focus shifted to <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/introducing-a-computing-curriculum-in-odisha/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">developing a formal computing curriculum for students in grades 9 and 10</a> (known locally as the Kaushali curriculum), in collaboration with two other partners.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Work in the 2024/2025 academic year</h2>



<p>Adaptation is a crucial aspect of how we ensure our computing resources are accessible to as many young people as possible. For our work in Odisha, we <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/computing-curriculum-framework-adapting-to-indias-diverse-landscapes/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">adapted content from The Computing Curriculum</a> and then localised it to fit the requirement of the students.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="750" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Day4-11.jpeg" alt="Teachers at a teacher training in Odisha." class="wp-image-91205" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Day4-11.jpeg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Day4-11-300x225.jpeg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Day4-11-500x375.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Day4-11-768x576.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Day4-11-800x600.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Day4-11-450x338.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Day4-11-900x675.jpeg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>In Odisha&#8217;s June 2024 to April 2025 academic year, we rolled out adapted computing curriculum content for grade 10 students, for students who had already learned with adapted grade 9 content in 2023/24. We worked with our partners to develop the curriculum content and trained 310 master teachers from across Odisha, along with 30 State Resource Groups (SRGs) to support them. Before the end of 2024, the 310 master teachers subsequently trained 8109 teachers, who would reach an estimated 880,000 students with the grade 9 and 10 curriculum content. We had an ongoing responsibility to support 1846 of these teachers in our allocated districts, with an estimated reach to around 205,000 students.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Impact of the grade 9 and 10 curriculum</h2>



<p>In early 2025 we issued a follow-up survey about student learning, content, and training to a sample of teachers in our allocated districts, and 310 teachers responded. (We used a stratified sampling approach designed to ensure the survey results were representative of all teachers.)</p>



<p>At least 87% of teachers agreed that students achieved the outcomes we asked about, e.g. regarding coding skills, staying safe online, and use of data in machine intelligence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Moreover, responses related to our grade 9 curriculum remained similarly high compared to 2024 survey responses.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-2.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="968" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-2.png" alt="2025 Odisha teacher survey responses regarding their students' learning." class="wp-image-91179" style="width:720px" title="Chart" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-2.png 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-2-300x182.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-2-500x303.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-2-768x465.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-2-1536x929.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-2-800x484.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-2-450x272.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-2-900x545.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">2025 Odisha teacher survey responses regarding their students&#8217; learning. Click to enlarge.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Teachers also expressed their appreciation for the computing curriculum resources and training in free-text comments and interviews, for example:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“IT and coding is essential nowadays. So a good initiative, adding this to schools&#8217; curriculum.” – Teacher in Odisha</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The training was quite informative, interesting and helpful.” – Teacher in Odisha</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“It is very useful training for me. It boosts my knowledge and helps me for classroom transaction.” – Teacher in Odisha</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Addressing challenges</h2>



<p>An ongoing challenge in Odisha has been supporting those teachers who lack experience with computing and/or with our <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/teach/pedagogy/resources" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">recommended teaching approaches for computing</a>. We have been working hard to help these teachers develop the knowledge, skills, and confidence to effectively deliver the curriculum content in the limited time they have alongside their other professional commitments.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="750" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3162-1.jpg" alt="Teachers at a teacher training in Odisha." class="wp-image-91201" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3162-1.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3162-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3162-1-500x375.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3162-1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3162-1-800x600.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3162-1-450x338.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3162-1-900x675.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>In the 2023/2024 academic year, many teachers had told us they needed further training and support. For this reason, we offered longer training in the 2024/25 academic year. We also adapted our training approach based on learning from earlier phases, such as including activities teachers could complete on their smartphones, enabling more hands-on learning while reducing dependence on available IT equipment. The outcome of this was positive: in the follow-up survey, fewer teachers felt they needed additional training to deliver the lessons, and most teachers we interviewed felt this year&#8217;s training was an improvement on the previous year&#8217;s.</p>



<p>Our team also ran weekly webinars to support teachers and address their queries. These were very well received by teachers. Of the responses received to feedback form available after each webinar:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>97% agreed that the “webinar helped me to understand the topics covered more clearly.”</li>



<li>98% agreed that the “webinar was useful to support my teaching.”</li>
</ul>



<p>This was supported by comments from teachers, for example:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“All questions were answered. The webinar was good. Gained a lot. Thank you very much.”&nbsp; – Teacher in Odisha</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I learned many unknown things about Scratch, it will help my classroom teaching.” – Teacher in Odisha</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In this year&#8217;s follow-up survey, teachers also less frequently indicated they felt they needed “additional content to support students”. They provided useful feedback and suggestions regarding the curriculum content, e.g. further simplifying and localising it, which we will incorporate into future resource development.</p>



<p>Another persistent challenge has been limited access to IT equipment and the internet in schools, and what this means for student-device ratios and how teachers are able to deliver the content. For future resources we are developing, we are therefore adapting the amount of content to be delivered over a series of lessons.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Next steps for our partnership in Odisha</h2>



<p>In 2025, we are working with the same partners to implement a curriculum for grades 6 to 8, initially in around 460 schools. We and our partners have developed the curriculum content and are currently in the process of training teachers in preparation for classroom delivery.</p>



<p>We are also continuing to support the teachers previously trained on the grade 9 and 10 curriculum through webinars and school visits.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Want to see our curriculum resources?</h2>



<p>You can access our <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/curriculum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">free Computing Curriculum resources on our website</a> — we are currently working to make the materials for India, and for Kenya, downloadable there.</p>



<p>Look out for the final blog in this mini-series next month, which will focus on our computer science curriculum in Telangana, India.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-our-computing-curriculum-resources-for-odisha-the-journey-so-far/">Adapting our computing curriculum resources for Odisha — the journey so far</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-our-computing-curriculum-resources-for-odisha-the-journey-so-far/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>From coder to mentor: Meet Isabelle</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/from-coder-to-mentor-meet-isabelle/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/from-coder-to-mentor-meet-isabelle/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sophie Ashford]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 10:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Code Club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=91156</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We love hearing from members of the community and sharing stories of amazing young people, volunteers, and educators who are using their passion for technology to create positive change in the world around them. Meet Isabelle, a youth mentor at a library Code Club, whose inspiring story tells how a passion for helping others and&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/from-coder-to-mentor-meet-isabelle/">From coder to mentor: Meet Isabelle</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We love hearing from members of the community and sharing stories of amazing young people, volunteers, and educators who are using their passion for technology to create positive change in the world around them.</p>



<p>Meet Isabelle, a youth mentor at a library Code Club, whose inspiring story tells how a passion for helping others and a love for reading led back to a childhood interest, shaping an unexpected and rewarding journey.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1080" height="1377" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-celebrating-her-18th-birthday.jpg" alt="Isabelle celebrating her 18th birthday." class="wp-image-91166" style="width:520px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-celebrating-her-18th-birthday.jpg 1080w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-celebrating-her-18th-birthday-196x250.jpg 196w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-celebrating-her-18th-birthday-500x638.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-celebrating-her-18th-birthday-768x979.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-celebrating-her-18th-birthday-800x1020.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-celebrating-her-18th-birthday-450x574.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-celebrating-her-18th-birthday-900x1148.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1080px) 100vw, 1080px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Saturdays spent at the library</strong></h2>



<p>Isabelle&#8217;s coding journey began around the age of nine. An avid reader, she regularly attended her local library in Stourbridge with her gran. When they saw there was a Code Club held on a Saturday morning, they both decided it might be a good skill for Isabelle to learn.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;I used to have like an entire folder of all the projects I’d completed. I&#8217;ve still got it somewhere in my room!&#8221;&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>She quickly progressed through Scratch, Python, and HTML, even finding herself teaching the adults at the club at some points! But, as secondary school approached, her involvement naturally tapered off as she began to focus on her studies.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>A return through volunteering&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p>In secondary school, Isabelle was looking for volunteering opportunities as part of her Duke of Edinburgh (DofE) award. Remembering her positive experiences at the library, and continued love of books, she initially considered volunteering there. Then, she had an idea.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I suddenly thought ‘What if they still do Code Club?’ I really enjoyed it when I did it and I still remembered enough about it to help others. So, I felt like I could actually be useful instead.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Isabelle reached out, and thanks to her gran&#8217;s long-standing connection with the library, she was remembered and welcomed back. What started as a three-month commitment for her DofE award soon extended to six.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I really looked forward to each session at the library and decided to stick with it for the whole time.”</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Embracing the chaos and connection</strong></h2>



<p>Isabelle&#8217;s return coincided with the Code Club restarting. Stepping into a mentoring role, she quickly found herself in the thick of it. With five computers and a group of new young people, most of whom had no prior coding experience, the first sessions were a whirlwind.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s like the best kind of chaos. It doesn&#8217;t get easier as such. But it&#8217;s so fun meeting these new kids, they&#8217;re all different and they bounce off each other.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>She works closely with Lucy, the club leader, helping manage the flow of projects and supporting the children as they navigate everything from creating Scratch accounts to tackling challenging projects.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="750" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-at-her-club-in-Stourbridge-with-Code-Club-Community-Coordinator-Rujeko.jpg" alt="Isabelle at her club in Stourbridge with Code Club Community Coordinator Rujeko." class="wp-image-91168" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-at-her-club-in-Stourbridge-with-Code-Club-Community-Coordinator-Rujeko.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-at-her-club-in-Stourbridge-with-Code-Club-Community-Coordinator-Rujeko-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-at-her-club-in-Stourbridge-with-Code-Club-Community-Coordinator-Rujeko-500x375.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-at-her-club-in-Stourbridge-with-Code-Club-Community-Coordinator-Rujeko-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-at-her-club-in-Stourbridge-with-Code-Club-Community-Coordinator-Rujeko-800x600.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-at-her-club-in-Stourbridge-with-Code-Club-Community-Coordinator-Rujeko-450x338.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-at-her-club-in-Stourbridge-with-Code-Club-Community-Coordinator-Rujeko-900x675.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Isabelle with Lucy, Stourbridge Library Assistant, and Rujeko, Code Club Community Coordinator</figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>More than just code</strong></h2>



<p>While the technical skills are central, Isabelle emphasises that Code Club offers so much more. She&#8217;s seen shy children blossom, making new friends and becoming more involved.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I think there&#8217;s the whole element of socialising as well. And beyond coding, kids develop essential IT skills, like learning how to use a mouse and keyboard. Something many who just use tablets and phones don&#8217;t know!”</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Four years and counting&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p>Isabelle, now preparing to go on to further education, could not have predicted how her mentoring journey would turn out. What began as a three-month DofE requirement has turned into a four-year commitment.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“It has just never been something that I thought &#8216;oh, I don&#8217;t want to do this anymore&#8217;. It&#8217;s just part of the weekly routine now. It&#8217;s been four years and it&#8217;s shocking how quickly it&#8217;s gone.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Isabelle&#8217;s dedication hasn&#8217;t gone unnoticed. She&#8217;s built strong bonds with the staff and gained invaluable experience. She&#8217;s learned to organise, work in a team, and even run sessions independently, developing skills that will be invaluable for her future.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;I like the bond that I have with the staff and with Lucy. It feels great to be trusted that much and it has just been such a nice experience.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Lucy, Stourbridge Code Club leader and Library Assistant, shared her experience with the club and collaborating.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Since Code Club offers so much more than just coding — confidence building, creativity, friendship, etc. — it plays an important role for children and young people in the community. The library is much more than just a place for books, and hosting Code Club here creates a welcoming space where young people can explore technology away from the classroom.”</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Isabelle has been absolutely fantastic both in supporting us with club admin as well as supporting the children with their coding! She understands the projects inside and out and is brilliant at not only solving problems, but also, importantly, encouraging the club to find ways of solving problems themselves. Our Code Club couldn&#8217;t have become what it is today without her input!”</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Isabelle&#8217;s advice for future mentors</strong></h2>



<p>As Isabelle prepares to head off to the Bath Spa University to study media communications and publishing, she offers this advice for other young people considering becoming a Code Club mentor…”just go for it!”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Isabelle admits to being anxious at times, but the experience has significantly boosted her confidence.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“It built my confidence a bit more. You make friends along the way and you learn a lot of new things. And don&#8217;t worry if you don’t have a lot of coding experience. I don&#8217;t think you need it. I had a little bit but I was still basing it mainly off of reading the project instructions. And in all fairness, the instructions are really helpful!”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Mentoring at Code Club isn&#8217;t just about teaching, it&#8217;s about learning, growing, and connecting. It&#8217;s an opportunity to give back, build confidence, and discover the joy in supporting the next generation of digital creators. As Isabelle&#8217;s journey shows, sometimes the most rewarding paths are the ones you never planned to take.</p>



<p>Lucy shared why she thinks having youth mentors involved with Code Club is such an important dynamic.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Youth mentors are great as role models and inspiration for children, and as a young person themselves they build such a great rapport with the club members. A mentor who’s closer to their age often feels more approachable, which helps create a comfortable and encouraging environment for them.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>If Isabelle&#8217;s story has inspired you, why not explore the world of coding? You can get started at home with over 250 free projects on the Code Club Projects website.</p>



<p>Looking for a little extra support in your own coding journey or open to mentoring others? Join a Code Club near you to meet a like-minded and supportive community.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/from-coder-to-mentor-meet-isabelle/">From coder to mentor: Meet Isabelle</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/from-coder-to-mentor-meet-isabelle/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to rapidly design and adapt quality learning experiences for your students</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-rapidly-design-and-adapt-quality-learning-experiences-for-your-students/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-rapidly-design-and-adapt-quality-learning-experiences-for-your-students/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Sayers]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 11:18:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research and impact]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ABC learning design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pedagogy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quick reads]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=91133</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>At this time of year, many educators are considering ways to update their content ahead of the new school term. Whether you’re a teaching assistant or head of department, it’s important to ensure that the content you’re updating — or even designing anew — is relevant and high quality, and meet learners’ needs. In today’s&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-rapidly-design-and-adapt-quality-learning-experiences-for-your-students/">How to rapidly design and adapt quality learning experiences for your students</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>At this time of year, many educators are considering ways to update their content ahead of the new school term. Whether you’re a teaching assistant or head of department, it’s important to ensure that the content you’re updating — or even designing anew — is relevant and high quality, and meet learners’ needs. In today’s blog we’re highlighting ‘ABC learning design’, and how it can be used to rapidly design and improve learning experiences.<br></p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-qw.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXc5FiRZIxZeO5tZYPZP6AccA7y83hELUEmRFpo-63hEHDaUqLX1395XdlYt0La02CkxlLXaNMpbWSGOjWo6sjqAsbqql4yrjf07rDPdFDqJUqneQt94eNHTjdhkKf4dELU4geutPQ?key=sKycVwYnLSkTt5scPtoJgQ" alt="Educators in the classroom" style="width:628px;height:auto"/></figure></div>


<p>We also share our <a href="https://the-cc.io/qr25" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new ABC-focused Pedagogy Quick Read</a>, which you can download for free to:&nbsp;</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Find practical tips on how to use the ABC process and related approaches with your learners</li>



<li>Read a summary of the research behind the framework</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What is ABC learning design?</strong></h2>



<p>ABC learning design is a rapid, hands-on approach to design and develop blended learning experiences. The framework has traditionally been used at undergrad level, and had a lot of success when used in response to the global pandemic in 2020, when learning experiences had to quickly transition from being delivered in-person to being accessible remotely.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The model is centred around six learning types:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Acquisition: Learning by reading, listening, or watching</li>



<li>Collaboration: Learning by working with others towards a common goal, involving co-creation and shared outputs</li>



<li>Discussion: Learning through dialogue, sharing ideas, and responding to others</li>



<li>Investigation: Learning by exploring, comparing, and evaluating new information or experiences</li>



<li>Practice: Learning by applying knowledge and skills, receiving feedback, and refining understanding</li>



<li>Production: Learning by expressing understanding or creating something to demonstrate knowledge and skills</li>
</ul>



<p>Before continuing, it&#8217;s important to distinguish between &#8216;learning types&#8217; and the widely discredited concept of &#8216;learning styles&#8217;. Whilst learning styles refer to fixed characteristics or preferences of learners, learning types refer to different kinds of learning activities and pedagogical approaches that can be designed into a course.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1200" height="630" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image.png" alt="Copy of the ABC learning design Pedagogy Quick Read" class="wp-image-91136" style="width:670px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image.png 1200w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-300x158.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-500x263.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-768x403.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-800x420.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-450x236.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-900x473.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></figure></div>


<p>These learning types are representative simplifications of pre-existing learning theories. For each learning type, educators can use different activities to deliver that type of learning. The activities will depend on your context and what’s right and applicable for your students.</p>



<p><strong>How can I apply ABC learning design?</strong></p>



<p>ABC learning design is often done in a team-based workshop setting (you can do it by yourself as well). Firstly, you analyse your existing content. Consider the goal of your current learning sequence, and assess how your learners are going to reach that goal with the different learning types.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-qw.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXcSMiFUtX9Gxm8rpKv6KxsbOBsMrw5DTvCk_gKobjR9LxsoxLkLUCnNy7ZYyqgpaYBj33lRH-6Ncb3degEJGeQyI65PNcd8Iuts4wqhRA_eBq_3nf_23IooPo95LCF-RYc8qx4YlA?key=sKycVwYnLSkTt5scPtoJgQ" alt="Educators in the classroom" style="width:596px;height:auto"/></figure></div>


<p>By analysing existing content and activities, you can then identify what&#8217;s missing from your sequence. This allows you to build on existing gaps and consider different types of activities you could implement. You then create a set of learning cards, which help you to storyboard and plan your new learning sequence.</p>



<p>Learning cards are typically postcard-sized and colour-coded to one of the six learning types. Colour coding helps you to tell the cards apart, and to easily see which learning types are or aren&#8217;t included in your sequence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Each card has the name and a short description of the learning type on the front, with examples of associated digital or in-person learning activities on the back. The learning cards:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Make the design process more engaging</li>



<li>Help with decision making</li>



<li>Support discussions if you&#8217;re working in a team</li>
</ul>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-qw.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXeZrE4L9LInJRiaNZq-PVi3QML3jyUNpHcmVH7eApq08Dbl0iGTpYUQd0JhsMqliPjGTl_7I1nD36Z4UmfVsHl-9UYMj8tneiMnZWvZgSnG5LZLK7vqNlfbIWM6EY8RnUjA42NRbw?key=sKycVwYnLSkTt5scPtoJgQ" alt="ABC Learning design cards and their application to an ABC storyboard plan " style="width:474px;height:auto"/></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Adapting ABC learning design for your context</strong></h2>



<p>ABC design can be contextualised to your classroom, practices, and school, and to the technologies you have available. For example, on the back of each learning card you could include a set of activities that have been tried and tested in, or approved by, your school. Alternatively, you could link to other frameworks or teaching approaches that work for you and your students.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Learning cards can also be used to collect other insights about teaching and learning within your context, and used as reminders of pedagogies to implement, as well as practical concerns. They can also help you to consider if there are opportunities for cross-curricular links within your learning sequence.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>A shared toolkit you can reuse</strong></h3>



<p>In a computing department, ABC learning cards can become a shared resource that give fellow educators an understanding of what&#8217;s possible. The cards can be used again and again to help plan future learning experiences.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1890" height="1260" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/AI-research-summit-27.jpg" alt="Educators sharing ideas on a whiteboard" class="wp-image-91148" style="width:633px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/AI-research-summit-27.jpg 1890w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/AI-research-summit-27-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/AI-research-summit-27-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/AI-research-summit-27-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/AI-research-summit-27-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/AI-research-summit-27-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/AI-research-summit-27-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/AI-research-summit-27-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1890px) 100vw, 1890px" /></figure></div>


<p>By running an ABC workshop and creating these learning cards, you and your team will put together a contextualised learning sequence toolkit specific to your school and learners.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Integration with universal design for learning to improve accessibility</strong></h3>



<p>In our blog <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-build-young-peoples-agency-through-accessible-learning/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">How to build young people’s agency through accessible learning</a>, we explored the universal design for learning (UDL) framework. UDL aims to support educators to reduce barriers for learners. It helps educators to create learning environments that are accessible and effective for all learners by providing multiple means of engagement, representation, and action and expression.</p>



<p>Gormley et al. (2022) described an initiative to integrate UDL within ABC learning design. They developed adapted ABC learning cards where the reverse side included specific UDL prompts, in addition to the usual example activities. For example:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>An acquisition card could include the prompt “Will materials be available in a variety of formats (text, audio, and visual)? Will videos be captioned and transcribed?”</li>



<li>A production card could include the prompt “Are there multiple ways for learners to demonstrate their understanding? Can they choose between writing, presenting, or creating?”</li>
</ul>



<p>By including these UDL considerations directly on the ABC cards, the design team ensured that accessibility and inclusivity were central to learning design conversations.</p>



<p>Adding UDL prompts to your learning cards is a fantastic way to help you design accessible learning sequences.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Applying ABC learning design: Some ideas for computing educators</strong></h2>



<p>In 2020, during the pandemic, the Computing at School (CAS) Research Working Group worked with classroom teachers to apply ABC learning design in their own contexts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Following some training, teachers analysed their existing classroom activities and then developed a range of suitable alternatives for remote learning, categorising them into low-tech, mid-tech, and high-tech options.&nbsp;<br>The different activity options were then added to their own sets of ABC learning cards and used to help adapt lessons for remote teaching. You can read more about the project and view example cards on the <a href="https://www.computingatschool.org.uk/resources/2020/may/remote-learning-options-abc-cards-for-schools/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">CAS website</a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The benefits of using ABC learning design</strong></h2>



<p>Potential benefits for educators:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Enables more rapid creation and delivery of high-quality content</li>



<li>Allows you to audit your current learning sequence and identify gaps that can be improved upon</li>



<li>Provides a shared, contextualised toolkit for curriculum design</li>
</ul>



<p>Potential benefits for students:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Tailored, engaging, high-quality learning experiences</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Want to hear more about ABC learning design?</strong></h2>



<p>If you’d like to find out more about ABC learning design, you can download our Quick Read for free.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://static.raspberrypi.org/files/curriculum/quickreads/25-Pedagogy_Summary_ABC_Learning_Design_2025_en-gb.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Download the ABC learning design Pedagogy Quick Read</a></div>
</div>



<p>You can also listen to a thought-provoking discussion on the topic between James Robinson, Carrie Anne Philbin, Jane Waite, and Matthew Wimpenny-Smith in season 1, episode 6 of the Hello World podcast: <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/podcast/s01e06-could-curriculum-design-be-as-simple-as-abc" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Could curriculum design be as simple as ABC?</a><br></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-rapidly-design-and-adapt-quality-learning-experiences-for-your-students/">How to rapidly design and adapt quality learning experiences for your students</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-rapidly-design-and-adapt-quality-learning-experiences-for-your-students/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
