<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Raspberry Pi Foundation</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/</link>
	<description>Teach, learn and make with Raspberry Pi</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 09:22:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.8.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/06/cropped-raspberrry_pi_logo-100x100.png</url>
	<title>Raspberry Pi Foundation</title>
	<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Opening the box: Tools to teach young people about AI</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/opening-the-box-tools-to-teach-young-people-about-ai/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/opening-the-box-tools-to-teach-young-people-about-ai/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Bonnie Sheppard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 11:09:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI literacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research and impact]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research seminar]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=91216</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>New research by the Alan Turing Institute, published in June, shows that in the UK nearly one in four children aged 8 to 12 is using artificial intelligence (AI) tools like ChatGPT. With learners exploring these tools at such young ages, it’s more urgent than ever to develop teaching resources that help them understand how&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/opening-the-box-tools-to-teach-young-people-about-ai/">Opening the box: Tools to teach young people about AI</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>New research by the <a href="https://www.turing.ac.uk/news/experts-call-greater-focus-childrens-ai-use-research-shows-nearly-1-4-children-use-ai-learning" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Alan Turing Institute</a>, published in June, shows that in the UK nearly one in four children aged 8 to 12 is using artificial intelligence (AI) tools like ChatGPT. With learners exploring these tools at such young ages, it’s more urgent than ever to develop teaching resources that help them understand how AI works.</p>



<p>One of the biggest challenges with AI is that it’s hard to tell how these tools function. With a chatbot, you enter a prompt and the tool returns a response, but what happens in between is invisible. For educators, that’s a problem: how can we help young people become thoughtful, creative users of AI tools if the technology feels like a closed box?</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-1 is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-is-layout-flex">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="500" height="650" data-id="91217" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-500x650.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-91217" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-500x650.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-192x250.jpeg 192w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-768x998.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-800x1040.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-450x585.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-900x1170.jpeg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image.jpeg 950w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="500" height="650" data-id="91218" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1-500x650.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-91218" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1-500x650.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1-192x250.jpeg 192w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1-768x998.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1-800x1040.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1-450x585.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1-900x1170.jpeg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1.jpeg 950w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure>
</figure>



<p>In our May research seminar, we welcomed <strong>Matti Tedre</strong> and <strong>Henriikka Vartiainen</strong> from the University of Eastern Finland. They’ve been <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/machine-learning-education-school-computational-thinking-2-0-research-seminar/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">working on how to teach about AI for years</a> and were frustrated with existing educational platforms: many of these are either too complex, raise privacy concerns, or rely on coding skills that not all students (or teachers) have. In response, they created an <a href="https://tm.gen-ai.fi/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">award-winning, classroom-friendly tool</a> designed to make AI technology more transparent and more hands-on.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>A practical way to teach AI in schools</strong></h2>



<p>Matti and Henriikka began by discussing the unique challenges of teaching young learners about AI technology. Many students start with “folk theories”, for example, thinking that computers understand language like humans do. These misconceptions can be surprisingly hard to shake.</p>



<p>They also pointed out broader issues:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>The abstract nature of AI means there are very few research-based approaches to teaching it effectively</li>



<li>Mastery of AI concepts requires sustained practice and curricular change, not just a few one-off interventions</li>



<li>In countries like Finland, where programming isn’t part of the curriculum, any teaching tool must be no-code to be accessible</li>
</ul>



<p>To address these challenges, Matti and Henriikka have spent three years co-designing tools and approaches with local schools, teachers, and over 200 students. Their approach is grounded in educational theory and a set of core AI learning principles:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>No-code for inclusivity:</strong> Removing the need for programming lowers the barrier to entry for both teachers and students</li>



<li><strong>Learner-centred co-design:</strong> Every part of the experience is developed in collaboration with schools to make sure it’s engaging and relevant</li>



<li><strong>Working with personal data:</strong> Learners create and work with their own data sets, which makes the experience more engaging and personally relevant</li>



<li><strong>Integration with school subjects:</strong> Integrating AI concepts into other subjects helps to make the uses of AI tools more concrete for learners</li>



<li><strong>Focus on specific applications:</strong> Rather than teaching about generic ‘AI’, the focus is on specific and understandable applications, such as facial recognition</li>



<li><strong>Hands-on experimentation:</strong> Practical projects help students understand tricky ideas like bias, fairness, and social impact</li>



<li><strong>Collaborative learning:</strong> Working together helps students reflect, question, and learn from each other</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>GenAI Teachable Machine: Opening the box</strong></h2>



<p>Frustrated by existing platforms that require programming skills, raise privacy concerns, or don’t allow collaboration, Matti and Henriikka’s team developed <a href="https://tm.gen-ai.fi/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GenAI Teachable Machine</a>: a no-code, browser-based tool designed to make key AI concepts tangible. In <a href="https://infedu.vu.lt/journal/INFEDU/article/779/info" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the central research study</a>, the team used the tool with Finnish students in grade 4–7 (10 to 14 years of age). It&#8217;s a great introductory tool that could also be used with younger and older students.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="1285" height="482" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image.png" alt="GenAI Teachable Machine is freely available online and maintains a “line of sight”: All important steps are visible to the learner." class="wp-image-91219" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image.png 1285w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-300x113.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-500x188.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-768x288.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-800x300.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-450x169.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-900x338.png 900w" sizes="(max-width: 1285px) 100vw, 1285px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>GenAI Teachable Machine is freely available online and maintains a “line of sight”: All important steps are visible to the learner</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Matti demonstrated how the tool addresses their core AI learning principles with a simple, creative project. Using hand puppets, he trained a model to recognise four distinct classes: a background, a bunny, a calm wolf, and an angry wolf. For each class, he assigned a specific action: a sound, an image, or both. This hands-on process gives students a direct line of sight from the data they might create (visuals of hand puppets) to the final behaviour of the model (outputted sounds and images). They learn about classifiers, training, and confidence levels not as abstract definitions, but as creative tools they can control.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="823" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1.png" alt="Matti Tedre demonstrating a bunny and wolf recognition model." class="wp-image-91220" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1.png 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1-300x154.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1-500x257.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1-768x395.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1-1536x790.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1-800x412.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1-450x231.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-1-900x463.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Matti Tedre demonstrating a bunny and wolf recognition model</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>But the learning really starts when things don’t work as expected. Students can easily open their models on their phones with an automatically created QR code and then move around the classroom to test their models. At this point, they quickly notice how fragile AI technology can be. For example, in the case of a simple recognition model trained on specific colours or features, with a change of lighting or a different shirt, the model might fail. These “failures” turn into powerful lessons. For instance, a face-recognition app trained mostly on students with blonde hair might not work well for someone with brown hair — sparking immediate conversations about bias. As Matti put it, students very quickly start asking deep questions.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1728" height="1152" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/03/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-8.jpg" alt="In a computing classroom, two girls concentrate on their programming task." class="wp-image-78793" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/03/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-8.jpg 1728w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/03/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-8-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/03/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-8-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/03/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-8-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/03/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-8-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/03/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-8-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/03/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-8-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/03/NCCE-Enfeild-Primary-8-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1728px) 100vw, 1728px" /></figure></div>


<p>GenAI Teachable Machine also allows students to apply their AI models to the physical world. By connecting to a simple, low-cost robotics kit, students can use their models to control motors, lights, and other actuators. This step into the physical world teaches fundamental concepts that are difficult to grasp in a purely virtual environment. Students learn about causality, as their model&#8217;s classifications trigger real, physical actions. They also learn about the need for a world model — an understanding of how the physical world works — and see that they must take responsibility for what happens when their abstract models have real-world consequences.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1128" height="602" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-2.png" alt="Examples of students’ robot creations." class="wp-image-91221" style="width:720px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-2.png 1128w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-2-300x160.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-2-500x267.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-2-768x410.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-2-800x427.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-2-450x240.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/08/image-2-900x480.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1128px) 100vw, 1128px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Examples of students’ robot creations</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>By combining a no-code platform with practical, well-designed learning experiences, Matti, Henriikka, and their team are showing what AI education can look like: hands-on, accessible, and grounded in real understanding. Their work is helping students see inside the box, and giving them the tools to think critically about the AI technologies that are becoming part of their everyday lives.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Find out more</strong></h2>



<p>If you&#8217;re an educator interested in including the topic of AI in your teaching, <a href="http://tm.gen-ai.fi" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">you can try GenAI Teachable Machine on its official website</a>.</p>



<p>You may also be interested in our own <a href="https://experience-ai.org/en/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Experience AI</a> resources, which are designed to help you and your learners navigate the fast-moving world of AI and machine learning technologies.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Join us at our next seminar</strong></h2>



<p>In September, Matti and his team are returning to discuss other ways to teach young people about AI technologies.</p>



<p>To sign up and take part in the Matti&#8217;s seminar on Tues 9 Sept at 17:00–18:30 BST, click the button below. We&#8217;ll then send you information about joining. We hope to see you there.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research-impact/research/seminars" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">I want to join the next seminar</a></div>
</div>



<p>The <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research-impact/research/seminars" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">schedule of our upcoming seminars is online</a>. You can catch up on past seminars on our <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research-impact/research/seminars/previous" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">previous seminars page</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/opening-the-box-tools-to-teach-young-people-about-ai/">Opening the box: Tools to teach young people about AI</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/opening-the-box-tools-to-teach-young-people-about-ai/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Adapting our computing curriculum resources for Odisha — the journey so far</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-our-computing-curriculum-resources-for-odisha-the-journey-so-far/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-our-computing-curriculum-resources-for-odisha-the-journey-so-far/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Fiona Coventry]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 10:56:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Computing Curriculum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Impact of our work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Odisha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research and impact]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=91177</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Today&#8217;s blog is the second in a mini-series of three sharing our experiences of adapting computing curriculum resources for different contexts, and of training teachers to use them in schools. Last month we wrote about our collaboration with partners in Kenya. Here we discuss our work in Odisha, India. This article has been written by&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-our-computing-curriculum-resources-for-odisha-the-journey-so-far/">Adapting our computing curriculum resources for Odisha — the journey so far</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Today&#8217;s blog is the second in a mini-series of three sharing our experiences of adapting computing curriculum resources for different contexts, and of training teachers to use them in schools. <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-our-computing-curriculum-resources-for-kenya-the-journey-so-far/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Last month we wrote about our collaboration with partners in Kenya</a>. Here we discuss our work in Odisha, India.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="750" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3118-1.jpg" alt="Teachers at a teacher training in Odisha." class="wp-image-91193" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3118-1.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3118-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3118-1-500x375.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3118-1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3118-1-800x600.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3118-1-450x338.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3118-1-900x675.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>This article has been written by Fiona Coventry, Impact Manager, and Mamta Manaktala, Senior Learning Manager.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A long-term partnership in Odisha</h2>



<p>We know that building long-term partnerships with organisations that have local expertise is key to making a real impact for young people. This fact was echoed by people involved in education initiatives worldwide who spoke at the <a href="https://www.wwhge.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">What Works Hub for Global Education</a> 2024 annual conference, which Fiona followed online. Our work in Odisha is an example of this.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="750" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3569-1.jpg" alt="Teachers at a teacher training in Odisha." class="wp-image-91197" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3569-1.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3569-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3569-1-500x375.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3569-1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3569-1-800x600.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3569-1-450x338.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3569-1-900x675.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>We have now been working with our government partner in Odisha, Panchasakha Shikhya Setu (formerly Mo School Abhiyan), for four years. Our journey began in 2021, when we worked together to <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-club-eastern-india-computer-science-education/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">establish a network of Code Clubs in government and government-aided schools</a> in the state. In 2023, our focus shifted to <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/introducing-a-computing-curriculum-in-odisha/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">developing a formal computing curriculum for students in grades 9 and 10</a> (known locally as the Kaushali curriculum), in collaboration with two other partners.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Work in the 2024/2025 academic year</h2>



<p>Adaptation is a crucial aspect of how we ensure our computing resources are accessible to as many young people as possible. For our work in Odisha, we <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/computing-curriculum-framework-adapting-to-indias-diverse-landscapes/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">adapted content from The Computing Curriculum</a> and then localised it to fit the requirement of the students.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="750" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Day4-11.jpeg" alt="Teachers at a teacher training in Odisha." class="wp-image-91205" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Day4-11.jpeg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Day4-11-300x225.jpeg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Day4-11-500x375.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Day4-11-768x576.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Day4-11-800x600.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Day4-11-450x338.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Day4-11-900x675.jpeg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>In Odisha&#8217;s June 2024 to April 2025 academic year, we rolled out adapted computing curriculum content for grade 10 students, for students who had already learned with adapted grade 9 content in 2023/24. We worked with our partners to develop the curriculum content and trained 310 master teachers from across Odisha, along with 30 State Resource Groups (SRGs) to support them. Before the end of 2024, the 310 master teachers subsequently trained 8109 teachers, who would reach an estimated 880,000 students with the grade 9 and 10 curriculum content. We had an ongoing responsibility to support 1846 of these teachers in our allocated districts, with an estimated reach to around 205,000 students.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Impact of the grade 9 and 10 curriculum</h2>



<p>In early 2025 we issued a follow-up survey about student learning, content, and training to a sample of teachers in our allocated districts, and 310 teachers responded. (We used a stratified sampling approach designed to ensure the survey results were representative of all teachers.)</p>



<p>At least 87% of teachers agreed that students achieved the outcomes we asked about, e.g. regarding coding skills, staying safe online, and use of data in machine intelligence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Moreover, responses related to our grade 9 curriculum remained similarly high compared to 2024 survey responses.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-2.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="968" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-2.png" alt="2025 Odisha teacher survey responses regarding their students' learning." class="wp-image-91179" style="width:720px" title="Chart" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-2.png 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-2-300x182.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-2-500x303.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-2-768x465.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-2-1536x929.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-2-800x484.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-2-450x272.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-2-900x545.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">2025 Odisha teacher survey responses regarding their students&#8217; learning. Click to enlarge.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Teachers also expressed their appreciation for the computing curriculum resources and training in free-text comments and interviews, for example:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“IT and coding is essential nowadays. So a good initiative, adding this to schools&#8217; curriculum.” – Teacher in Odisha</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The training was quite informative, interesting and helpful.” – Teacher in Odisha</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“It is very useful training for me. It boosts my knowledge and helps me for classroom transaction.” – Teacher in Odisha</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Addressing challenges</h2>



<p>An ongoing challenge in Odisha has been supporting those teachers who lack experience with computing and/or with our <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/teach/pedagogy/resources" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">recommended teaching approaches for computing</a>. We have been working hard to help these teachers develop the knowledge, skills, and confidence to effectively deliver the curriculum content in the limited time they have alongside their other professional commitments.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="750" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3162-1.jpg" alt="Teachers at a teacher training in Odisha." class="wp-image-91201" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3162-1.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3162-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3162-1-500x375.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3162-1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3162-1-800x600.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3162-1-450x338.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_3162-1-900x675.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>In the 2023/2024 academic year, many teachers had told us they needed further training and support. For this reason, we offered longer training in the 2024/25 academic year. We also adapted our training approach based on learning from earlier phases, such as including activities teachers could complete on their smartphones, enabling more hands-on learning while reducing dependence on available IT equipment. The outcome of this was positive: in the follow-up survey, fewer teachers felt they needed additional training to deliver the lessons, and most teachers we interviewed felt this year&#8217;s training was an improvement on the previous year&#8217;s.</p>



<p>Our team also ran weekly webinars to support teachers and address their queries. These were very well received by teachers. Of the responses received to feedback form available after each webinar:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>97% agreed that the “webinar helped me to understand the topics covered more clearly.”</li>



<li>98% agreed that the “webinar was useful to support my teaching.”</li>
</ul>



<p>This was supported by comments from teachers, for example:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“All questions were answered. The webinar was good. Gained a lot. Thank you very much.”&nbsp; – Teacher in Odisha</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I learned many unknown things about Scratch, it will help my classroom teaching.” – Teacher in Odisha</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In this year&#8217;s follow-up survey, teachers also less frequently indicated they felt they needed “additional content to support students”. They provided useful feedback and suggestions regarding the curriculum content, e.g. further simplifying and localising it, which we will incorporate into future resource development.</p>



<p>Another persistent challenge has been limited access to IT equipment and the internet in schools, and what this means for student-device ratios and how teachers are able to deliver the content. For future resources we are developing, we are therefore adapting the amount of content to be delivered over a series of lessons.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Next steps for our partnership in Odisha</h2>



<p>In 2025, we are working with the same partners to implement a curriculum for grades 6 to 8, initially in around 460 schools. We and our partners have developed the curriculum content and are currently in the process of training teachers in preparation for classroom delivery.</p>



<p>We are also continuing to support the teachers previously trained on the grade 9 and 10 curriculum through webinars and school visits.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Want to see our curriculum resources?</h2>



<p>You can access our <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/curriculum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">free Computing Curriculum resources on our website</a> — we are currently working to make the materials for India, and for Kenya, downloadable there.</p>



<p>Look out for the final blog in this mini-series next month, which will focus on our computer science curriculum in Telangana, India.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-our-computing-curriculum-resources-for-odisha-the-journey-so-far/">Adapting our computing curriculum resources for Odisha — the journey so far</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/adapting-our-computing-curriculum-resources-for-odisha-the-journey-so-far/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>From coder to mentor: Meet Isabelle</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/from-coder-to-mentor-meet-isabelle/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/from-coder-to-mentor-meet-isabelle/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sophie Ashford]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 10:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Code Club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=91156</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We love hearing from members of the community and sharing stories of amazing young people, volunteers, and educators who are using their passion for technology to create positive change in the world around them. Meet Isabelle, a youth mentor at a library Code Club, whose inspiring story tells how a passion for helping others and&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/from-coder-to-mentor-meet-isabelle/">From coder to mentor: Meet Isabelle</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We love hearing from members of the community and sharing stories of amazing young people, volunteers, and educators who are using their passion for technology to create positive change in the world around them.</p>



<p>Meet Isabelle, a youth mentor at a library Code Club, whose inspiring story tells how a passion for helping others and a love for reading led back to a childhood interest, shaping an unexpected and rewarding journey.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1080" height="1377" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-celebrating-her-18th-birthday.jpg" alt="Isabelle celebrating her 18th birthday." class="wp-image-91166" style="width:520px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-celebrating-her-18th-birthday.jpg 1080w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-celebrating-her-18th-birthday-196x250.jpg 196w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-celebrating-her-18th-birthday-500x638.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-celebrating-her-18th-birthday-768x979.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-celebrating-her-18th-birthday-800x1020.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-celebrating-her-18th-birthday-450x574.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-celebrating-her-18th-birthday-900x1148.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1080px) 100vw, 1080px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Saturdays spent at the library</strong></h2>



<p>Isabelle&#8217;s coding journey began around the age of nine. An avid reader, she regularly attended her local library in Stourbridge with her gran. When they saw there was a Code Club held on a Saturday morning, they both decided it might be a good skill for Isabelle to learn.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;I used to have like an entire folder of all the projects I’d completed. I&#8217;ve still got it somewhere in my room!&#8221;&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>She quickly progressed through Scratch, Python, and HTML, even finding herself teaching the adults at the club at some points! But, as secondary school approached, her involvement naturally tapered off as she began to focus on her studies.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>A return through volunteering&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p>In secondary school, Isabelle was looking for volunteering opportunities as part of her Duke of Edinburgh (DofE) award. Remembering her positive experiences at the library, and continued love of books, she initially considered volunteering there. Then, she had an idea.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I suddenly thought ‘What if they still do Code Club?’ I really enjoyed it when I did it and I still remembered enough about it to help others. So, I felt like I could actually be useful instead.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Isabelle reached out, and thanks to her gran&#8217;s long-standing connection with the library, she was remembered and welcomed back. What started as a three-month commitment for her DofE award soon extended to six.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I really looked forward to each session at the library and decided to stick with it for the whole time.”</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Embracing the chaos and connection</strong></h2>



<p>Isabelle&#8217;s return coincided with the Code Club restarting. Stepping into a mentoring role, she quickly found herself in the thick of it. With five computers and a group of new young people, most of whom had no prior coding experience, the first sessions were a whirlwind.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s like the best kind of chaos. It doesn&#8217;t get easier as such. But it&#8217;s so fun meeting these new kids, they&#8217;re all different and they bounce off each other.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>She works closely with Lucy, the club leader, helping manage the flow of projects and supporting the children as they navigate everything from creating Scratch accounts to tackling challenging projects.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="750" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-at-her-club-in-Stourbridge-with-Code-Club-Community-Coordinator-Rujeko.jpg" alt="Isabelle at her club in Stourbridge with Code Club Community Coordinator Rujeko." class="wp-image-91168" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-at-her-club-in-Stourbridge-with-Code-Club-Community-Coordinator-Rujeko.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-at-her-club-in-Stourbridge-with-Code-Club-Community-Coordinator-Rujeko-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-at-her-club-in-Stourbridge-with-Code-Club-Community-Coordinator-Rujeko-500x375.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-at-her-club-in-Stourbridge-with-Code-Club-Community-Coordinator-Rujeko-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-at-her-club-in-Stourbridge-with-Code-Club-Community-Coordinator-Rujeko-800x600.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-at-her-club-in-Stourbridge-with-Code-Club-Community-Coordinator-Rujeko-450x338.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Isabelle-at-her-club-in-Stourbridge-with-Code-Club-Community-Coordinator-Rujeko-900x675.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Isabelle with Lucy, Stourbridge Library Assistant, and Rujeko, Code Club Community Coordinator</figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>More than just code</strong></h2>



<p>While the technical skills are central, Isabelle emphasises that Code Club offers so much more. She&#8217;s seen shy children blossom, making new friends and becoming more involved.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I think there&#8217;s the whole element of socialising as well. And beyond coding, kids develop essential IT skills, like learning how to use a mouse and keyboard. Something many who just use tablets and phones don&#8217;t know!”</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Four years and counting&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p>Isabelle, now preparing to go on to further education, could not have predicted how her mentoring journey would turn out. What began as a three-month DofE requirement has turned into a four-year commitment.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“It has just never been something that I thought &#8216;oh, I don&#8217;t want to do this anymore&#8217;. It&#8217;s just part of the weekly routine now. It&#8217;s been four years and it&#8217;s shocking how quickly it&#8217;s gone.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Isabelle&#8217;s dedication hasn&#8217;t gone unnoticed. She&#8217;s built strong bonds with the staff and gained invaluable experience. She&#8217;s learned to organise, work in a team, and even run sessions independently, developing skills that will be invaluable for her future.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;I like the bond that I have with the staff and with Lucy. It feels great to be trusted that much and it has just been such a nice experience.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Lucy, Stourbridge Code Club leader and Library Assistant, shared her experience with the club and collaborating.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Since Code Club offers so much more than just coding — confidence building, creativity, friendship, etc. — it plays an important role for children and young people in the community. The library is much more than just a place for books, and hosting Code Club here creates a welcoming space where young people can explore technology away from the classroom.”</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Isabelle has been absolutely fantastic both in supporting us with club admin as well as supporting the children with their coding! She understands the projects inside and out and is brilliant at not only solving problems, but also, importantly, encouraging the club to find ways of solving problems themselves. Our Code Club couldn&#8217;t have become what it is today without her input!”</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Isabelle&#8217;s advice for future mentors</strong></h2>



<p>As Isabelle prepares to head off to the Bath Spa University to study media communications and publishing, she offers this advice for other young people considering becoming a Code Club mentor…”just go for it!”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Isabelle admits to being anxious at times, but the experience has significantly boosted her confidence.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“It built my confidence a bit more. You make friends along the way and you learn a lot of new things. And don&#8217;t worry if you don’t have a lot of coding experience. I don&#8217;t think you need it. I had a little bit but I was still basing it mainly off of reading the project instructions. And in all fairness, the instructions are really helpful!”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Mentoring at Code Club isn&#8217;t just about teaching, it&#8217;s about learning, growing, and connecting. It&#8217;s an opportunity to give back, build confidence, and discover the joy in supporting the next generation of digital creators. As Isabelle&#8217;s journey shows, sometimes the most rewarding paths are the ones you never planned to take.</p>



<p>Lucy shared why she thinks having youth mentors involved with Code Club is such an important dynamic.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Youth mentors are great as role models and inspiration for children, and as a young person themselves they build such a great rapport with the club members. A mentor who’s closer to their age often feels more approachable, which helps create a comfortable and encouraging environment for them.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>If Isabelle&#8217;s story has inspired you, why not explore the world of coding? You can get started at home with over 250 free projects on the Code Club Projects website.</p>



<p>Looking for a little extra support in your own coding journey or open to mentoring others? Join a Code Club near you to meet a like-minded and supportive community.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/from-coder-to-mentor-meet-isabelle/">From coder to mentor: Meet Isabelle</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/from-coder-to-mentor-meet-isabelle/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to rapidly design and adapt quality learning experiences for your students</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-rapidly-design-and-adapt-quality-learning-experiences-for-your-students/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-rapidly-design-and-adapt-quality-learning-experiences-for-your-students/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Sayers]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 11:18:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pedagogy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quick reads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research and impact]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ABC learning design]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=91133</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>At this time of year, many educators are considering ways to update their content ahead of the new school term. Whether you’re a teaching assistant or head of department, it’s important to ensure that the content you’re updating — or even designing anew — is relevant and high quality, and meet learners’ needs. In today’s&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-rapidly-design-and-adapt-quality-learning-experiences-for-your-students/">How to rapidly design and adapt quality learning experiences for your students</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>At this time of year, many educators are considering ways to update their content ahead of the new school term. Whether you’re a teaching assistant or head of department, it’s important to ensure that the content you’re updating — or even designing anew — is relevant and high quality, and meet learners’ needs. In today’s blog we’re highlighting ‘ABC learning design’, and how it can be used to rapidly design and improve learning experiences.<br></p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-qw.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXc5FiRZIxZeO5tZYPZP6AccA7y83hELUEmRFpo-63hEHDaUqLX1395XdlYt0La02CkxlLXaNMpbWSGOjWo6sjqAsbqql4yrjf07rDPdFDqJUqneQt94eNHTjdhkKf4dELU4geutPQ?key=sKycVwYnLSkTt5scPtoJgQ" alt="Educators in the classroom" style="width:628px;height:auto"/></figure></div>


<p>We also share our <a href="https://the-cc.io/qr25" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new ABC-focused Pedagogy Quick Read</a>, which you can download for free to:&nbsp;</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Find practical tips on how to use the ABC process and related approaches with your learners</li>



<li>Read a summary of the research behind the framework</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What is ABC learning design?</strong></h2>



<p>ABC learning design is a rapid, hands-on approach to design and develop blended learning experiences. The framework has traditionally been used at undergrad level, and had a lot of success when used in response to the global pandemic in 2020, when learning experiences had to quickly transition from being delivered in-person to being accessible remotely.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The model is centred around six learning types:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Acquisition: Learning by reading, listening, or watching</li>



<li>Collaboration: Learning by working with others towards a common goal, involving co-creation and shared outputs</li>



<li>Discussion: Learning through dialogue, sharing ideas, and responding to others</li>



<li>Investigation: Learning by exploring, comparing, and evaluating new information or experiences</li>



<li>Practice: Learning by applying knowledge and skills, receiving feedback, and refining understanding</li>



<li>Production: Learning by expressing understanding or creating something to demonstrate knowledge and skills</li>
</ul>



<p>Before continuing, it&#8217;s important to distinguish between &#8216;learning types&#8217; and the widely discredited concept of &#8216;learning styles&#8217;. Whilst learning styles refer to fixed characteristics or preferences of learners, learning types refer to different kinds of learning activities and pedagogical approaches that can be designed into a course.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1200" height="630" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image.png" alt="Copy of the ABC learning design Pedagogy Quick Read" class="wp-image-91136" style="width:670px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image.png 1200w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-300x158.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-500x263.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-768x403.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-800x420.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-450x236.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-900x473.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></figure></div>


<p>These learning types are representative simplifications of pre-existing learning theories. For each learning type, educators can use different activities to deliver that type of learning. The activities will depend on your context and what’s right and applicable for your students.</p>



<p><strong>How can I apply ABC learning design?</strong></p>



<p>ABC learning design is often done in a team-based workshop setting (you can do it by yourself as well). Firstly, you analyse your existing content. Consider the goal of your current learning sequence, and assess how your learners are going to reach that goal with the different learning types.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-qw.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXcSMiFUtX9Gxm8rpKv6KxsbOBsMrw5DTvCk_gKobjR9LxsoxLkLUCnNy7ZYyqgpaYBj33lRH-6Ncb3degEJGeQyI65PNcd8Iuts4wqhRA_eBq_3nf_23IooPo95LCF-RYc8qx4YlA?key=sKycVwYnLSkTt5scPtoJgQ" alt="Educators in the classroom" style="width:596px;height:auto"/></figure></div>


<p>By analysing existing content and activities, you can then identify what&#8217;s missing from your sequence. This allows you to build on existing gaps and consider different types of activities you could implement. You then create a set of learning cards, which help you to storyboard and plan your new learning sequence.</p>



<p>Learning cards are typically postcard-sized and colour-coded to one of the six learning types. Colour coding helps you to tell the cards apart, and to easily see which learning types are or aren&#8217;t included in your sequence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Each card has the name and a short description of the learning type on the front, with examples of associated digital or in-person learning activities on the back. The learning cards:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Make the design process more engaging</li>



<li>Help with decision making</li>



<li>Support discussions if you&#8217;re working in a team</li>
</ul>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-qw.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXeZrE4L9LInJRiaNZq-PVi3QML3jyUNpHcmVH7eApq08Dbl0iGTpYUQd0JhsMqliPjGTl_7I1nD36Z4UmfVsHl-9UYMj8tneiMnZWvZgSnG5LZLK7vqNlfbIWM6EY8RnUjA42NRbw?key=sKycVwYnLSkTt5scPtoJgQ" alt="ABC Learning design cards and their application to an ABC storyboard plan " style="width:474px;height:auto"/></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Adapting ABC learning design for your context</strong></h2>



<p>ABC design can be contextualised to your classroom, practices, and school, and to the technologies you have available. For example, on the back of each learning card you could include a set of activities that have been tried and tested in, or approved by, your school. Alternatively, you could link to other frameworks or teaching approaches that work for you and your students.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Learning cards can also be used to collect other insights about teaching and learning within your context, and used as reminders of pedagogies to implement, as well as practical concerns. They can also help you to consider if there are opportunities for cross-curricular links within your learning sequence.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>A shared toolkit you can reuse</strong></h3>



<p>In a computing department, ABC learning cards can become a shared resource that give fellow educators an understanding of what&#8217;s possible. The cards can be used again and again to help plan future learning experiences.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1890" height="1260" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/AI-research-summit-27.jpg" alt="Educators sharing ideas on a whiteboard" class="wp-image-91148" style="width:633px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/AI-research-summit-27.jpg 1890w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/AI-research-summit-27-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/AI-research-summit-27-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/AI-research-summit-27-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/AI-research-summit-27-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/AI-research-summit-27-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/AI-research-summit-27-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/AI-research-summit-27-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1890px) 100vw, 1890px" /></figure></div>


<p>By running an ABC workshop and creating these learning cards, you and your team will put together a contextualised learning sequence toolkit specific to your school and learners.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Integration with universal design for learning to improve accessibility</strong></h3>



<p>In our blog <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-build-young-peoples-agency-through-accessible-learning/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">How to build young people’s agency through accessible learning</a>, we explored the universal design for learning (UDL) framework. UDL aims to support educators to reduce barriers for learners. It helps educators to create learning environments that are accessible and effective for all learners by providing multiple means of engagement, representation, and action and expression.</p>



<p>Gormley et al. (2022) described an initiative to integrate UDL within ABC learning design. They developed adapted ABC learning cards where the reverse side included specific UDL prompts, in addition to the usual example activities. For example:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>An acquisition card could include the prompt “Will materials be available in a variety of formats (text, audio, and visual)? Will videos be captioned and transcribed?”</li>



<li>A production card could include the prompt “Are there multiple ways for learners to demonstrate their understanding? Can they choose between writing, presenting, or creating?”</li>
</ul>



<p>By including these UDL considerations directly on the ABC cards, the design team ensured that accessibility and inclusivity were central to learning design conversations.</p>



<p>Adding UDL prompts to your learning cards is a fantastic way to help you design accessible learning sequences.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Applying ABC learning design: Some ideas for computing educators</strong></h2>



<p>In 2020, during the pandemic, the Computing at School (CAS) Research Working Group worked with classroom teachers to apply ABC learning design in their own contexts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Following some training, teachers analysed their existing classroom activities and then developed a range of suitable alternatives for remote learning, categorising them into low-tech, mid-tech, and high-tech options.&nbsp;<br>The different activity options were then added to their own sets of ABC learning cards and used to help adapt lessons for remote teaching. You can read more about the project and view example cards on the <a href="https://www.computingatschool.org.uk/resources/2020/may/remote-learning-options-abc-cards-for-schools/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">CAS website</a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The benefits of using ABC learning design</strong></h2>



<p>Potential benefits for educators:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Enables more rapid creation and delivery of high-quality content</li>



<li>Allows you to audit your current learning sequence and identify gaps that can be improved upon</li>



<li>Provides a shared, contextualised toolkit for curriculum design</li>
</ul>



<p>Potential benefits for students:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Tailored, engaging, high-quality learning experiences</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Want to hear more about ABC learning design?</strong></h2>



<p>If you’d like to find out more about ABC learning design, you can download our Quick Read for free.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://static.raspberrypi.org/files/curriculum/quickreads/25-Pedagogy_Summary_ABC_Learning_Design_2025_en-gb.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Download the ABC learning design Pedagogy Quick Read</a></div>
</div>



<p>You can also listen to a thought-provoking discussion on the topic between James Robinson, Carrie Anne Philbin, Jane Waite, and Matthew Wimpenny-Smith in season 1, episode 6 of the Hello World podcast: <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/podcast/s01e06-could-curriculum-design-be-as-simple-as-abc" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Could curriculum design be as simple as ABC?</a><br></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-rapidly-design-and-adapt-quality-learning-experiences-for-your-students/">How to rapidly design and adapt quality learning experiences for your students</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-to-rapidly-design-and-adapt-quality-learning-experiences-for-your-students/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hello World podcast: What does AI education look like around the world?</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/hello-world-podcast-what-does-ai-education-look-like-around-the-world/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/hello-world-podcast-what-does-ai-education-look-like-around-the-world/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liz Eaton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 10:26:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Experience AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hello World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hello world podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI literacy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=91053</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In a rapidly evolving digital landscape, AI literacy is becoming as fundamental as traditional reading and writing. The latest episode of the Hello World podcast explores this crucial topic, bringing together experts from Kenya, Lithuania, and Malaysia to discuss the current state of AI literacy in their countries. Together, they shed light on the challenges&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/hello-world-podcast-what-does-ai-education-look-like-around-the-world/">Hello World podcast: What does AI education look like around the world?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In a rapidly evolving digital landscape, AI literacy is becoming as fundamental as traditional reading and writing. The <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/podcast/what-does-ai-education-look-like-around-the-world" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">latest episode of the Hello World podcast</a> explores this crucial topic, bringing together experts from Kenya, Lithuania, and Malaysia to discuss the current state of AI literacy in their countries. Together, they shed light on the challenges and immense potential of AI education globally.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/podcast/what-does-ai-education-look-like-around-the-world"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1300" height="731" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.4-Experience-AI-AI-Ed-Global-Perspectives-Title-YT-Player-1.jpg" alt="HW Podcast Thumbnail: AI education: Global perspectives " class="wp-image-91121" style="width:715px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.4-Experience-AI-AI-Ed-Global-Perspectives-Title-YT-Player-1.jpg 1300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.4-Experience-AI-AI-Ed-Global-Perspectives-Title-YT-Player-1-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.4-Experience-AI-AI-Ed-Global-Perspectives-Title-YT-Player-1-500x281.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.4-Experience-AI-AI-Ed-Global-Perspectives-Title-YT-Player-1-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.4-Experience-AI-AI-Ed-Global-Perspectives-Title-YT-Player-1-800x450.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.4-Experience-AI-AI-Ed-Global-Perspectives-Title-YT-Player-1-450x253.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.4-Experience-AI-AI-Ed-Global-Perspectives-Title-YT-Player-1-900x506.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1300px) 100vw, 1300px" /></a></figure></div>


<p>This episode features a conversation led by Ben Garside (Raspberry Pi Foundation), with contributions from Leonida Soi (Raspberry Pi Foundation, Kenya), Aimy Lee (Penang Science Cluster, Malaysia), and Monika Katkutė-Gelžinė (Vedliai, Lithuania). All are key collaborators in the Raspberry Pi Foundation&#8217;s AI literacy programme, Experience AI.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GvVe9a54cpE" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Watch here</a></div>
</div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The digital literacy gap</strong></h2>



<p>One of the most striking takeaways from the conversation is the universal excitement surrounding AI, coupled with a significant need for foundational digital literacy. As Leonida explains:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>&#8220;There&#8217;s an excitement about AI literacy, both from the learners and the teachers&#8230; However, one thing to look into is, we still have low digital literacy. As much as we are bringing in AI, if it is not bundled up together with digital literacy, then there is also misuse.&#8221;&nbsp;</em></p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1080" height="720" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image1.jpg" alt=" Leonida Soi, Learning Manager, Raspberry Pi Foundation" class="wp-image-91056" style="width:616px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image1.jpg 1080w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image1-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image1-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image1-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image1-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1080px) 100vw, 1080px" /></figure></div>


<p>This highlights a crucial point: simply introducing AI tools isn&#8217;t enough. A solid understanding of digital fundamentals is essential for responsible and effective use of AI.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Different contexts, shared challenges</strong></h2>



<p>The discussion also reveals the varying approaches to AI education in different countries. Monika shares her experience in Lithuania:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>&#8220;We&#8217;ve been teaching AI for the last 5 years&#8230; I see a lot of opportunity in it, but a lot of challenges not to overburden teachers with the noise and changes.&#8221;</em></p>
</blockquote>



<p>Her insight highlights the ongoing need for teacher training and sustainable pedagogical strategies, particularly in a field that evolves so quickly.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>AI literacy beyond computer science</strong></h2>



<p>A key theme throughout the podcast is the importance of integrating AI literacy beyond traditional computer science classrooms. As Leonida emphasises:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>&#8220;It&#8217;s time that AI literacy is looked at from a broader view, not just in computing&#8230; something that cuts across all the learning areas.&#8221;</em></p>
</blockquote>



<p>This sentiment is echoed by Monika, who suggests:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>&#8220;I feel like the entire education system needs to go through an AI filter and come out of it with a bit more efficiency, with a bit more understanding, so it lives in a 21st-century AI world. And I see AI as a form of, you know, building and also as a co-worker for everyone in the future.&#8221;</em></p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1999" height="1325" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image2.jpg" alt="Monica Katkute-Gelzine, Vedliai, Experience AI global partner, Lithuania." class="wp-image-91059" style="width:564px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image2.jpg 1999w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image2-300x199.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image2-500x331.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image2-768x509.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image2-1536x1018.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image2-800x530.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image2-450x298.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image2-900x597.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /></figure></div>


<p>The vision of AI as a &#8220;co-worker&#8221; for all, empowering young people rather than replacing them, offers a powerful perspective for future education.<br></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Addressing the digital divide</strong></h2>



<p>Equity is another critical issue, particularly in rural areas. Aimy highlights the ongoing challenge of access:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>&#8220;The digital divide is in the access to devices, as well as access to high-speed internet connections&#8230; but the other thing is also in terms of trained teachers as well.&#8221;</em></p>
</blockquote>



<p>Leonida adds that in Kenya there&#8217;s a need for unplugged activities to give students an idea of what the world is doing, so that we can start to bridge that gap.</p>



<p>These insights highlight the need for equitable access and innovative teaching methods to ensure no one is left behind.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Encouragement for educators: start small, support each other</strong></h2>



<p>For teachers who might feel overwhelmed by the prospect of teaching AI, the advice is clear and encouraging. Aimy suggests:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>&#8220;Start small, cover one topic at a time, one concept at a time. Don&#8217;t feel the need to cover everything all at the same time.&#8221; </em></p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="1000" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image3.png" alt="Aimy Lee, Penang Science Cluster, Experience AI global partner, Malaysia." class="wp-image-91061" style="width:416px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image3.png 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image3-250x250.png 250w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image3-500x500.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image3-150x150.png 150w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image3-768x768.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image3-800x800.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image3-100x100.png 100w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image3-300x300.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image3-450x450.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image3-900x900.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p><br>Leonida advocates for the power of community, suggesting a <em>&#8220;community of practice where [teachers] can share amongst each other and where they can encourage others.&#8221;</em><br><br>Building a network of support and shared resources is key as educators take their first steps into teaching AI.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Listen now</strong></h2>



<p>This episode of the Hello World podcast is a powerful reminder that AI literacy is not just a skill, but a mindset that needs to be nurtured across all subjects and communities. It also underscores that the commitment to prepare the next generation for an AI-powered world is global.</p>



<p>Listen to the full episode of the Hello World podcast to learn more about the global state of AI literacy and gain practical insights for your classroom.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/podcast/what-does-ai-education-look-like-around-the-world" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Listen to the full episode</a></div>
</div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Learn more about Experience AI</strong></h2>



<p>The Experience AI programme is a collaboration between the Raspberry Pi Foundation and Google DeepMind to help young people and educators understand and engage with artificial intelligence. Through free, classroom-ready resources, professional development for teachers, and global partnerships, the programme aims to make AI literacy accessible to all, regardless of geography or background. By supporting educators and inspiring students, Experience AI is helping to prepare the next generation to thrive in a world increasingly shaped by artificial intelligence.</p>



<p><a href="https://experience-ai.org/">Find out more about Experience AI</a> and how it can support you to bring AI literacy skills to your learners.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/hello-world-podcast-what-does-ai-education-look-like-around-the-world/">Hello World podcast: What does AI education look like around the world?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/hello-world-podcast-what-does-ai-education-look-like-around-the-world/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Creating a space for connection and code: Meet Seung Woo (Tony), Canada</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/creating-a-space-for-connection-and-code-meet-seung-woo-tony-canada/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/creating-a-space-for-connection-and-code-meet-seung-woo-tony-canada/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sophie Ashford]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 09:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Code Club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=91087</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We love hearing from members of the community and sharing the stories of amazing young people, volunteers, and educators who are using their passion for technology to create positive change in the world around them. Seung Woo, also known as Tony, is a 17-year-old student from Canada and the co-founder of his school’s Code Club,&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/creating-a-space-for-connection-and-code-meet-seung-woo-tony-canada/">Creating a space for connection and code: Meet Seung Woo (Tony), Canada</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We love hearing from members of the community and sharing the stories of amazing young people, volunteers, and educators who are using their passion for technology to create positive change in the world around them.</p>



<p>Seung Woo, also known as Tony, is a 17-year-old student from Canada and the co-founder of his school’s Code Club, alongside his teacher, Kay. A curious and driven teen with big ambitions in computer science, Tony is not only passionate about technology, but also dedicated to building a safe, welcoming space where others can learn, explore, and grow alongside him.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="800" height="600" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Image-1.jpg" alt="Tony working on a programming project using a laptop." class="wp-image-91091" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Image-1.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Image-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Image-1-500x375.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Image-1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Image-1-450x338.jpg 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>A spark of inspiration</strong></h2>



<p>Tony’s fascination with computers started early, driven by his love of video games, coding, and, perhaps most memorably, his admiration for Tony Stark, the comic-book and film character who becomes the superhero Iron Man! The idea of building something powerful from scratch stuck with him.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“My whole life, I have been curious about the inner workings of a computer and my inspiration for coding is Tony Stark or Iron Man from the Marvel Cinematic Universe!”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Tony’s early coding journey wasn’t without its challenges. Finding the right resources was difficult, and staying motivated during tough moments was often hard without a support system.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Like many others, I was independently taught, and during this time of independent learning I’d find many different roadblocks and challenges that I had to overcome alone. A big setback for me was finding the right resources in order to learn how to code. Another big obstacle for me was motivation. I would find myself losing interest in a project. I didn’t have the exterior motivation to help me push through the inevitable hardships that come with coding.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>That’s where the idea for a coding club began to take shape.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Creating a community of coders</strong></h2>



<p>Tony co-founded the Code Club at Collège Jeanne-Sauvé in December 2024 with that exact vision in mind — he wanted to provide a fun, collaborative, and welcoming environment where students of all skill levels could explore their love of technology together.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I created the coding club to help everyone on their journey of computer science, no matter their skill level, and that is exactly what it is turning out to be. Finding resources is easier than ever with a teacher and all of the amazing members.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Tony’s teacher and co-founder, Kay, shared why Code Club was the right fit for the school.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I thought Code Club was the best way to start our club for a few reasons. The amount of coding language options was varied and appealed to the different learners in our club. It was also important for us to promote our club and let our community know about the presence of a coding club in our school, and Code Club helped us do so via their online presence.”</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What makes Code Club special</strong></h2>



<p>For Tony, the secret ingredient behind his club’s success is simple: teamwork.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Without teamwork, our club wouldn&#8217;t really be a club, it would simply be an ensemble of people coding in their own little cubicles, much like a stereotypical office job, and to me, that does not sound too enjoyable. Teamwork is our little secret ingredient in problem-solving and building motivation, we embrace it by creating a safe space where everyone can speak their minds without judgement!”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Members are free to choose their own learning paths. No matter the project, the atmosphere is always filled with laughter, energy, and curiosity.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Coding should be something that is fun — not stressful like others may make it seem. Celebrating achievements, making short term goals, and problem solving with friends are all great ways that we make coding fun in our club. A second word would be teamwork. Without teamwork, our club wouldn’t really be a club.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Teamwork, he adds, transforms what could be a solitary activity into something social and deeply motivating.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Looking to the future</strong></h2>



<p>Tony hopes the club will continue to grow, bringing more students into the world of coding and helping them feel at home in it. His story is a great reminder that learning to code isn’t just about computers — it’s about building community, confidence, and creativity.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I wanted to create a space where everyone would be accepted and encouraged to learn more about coding and not be ashamed to ‘nerd out’ about this subject like I do very frequently. I’ve dreamed of creating a space that embraces this beautiful passion.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>If you’d like to explore coding, you can get started at home with <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">over 250 free projects</a>. </p>



<p>For a little more support, or if you’re open to mentoring others, you can also join a Code Club. <a href="https://codeclub.org/en/find" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Check our website to find a club near you</a> and become part of a like-minded and welcoming community.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/creating-a-space-for-connection-and-code-meet-seung-woo-tony-canada/">Creating a space for connection and code: Meet Seung Woo (Tony), Canada</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/creating-a-space-for-connection-and-code-meet-seung-woo-tony-canada/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Essential tips to integrate computer science into your lessons: Teacher tips from CSTA 2025</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teacher-tips-csta-2025-integrating-computer-science/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teacher-tips-csta-2025-integrating-computer-science/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Sayers]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 14:49:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hello World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CSTA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teacher tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CSTA2025]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=91014</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In our latest podcast miniseries, we spoke to educators live from the CSTA 2025 annual conference in Cleveland, Ohio, to hear their top tips for integrating computer science (CS) into other subjects. Hello World editor, Meg Wang and the team met teachers in the exhibit hall for real-time reflections and essential teacher tips on teaching&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teacher-tips-csta-2025-integrating-computer-science/">Essential tips to integrate computer science into your lessons: Teacher tips from CSTA 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In our latest podcast miniseries, we spoke to educators live from the CSTA 2025 annual conference in Cleveland, Ohio, to hear their top tips for integrating computer science (CS) into other subjects.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1200" height="1600" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image.jpeg" alt="Behind the scenes of Meg Wang, editor of the Hello World magazine presenting the latest episodes of the Hello World podcast, from CSTA 2025." class="wp-image-91017" style="width:403px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image.jpeg 1200w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-188x250.jpeg 188w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-500x667.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-768x1024.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-1152x1536.jpeg 1152w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-800x1067.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-450x600.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/image-900x1200.jpeg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></figure></div>


<p>Hello World editor, Meg Wang and the team met teachers in the exhibit hall for real-time reflections and essential teacher tips on teaching cross-curricular CS. They spoke to some amazing educators from across the United States and had a great time interacting with everyone in attendance.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Meeting teachers and hearing first-hand about their experiences, challenges, and triumphs was invaluable. It was amazing to meet Hello World writers in person, and to also meet future writers. Like I said at the conference, Hello World is for educators, by educators, so that means you! Everyone has valuable experience or useful advice to share, and we’re here to help you amplify that.” – Meg Wang, editor of the Hello World magazine</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Who features in the episode, and what are their tips?</strong></h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Lisa Wenzel, CS teacher from Maryland, USA</h3>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-qw.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXd-4xIDnUeEND7pwPV11mhoJ5TuSDSL8WLp0_k-tvwYtGk6030rtnvZCmNlwcQkQbGIax7WrcQAvUwycf20HOZTq62l-7b9ii0Q95t9Q_eessI1ZTUY7lVmXH1oYcBenGeL6h7H?key=7RhKhvZxEipxlaKP-6eDxA" alt="Lisa Wenzel, CS teacher in Maryland, USA, smiling and holding a physical copy of Hello World, issue 27." style="width:736px;height:auto"/></figure></div>


<p>Lisa&#8217;s top tip for integrating computer science into your lessons is to start with topics that you&#8217;re passionate about. If you&#8217;re not a CS teacher yourself, Lisa suggests finding a colleague who teaches the subject. She advises having a chat with them to explore how you can include CS concepts into subjects you&#8217;re particularly interested in.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;I guarantee you that they&#8217;re going to have something [&#8230;] to teach [another subject], and it&#8217;s going to involve computer science.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Through peer discussions and collaboration between educators, you’ll discover engaging ways that you can incorporate CS into your teaching. Give it a try the next time you’re chatting to a CS teacher.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Tiffany N. Jones, CS and Cybersecurity teacher in Georgia, USA</h3>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-qw.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXdnhiKOz-voQhdjuyhXwwsswUfrJXZCk-4yrptvIjZlbdy0-J-ETwByI4ujl8a2yXx5yPpOitz6GH7x1ccbbP0vZzEa8E35uemeKYKzDYs1Yvn0w5qBewD6TDpg7ytzGVD4uhOQ?key=7RhKhvZxEipxlaKP-6eDxA" alt="Tiffany N. Jones CS &amp; Cybersecurity teacher in Georgia, USA smiling showcasing her article in Hello World Issue 27." style="width:257px;height:auto"/></figure></div>


<p>Tiffany N. Jones, author of ‘Belonging in Tech’ (featured on page 82 of <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/issues/27" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hello World Issue 27</a>), shares her top tip to seamlessly integrate computer science into other subjects.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Using the example of a class studying ocean health and pollution, Tiffany shares how you can introduce students to real-world applications of computer science by exploring how sensors and microcontrollers can be used to collect environmental data.&nbsp;</p>



<p>She then suggests exploring how databases and programming languages can be used to analyse and visualise the data that the sensors and microcontrollers have recorded. This not only deepens your learner&#8217;s scientific understanding but also demonstrates how computing concepts are used in real-world industry practices.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Rick Ballew, CS and Engineering teacher in Minnesota, USA</h3>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-qw.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXfSDI8LnhX0lo4bHMS561Nu_oCpHQRpWQSm1sq5xxlvA9RbbVAUXgqG9AprjKqwQj4TGYfObiEnVsWYzTFPgUPwIk_qjVoDIgsFqC_3BGH3Ndc1-IerUCfouWR-tBBHxhYlNpfL5g?key=7RhKhvZxEipxlaKP-6eDxA" alt="Rick Ballew CS &amp; Engineering teacher in Minnesota, USA smiling holding a physical copy of Hello World issue 27" style="width:320px;height:auto"/></figure></div>


<p>Rick’s top tip for integrating CS is to first think about your favourite lesson and consider ways that you can introduce computational thinking.</p>



<p>In the podcast, Rick says:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p> “chances are, computational thinking is already a part of that lesson you&#8217;re doing. Call it out to the students, and that&#8217;s going to help them to start understanding how computer science is baked into everything we do.”&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Rick also offers a great example from his experience as a band teacher. He shares how learning to read a new piece of music is very similar to the steps involved in computational thinking.&nbsp;s</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“[You’ve] got to break it down. There&#8217;s abstraction. You&#8217;ve got to figure out the sequencing, and you create the way that you&#8217;re going to learn it. And that is all part of computational thinking.”&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>This approach shows students that CS isn&#8217;t just coding; it&#8217;s a way of thinking that can be applied across disciplines.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Listen now</strong></h2>



<p>To hear more practical teacher tips and discover what else our guest teachers had to say, <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/podcast/teacher-tips-csta-2025" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">listen to or watch the full episode here</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We hope this episode inspires you and helps you to engage your students in computing. We’d love to hear your thoughts, your feedback, and any of your own tips on how to integrate CS into other subjects. Share your advice in the comments section below.</p>



<p>We hope you enjoy the episode!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>More to listen to next week</strong></h2>



<p>Next week, we’ll be sharing an interesting conversation between Ben Garside, Senior Learning Manager (AI Literacy) at the Raspberry Pi Foundation, Leonida Soi, Learning Manager (Kenya) at the Raspberry Pi Foundation, and two of our global <a href="https://experience-ai.org/en/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Experience AI</a> partners, Monika Katkutė-Gelžinė from Vedliai in Lithuania, and Aimy Lee from Penang Science Cluster in Malaysia.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-qw.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXcLKAKrtJ25fjJT2E4r7AHOU3g52XjpM_BzF7h6bLohXv5jXqzqhpGYeYimSnoofDuwSwbY_f9HBris0uckm14poC3pi8FUuhaClS4nJoyeg6T3UyOiHIaw70s8w-rdYneqKG8z5A?key=7RhKhvZxEipxlaKP-6eDxA" alt="Selfie with the Hello World Podcast team" style="width:368px;height:auto"/></figure></div>


<p>They’ll be exploring what AI education looks like around the world and what teachers need to feel confident teaching it.</p>



<p>You can watch or listen to each episode of our podcast on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLxyaWvsfmq49s-6lJKH1sNcYAeBUizoMr" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">YouTube</a>, or listen via your preferred audio streaming service, whether that’s <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/hello-world/id1564031383" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Apple Podcasts</a>, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/1CagYUqVlkJK9zRN6yaQwG">Spotify</a>, or <a href="https://music.amazon.com/podcasts/7954c4f7-884c-4a91-90e3-1fbd3fdc4ff3/hello-world" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Amazon Music</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Subscribe to Hello World today</a> to ensure you never miss a podcast episode or issue of the magazine.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-16018d1d wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world">Subscribe</a></div>
</div>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teacher-tips-csta-2025-integrating-computer-science/">Essential tips to integrate computer science into your lessons: Teacher tips from CSTA 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teacher-tips-csta-2025-integrating-computer-science/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Giving back through Code Club: Meet Douglas</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/giving-back-through-code-club-meet-douglas/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/giving-back-through-code-club-meet-douglas/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sophie Ashford]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 10:03:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Code Club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=90978</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We love hearing from members of the community and sharing the stories of amazing young people, volunteers, and educators who are using their passion for technology to create positive change in the world around them. Growing up in Mathare, one of Nairobi’s largest informal settlements, Douglas experienced first-hand what it meant to go without access&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/giving-back-through-code-club-meet-douglas/">Giving back through Code Club: Meet Douglas</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We love hearing from members of the community and sharing the stories of amazing young people, volunteers, and educators who are using their passion for technology to create positive change in the world around them.</p>



<p>Growing up in Mathare, one of Nairobi’s largest informal settlements, Douglas experienced first-hand what it meant to go without access to education and opportunity. His experience sparked a <a href="https://codeclub.org/en/">Code Club</a> journey that is already hugely inspiring… and it’s only just getting started.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="668" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6616.jpg" alt="Douglas (second from left) with members of the Raspberry Pi Foundation team" class="wp-image-90980" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6616.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6616-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6616-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6616-768x513.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6616-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6616-450x301.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6616-900x601.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Douglas (second from left) with members of the Raspberry Pi Foundation team</figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Driven by a desire to help&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p>For Douglas and many of his peers, the limited access to education in Mathare often meant being left with no clear path to earn a livelihood. Douglas saw opportunity in technology — he wanted to increase access in this field for the young people in Mathare and raise their ambitions.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Why are we doing technology? Because we believe that tech does not have a boundary. As long as you have access to the internet and you can learn some basic skills… the opportunities are limitless.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>That belief became the keystone of Oasis Mathare, an organisation co-founded by Douglas and a group of others with similar lived experiences. Like Douglas, most of the founding members haven’t followed a standard path with formal schooling, but all understand the power of technology to transform lives.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>From Photoshop to programming</strong></h2>



<p>Douglas’ own tech journey began humbly, and was sparked by his curiosity.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“After primary, I didn’t go straight to high school. I spent two years working in a nearby barber shop. Then I think I just fell in love with computers. I learned how to do some basic stuff with design and used to play around with Photoshop.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>From there, he taught himself web design and programming skills, which began to open new doors. Eventually, he went back to university to study business and information technology to deepen his knowledge, but even before that, Douglas had already started giving back.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“We used to hold a club providing a space for kids to come and play games on computers. That sort of grew from just Saturdays to a few times a week… and now it&#8217;s full time.”</p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="668" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6548.jpg" alt="One of Oasis Mathare’s Code Clubs in action" class="wp-image-90982" style="width:720px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6548.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6548-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6548-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6548-768x513.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6548-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6548-450x301.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6548-900x601.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>One of Oasis Mathare’s Code Clubs in action</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Why Code Clubs?</strong></h2>



<p>Today, Oasis Mathare runs intensive software engineering and robotics programs that last between 9 and 12 months. But back in the early days of the organisation, Douglas quickly realised that many young people were struggling to keep up — not because of ability, but because they’d never used a computer before.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“So, we started Code Clubs to introduce these principles of programming at an early age… and we actually realised that those who have gone through Code Club take less time to complete our software engineering and robotics classes.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Code Clubs now serve as a stepping stone at Oasis Mathare. They help introduce computer literacy and programming concepts to young people early, making it easier for them to thrive in more advanced programs.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The power of role models</strong></h2>



<p>The impact of the program is already visible. Many graduates of Oasis Mathare programs go on to volunteer and eventually teach, serving as role models for the younger learners.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Oasis Mathare has 6 full-time staff. There are 12 Code Club leaders. They are our graduates from the software engineering program. We are plugging them into the Code Clubs to help them gain confidence and help the next generation.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The Code Clubs are held both in schools and at the Oasis Mathare centre, creating safe, structured environments for learning, experimenting, and collaborating.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="668" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6534.jpg" alt="Douglas supporting a Code Club mentor" class="wp-image-90983" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6534.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6534-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6534-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6534-768x513.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6534-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6534-450x301.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6534-900x601.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Douglas supporting a Code Club mentor</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Building with what they have</strong></h2>



<p>Before setting up Code Clubs, Oasis Mathare ran STEM clubs that used a variety of resources, but the cost and maintenance became a barrier. When they discovered Code Club’s free-to-access resources, everything changed.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“We found [the resources] very useful. The good thing about Code Club is you can plan sessions using resources that are freely available, like Scratch. It&#8217;s really straightforward.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The biggest challenge now? Internet access is limited, so Douglas and his team often work offline. The team have started using the Raspberry Pi Foundation’s offline resources, and look forward to more being available in the future.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What’s next for Douglas and Oasis Mathare?</strong></h2>



<p>Douglas and the Oasis Mathare team have already achieved so much. This was recognised with a royal seal of approval in 2018, when Douglas was honoured with the Queen’s Young Leaders Award by Queen Elizabeth at Buckingham Palace. Through the award, he gained access to world-class mentoring and leadership training from the University of Cambridge, helping him to amplify his impact back home.</p>



<p>So, what’s next? Douglas’ vision for the future is bold and clear.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The main idea is to ensure that all kids in Mathare know at least one computer language. Not for the sake of it, but to use the principles of programming to solve their local problems.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>By learning coding, young people build more than just technical skills. They learn to think critically, work in teams, and solve problems in their communities. For Douglas, that’s the real impact.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The overall goal is to ensure that no youth in Mathare are left behind and they all have the opportunity to develop essential skills from an early age.”</p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="668" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6594.jpg" alt="Students at an Oasis Mathare Code Club working together" class="wp-image-90984" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6594.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6594-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6594-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6594-768x513.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6594-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6594-450x301.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC_6594-900x601.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Looking further ahead</strong></h2>



<p>Oasis Mathare runs Code Clubs weekly, all year round, and Douglas is always looking for ways to expand the program’s reach, especially through partnerships, sponsorships, and sharing their successes so far.</p>



<p>With more resources, more local leaders, and a whole community behind him, Douglas is rewriting the narrative for young people in Mathare. You can find out more about Oasis Mathare on their <a href="https://www.oasismathare.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">official website.</a></p>



<p>If you’d like to support young people in your community to explore coding, why not start a Code Club? The team will support you every step of the way with resources, training, and a collaborative community. Find out more on the <a href="https://codeclub.org/en/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Code Club</a> website.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/giving-back-through-code-club-meet-douglas/">Giving back through Code Club: Meet Douglas</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/giving-back-through-code-club-meet-douglas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Code, karaoke, and creativity: Meet Matthew</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-karaoke-and-creativity-meet-matthew/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-karaoke-and-creativity-meet-matthew/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sophie Ashford]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 09:31:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Code Club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=90961</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We love hearing from members of the community and sharing stories of amazing young people, volunteers, and educators who are using their passion for technology to create positive change in the world around them. It’s especially inspiring to hear about young people who are not only passionate about technology, but who are also driven to&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-karaoke-and-creativity-meet-matthew/">Code, karaoke, and creativity: Meet Matthew</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We love hearing from members of the community and sharing stories of amazing young people, volunteers, and educators who are using their passion for technology to create positive change in the world around them.</p>



<p>It’s especially inspiring to hear about young people who are not only passionate about technology, but who are also driven to share that passion with others. Meet Matthew, a 15-year-old creator and youth mentor at Code Club, who builds his own projects and inspires peers by organising hackathons.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="667" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/B75E500F-1628-4FF9-B924-D7CA70562AA4_1_102_o.jpeg" alt="Matthew and his team at Cool as Hack at the RPF offices" class="wp-image-90962" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/B75E500F-1628-4FF9-B924-D7CA70562AA4_1_102_o.jpeg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/B75E500F-1628-4FF9-B924-D7CA70562AA4_1_102_o-300x200.jpeg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/B75E500F-1628-4FF9-B924-D7CA70562AA4_1_102_o-500x334.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/B75E500F-1628-4FF9-B924-D7CA70562AA4_1_102_o-768x512.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/B75E500F-1628-4FF9-B924-D7CA70562AA4_1_102_o-800x534.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/B75E500F-1628-4FF9-B924-D7CA70562AA4_1_102_o-450x300.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/B75E500F-1628-4FF9-B924-D7CA70562AA4_1_102_o-900x600.jpeg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Matthew and his team at Cool as Hack at the RPF offices</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Matthew’s early experience with coding&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p>Matthew’s journey into the world of coding began at a young age. His initial exposure was through Scratch at school in Singapore. From there, he began exploring self-learn platforms in his own time, getting to grips with HTML and basic web development.</p>



<p>His enthusiasm for creating led him to participate in a technology week in Year 6, where he took on a BBC micro:bit challenge. He dedicated his summer holiday to developing a token system that encouraged community recycling, using an ultrasonic sensor to award points for good behaviour. This early project showcased his knack for problem-solving and innovation.</p>



<p>What truly captivated Matthew was the possibility of combining the logical challenges of competitive programming with the joy of project creation.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1080" height="1440" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6750.jpeg" alt="Matthew with his device developed in Year 6 to promote recycling behaviour in his residential community" class="wp-image-90963" style="width:520px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6750.jpeg 1080w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6750-188x250.jpeg 188w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6750-500x667.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6750-768x1024.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6750-800x1067.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6750-450x600.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6750-900x1200.jpeg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1080px) 100vw, 1080px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Matthew with his device developed in Year 6 to promote recycling behaviour in his residential community</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Connecting with the community</strong></h2>



<p>Through <a href="https://youthacks.org/">Youthhacks</a>, an initiative he co-founded to support teenage hackathon organisers, Matthew aims to expand access to hackathons across the UK (a hackathon is an event where individuals or teams work intensively over a relatively short time period to build software, hardware, or other kinds of technology). Matthew wants to offer advice and support, making it easier for young people to run their own hackathons. He puts a lot of time into ensuring that the content and atmosphere truly resonate with the participants.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“So, we made Youthhacks basically as an idea to be able to support these teenage organisers, you know, like hackathons for teenagers by teenagers.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Matthew’s connection with the Raspberry Pi Foundation came from his keen interest in the hackathon community and a need for a local venue. Having previously toured the Foundation’s offices for a school robotics club, he decided to reach out when organising a satellite hackathon called Counterspell.</p>



<p>This initial collaboration led to further events at the Foundation, including Scrapyard Cambridge and, more recently, Cool as Hack.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Coolest Projects hackathon: A new approach to collaborative coding&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p><a href="https://coolashack.youthacks.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Cool as Hack</a> was Matthew’s third event held at the Raspberry Pi Foundation offices. Unlike traditional hackathons with intense time pressure, this event, inspired by the spirit of <a href="https://online.coolestprojects.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Coolest Projects</a>, aimed to be more relaxed and collaborative.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“For this, people could bring in their own project scraps and then they could put it together with a team, finalise it, and then enter it to Coolest Projects.”&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The focus was on showcasing creativity and sharing projects globally, rather than competitive prizes. Everyone then entered their creations into the Coolest Projects online showcase.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="667" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9590.jpg" alt="Young coders at Cool as Hack" class="wp-image-90964" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9590.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9590-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9590-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9590-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9590-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9590-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9590-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Cool as Hack in progress at RPF HQ. Credit: W O Wallace</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Cool as Hack was a huge success. The atmosphere was incredible — there was even a karaoke session and a “swag shop” where participants could exchange tokens earned for innovative ideas or project milestones. This token system, designed by Matthew and harking back to his own recycling project from years ago, created a fun and engaging reward system.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Inspiring the next generation</strong></h2>



<p>Matthew’s drive to organise these events and encourage other young people to code stems from his enjoyment of project creation and the community aspect of hackathons.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Well, I suppose it links back to me enjoying making projects and when you attend a hackathon, it&#8217;s not a competition really. It&#8217;s more of a social event. So, you&#8217;re making a project and then you&#8217;re meeting quite a lot of coders, or even artists and musicians, and so many other people.”</p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="667" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9679.jpg" alt="Young coders at Cool as Hack at the RPF offices" class="wp-image-90966" style="width:720px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9679.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9679-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9679-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9679-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9679-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9679-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/DSC9679-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">All of the creators that took part in Cool as Hack. Credit: W O Wallace</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Now a regular volunteer at the Raspberry Pi Foundation’s monthly Code Club in Cambridge, Matthew remains focused on encouraging others into tech. For aspiring young coders, he says that coding is far more diverse and creative than many might initially perceive, encompassing art, storytelling, and problem-solving. Matthew’s advice is simple:&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Enjoy the process and as you learn new things you’ll realise that all of this is like super interesting, and that there are so many ways to make what you want. Just enjoy it and continue meeting new people and, yeah, be creative.”&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Matthew’s journey shows how an intro to computing at a young age can lead to an incredible amount of impact. With his continued dedication, he&#8217;s sure to inspire many more young minds to start on their own coding adventures.</p>



<p><strong>If you would like to explore coding, you can get started at home with <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">over 250 free projects</a>.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p><strong>Looking for a little extra support in your own coding journey or open to mentoring others? <a href="https://codeclub.org/en/join-a-club" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Join a Code Club</a> near you to meet a like-minded and supportive community.</strong></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-karaoke-and-creativity-meet-matthew/">Code, karaoke, and creativity: Meet Matthew</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/code-karaoke-and-creativity-meet-matthew/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Hello World podcast series: Bringing computer science into every classroom</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/new-hello-world-podcast-series-bringing-computer-science-into-every-classroom/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/new-hello-world-podcast-series-bringing-computer-science-into-every-classroom/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Sayers]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 11:34:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hello World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cross-curricular teaching]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cross-disciplinary computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CSTA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Integrated CS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hello world podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=90935</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Hello World podcast is back, accompanying the latest issue of Hello World magazine. This new three-part miniseries explores some of the topics from issue 27 of Hello World, which focuses on integrating computing education across the curriculum. Whether you&#8217;re a seasoned educator or just starting your journey with computing education, this podcast audio and&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/new-hello-world-podcast-series-bringing-computer-science-into-every-classroom/">New Hello World podcast series: Bringing computer science into every classroom</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Hello World podcast is back, accompanying the latest issue of <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world">Hello World</a> magazine. This new three-part miniseries explores some of the topics from <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/issues/27">issue 27 of Hello World</a>, which focuses on integrating computing education across the curriculum.<br></p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="https://youtu.be/2NT2R-kbZaA"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.1-Thumbnail-Title-Positioned-Bottom-YT-Player.png" alt="" class="wp-image-90944" style="width:698px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.1-Thumbnail-Title-Positioned-Bottom-YT-Player.png 1920w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.1-Thumbnail-Title-Positioned-Bottom-YT-Player-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.1-Thumbnail-Title-Positioned-Bottom-YT-Player-500x281.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.1-Thumbnail-Title-Positioned-Bottom-YT-Player-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.1-Thumbnail-Title-Positioned-Bottom-YT-Player-1536x864.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.1-Thumbnail-Title-Positioned-Bottom-YT-Player-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.1-Thumbnail-Title-Positioned-Bottom-YT-Player-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.1-Thumbnail-Title-Positioned-Bottom-YT-Player-900x506.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /></a></figure></div>


<p>Whether you&#8217;re a seasoned educator or just starting your journey with computing education, this podcast audio and video series is full of insights, inspiration, and practical tips from educators and experts around the world. </p>



<p>If you’re already subscribed, the new episodes will appear automatically in your favourite podcast app every Tuesday.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Episode 1: Why kids still need to learn to code in the age of AI</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Out now</strong></h3>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="https://youtu.be/_pWmaytjLBA"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.2-No-James-Kids-and-code-in-the-age-of-AI-Title-Positioned-Bottom-Plain-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-90945" style="width:759px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.2-No-James-Kids-and-code-in-the-age-of-AI-Title-Positioned-Bottom-Plain-1.jpg 1920w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.2-No-James-Kids-and-code-in-the-age-of-AI-Title-Positioned-Bottom-Plain-1-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.2-No-James-Kids-and-code-in-the-age-of-AI-Title-Positioned-Bottom-Plain-1-500x281.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.2-No-James-Kids-and-code-in-the-age-of-AI-Title-Positioned-Bottom-Plain-1-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.2-No-James-Kids-and-code-in-the-age-of-AI-Title-Positioned-Bottom-Plain-1-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.2-No-James-Kids-and-code-in-the-age-of-AI-Title-Positioned-Bottom-Plain-1-800x450.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.2-No-James-Kids-and-code-in-the-age-of-AI-Title-Positioned-Bottom-Plain-1-450x253.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/27.2-No-James-Kids-and-code-in-the-age-of-AI-Title-Positioned-Bottom-Plain-1-900x506.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /></a></figure></div>


<p>In our first episode, Raspberry Pi Foundation CEO Philip Colligan, CBE, sits down with teacher Janine Kirk to discuss <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/why-kids-still-need-to-learn-to-code-in-the-age-of-ai/">why, in the age of AI, it’s more important than ever for young people to learn to code</a>. Their conversation draws on ideas from <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/why-kids-still-need-to-learn-to-code-in-the-age-of-ai/">our downloadable position paper</a>, which is also featured in issue 27 of Hello World magazine.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Episode 2: Voices &amp; tips from CSTA conference</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Released Tuesday 15 July</strong></h3>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="667" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6707-500x667.jpg" alt="Photo of Hello World editor, Meg Wang, and contributing editor Dominick Sanders at CSTA 2025." class="wp-image-90946" style="width:350px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6707-500x667.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6707-188x250.jpg 188w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6707-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6707-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6707-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6707-800x1067.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6707-450x600.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6707-900x1200.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/IMG_6707-scaled.jpg 1920w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>Next week, we’ll bring you the buzz from the Computer Science Teachers Association’s annual conference in Cleveland, USA. We’re speaking with educators at the conference to hear how they’re integrating computer science across subjects, and you&#8217;ll hear their top classroom tips for teaching CS in context.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Episode 3: Global perspectives on AI education</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Released Tuesday 22 July</strong></h3>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2560" height="1706" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Photo-Episode-27.4-1-scaled.jpg" alt="Episode 3 of the Hello World Podcast set" class="wp-image-90936" style="width:674px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Photo-Episode-27.4-1-scaled.jpg 2560w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Photo-Episode-27.4-1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Photo-Episode-27.4-1-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Photo-Episode-27.4-1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Photo-Episode-27.4-1-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Photo-Episode-27.4-1-2048x1365.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Photo-Episode-27.4-1-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Photo-Episode-27.4-1-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/07/Photo-Episode-27.4-1-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /></figure></div>


<p>The miniseries wraps up with an in-depth discussion about <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/teach/ai-education">AI education</a> around the world. Hosted by <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/author/ben-garside/">Ben Garside</a>, Senior Learning Manager for <a href="https://experience-ai.org/?utm_source=web&amp;utm_medium=rpf-ai-education-page">Experience AI</a>, the conversation features Leonida Soi, Learning Manager in Kenya; Monika Katkute-Gelzine, CEO of Vedliai in Lithuania; and <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teaching-a-generation-of-ai-innovators-in-malaysia-with-experience-ai/">Aimy Lee</a>, COO of Penang Science Cluster in Malaysia. Monika and Aimy work with us in our <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-expands-to-reach-over-2-million-students/">global Experience AI partner programme</a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Listen, read, learn, subscribe, and share</h2>



<p>Each of these three podcast episode builds on the themes in the latest Hello World issue, where you&#8217;ll find inspiration and practical tips from educators who are integrating CS across a variety of subjects and for all school ages.</p>



<p>Subscribe to the Hello World podcast wherever you get your podcasts to never miss an episode, and to help us reach more teachers. If you&#8217;re subscribe to Hello World magazine (it&#8217;s free), we’ll also let you know when new podcast episodes are available.</p>



<p>And, don’t forget to share this new podcast series with your fellow educators.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/new-hello-world-podcast-series-bringing-computer-science-into-every-classroom/">New Hello World podcast series: Bringing computer science into every classroom</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/new-hello-world-podcast-series-bringing-computer-science-into-every-classroom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
