<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Raspberry Pi Foundation</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/</link>
	<description>Teach, learn and make with Raspberry Pi</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 08:41:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/06/cropped-raspberrry_pi_logo-100x100.png</url>
	<title>Raspberry Pi Foundation</title>
	<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Helping young people navigate AI safely</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/helping-young-people-navigate-ai-safely/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/helping-young-people-navigate-ai-safely/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mac Bowley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 09:46:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Experience AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI Safety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI education]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89321</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>AI safety and Experience AI As our lives become increasingly intertwined with AI-powered tools and systems, it’s more important than ever to equip young people with the skills and knowledge they need to engage with AI safely and responsibly. AI literacy isn’t just about understanding the technology — it’s about fostering critical conversations on how&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/helping-young-people-navigate-ai-safely/">Helping young people navigate AI safely</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">AI safety and Experience AI</h2>



<p>As our lives become increasingly intertwined with AI-powered tools and systems, it’s more important than ever to equip young people with the skills and knowledge they need to engage with AI safely and responsibly. AI literacy isn’t just about understanding the technology — it’s about fostering critical conversations on how to integrate AI tools into our lives while minimising potential harm — otherwise known as ‘AI safety’.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage1-1-500x281.png" alt="" class="wp-image-89322" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage1-1-500x281.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage1-1-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage1-1-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage1-1-1536x864.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage1-1-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage1-1-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage1-1-900x506.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage1-1.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p><a href="https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/media/65438d159e05fd0014be7bd9/introducing-ai-safety-institute-web-accessible.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The UK AI Safety Institute defines AI safety as</a>: “The understanding, prevention, and mitigation of harms from AI. These harms could be deliberate or accidental; caused to individuals, groups, organisations, nations or globally; and of many types, including but not limited to physical, psychological, social, or economic harms.”</p>



<p>As a result of this growing need, we’re thrilled to announce the latest addition to our AI literacy programme, Experience AI —&nbsp; ‘AI safety: responsibility, privacy, and security’. Co-developed with Google DeepMind, this comprehensive suite of free resources is designed to empower 11- to 14-year-olds to understand and address the challenges of AI technologies. Whether you’re a teacher, youth leader, or parent, these resources provide everything you need to start the conversation.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Linking old and new topics</h2>



<p>AI technologies are providing huge benefits to society, but as they become more prevalent we cannot ignore the challenges AI tools bring with them. Many of the challenges aren’t new, such as concerns over data privacy or misinformation, but AI systems have the potential to amplify these issues.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage4-1-500x281.png" alt="Digital image depicting computer science related elements." class="wp-image-89325" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage4-1-500x281.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage4-1-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage4-1-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage4-1-1536x864.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage4-1-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage4-1-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage4-1-900x506.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage4-1.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>Our resources use familiar online safety themes — like data privacy and media literacy — and apply AI concepts to start the conversation about how AI systems might change the way we approach our digital lives.</p>



<p>Each session explores a specific area:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Your data and AI:</strong> How data-driven AI systems use data differently to traditional software and why that changes data privacy concerns</li>



<li><strong>Media literacy in the age of AI:</strong> The ease of creating believable, AI-generated content and the importance of verifying information</li>



<li><strong>Using AI tools responsibly:</strong> Encouraging critical thinking about how AI is marketed and understanding personal and developer responsibilities</li>
</ul>



<p>Each topic is designed to engage young people to consider both their own interactions with AI systems and the ethical responsibilities of developers.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Designed to be flexible</h2>



<p>Our AI safety resources have flexibility and ease of delivery at their core, and each session is built around three key components:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Animations:</strong> Each session begins with a concise, engaging video introducing the key AI concept using sound pedagogy — making it easy to deliver and effective. The video then links the AI concept to the online safety topic and opens threads for thought and conversation, which the learners explore through the rest of the activities. </li>



<li><strong>Unplugged activities:</strong> These hands-on, screen-free activities — ranging from role-playing games to thought-provoking challenges — allow learners to engage directly with the topics.</li>



<li><strong>Discussion questions:</strong> Tailored for various settings, these questions help spark meaningful conversations in classrooms, clubs, or at home.</li>
</ol>



<p><a href="https://experience-ai.org" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Experience AI</a> has always been about allowing everyone — including those without a technical background or specialism in computer science — to deliver high-quality AI learning experiences, which is why we often use videos to support conceptual learning. </p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage3-1-500x281.png" alt="Digital image featuring two computer screens. One screen seems to represent errors, or misinformation. The other depicts a person potentially plotting something." class="wp-image-89324" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage3-1-500x281.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage3-1-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage3-1-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage3-1-1536x864.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage3-1-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage3-1-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage3-1-900x506.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage3-1.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>In addition, we want these sessions to be impactful in many different contexts, so we included unplugged activities so that you don’t need a computer room to run them! There is also advice on shortening the activities or splitting them so you can deliver them over two sessions if you want.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The discussion topics provide a time-efficient way of exploring some key implications with learners, which we think will be more effective in smaller groups or more informal settings. They also highlight topics that we feel are important but may not be appropriate for every learner, for example, the rise of inappropriate deepfake images, which you might discuss with a 14-year-old but not an 11-year-old.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A modular approach for all contexts</h2>



<p>Our previous resources have all followed a format suitable for delivery in a classroom, but for these resources, we wanted to widen the potential contexts in which they could be used. Instead of prescribing the exact order to deliver them, educators are encouraged to mix and match activities that they feel would be effective for their context.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage2-1-500x281.png" alt="Digital image depicting computer science related elements." class="wp-image-89323" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage2-1-500x281.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage2-1-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage2-1-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage2-1-1536x864.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage2-1-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage2-1-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage2-1-900x506.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/AISAfetyImage2-1.png 1920w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>We hope this will empower anyone, no matter their surroundings, to have meaningful conversations about AI safety with young people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The modular design ensures maximum flexibility. For example:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>A teacher might combine the video with an unplugged activity and follow-up discussion for a 60-minute lesson</li>



<li>A club leader could show the video and run a quick activity in a 30-minute session</li>



<li>A parent might watch the video and use the discussion questions during dinner to explore how generative AI shapes the content their children encounter</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The importance of AI safety education</h2>



<p>With AI becoming a larger part of daily life, young people need the tools to think critically about its use. From understanding how their data is used to spotting misinformation, these resources are designed to build confidence and critical thinking in an AI-powered world.</p>



<p>AI safety is about empowering young people to be informed consumers of AI tools. By using these resources, you’ll help the next generation not only navigate AI, but shape its future. Dive into our materials, start a conversation, and inspire young minds to think critically about the role of AI in their lives.</p>



<p>Ready to get started? Explore our AI safety resources today: <a href="https://rpf.io/aisafetyblog">rpf.io/aisafetyblog</a>. Together, we can empower every child to thrive in a digital world.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/helping-young-people-navigate-ai-safely/">Helping young people navigate AI safely</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/helping-young-people-navigate-ai-safely/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The need to invest in AI skills in schools</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/the-need-to-invest-in-ai-skills-in-schools/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/the-need-to-invest-in-ai-skills-in-schools/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Philip Colligan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 15:07:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Experience AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI in education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI literacy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89294</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Earlier this week, the UK Government published its AI Opportunities Action Plan, which sets out an ambitious vision to maintain the UK&#8217;s position as a global leader in artificial intelligence.&#160; Whether you&#8217;re from the UK or not, it&#8217;s a good read, setting out the opportunities and challenges facing any country that aspires to lead the&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/the-need-to-invest-in-ai-skills-in-schools/">The need to invest in AI skills in schools</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Earlier this week, the UK Government published its <a href="https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/media/67851771f0528401055d2329/ai_opportunities_action_plan.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">AI Opportunities Action Plan</a>, which sets out an ambitious vision to maintain the UK&#8217;s position as a global leader in artificial intelligence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Whether you&#8217;re from the UK or not, it&#8217;s a good read, setting out the opportunities and challenges facing any country that aspires to lead the world in the development and application of AI technologies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of skills, the Action Plan highlights the need for the UK to train tens of thousands more AI professionals by 2030 and sets out important goals to expand education pathways into AI, invest in new undergraduate and master&#8217;s scholarships, tackle the lack of diversity in the sector, and ensure that the lifelong skills agenda focuses on AI skills.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-2-500x281.jpg" alt="Photo of a group of young people working through some Experience AI content." class="wp-image-89305" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-2-500x281.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-2-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-2-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-2-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-2-800x450.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-2-450x253.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-2-900x506.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-2.jpg 1920w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>This is all very important, but the Action Plan fails to mention what I think is one of the most important investments we need to make, which is in schools.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;Most people overestimate what they can achieve in a year and underestimate what they can achieve in ten years.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>While reading the section of the Action Plan that dealt with AI skills, I was reminded of this quote attributed to Bill Gates, which was adapted from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roy_Amara" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Roy Amara&#8217;s law of technology</a>. We tend to overestimate what we can achieve in the short term and underestimate what we can achieve in the long term.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In focusing on the immediate AI gold rush, there is a risk that the government overlooks the investments we need to make right now in schools, which will yield huge returns — for individuals, communities, and economies — over the long term. Realising the full potential of a future where AI technologies are ubiquitous requires genuinely long-term thinking, which isn&#8217;t always easy for political systems that are designed around short-term results.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="500" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-500x500.png" alt="Photo focused on a young person working on a computer in a classroom." class="wp-image-89304" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-500x500.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-250x250.png 250w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-150x150.png 150w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-768x768.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-800x800.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-100x100.png 100w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-300x300.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-450x450.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-900x900.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-400x400.png 400w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-600x600.png 600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36.png 1080w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>But what are those investments? The Action Plan rightly points out that the first step for the government is to accurately assess the size of the skills gap. As part of that work, we need to figure out what needs to change in the school system to build a genuinely diverse and broad pipeline of young people with AI skills. The good news is that we&#8217;ve already made a lot of progress.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">AI literacy</h2>



<p>Over the past three years, the Raspberry Pi Foundation and our colleagues in the <a href="https://computingeducationresearch.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Raspberry Pi Computing Education Research Centre</a> at the University of Cambridge have been working to understand and define what AI literacy means. That led us to create a research-informed <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ai-education-resources-what-to-teach-seame-framework/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">model for AI literacy</a> that unpacks the concepts and knowledge that constitute a foundational understanding of AI.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In partnership with one of the leading UK-based AI companies, Google DeepMind, we used that model to create <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-ai-deepmind-ai-education/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Experience AI</a>. This suite of classroom resources, teacher professional development, and hands-on practical activities enables non-specialist teachers to deliver engaging lessons that help young people build that foundational understanding of AI technologies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve seen huge demand from UK schools already, with thousands of lessons taught in UK schools, and we&#8217;re delighted to be working with <a href="https://parentzone.org.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Parent Zone</a> to support a wider roll out in the UK, along with free teacher professional development.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Experience-AI-Blog-Asset-500x333.jpg" alt="CEO Philip Colligan and  Prime Minister Keir Starmer at the UK launch of Experience AI." class="wp-image-89295" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Experience-AI-Blog-Asset-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Experience-AI-Blog-Asset-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Experience-AI-Blog-Asset-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Experience-AI-Blog-Asset.jpg 512w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">CEO Philip Colligan and Prime Minister Keir Starmer at the UK launch of Experience AI.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>With the generous support of Google.org, we are working with a global network of education partners — from Nigeria to Nepal — to localise and translate these resources, and deliver locally organised teacher professional development. With over 1 million young people reached already, Experience AI can plausibly claim to be the most widely used AI literacy curriculum in the world, and we&#8217;re improving it all the time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All of the materials are available for anyone to use and can be found on the <a href="https://experience-ai.org/en/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Experience AI website</a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">There is no AI without CS</h2>



<p>With the CEO of GitHub claiming that it won&#8217;t be long before <a href="https://www.freethink.com/robots-ai/github-copilot" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">80% of code is written by AI</a>, it&#8217;s perhaps not surprising that some people are questioning whether we still need to teach kids how to code.</p>



<p>I&#8217;ll have much more to say on this in a future blog post, but the short answer is that computer science and programming is set to become more — not less — important in the age of AI. This is particularly important if we want to tackle the lack of diversity in the tech sector and ensure that young people from all backgrounds have the opportunity to shape the AI-enabled future that they will be living in.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Hills-Road-Dojo__22-01-23-36-1-500x333.jpg" alt="Close up of two young people working at a computer." class="wp-image-89303" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Hills-Road-Dojo__22-01-23-36-1-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Hills-Road-Dojo__22-01-23-36-1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Hills-Road-Dojo__22-01-23-36-1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Hills-Road-Dojo__22-01-23-36-1-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Hills-Road-Dojo__22-01-23-36-1-2048x1365.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Hills-Road-Dojo__22-01-23-36-1-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Hills-Road-Dojo__22-01-23-36-1-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Hills-Road-Dojo__22-01-23-36-1-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>The simple truth is that there is no artificial intelligence without computer science. The rapid advances in AI are likely to increase the range of problems that can be solved by technology, creating demand for more complex software, which in turn will create demand for more programmers with increasingly sophisticated and complex skills.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why we&#8217;ve set ourselves the ambition that we will inspire <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/introducing-the-new-code-club/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">10 million more young people</a> to learn how to get creative with technology over the next 10 years through Code Club.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Curriculum reform&nbsp;</h2>



<p>But we also need to think about what needs to change in the curriculum to ensure that schools are equipping young people with the skills and knowledge they need to thrive in an AI-powered world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That will mean changes to the computer science curriculum, providing different pathways that reflect young people&#8217;s interests and passions, but ensuring that every child leaves school with a qualification in computer science or applied digital skills.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s not just computer science courses. We need to modernise mathematics and figure out what a data science curriculum looks like (and where it fits). We also need to recognise that AI skills are just as relevant to biology, geography, and languages as they are to computer science.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="334" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_030-500x334.jpg" alt="A teacher assisting a young person with a coding project." class="wp-image-89308" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_030-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_030-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_030-768x513.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_030-1536x1026.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_030-2048x1367.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_030-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_030-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_030-900x601.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>To be clear, I am not talking about how AI technologies will save teachers time, transform assessments, or be used by students to write essays. I am talking about the fundamentals of the subjects themselves and how AI technologies are revolutionising the sciences and humanities in practice in the real world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These are all areas where the Raspberry Pi Foundation is engaged in original research and experimentation. Stay tuned.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Supporting teachers</h2>



<p>All of this needs to be underpinned by a commitment to supporting teachers, including through funding and time to engage in meaningful professional development. This is probably the biggest challenge for policy makers at a time when budgets are under so much pressure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For any nation to plausibly claim that it has an Action Plan to be an AI superpower, it needs to recognise the importance of making the long-term investment in supporting our teachers to develop the skills and confidence to teach students about AI and the role that it will play in their lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;d love to hear what you think and if you want to get involved, please <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/contact/">get in touch</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/the-need-to-invest-in-ai-skills-in-schools/">The need to invest in AI skills in schools</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/the-need-to-invest-in-ai-skills-in-schools/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Entry is open for Coolest Projects 2025</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/entry-is-open-for-coolest-projects-2025/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/entry-is-open-for-coolest-projects-2025/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lizzie Jackson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 11:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Coolest Projects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Impact of our work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coolest projects 2025]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital making]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coolest projects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding for kids]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89264</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Coolest Projects is our global technology showcase for young people aged up to 18. Coolest Projects gives young creators the incredible opportunity to share the cool stuff they’ve made using digital technology with a global audience. Everyone who takes part will also receive certificates and rewards to celebrate their achievements. What you need to know&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/entry-is-open-for-coolest-projects-2025/">Entry is open for Coolest Projects 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Coolest Projects is our global technology showcase for young people aged up to 18. Coolest Projects gives young creators the incredible opportunity to share the cool stuff they’ve made using digital technology with a global audience. Everyone who takes part will also receive certificates and rewards to celebrate their achievements.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CP_UK_Bradfird_2024_-18-500x333.jpg" alt="Young creator Jay showcases his Coolest Projects creation at an in-person event." class="wp-image-89275" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CP_UK_Bradfird_2024_-18-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CP_UK_Bradfird_2024_-18-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CP_UK_Bradfird_2024_-18-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CP_UK_Bradfird_2024_-18-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CP_UK_Bradfird_2024_-18-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CP_UK_Bradfird_2024_-18-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CP_UK_Bradfird_2024_-18-900x600.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CP_UK_Bradfird_2024_-18.jpg 2000w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What you need to know about Coolest Projects</strong></h2>



<p>The Coolest Projects online showcase is open to young people worldwide. Young creators can enter their projects to share them with the world in our <a href="https://online.coolestprojects.org/events/cp-2024/gallery" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">online project gallery</a> and join our extra special livestream event to celebrate what they have made with the global Coolest Projects community.</p>



<p>By taking part in Coolest Projects, young people can join an international community of young makers, represent their country, receive feedback on their projects, and get certificates to recognise their achievements.</p>



<p>Coolest Projects is completely free to take part in, and we welcome all digital technology projects, from young people’s very first projects to advanced builds. The projects also don’t have to be completed before they can be submitted.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CP_UK_Bradfird_2024_-22-500x333.jpg" alt="Photo of two young people sitting at laptops at a Coolest Projects event." class="wp-image-89276" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CP_UK_Bradfird_2024_-22-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CP_UK_Bradfird_2024_-22-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CP_UK_Bradfird_2024_-22-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CP_UK_Bradfird_2024_-22-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CP_UK_Bradfird_2024_-22-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CP_UK_Bradfird_2024_-22-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CP_UK_Bradfird_2024_-22-900x600.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CP_UK_Bradfird_2024_-22.jpg 2000w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>Projects can be submitted to one of <a href="https://online.coolestprojects.org/categories" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">seven categories:</a> Scratch, games, web, mobile apps, hardware, advanced programming, and AI (new for 2025).</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Young creators up to age 18 can take part individually or in teams of up to five friends</li>



<li>Any young person anywhere in the world can take part in the online showcase, and there are in-person events in some countries for local creators, too (find out more below)</li>



<li>Submissions for the <strong>online showcase </strong>are now open and close on <strong>28 May 2025</strong></li>



<li>All creators, mentors, volunteers, teachers, parents, and supporters are invited to the special celebration livestream on <strong>25 June 2025</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>We know Coolest Projects has a big impact on young people all over the world, and we can’t wait to see your creations for 2025. You can find out more about the incredible creativity and collaboration from mentors and makers worldwide in our <a href="https://static.raspberrypi.org/files/coolestprojects/Coolest_Projects_Impact_Report_2024.pdf">2024 impact report</a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How to submit your project</strong></h2>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Coolest-Projects_2024_35-500x333.jpg" alt="Photo of three young creators discussing their project at an in-person Coolest Projects event." class="wp-image-89285" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Coolest-Projects_2024_35-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Coolest-Projects_2024_35-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Coolest-Projects_2024_35-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Coolest-Projects_2024_35-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Coolest-Projects_2024_35-2048x1366.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Coolest-Projects_2024_35-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Coolest-Projects_2024_35-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Coolest-Projects_2024_35-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>Taking part in Coolest Projects is simple:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Young people think of an idea for their project or choose something they’ve already made and are proud of</li>



<li>Young people work with friends to create their project or make it on their own&nbsp;</li>



<li>Creators (with the help of mentors if needed) enter projects via the <a href="https://online.coolestprojects.org/take-part" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Coolest Projects website</a> by 28 May</li>



<li>Creators’ projects are shared with the world in the online showcase gallery</li>



<li>Creators, mentors, and supporters explore the amazing projects in the online gallery and join the livestream on 25 June to celebrate young creators’ achievements with the Coolest Projects community worldwide</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Mentors — entering more than one project?</strong> Sign up for a group code, and your young people can link their projects to your account.</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Sign up or log in</strong>. If you don’t have one already, you’ll need to set up a Raspberry Pi account. Click on the ‘sign up’ link in the top right-hand corner of the website to create one, and provide your details. You’ll be emailed a verification code as part of the sign-up process. If you already have an account, you can just log in.</li>
</ol>



<ol start="2" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Create a group</strong>. Once signed in, you’ll be able to create a group. You’ll be asked questions about your group, including the group name and the country you’re based in, and be asked to agree to some privacy policies before continuing. You will then be able to view your group code and group submissions on your group dashboard.&nbsp;</li>
</ol>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="266" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CP-2025-group-code-dashboard-500x266.png" alt="Digital photo of the Coolest Porjects 2025 group code dashboard" class="wp-image-89265" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CP-2025-group-code-dashboard-500x266.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CP-2025-group-code-dashboard-300x160.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CP-2025-group-code-dashboard-768x409.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CP-2025-group-code-dashboard-1536x817.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CP-2025-group-code-dashboard-2048x1090.png 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CP-2025-group-code-dashboard-800x426.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CP-2025-group-code-dashboard-450x239.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/CP-2025-group-code-dashboard-900x479.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<ol start="3" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Share your group code with your young people.</strong> Your group dashboard should look like this, with your group code displayed. The group code is what your young people will need to link their submissions to your account. They’ll be asked to input their group code at the start of the project submission form.</li>
</ol>



<p><strong>Submit your coolest projects.</strong> Every young person who uses your group code will have their project linked to your account. You can review and edit their projects in your group dashboard and submit them from there. There is no limit to the number of young people who can submit entries using your group code.</p>



<p>For a more detailed run-through of how to use group codes, please see our <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=q3nXc8BhGGg&amp;list=PLxyaWvsfmq4_sMdhq5hucFpGZ8983XW-l&amp;index=1">‘how-to’ video</a>.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-1 wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-text-align-center wp-element-button" href="https://online.coolestprojects.org/take-part">I want to enter a project</a></div>
</div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Coolest Projects in-person events in 2025</strong></h2>



<p>As well as the global online showcase, Coolest Projects in-person events are held for young people locally in certain countries. We encourage creators to take part in both the online showcase <strong>and</strong> their local in-person event. In 2025, creators can attend the following in-person events, run by the Raspberry Pi Foundation and partner organisations around the world:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Coolest Projects Ireland, 1 March 2025 (run by the Foundation) — entry closes on Friday 14 February&nbsp;</li>



<li>Coolest Projects Belgium, 26 April 2025 (run by <a href="https://coderdojobelgium.be/nl/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">CoderDojo Belgium</a>)</li>



<li>Coolest Projects USA, 5 April 2025 (run by the Foundation) — entry closes on Friday 14 March 2025</li>



<li>Coolest Projects UK, 17 May 2025 (run by the Foundation) — entry closes on Friday 2 May 2025&nbsp;</li>



<li>Coolest Projects India, 2025 date coming soon (run by the Foundation)</li>



<li>Coolest Projects Ghana, 2025 date coming soon (run by <a href="https://ghanacodeclub.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ghana Code Club</a>)</li>



<li>Coolest Projects Malaysia, 2025 date coming soon (run by <a href="https://www.pscpen.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Penang Science Cluster</a>)</li>



<li>Coolest Projects South Africa, 2025 date coming soon (run by <a href="https://coderlevelup.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">CoderLevelUp</a>)</li>
</ul>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Coolest-Projects_2024_18-500x333.jpg" alt="Photo of young creators getting ready to cheer, whilst attending an in-person Coolest Projects event." class="wp-image-89280" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Coolest-Projects_2024_18-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Coolest-Projects_2024_18-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Coolest-Projects_2024_18-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Coolest-Projects_2024_18-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Coolest-Projects_2024_18-2048x1365.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Coolest-Projects_2024_18-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Coolest-Projects_2024_18-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Coolest-Projects_2024_18-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>More events are on the way, so sign up for the <a href="http://rpf.io/coolestprojectsnews" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Coolest Projects newsletter</a> to be sure you hear about any in-person events in your country. And if there isn’t an event near you, don’t worry, as the online showcase is open to any young person anywhere in the world.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Need help with your submission?&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p>Coolest Projects welcomes all digital tech projects, from beginner to advanced, and there are loads of great resources available to help you help the young people in your community to take part. If you’re searching for inspiration, take a look at the <a href="https://online.coolestprojects.org/events/cp-2024/gallery">2024 showcase gallery</a>, where you can explore the incredible projects submitted by participants last year.</p>



<p>You’ll find everything you need to know about all seven Coolest Projects categories on our <a href="https://online.coolestprojects.org/categories">category pages</a>, including our brand new AI category. Our <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/">projects site</a> is also a great place for participants to begin — there are hundreds of free step-by-step project guides to help young people create their own projects, whether they’re experienced tech creators or just getting started.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Coolest-Projects_2024_56-500x333.jpg" alt="Photo of a young creator showcasing they're project to two Raspberry Pi Foundation judges." class="wp-image-89281" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Coolest-Projects_2024_56-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Coolest-Projects_2024_56-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Coolest-Projects_2024_56-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Coolest-Projects_2024_56-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Coolest-Projects_2024_56-2048x1365.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Coolest-Projects_2024_56-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Coolest-Projects_2024_56-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Coolest-Projects_2024_56-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>We will also be running a series of online webinars for mentors and young people to help participants develop their creations for each Coolest Projects category. <a href="https://online.coolestprojects.org/webinars">Sign up for the sessions here</a>. All sessions will be recorded, so you can watch them back if you can’t join live.</p>



<p>Be sure to check out the Coolest Projects <a href="https://online.coolestprojects.org/guidance">guidance page</a> for resources to help you support young people throughout their Coolest Projects journey, including a mentor guide and session plans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There’s lots more exciting news to come, from the announcement of our VIP judges to details about this year’s swag, so <a href="http://rpf.io/coolestprojectsnews">sign up for updates</a> to be the first to know.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Whether your coders have already made something that they want to share, or they’re inspired to make something new, Coolest Projects is the place for them. We can’t wait to see what they create!</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/entry-is-open-for-coolest-projects-2025/">Entry is open for Coolest Projects 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/entry-is-open-for-coolest-projects-2025/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Highlights from Coolest Projects South Africa 2024</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/highlights-from-coolest-projects-south-africa-2024/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/highlights-from-coolest-projects-south-africa-2024/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Afandi Indiatsi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 08:34:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Coding Projects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coolest projects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coolest Projects South Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coolest projects 2024]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89225</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Afandi Indiatsi, our Programme Coordinator in Africa, recently attended Coolest Projects South Africa 2024. Read on to hear her highlights. What happens when creativity, enthusiasm, fun, and innovation come together? You get Coolest Projects South Africa 2024 — a vibrant showcase of students from all walks of life displaying their talent and shaping the future&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/highlights-from-coolest-projects-south-africa-2024/">Highlights from Coolest Projects South Africa 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Afandi Indiatsi, our Programme Coordinator in Africa, recently attended Coolest Projects South Africa 2024. Read on to hear her highlights.</strong></p>



<p>What happens when creativity, enthusiasm, fun, and innovation come together? You get Coolest Projects South Africa 2024 — a vibrant showcase of students from all walks of life displaying their talent and shaping the future of technology.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Dozens of projects exhibited at the event in Cape Town</strong></h2>



<p>Hosted by our partner, Coder Level Up, Coolest Projects South Africa brought together creators, mentors, educators, and industry leaders to celebrate the creativity and ingenuity of young tech enthusiasts from across the country. </p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="1000" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241108_143614.jpg" alt="A group of educators at the Coolest Projects South Africa event. " class="wp-image-89244" style="width:511px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241108_143614.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241108_143614-250x250.jpg 250w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241108_143614-500x500.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241108_143614-150x150.jpg 150w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241108_143614-768x768.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241108_143614-800x800.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241108_143614-100x100.jpg 100w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241108_143614-300x300.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241108_143614-450x450.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241108_143614-900x900.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241108_143614-400x400.jpg 400w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241108_143614-600x600.jpg 600w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>With nearly 200 projects submitted and dozens showcased, the event highlighted the impressive talent and potential of South Africa’s next generation of innovators.</p>



<p>Taking place at the University of Western Cape&#8217;s Department of Education in Cape Town, the event was a hub of excitement. Right from the start the venue was buzzing with activity, with the South African World Robot Olympiad (WRO) team kicking things off with a fantastic demonstration of their robotic inventions. Their creations came alive to cheers and applause as they performed flawlessly, leaving attendees in awe — what an inspiration they were!</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="750" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_130343.jpg" alt="A group of young people showcases their projects at Coolest Projects South Africa." class="wp-image-89237" style="width:672px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_130343.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_130343-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_130343-500x375.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_130343-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_130343-800x600.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_130343-450x338.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_130343-900x675.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Standout projects ranged from garbage collection to chocolate</strong></h2>



<p>The participants then presented their projects, each of which was ingenious in its own way. From hardware and visual programming to game development and website creation, there was a wealth of ideas on display — and a demonstration of the boundless potential of young minds when given the right tools and guidance. Adding to the inclusive spirit of the event, participants from Durban and East London joined remotely, their energy resonating through Zoom.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="750" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_115058.jpg" alt="Two young students display their creations at Coolest Projects South Africa." class="wp-image-89238" style="width:670px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_115058.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_115058-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_115058-500x375.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_115058-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_115058-800x600.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_115058-450x338.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_115058-900x675.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>One standout project was a garbage collection robot created by an all-girls team from Nguzo Saba School. Using a LEGO kit, these creators transformed their idea into a functional invention. What made their project exceptional was their ability to improvise and enhance the kit to achieve their desired functionality. This was a true testament to their creativity, resilience, and problem-solving skills.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="750" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_115310.jpg" alt="A group of young people showcases their projects at Coolest Projects South Africa." class="wp-image-89239" style="width:666px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_115310.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_115310-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_115310-500x375.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_115310-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_115310-800x600.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_115310-450x338.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_115310-900x675.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>Another memorable presentation came from Emma, who used Scratch to tell the story of the history of chocolate. Her engaging narrative spanned the journey of chocolate from the Olmec civilisation in Latin America to today’s chocolate museums. Emma’s research was extensive, and she captivated the judges not only with her presentation but also with chocolate samples for everyone to enjoy — a sweet touch that left a lasting impression!</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="750" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_114751.jpg" alt="Young people display their creations at Coolest Projects South Africa." class="wp-image-89242" style="width:666px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_114751.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_114751-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_114751-500x375.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_114751-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_114751-800x600.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_114751-450x338.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/20241109_114751-900x675.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How Coolest Projects harnesses the power of education, creativity, and mentorship&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p>A recurring theme throughout the event was the importance of mentorship. Many of the young people shared that they had sought guidance from mentors, teachers, and family members while developing their projects. This collaborative spirit underscored the role of supportive communities in fostering innovation and creativity among young creators.</p>



<p>Coolest Projects South Africa 2024 was more than a showcase of talent. It was a reminder of the transformative power of education, mentorship, and creativity. Every project had a story of passion and perseverance, and every creator left inspired to dream bigger.</p>



<p>As we reflect on this event — and the many other Coolest Projects events that took place around the world this past year — we are reminded that the future of technology is in capable, imaginative hands.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Get involved with Coolest Projects in 2025</strong></h2>



<p>Coolest Projects will be back and bigger than ever before in 2025.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Coolest Projects online showcase is open globally to any young person up to age 18. Registration opens 14 January, and we’ll host a celebratory livestream on 25 June.</p>



<p>Thanks to an incredible network of partners, Coolest Projects events will also be hosted in person in many countries around the world. Go to the <a href="https://online.coolestprojects.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Coolest Projects website</a> for more event dates and details.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/highlights-from-coolest-projects-south-africa-2024/">Highlights from Coolest Projects South Africa 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/highlights-from-coolest-projects-south-africa-2024/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ready to remix? Favourite projects to tinker with</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ready-to-remix-favourite-projects-to-tinker-with/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ready-to-remix-favourite-projects-to-tinker-with/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pete Bell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:25:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Coding Projects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding for kids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding projects]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89190</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>From crafting interactive stories to designing captivating games, the Raspberry Pi Foundation’s coding projects offer a hands-on approach to learning, igniting creativity and developing the skills young people need, like perseverance and problem-solving. In this blog, I explore two of my favourite projects that young coders will love. Our projects are free and open to&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ready-to-remix-favourite-projects-to-tinker-with/">Ready to remix? Favourite projects to tinker with</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>From crafting interactive stories to designing captivating games, the Raspberry Pi Foundation’s coding projects offer a hands-on approach to learning, igniting creativity and developing the skills young people need, like perseverance and problem-solving. In this blog, I explore two of my favourite projects that young coders will love.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2560" height="1707" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/CodeClub_ParkStreet-22-scaled.jpg" alt="An educator helps two young learners with a coding project in a classroom." class="wp-image-88307" style="width:634px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/CodeClub_ParkStreet-22-scaled.jpg 2560w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/CodeClub_ParkStreet-22-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/CodeClub_ParkStreet-22-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/CodeClub_ParkStreet-22-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/CodeClub_ParkStreet-22-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/CodeClub_ParkStreet-22-2048x1366.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/CodeClub_ParkStreet-22-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/CodeClub_ParkStreet-22-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/CodeClub_ParkStreet-22-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /></figure></div>


<p>Our projects are free and open to all. They are easy-to-follow, step-by-step guides that young people use to make their own games, animations, and websites using coding languages such as Scratch, HTML/CSS, and Python. The projects introduce coding concepts one by one and allow young people to build their knowledge progressively. As such, educators and volunteers running clubs don’t need to be experienced coders, and many volunteers in our community enjoy learning alongside their club members.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The power of remixing</h2>



<p>One of the brilliant things about our projects is how easy it is to adapt them. This is called remixing, and it gives the learner the opportunity to create and modify a brand-new project that is personal to them.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Remixing allows beginners to tinker with a pre-existing project and make increasingly complex modifications”</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Do you have the reaction speeds of an astronaut?</strong></h2>



<p>My favourite project brings space into the classroom. Space is such an intriguing and mysterious thing, but aspects like the extremely high speeds that satellites and the International Space Station (ISS) travel at are difficult concepts for young people to understand.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="http://helloworld.cc/astronautreaction">The Astronaut Reaction Time Game</a> in Scratch introduces young people to the fact that things happen very quickly at the speed the ISS travels. It includes links to maths and science (speed, distance, time, velocity, units, calculations, operators) and, for older learners, prompts discussions on computational abstractions and problem-solving.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1524" height="1276" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-23-at-12.41.34.png" alt="The Astronaut Reaction Time Game in Scratch." class="wp-image-89207" style="width:688px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-23-at-12.41.34.png 1524w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-23-at-12.41.34-300x250.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-23-at-12.41.34-500x419.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-23-at-12.41.34-768x643.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-23-at-12.41.34-800x670.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-23-at-12.41.34-450x377.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-23-at-12.41.34-900x754.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1524px) 100vw, 1524px" /></figure></div>


<p>The project tests reaction speeds, something that real astronauts have to do as part of their training. NASA has found that reaction speeds are slower on the ISS than on Earth, possibly as a result of the stress of zero gravity. It’s also a fun activity young people can share and play with their friends. Sharing is a key part of the club environment, and this project is ideal for generating a little bit of competition.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As with all projects, a scaffolded approach is taken, with challenges set for learners so that they can complete part of the project independently. If someone is stuck, they can get a hint in the form of an explanation or sentence, which then turns into the code blocks they need to solve the problems, finally giving them the solution if they really need it.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Remix: Exploring speed on planet Earth</strong></h2>



<p>Club volunteers can also introduce their learners to some of our <a href="http://helloworld.cc/PythonQuickGame">physical computing projects, </a>or they could design their own race track that measures the speed of a vehicle. They could even develop a program on a microcontroller like a Pico or micro:bit to measure the speed of young athletes on a running track. If learners are inspired to do more space-themed projects, we have that covered in our <a href="http://projects.raspberrypi.org">project collection</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Unleashing the creativity of coding through colour</strong></h2>



<p>My other go-to project is <a href="http://helloworld.cc/colourfulcreations">Colourful Creations</a>. Coding is an excellent vehicle for self-expression, and this project showcases the ways programming can be used to create digital art. It uses the turtle library, which is an excellent tool for creating designs and patterns.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="400" height="400" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/colourful-creations.png" alt="An example of a colourful poster." class="wp-image-89210" style="width:438px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/colourful-creations.png 400w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/colourful-creations-250x250.png 250w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/colourful-creations-150x150.png 150w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/colourful-creations-100x100.png 100w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/colourful-creations-300x300.png 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" /></figure></div>


<p>The name “turtle” stems from the Logo programming language created in the 1960s. Logo is mainly known for drawing lines, shapes and patterns on the screen and using a “turtle” on the floor to draw them on paper. The turtle library is, therefore, a selection of functions that can be used for drawing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Part of the project’s appeal is that learners are given a blank canvas to which they can apply any theme. There are limited instructions, leaving lots of space for creativity. Whether it be climate change, a period in history, or some other topic, learners can work on their own poster or in pairs to create something bigger.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Remix: From project to presentation</strong></h2>



<p>The possibilities for remixing are almost endless, as learners can add more screens and turn their project into a mini presentation or unleash their artistic side and go wild with colours. The learning in this project leads perfectly to more complex turtle drawing projects like Robo-Trumps, providing a solid foundation in creative computing for you to build on later.</p>



<p>We want you to create your own versions of these projects. You could organise a themed day, which can give learners more freedom, or link with other projects such as <a href="http://astro-pi.org">Astro Pi</a>. Try remixing the projects to start with, then building up to develop new and exciting projects based on the skills that have been learnt. Happy coding!</p>



<p><em>A version of this article also appears in </em><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world"><em>Hello World</em></a><em> issue 24.</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ready-to-remix-favourite-projects-to-tinker-with/">Ready to remix? Favourite projects to tinker with</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ready-to-remix-favourite-projects-to-tinker-with/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Computing Curriculum Framework: Adapting to India&#8217;s diverse landscapes</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/computing-curriculum-framework-adapting-to-indias-diverse-landscapes/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/computing-curriculum-framework-adapting-to-indias-diverse-landscapes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mamta Manaktala]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:06:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89135</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The digital revolution has reshaped every facet of our lives, underscoring the need for robust computing education. At the Raspberry Pi Foundation our mission is to enable young people to realise their full potential through the power of computing and digital technologies. Since starting out in 2008 as a UK-based educational charity, we’ve grown into&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/computing-curriculum-framework-adapting-to-indias-diverse-landscapes/">Computing Curriculum Framework: Adapting to India&#8217;s diverse landscapes</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The digital revolution has reshaped every facet of our lives, underscoring the need for robust computing education. At the Raspberry Pi Foundation our mission is to enable young people to realise their full potential through the power of computing and digital technologies. Since starting out in 2008 as a UK-based educational charity, we’ve grown into a global leader in advancing computing literacy.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="734" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/DSC00893.jpg" alt="An educator and students working on a coding task." class="wp-image-89139" style="width:580px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/DSC00893.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/DSC00893-300x220.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/DSC00893-500x367.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/DSC00893-768x564.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/DSC00893-800x587.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/DSC00893-450x330.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/DSC00893-900x661.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>At the heart of our efforts lies a simple yet powerful vision: to ensure every young person develops the knowledge, skills, and confidence to use digital technologies effectively. This includes understanding societal and ethical issues, using technology for creative problem solving, and fostering a mindset of adaptability that will enable them to thrive amid rapid technological change.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>A vision for global computing education</strong></h2>



<p>To realise this vision, we developed <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/curriculum">The Computing Curriculum (TCC</a>). Launched in 2018 as part of the UK’s National Centre for Computing Education, TCC is a comprehensive set of free teaching resources tailored for students aged 5–16. Over the years, the curriculum has evolved through rigorous testing and teacher feedback, which has helped to make it one of the most effective and inclusive computing education tools globally.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="767" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/IMG_20240927_150327741_HDR.jpg" alt="A group of students in a classroom." class="wp-image-89141" style="width:586px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/IMG_20240927_150327741_HDR.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/IMG_20240927_150327741_HDR-300x230.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/IMG_20240927_150327741_HDR-500x384.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/IMG_20240927_150327741_HDR-768x589.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/IMG_20240927_150327741_HDR-800x614.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/IMG_20240927_150327741_HDR-450x345.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/IMG_20240927_150327741_HDR-900x690.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Contextualising computing education for India</strong></h2>



<p>India’s vast diversity — in languages, social and economic contexts, and educational infrastructure — creates unique challenges and opportunities. As a result, we at the Raspberry Pi Foundation have adapted and localised our computing curriculum to meet the needs of Indian students. Collaborations with the <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/implementing-a-computing-curriculum-in-telangana/">Telangana Social Welfare Residential Educational Institutions Society</a> (TGSWREIS) and the <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/introducing-a-computing-curriculum-in-odisha/">Odisha Mo School programme</a> have been pivotal in this endeavour.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="3200" height="1500" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/Untitled-design.png" alt="" class="wp-image-89171" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/Untitled-design.png 3200w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/Untitled-design-300x141.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/Untitled-design-500x234.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/Untitled-design-768x360.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/Untitled-design-1536x720.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/Untitled-design-2048x960.png 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/Untitled-design-800x375.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/Untitled-design-450x211.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/Untitled-design-900x422.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 3200px) 100vw, 3200px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Modelling data using a spreadsheet (Grade 9)</figcaption></figure></div>

<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="3300" height="1000" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/podcasts-1.png" alt="" class="wp-image-89185" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/podcasts-1.png 3300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/podcasts-1-300x91.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/podcasts-1-500x152.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/podcasts-1-768x233.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/podcasts-1-1536x465.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/podcasts-1-2048x621.png 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/podcasts-1-800x242.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/podcasts-1-450x136.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/podcasts-1-900x273.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 3300px) 100vw, 3300px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Creating media — audio production (Grade 7)</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>In Telangana, we adapted TCC to create a 70+ hour computing curriculum designed for government schools with limited resources. Similarly, in Odisha, elements of this curriculum have been tailored to develop <strong>Kaushali</strong>, an IT and coding curriculum for over 8,000 state schools. This localised approach ensures that computing education becomes accessible and relevant for students across India.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>A curriculum designed for impact</strong></h2>



<p>The computing curriculum for India spans Grades 6 to 10 (age group 11-16) and is structured to ensure progressive learning. Students revisit foundational concepts repeatedly, building on prior knowledge as they advance through the grades. The curriculum emphasises forming a strong understanding of concepts over rote learning and integrates research-informed pedagogical approaches.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="949" height="837" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/2023-09-27-at-12.33.41-PM-1.jpeg" alt="Students using computers in a classroom." class="wp-image-89154" style="width:586px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/2023-09-27-at-12.33.41-PM-1.jpeg 949w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/2023-09-27-at-12.33.41-PM-1-283x250.jpeg 283w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/2023-09-27-at-12.33.41-PM-1-500x441.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/2023-09-27-at-12.33.41-PM-1-768x677.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/2023-09-27-at-12.33.41-PM-1-800x706.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/2023-09-27-at-12.33.41-PM-1-450x397.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/2023-09-27-at-12.33.41-PM-1-900x794.jpeg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 949px) 100vw, 949px" /></figure></div>


<p>We tested our localised curriculum resources in Telangana Coding Academy, and there was lots of positive feedback from educators and observers.<strong> </strong>Overall, the educators were happy with the content format, and the observers noted that students enjoyed learning and completing the activities. This was also evident from the student discussion notes and student survey responses.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“[&#8230;] this content is more than what we are expecting for the school years[&#8230;] this time they [are] having [a] practical session. So they are very happy to do it and whenever they are free[,] they will come and ask us. ‘[C]an you take [an] extra class for us?’” – Educator</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“[&#8230;] They are very [appreciative of] the content and [t]hey [are] learning very well, and the response is very good.” – Educator</p>
</blockquote>



<p><strong>Key features of the curriculum:</strong></p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Tailored content:</strong> Materials are customised to align with the proficiency levels and contexts of Indian students, ensuring accessibility</li>



<li><strong>Localised examples:</strong> By incorporating culturally relevant examples, students find the learning experience relatable and engaging</li>



<li><strong>Simplified language:</strong> Designed for students who may lack confidence in English, the curriculum employs clear and concise language for better comprehension</li>



<li><strong>Hands-on learning:</strong> Practical activities, including projects and model creation, solidify understanding and foster creativity</li>



<li><strong>Ready-to-use resources:</strong> Teachers are equipped with lesson plans, presentations, worksheets, and activity sheets, reducing preparation time and enhancing delivery</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Learning objectives:</strong><strong><br></strong>The curriculum focuses on equipping students with:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>An understanding of digital systems and their impact on people and society</li>



<li>Computational thinking and problem-solving skills for real-world applications</li>



<li>Confidence and knowledge to become creators and innovators</li>



<li>Awareness of digital citizenship and responsible technology use</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Curriculum structure:</strong><strong><br></strong>Each academic year includes 30–34 sessions, each lasting 45–60 minutes. Lessons are structured into deliverable units comprising detailed plans, presentations, and worksheets. Both plugged (computer-based) and unplugged (activity-based) learning methods are used, with a 60:40 ratio, ensuring balanced and inclusive learning experiences.</p>



<p><strong>Sample progression across grades:</strong></p>



<p><strong>Curriculum highlights</strong></p>



<p><strong>Grade 6: Building a foundation</strong></p>



<p>Students develop foundational computer skills, learn basic text formatting, and explore introductory programming concepts using Scratch. They also begin to understand how to group and describe objects based on their properties.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Grade 7: Expanding horizons</strong></p>



<p>Students delve into computer networks, the internet, and the World Wide Web. They learn to use loops in Scratch programming and explore data organisation using flat-file databases and spreadsheets.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Grade 8: Deepening understanding</strong></p>



<p>Students gain a deeper understanding of how computer systems function and use spreadsheets for data analysis. They continue to build their programming skills in Scratch, focusing on sequences, variables, and selection. They are also introduced to HTML and CSS for basic web development.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Grade 9: Exploring advanced concepts</strong></p>



<p>Students learn about data representation, including binary and character coding schemes. They design and create websites using HTML and CSS, incorporating accessibility and good web design principles. They also explore the layers of computing systems, including hardware, operating systems, and logic circuits.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Grade 10: Applying knowledge and skills</strong></p>



<p>Students explore advanced data representation, including image and sound representation. They are introduced to cybersecurity concepts and delve deeper into Python programming, focusing on selection and iteration. They also learn about data science and how to create a blog to support a cause.</p>



<p><strong>Assessment framework:</strong><strong><br></strong>To measure student progress effectively, the curriculum incorporates both formative and summative assessments:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Formative assessments:</strong> Embedded in lessons to monitor progress and identify misconceptions early.</li>



<li><strong>Summative assessments:</strong> Provide a holistic overview of learning outcomes through tools like multiple-choice quizzes and rubrics. These assessments focus on understanding concepts and skills, moving beyond mere code writing.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Bridging the digital divide</strong></h2>



<p>Our localised computing curriculum is more than a technical education initiative — it is helping to bridge the digital divide. By empowering students with essential digital skills, it fosters innovation, enhances employability, and enables young people to participate actively in the global digital economy.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The road ahead</strong></h2>



<p>As technology continues to evolve, so does the need for adaptive and inclusive computing education. We remain committed to supporting governments, educators, and students in this journey. By fostering a generation of digitally literate and empowered individuals, we can create a future where technology serves as a force for good in society.</p>



<p>Through collaborations and localised efforts, the dream of making computing education accessible to every corner of India is steadily becoming a reality. Together, we can equip students with the skills and mindset needed to navigate the complexities of the digital age and shape a brighter, more inclusive future.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/computing-curriculum-framework-adapting-to-indias-diverse-landscapes/">Computing Curriculum Framework: Adapting to India&#8217;s diverse landscapes</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/computing-curriculum-framework-adapting-to-indias-diverse-landscapes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Five reasons to join the Astro Pi Challenge, backed by our impact report</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/five-reasons-to-join-the-astro-pi-challenge/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/five-reasons-to-join-the-astro-pi-challenge/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vicky Fisher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 13:26:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Astro Pi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[astro pi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mission Space Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mission Zero]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european astro pi challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Impact of our work]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89097</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We are excited to share our report on the impact of the 2023/24 Astro Pi Challenge. Earlier this year we conducted surveys and focus groups with mentors who took part in the Astro Pi Challenge, to understand the value and impact the challenge offers to young people and mentors. You can read the full report&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/five-reasons-to-join-the-astro-pi-challenge/">Five reasons to join the Astro Pi Challenge, backed by our impact report</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We are excited to share our report on the impact of the 2023/24 Astro Pi Challenge. Earlier this year we conducted surveys and focus groups with mentors who took part in the Astro Pi Challenge, to understand the value and impact the challenge offers to young people and mentors. You can read the full report <a href="https://static.raspberrypi.org/files/astro-pi/AstroPi_Impact_Report_2024.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>, but here are the highlights.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="667" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/CC-Hills-Road-15.jpg" alt="A child taking part in Astro Pi Mission Zero." class="wp-image-89106" style="width:542px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/CC-Hills-Road-15.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/CC-Hills-Road-15-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/CC-Hills-Road-15-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/CC-Hills-Road-15-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/CC-Hills-Road-15-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/CC-Hills-Road-15-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/CC-Hills-Road-15-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What is the Astro Pi Challenge?</h2>



<p>The European Astro Pi Challenge is an ESA Education project run in collaboration with the Raspberry Pi Foundation. It offers young people the amazing opportunity to learn how to code and conduct scientific investigations in space, by writing computer programs that run on Raspberry Pi computers on board the International Space Station (ISS). The annual Astro Pi Challenge is open to young people up to age 19 in ESA member and associate countries.</p>



<p>Each year, there are two missions: Mission Zero and Mission Space Lab.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Five reasons to take part in the Astro Pi Challenge</h2>



<p>Based on the findings in this report, we wanted to highlight five great reasons to take part in the Astro Pi Challenge, and direct you to some resources to help you get started — there is still plenty of time to enter the 2024/25 challenge!</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="667" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/71574-European-Space-Agency-ESA.jpg" alt="ESA astronaut Sławosz Uznański Astro Pi Challenge 2025 ambassador." class="wp-image-89110" style="width:542px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/71574-European-Space-Agency-ESA.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/71574-European-Space-Agency-ESA-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/71574-European-Space-Agency-ESA-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/71574-European-Space-Agency-ESA-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/71574-European-Space-Agency-ESA-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/71574-European-Space-Agency-ESA-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/71574-European-Space-Agency-ESA-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<h3 class="wp-block-heading">1. Young people get to run their code in space</h3>



<p>Mentors told us how excited young people were to be working on something that connected with the real world, and how proud they were that their code ran on the International Space Station.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;Participating in Mission Space Labs offers students a great opportunity to work with the International Space Station, to see the Earth from above, to challenge them to overcome the terrestrial limits.&#8221; – Mission Space Lab mentor</p>
</blockquote>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">2. Young people are inspired to continue to learn</h3>



<p>91% of mentors told us that young people who successfully wrote code for Mission Space Lab were likely or very likely to participate in computing and digital making challenges in the future.</p>



<p>Mission Zero mentors shared that young people who saw others take part in the mission were inspired to get involved.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">3. Young people learn new skills</h3>



<p>Mission Space Lab mentors told us that young people who successfully wrote code for Mission Space Lab had a greater understanding of STEM concepts, and increased their skills and confidence in computing and digital making.</p>



<p>Mentors also said that Mission Zero provides a great first step into using Python.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;I think it was very good at setting up the first bit of Python and just having a very limited command set and a very quick result…&#8221; – Mission Zero mentor</p>
</blockquote>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">4. Astro Pi mentors have fun</h3>



<p>It’s not just the young people that enjoy Astro Pi — 95% of Mission Space Lab mentors and 99% of Mission Zero mentors said they somewhat or very much enjoyed taking part.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">5. We provide the resources and support Astro Pi mentors need</h3>



<p>Mentors gave us positive feedback on the guidance we provided to help them support young people. This year, we have produced even more resources and ways to support mentors to lead missions.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The Mission [Space] Lab guide was fantastic for my students; step by step&#8221; – Mission Space Lab mentor</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How to get involved</h2>



<p>Astro Pi opened for registration on 16 September this year, and there is still plenty of time for you to sign up and run the missions with your young people. You can find all the information you need to take part on <a href="http://astro-pi.org" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">astro-pi.org</a>, including the mentor guides, which help you prepare to run the activities.</p>



<p><a href="https://astro-pi.org/mission-zero/mentor-guide" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mission Zero mentor guide</a><br><a href="https://astro-pi.org/mission-space-lab/mentor-guide" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mission Space Lab mentor guide</a></p>



<p>We also provide project guides for <a href="http://rpf.io/mzguide" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mission Zero</a> and <a href="http://rpf.io/msl-creator" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mission Space Lab</a> that walk young people through the steps they need to follow to get a working program ready for submission.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="750" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/IMG_1017.jpg" alt="Mission Space Lab workshop held at RPF HQ." class="wp-image-89113" style="width:548px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/IMG_1017.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/IMG_1017-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/IMG_1017-500x375.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/IMG_1017-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/IMG_1017-800x600.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/IMG_1017-450x338.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/IMG_1017-900x675.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>If you would like some help getting started, you can:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Watch a recording of our ‘<a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/USQ9VZiu3tw?si=5_STaiPZzLA4yNqL" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Getting started with Mission Space Lab</a>’ livestream</li>



<li>Sign up for our next <a href="https://form.raspberrypi.org/f/astropijan" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mission Zero codealong</a> in January 2025</li>



<li>Get in touch at <a href="mailto:contact@astro-pi.org" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">contact@astro-pi.org</a></li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Key dates</h2>



<p><strong>17:30 &#8211; 18:30 CET, 16 January – Mission Space Lab livestream and technical Q&amp;A<br>17:30 &#8211; 18:30 CET, 28 January – Mission Zero codealong<br>09:00 CET, 24 February – Mission Space Lab closes<br>09:00 CET, 24 March – Mission Zero closes</strong></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/five-reasons-to-join-the-astro-pi-challenge/">Five reasons to join the Astro Pi Challenge, backed by our impact report</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/five-reasons-to-join-the-astro-pi-challenge/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How can we teach students about AI and data science? Join our 2025 seminar series to learn more about the topic</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-can-we-teach-students-about-ai-and-data-science-2025-seminar-series/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-can-we-teach-students-about-ai-and-data-science-2025-seminar-series/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jane Waite]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 09:54:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research seminar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI in education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89069</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>AI, machine learning (ML), and data science infuse our daily lives, from the recommendation functionality on music apps to technologies that influence our healthcare, transport, education, defence, and more. What jobs will be affected by AL, ML, and data science remains to be seen, but it is increasingly clear that students will need to learn&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-can-we-teach-students-about-ai-and-data-science-2025-seminar-series/">How can we teach students about AI and data science? Join our 2025 seminar series to learn more about the topic</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>AI, machine learning (ML), and data science infuse our daily lives, from the recommendation functionality on music apps to technologies that influence our healthcare, transport, education, defence, and more.</p>



<p>What jobs will be affected by AL, ML, and data science remains to be seen, but it is increasingly clear that students will need to learn something about these topics. There will be new concepts to be taught, new instructional approaches and assessment techniques to be used, new learning activities to be delivered, and we must not neglect the professional development required to help educators master all of this.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="1066" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/image.jpeg" alt="An educator is helping a young learner with a coding task." class="wp-image-89070" style="width:648px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/image.jpeg 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/image-300x200.jpeg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/image-500x333.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/image-768x512.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/image-1536x1023.jpeg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/image-800x533.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/image-450x300.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/image-900x600.jpeg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure></div>


<p>As AI and data science are incorporated into school curricula and teaching and learning materials worldwide, we ask: What’s the research basis for these curricula, pedagogy, and resource choices?</p>



<p>In 2024, we showcased researchers who are investigating how AI can be leveraged to support the teaching and learning of programming. But in 2025, we look at <strong>what</strong> should be taught <strong>about</strong> AI, ML, and data science in schools and<strong> how</strong> we should teach this.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Our 2025 seminar speakers — so far!</strong></h2>



<p>We are very excited that we have already secured several key researchers in the field.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On 21 January, <strong>Shuchi Grover</strong> will kick off the seminar series by giving an important overview of AI in the K–12 landscape, including developing both AI literacy and AI ethics. Shuchi will provide concrete examples and recently developed frameworks to give educators practical insights on the topic.</p>



<p>Our second session will focus on a teacher professional development (PD) programme to support the introduction of AI in Upper Bavarian schools. <strong>Franz </strong><strong>Jetzinger</strong> from the Technical University of Munich will summarise the PD programme and share how teachers implemented the topic in their classroom, including the difficulties they encountered.</p>



<p>Again from Germany, <strong>Lukas Höper </strong>from Paderborn University, with <strong>Carsten Schulte</strong> will describe important research on data awareness and introduce a framework that is likely to be key for learning about data-driven technology. The pair will talk about the Data Awareness Framework and how it has been used to help learners explore, evaluate, and be empowered in looking at the role of data in everyday applications. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Our April seminar will see <strong>David Weintrop</strong> from the University of Maryland introduce, with his colleagues, a data science curriculum called API Can Code, aimed at high-school students. The group will highlight the strategies needed for integrating data science learning within students’ lived experiences and fostering authentic engagement.</p>



<p>Later in the year, <strong>Jesús Moreno-Leon</strong> from the University of Seville will help us consider the&nbsp; thorny but essential question of how we measure AI literacy. Jesús will present an assessment instrument that has been successfully implemented in several research studies involving thousands of primary and secondary education students across Spain, discussing both its strengths and limitations.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What to expect from the seminars</strong></h2>



<p>Our seminars are designed to be accessible to anyone interested in the latest research about AI education — whether you’re a teacher, educator, researcher, or simply curious. Each session begins with a presentation from our guest speaker about their latest research findings. We then move into small groups for a short discussion and exchange of ideas before coming back together for a Q&amp;A session with the presenter.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="720" height="513" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/image3.jpg" alt="An educator is helping two young learners with a coding task." class="wp-image-89074" style="width:658px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/image3.jpg 720w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/image3-300x214.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/image3-500x356.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/image3-450x321.jpg 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 720px) 100vw, 720px" /></figure></div>


<p>Attendees of our 2024 series told us that they valued that the talks “explore a relevant topic in an informative way“, the “enthusiasm and inspiration”, and particularly the small-group discussions because they “are always filled with interesting and varied ideas and help to spark my own thoughts”.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The seminars usually take place on Zoom on the first Tuesday of each month at 17:00–18:30 GMT / 12:00–13:30 ET / 9:00–10:30 PT / 18:00–19:30 CET.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You can find out more about each seminar and the speakers on our <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research/seminars">upcoming seminar page</a>. And if you are unable to attend one of our talks, you can watch them from our <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research/seminars/previous">previous seminar page</a>, where you will also find an archive of all of our previous seminars dating back to 2020.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How to sign up</strong></h2>



<p>To attend the seminars, please <a href="https://form.raspberrypi.org/f/research-seminar-sign-up">register here</a>. You will receive an email with the link to join our next Zoom call. Once signed up, you will automatically be notified of upcoming seminars. You can unsubscribe from our seminar notifications at any time.</p>



<p>We hope to see you at a seminar soon!</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-can-we-teach-students-about-ai-and-data-science-2025-seminar-series/">How can we teach students about AI and data science? Join our 2025 seminar series to learn more about the topic</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-can-we-teach-students-about-ai-and-data-science-2025-seminar-series/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Does AI-assisted coding boost novice programmers’ skills or is it just a shortcut?</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/does-ai-assisted-coding-boost-novice-programmers-skills-or-is-it-just-a-shortcut/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/does-ai-assisted-coding-boost-novice-programmers-skills-or-is-it-just-a-shortcut/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Isabella Grassl]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 14:44:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research seminar]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89030</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Artificial intelligence (AI) is transforming industries, and education is no exception. AI-driven development environments (AIDEs), like GitHub Copilot, are opening up new possibilities, and educators and researchers are keen to understand how these tools impact students learning to code.&#160; In our 50th research seminar, Nicholas Gardella, a PhD candidate at the University of Virginia, shared&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/does-ai-assisted-coding-boost-novice-programmers-skills-or-is-it-just-a-shortcut/">Does AI-assisted coding boost novice programmers’ skills or is it just a shortcut?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Artificial intelligence (AI) is transforming industries, and education is no exception. AI-driven development environments (AIDEs), like GitHub Copilot, are opening up new possibilities, and educators and researchers are keen to understand how these tools impact students learning to code.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In our 50th research seminar, <strong>Nicholas Gardella</strong>, a PhD candidate at the University of Virginia, shared insights from his research on the effects of AIDEs on beginner programmers’ skills.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="473" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/Nicholas-Gardella-500x473.jpg" alt="Headshot of Nicholas Gardella." class="wp-image-89031" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/Nicholas-Gardella-500x473.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/Nicholas-Gardella-265x250.jpg 265w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/Nicholas-Gardella-768x726.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/Nicholas-Gardella-800x756.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/Nicholas-Gardella-450x425.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/Nicholas-Gardella-900x851.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/Nicholas-Gardella.jpg 1494w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Nicholas Gardella focuses his research on understanding human interactions with artificial intelligence-based code generators to inform responsible adoption in computer science education.</figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Measuring AI’s impact on students</strong></h2>



<p>AI tools are becoming a big part of software development, but what does that mean for students learning to code? As tools like GitHub Copilot become more common, it’s crucial to ask: Do these tools help students to learn better and work more effectively, especially when time is tight?</p>



<p>This is precisely what Nicholas’s research aims to identify by examining the impact of AIDEs on four key areas:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Performance (how well students completed the tasks)</li>



<li>Workload (the effort required)</li>



<li>Emotion (their emotional state during the task)</li>



<li>Self-efficacy (their belief in their own abilities to succeed)</li>
</ul>



<p>Nicholas conducted his study with 17 undergraduate students from an introductory computer science course, who were mostly first-time programmers, with different genders and backgrounds.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="333" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/AdobeStock_281866385-500x333.jpeg" alt="Girl in class at IT workshop at university." class="wp-image-89046" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/AdobeStock_281866385-500x333.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/AdobeStock_281866385-300x200.jpeg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/AdobeStock_281866385-768x512.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/AdobeStock_281866385-1536x1024.jpeg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/AdobeStock_281866385-2048x1365.jpeg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/AdobeStock_281866385-800x533.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/AdobeStock_281866385-450x300.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/AdobeStock_281866385-900x600.jpeg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">By luckybusiness</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>The students completed programming tasks both with and without the assistance of GitHub Copilot. Nicholas selected the tasks from OpenAI&#8217;s human evaluation data set, ensuring they represented a range of difficulty levels. He also used a repeated measures design for the study, meaning that each student had the opportunity to program both independently and with AI assistance multiple times. This design helped him to compare individual progress and attitudes towards using AI in programming.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Less workload, more performance and self-efficacy in learning</strong></h2>



<p>The results were promising for those advocating AI’s role in education. Nicholas’s research found that participants who used GitHub Copilot performed better overall, completing tasks with less mental workload and effort compared to solo programming.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="271" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/RQ1-Results-November-Research-Seminar-2024-500x271.png" alt="Graphic depicting Nicholas' results." class="wp-image-89032" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/RQ1-Results-November-Research-Seminar-2024-500x271.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/RQ1-Results-November-Research-Seminar-2024-300x162.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/RQ1-Results-November-Research-Seminar-2024-768x416.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/RQ1-Results-November-Research-Seminar-2024-800x433.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/RQ1-Results-November-Research-Seminar-2024-450x244.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/RQ1-Results-November-Research-Seminar-2024-900x487.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/RQ1-Results-November-Research-Seminar-2024.png 1326w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Nicholas used several measures to find out whether AIDEs affected students’ emotional states.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>However, the immediate impact on students’ emotional state and self-confidence was less pronounced. Initially, participants did not report feeling more confident while coding with AI. Over time, though, as they became more familiar with the tool, their confidence in their abilities improved slightly. This indicates that students need time and practice to fully integrate AI into their learning process. Students increasingly attributed their progress not to the AI doing the work for them, but to their own growing proficiency in using the tool effectively. This suggests that with sustained practice, students can gain confidence in their abilities to work with AI, rather than becoming overly reliant on it.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="271" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/RQ2-Results-November-Research-Seminar-2024-500x271.png" alt="Graphic depicting Nicholas' RQ1 results." class="wp-image-89033" style="width:500px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/RQ2-Results-November-Research-Seminar-2024-500x271.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/RQ2-Results-November-Research-Seminar-2024-300x162.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/RQ2-Results-November-Research-Seminar-2024-768x416.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/RQ2-Results-November-Research-Seminar-2024-800x433.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/RQ2-Results-November-Research-Seminar-2024-450x244.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/RQ2-Results-November-Research-Seminar-2024-900x487.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/RQ2-Results-November-Research-Seminar-2024.png 1326w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Students who used AI tools seemed to improve more quickly than students who worked on the exercises themselves.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>A particularly important takeaway from the talk was the reduction in workload when using AI tools. Novice programmers, who often find programming challenging, reported that AI assistance lightened the workload. This reduced effort could create a more relaxed learning environment, where students feel less overwhelmed and more capable of tackling challenging tasks.</p>



<p>However, while workload decreased, use of the AI tool did not significantly boost emotional satisfaction or happiness during the coding process. Nicholas explained that although students worked more efficiently, using the AI tool did not necessarily make coding a more enjoyable experience. This highlights a key challenge for educators: finding ways to make learning both effective and engaging, even when using advanced tools like AI.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>AI as a tool for collaboration, not replacement</strong></h2>



<p>Nicholas’s findings raise interesting questions about how AI should be introduced in computer science education. While tools like GitHub Copilot can enhance performance, they should not be seen as shortcuts for learning. Students still need guidance in how to use these tools responsibly. Importantly, the study showed that students did not take credit for the AI tool’s work — instead, they felt responsible for their own progress, especially as they improved their interactions with the tool over time.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="241" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/RickPayne-and-team-Aiis.-Banner-1280x618-1-500x241.png" alt="Seventeen multicoloured post-it notes are roughly positioned in a strip shape on a white board. Each one of them has a hand drawn sketch in pen on them, answering the prompt on one of the post-it notes &quot;AI is....&quot; The sketches are all very different, some are patterns representing data, some are cartoons, some show drawings of things like data centres, or stick figure drawings of the people involved." class="wp-image-88362" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/RickPayne-and-team-Aiis.-Banner-1280x618-1-500x241.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/RickPayne-and-team-Aiis.-Banner-1280x618-1-300x145.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/RickPayne-and-team-Aiis.-Banner-1280x618-1-768x371.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/RickPayne-and-team-Aiis.-Banner-1280x618-1-800x386.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/RickPayne-and-team-Aiis.-Banner-1280x618-1-450x217.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/RickPayne-and-team-Aiis.-Banner-1280x618-1-900x435.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/09/RickPayne-and-team-Aiis.-Banner-1280x618-1.png 1280w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Rick Payne and team / Better Images of AI / Ai is&#8230; Banner / CC-BY 4.0</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Students might become better programmers when they learn how to work alongside AI systems, using them to enhance their problem-solving skills rather than relying on them for answers. This suggests that educators should focus on teaching students how to collaborate with AI, rather than fearing that these tools will undermine the learning process.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Bridging research and classroom realities</strong></h2>



<p>Moreover, the study touched on an important point about the limits of its findings. Since the experiment was conducted in a controlled environment with only 17 participants, researchers need to conduct further studies to explore how AI tools perform in real-world classroom settings. For example, the role of internet usage plays a fundamental role. It will be relevant to understand how factors such as class size, prior varying experience, and the age of students affect their ability to integrate AI into their learning.</p>



<p>In the follow-up discussion, Nicholas also demonstrated how AI tools are becoming more accessible within browsers and how teachers can integrate AI-driven development environments more easily into their courses. By making AI technology more readily available, these tools are democratising access to advanced programming aids, enabling students to build applications directly in their web browsers with minimal setup.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The path ahead</strong></h2>



<p>Nicholas’s talk provided an insightful look into the evolving relationship between AI tools and novice programmers. While AI can improve performance and reduce workload, it is not a magic solution to all the challenges of learning to code.</p>



<p>Based on the discussion after the talk, educators should support students in developing the skills to use these tools effectively, shaping an environment where they can feel confident working with AI systems. The researchers and educators agreed that more research is needed to expand on these findings, particularly in more diverse and larger-scale educational settings.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As AI continues to shape the future of programming education, the role of educators will remain crucial in guiding students towards responsible and effective use of these technologies, as we are only at the beginning.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Join our next seminar</strong></h2>



<p>In our current seminar series, we are exploring how to teach programming with and without AI technology. Join us at our next seminar on Tuesday, 10 December at 17:00–18:30 GMT to hear Leo Porter (UC San Diego) and Daniel Zingaro (University of Toronto) discuss how they are working to create an introductory programming course for majors and non-majors that fully incorporates generative AI into the learning goals of the course.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To sign up and take part in the seminar, click the button below — we’ll then send you information about joining. We hope to see you there.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-2 wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://form.raspberrypi.org/f/research-seminar-sign-up">I want to join the next seminar</a></div>
</div>



<p>The <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research/seminars">schedule of our upcoming seminars</a> is online. You can catch up on past seminars on our <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research/seminars/previous">previous seminars and recordings page</a>.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/does-ai-assisted-coding-boost-novice-programmers-skills-or-is-it-just-a-shortcut/">Does AI-assisted coding boost novice programmers’ skills or is it just a shortcut?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/does-ai-assisted-coding-boost-novice-programmers-skills-or-is-it-just-a-shortcut/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ocean Prompting Process: How to get the results you want from an LLM</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ocean-prompting-process-how-to-get-the-results-you-want-from-an-llm/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ocean-prompting-process-how-to-get-the-results-you-want-from-an-llm/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Calleja]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 09:04:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hello World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI literacy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89001</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Have you heard of ChatGPT, Gemini, or Claude, but haven’t tried any of them yourself? Navigating the world of large language models (LLMs) might feel a bit daunting. However, with the right approach, these tools can really enhance your teaching and make classroom admin and planning easier and quicker.&#160; That’s where the OCEAN prompting process&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ocean-prompting-process-how-to-get-the-results-you-want-from-an-llm/">Ocean Prompting Process: How to get the results you want from an LLM</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Have you heard of ChatGPT, Gemini, or Claude, but haven’t tried any of them yourself? Navigating the world of large language models (LLMs) might feel a bit daunting. However, with the right approach, these tools can really enhance your teaching and make classroom admin and planning easier and quicker.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1500" height="1012" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/BARROWHILL_CC4282.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-89026" style="width:652px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/BARROWHILL_CC4282.jpg 1500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/BARROWHILL_CC4282-300x202.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/BARROWHILL_CC4282-500x337.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/BARROWHILL_CC4282-768x518.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/BARROWHILL_CC4282-800x540.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/BARROWHILL_CC4282-450x304.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/BARROWHILL_CC4282-900x607.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1500px) 100vw, 1500px" /></figure></div>


<p>That’s where the OCEAN prompting process comes in: it’s a straightforward framework designed to work with any LLM, helping you reliably get the results you want.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The great thing about the OCEAN process is that it takes the guesswork out of using LLMs. It helps you move past that ‘blank page syndrome’ — that moment when you can ask the model anything but aren’t sure where to start. By focusing on clear objectives and guiding the model with the right context, you can generate content that is spot on for your needs, every single time.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">5 ways to make LLMs work for you using the OCEAN prompting process</h2>



<p>OCEAN’s name is an acronym: objective, context, examples, assess, negotiate — so let’s begin at the top.</p>



<p><strong>1. Define your objective</strong></p>



<p>Think of this as setting a clear goal for your interaction with the LLM. A well-defined objective ensures that the responses you get are focused and relevant.</p>



<p>Maybe you need to:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Draft an email to parents about an upcoming school event</li>



<li>Create a beginner’s guide for a new Scratch project</li>



<li>Come up with engaging quiz questions for your next science lesson</li>
</ul>



<p>By knowing exactly what you want, you can give the LLM clear directions to follow, turning a broad idea into a focused task.</p>



<p><strong>2. Provide some context&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>This is where you give the LLM the background information it needs to deliver the right kind of response. Think of it as setting the scene and providing some of the important information about why, and for whom, you are making the document.</p>



<p>You might include:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>The length of the document you need</li>



<li>Who your audience is — their age, profession, or interests</li>



<li>The tone and style you’re after, whether that’s formal, informal, or somewhere in between</li>
</ul>



<p>All of this helps the LLM include the bigger picture in its analysis and tailor its responses to suit your needs.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="1066" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/unnamed-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-89009" style="width:656px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/unnamed-1.jpg 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/unnamed-1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/unnamed-1-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/unnamed-1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/unnamed-1-1536x1023.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/unnamed-1-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/unnamed-1-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/unnamed-1-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Photo by <a href="https://stock.adobe.com/uk/images/business-organization-achievement-from-chaos-to-order/232628568?prev_url=detail">Andril Zastrozhnov</a>.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p><strong>3. Include examples</strong></p>



<p>By showing the LLM what you’re aiming for, you make it easier for the model to deliver the kind of output you want. This is called one-shot, few-shot, or many-shot prompting, depending on how many examples you provide.</p>



<p>You can:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Include URL links&nbsp;</li>



<li>Upload documents and images (some LLMs don’t have this feature)</li>



<li>Copy and paste other text examples into your prompt</li>
</ul>



<p>Without any examples at all (zero-shot prompting), you’ll still get a response, but it might not be exactly what you had in mind. Providing examples is like giving a recipe to follow that includes pictures of the desired result, rather than just vague instructions — it helps to ensure the final product comes out the way you want it.</p>



<p><strong>4. Assess the LLM’s response</strong></p>



<p>This is where you check whether what you’ve got aligns with your original goal and meets your standards.</p>



<p>Keep an eye out for:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Hallucinations: incorrect information that’s presented as fact</li>



<li>Misunderstandings: did the LLM interpret your request correctly?</li>



<li>Bias: make sure the output is fair and aligned with diversity and inclusion principles</li>
</ul>



<p>A good assessment ensures that the LLM’s response is accurate and useful. Remember, LLMs don’t make decisions — they just follow instructions, so it’s up to you to guide them. This brings us neatly to the next step: negotiate the results.</p>



<p><strong>5. Negotiate the results</strong></p>



<p>If the first response isn’t quite right, don’t worry — that’s where negotiation comes in. You should give the LLM frank and clear feedback and tweak the output until it’s just right. (Don’t worry, it doesn’t have any feelings to be hurt!)&nbsp;</p>



<p>When you negotiate, tell the LLM if it made any mistakes, and what you did and didn’t like in the output. Tell it to ‘Add a bit at the end about …’ or ‘Stop using the word “delve” all the time!’&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="1066" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/classroom.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-89010" style="width:660px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/classroom.jpg 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/classroom-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/classroom-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/classroom-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/classroom-1536x1023.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/classroom-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/classroom-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/classroom-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Photo by <a href="https://stock.adobe.com/uk/images/female-professor-correcting-students-errors-at-an-informatics-lecture/377340930?prev_url=detail">luckybusiness</a>.</figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How to get the tone of the document just right</strong></h2>



<p>Another excellent tip is to use descriptors for the desired tone of the document in your negotiations with the LLM, such as, ‘Make that output slightly more casual.’</p>



<p>In this way, you can guide the LLM to be:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Approachable: the language will be warm and friendly, making the content welcoming and easy to understand</li>



<li>Casual: expect laid-back, informal language that feels more like a chat than a formal document</li>



<li>Concise: the response will be brief and straight to the point, cutting out any fluff and focusing on the essentials</li>



<li>Conversational: the tone will be natural and relaxed, as if you’re having a friendly conversation</li>



<li>Educational: the language will be clear and instructive, with step-by-step explanations and helpful details</li>



<li>Formal: the response will be polished and professional, using structured language and avoiding slang</li>



<li>Professional: the tone will be business-like and precise, with industry-specific terms and a focus on clarity</li>
</ul>



<p>Remember: LLMs have no idea what their output says or means; they are literally just very powerful autocomplete tools, just like those in text messaging apps. It’s up to you, the human, to make sure they are on the right track.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Don’t forget the human edit&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p>Even after you’ve refined the LLM’s response, it’s important to do a final human edit. This is your chance to make sure everything’s perfect, checking for accuracy, clarity, and anything the LLM might have missed. LLMs are great tools, but they don’t catch everything, so your final touch ensures the content is just right.</p>



<p>At a certain point it’s also simpler and less time-consuming for you to alter individual words in the output, or use your unique expertise to massage the language for just the right tone and clarity, than going back to the LLM for a further iteration.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="1048" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/ocean.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-89011" style="width:664px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/ocean.jpg 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/ocean-300x197.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/ocean-500x328.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/ocean-768x503.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/ocean-1536x1006.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/ocean-800x524.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/ocean-450x295.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/ocean-900x590.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Photo by <a href="https://stock.adobe.com/uk/images/tropical-sea-background/221559623">1xpert</a>.</figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Ready to dive in?&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p>Now it’s time to put the OCEAN process into action! Log in to your preferred LLM platform, take a simple prompt you’ve used before, and see how the process improves the output. Then share your findings with your colleagues. This hands-on approach will help you see the difference the OCEAN method can make!</p>



<p>Sign up for a free account at one of these platforms:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>ChatGPT (<strong>chat.openai.com</strong>)</li>



<li>Gemini (<strong>gemini.google.com</strong>)</li>
</ul>



<p>By embracing the OCEAN prompting process, you can quickly and easily make LLMs a valuable part of your teaching toolkit. The process helps you get the most out of these powerful tools, while keeping things ethical, fair, and effective.</p>



<p>If you’re excited about using AI in your classroom preparation, and want to build more confidence in integrating it responsibly, we’ve got great news for you. You can sign up for our totally free online course on edX called ‘Teach Teens Computing: Understanding AI for Educators’ (<strong>helloworld.cc/ai-for-educators</strong>). In this course, you’ll learn all about the OCEAN process and how to better integrate generative AI into your teaching practice. It’s a fantastic way to ensure you’re using these technologies responsibly and ethically while making the most of what they have to offer. Join us and take your AI skills to the next level!</p>



<p><em>A version of this article also appears in </em><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world"><em>Hello World</em></a><em> issue 25.</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ocean-prompting-process-how-to-get-the-results-you-want-from-an-llm/">Ocean Prompting Process: How to get the results you want from an LLM</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/ocean-prompting-process-how-to-get-the-results-you-want-from-an-llm/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
