<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Raspberry Pi Foundation</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/</link>
	<description>Teach, learn and make with Raspberry Pi</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 10:38:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2020/06/cropped-raspberrry_pi_logo-100x100.png</url>
	<title>Raspberry Pi Foundation</title>
	<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How can we empower girls in computing? An important conversation on the Hello World podcast</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-can-we-empower-girls-in-computing-hello-world-podcast/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-can-we-empower-girls-in-computing-hello-world-podcast/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Meg Wang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 10:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hello World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gender Balance in Computing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89918</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A key part of digital literacy is ensuring that all learners, regardless of their background or gender, have equal opportunities to develop computing skills and confidence in using technology. However, the Department for Education in the UK recently released a report highlighting the growing gender gap in maths and science education. With International Girls in&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-can-we-empower-girls-in-computing-hello-world-podcast/">How can we empower girls in computing? An important conversation on the Hello World podcast</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A key part of digital literacy is ensuring that all learners, regardless of their background or gender, have equal opportunities to develop computing skills and confidence in using technology.<br><br>However, the <a href="https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/media/67c05df4750837d7604dbc5c/TIMSS_national_report_for_england_volume_2.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Department for Education</a> in the UK recently released a report highlighting the growing gender gap in maths and science education. With <a href="https://www.itu.int/women-and-girls/girls-in-ict/international-girls-in-ict-day-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">International Girls in ICT Day</a> just around the corner, it’s a timely reminder of the need to empower more girls and women within the computing sector.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1600" height="900" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-2.png" alt="" class="wp-image-89919" style="width:756px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-2.png 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-2-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-2-500x281.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-2-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-2-1536x864.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-2-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-2-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-2-900x506.png 900w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure></div>


<p>In the <a href="http://rpf.io/hwp-empowering-podcastlinkblog">latest episode of the Hello World podcast</a>, Rachel Arthur, Chief Learning Officer at the Raspberry Pi Foundation, is joined by Dr. Jessica Hamer from King’s College London and Becky Patel from Tech She Can. Together, they explore the current state of girls’ engagement in computing and what we can do to support change.</p>



<p>This episode is the second in our three-part mini series on digital literacy. Each episode continues the conversations featured in the latest issue of the Hello World magazine, offering expert perspectives and practical examples from educators making a difference.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What is the gender gap, and why is it a problem?</strong></h2>



<p>The gender gap in computing refers to the disparity between the proportion of female and male students who choose computing as a subject or career. This is problematic because:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>It reinforces harmful societal stereotypes that limit opportunities for girls</li>



<li>It hinders economic growth and innovation</li>



<li>It limits diversity in tech development, potentially leading to biased products, especially in artificial intelligence (AI)</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Who are the guests on the podcast, and what will I learn?</strong></h2>



<p>To address these issues in detail, Rachel is joined by two guests who have dedicated years to understanding and addressing the gender gap.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="500" height="655" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-4-500x655.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-89921" style="width:330px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-4-500x655.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-4-191x250.jpeg 191w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-4-768x1006.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-4-1173x1536.jpeg 1173w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-4-800x1047.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-4-450x589.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-4-900x1178.jpeg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-4.jpeg 1222w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><strong>Dr. Jessica Hamer, King’s College London</strong></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Dr. Jessica Hamer is a Research Associate at King&#8217;s College London. She transitioned to academic research after working for a decade as a science teacher in secondary education. With a focus on projects like the <a href="https://scari.sites.er.kcl.ac.uk/">SCARI project</a>, she investigates factors affecting girls&#8217; performance and participation in secondary-level computing. Her work includes a key report published last year on this topic.</p>



<p>In the <a href="http://rpf.io/hwp-empowering-podcastlinkblog">podcast</a>, Dr. Hamer reveals concerning findings about stereotypes in computing and how early they form. She explains that beliefs portraying girls as less interested in computing emerge as early as ages five or six, which significantly hinders girls’ engagement and involvement in the field.</p>



<p>Further, when students were asked to name famous figures in computing, most cited white, male tech entrepreneurs who are frequently in the news. This revealed a limited view of the kinds of people involved in computing, as well as a narrow conception of tech careers, with roles in areas like climate change and social justice being overlooked. However, Jessica highlights a key insight: <em>“We found that girls were three times more likely to suggest a female famous face”,</em> emphasising the vital importance of female representation and the need for relatable role models.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="500" height="500" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-3-500x500.png" alt="" class="wp-image-89922" style="width:360px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-3-500x500.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-3-250x250.png 250w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-3-150x150.png 150w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-3-768x768.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-3-800x800.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-3-100x100.png 100w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-3-300x300.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-3-450x450.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-3-900x900.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-3.png 982w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><strong>Becky Patel, Tech She Can</strong></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Becky Patel is the Head of Education and Learning at <a href="https://techshecan.org/tech-we-can">Tech She Can</a>, a UK charity focused on increasing women&#8217;s representation in technology. She has a decade of teaching experience in both primary and secondary education and now develops the ‘Tech WE Can’ educational resources, which aim to inspire all children, particularly girls, to pursue careers in technology.</p>



<p>In the <a href="http://rpf.io/hwp-empowering-podcastlinkblog">podcast</a>, Becky emphasises the importance of early intervention to address gender stereotypes. She advocates for introducing children to a wide range of STEM careers, and to do this not just in computing lessons but across the whole curriculum. <br><br>Another key strategy Becky highlights is showing children that they can explore their hobbies and interests further through technology, even when at first glance it might seem that technology can’t play a role. She explains:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>“There are so many tech roles which you can do working behind the scenes, training the athlete, helping them with health and physiotherapy, working on goal-line technology… There&#8217;s so many cool things and when you show children this, you see the attention. You see them sit up like, hold on, she&#8217;s talking about me and the thing I love. And she&#8217;s also talking about computing.”&nbsp;</em></p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Listen or watch now</strong></h2>



<p>To hear more about how to empower girls into computing, listen to or watch the full episode.&nbsp;</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-1 wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="http://rpf.io/hwp-empowering-listenblogpost" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Listen or watch here</a></div>
</div>



<p>We hope this episode inspires you and helps you to engage your students more in computing. In the comments section below, we’d love to hear your thoughts, your feedback, and any of your own tips for empowering girls and young women.</p>



<p>Enjoy the conversation!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>More to discover next week</strong></h2>



<p>Next week, in the final podcast in our mini series, we’ll be looking at the notion of the ‘digital native’. Are young people truly tech-savvy, or are they simply reliant on digital tools without understanding the underlying mechanics?</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/26.4a-Digital-natives-2.png" alt="" class="wp-image-89940" style="width:760px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/26.4a-Digital-natives-2.png 1920w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/26.4a-Digital-natives-2-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/26.4a-Digital-natives-2-500x281.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/26.4a-Digital-natives-2-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/26.4a-Digital-natives-2-1536x864.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/26.4a-Digital-natives-2-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/26.4a-Digital-natives-2-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/26.4a-Digital-natives-2-900x506.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /></figure></div>


<p>James Robinson, Senior Learning Manager at the Raspberry Pi Foundation, will be joined by fellow colleague Sway Gratham and two guest speakers, Anna Lahtinen from Haaga-Helia University and Nicole O’Connor from Digi Know This, as they debate the complexities of digital skills, access, and education. Discover how the label ‘digital native’ can mask crucial issues and learn what real digital literacy looks like today.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Subscribe to Hello World</strong></h2>



<p>You can watch, or listen, to each episode of our podcast on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLxyaWvsfmq49s-6lJKH1sNcYAeBUizoMr">YouTube</a>, or listen via your preferred audio streaming service, whether that’s <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/hello-world/id1564031383">Apple Podcasts</a>, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/1CagYUqVlkJK9zRN6yaQwG">Spotify</a>, or <a href="https://music.amazon.com/podcasts/7954c4f7-884c-4a91-90e3-1fbd3fdc4ff3/hello-world">Amazon Music</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Don’t miss out on this discussion — <a href="http://rpf.io/hwp-empowering-blogpostsubscribe">subscribe to Hello World</a> today to ensure you never miss a podcast episode or issue of the magazine.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-2 wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Subscribe</a></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-can-we-empower-girls-in-computing-hello-world-podcast/">How can we empower girls in computing? An important conversation on the Hello World podcast</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/how-can-we-empower-girls-in-computing-hello-world-podcast/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Research insights to help learners develop data awareness</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/research-insights-to-help-learners-develop-data-awareness/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/research-insights-to-help-learners-develop-data-awareness/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Claire Johnson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 09:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research seminar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data awareness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89892</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>An increasing number of frameworks describe the possible contents of a K–12 artificial intelligence (AI) curriculum and suggest possible learning activities (for example, see the UNESCO competency framework for students, 2024). In our March seminar, Lukas Höper and Carsten Schulte from the Department of Computing Education at Paderborn University in Germany shared with us a&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/research-insights-to-help-learners-develop-data-awareness/">Research insights to help learners develop data awareness</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>An increasing number of frameworks describe the possible contents of a K–12 artificial intelligence (AI) curriculum and suggest possible learning activities (for example, see the <a href="https://unesdoc.unesco.org/ark:/48223/pf0000391105" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">UNESCO competency framework for students</a>, 2024). In our March seminar, Lukas Höper and Carsten Schulte from the Department of Computing Education at Paderborn University in Germany shared with us a unit of work they’ve developed that could inform such a curriculum. At its core, the unit enhances young people’s awareness of how their personal data is used in the data-driven technologies that form part of their everyday lives.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-1 is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-is-layout-flex">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="310" height="443" data-id="89893" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image2.png" alt="Headshot of Lukas Höper" class="wp-image-89893" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image2.png 310w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image2-175x250.png 175w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 310px) 100vw, 310px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Lukas Höper</figcaption></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="220" height="315" data-id="89894" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image1.png" alt="Headshot of Dr Carsten Schulte" class="wp-image-89894" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image1.png 220w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image1-175x250.png 175w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 220px) 100vw, 220px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Carsten Schulte</figcaption></figure>
</figure>



<p>Lukas Höper and Carsten Schulte are part of a larger team who are investigating how to teach school students about data science and Big Data.</p>



<p>Carsten explained that Germany&#8217;s informatics (computing) curriculum includes a competency area known as Informatics, People and Society (IPS), which explores the interrelationships between technology, individuals, and society, and how computation influences and is influenced by social, ethical, and cultural factors. However, research has suggested that teachers face several problems in delivering this topic, including:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Lack of subject knowledge&nbsp;</li>



<li>Lack of teaching material</li>



<li>Lack of integration with other topics in informatics lessons</li>



<li>A perception that IPS is the responsibility of other subjects</li>
</ul>



<p>Some of the findings of that 2007 research were mirrored in a more recent local study in 2025, which found that although there have been some gains in subject knowledge in the interval period, the problems of a lack of teaching material and integration with other computer science (CS) topics persist, with IPS increasingly perceived as the responsibility of the informatics subject area alone. Despite this, within the informatics curriculum, IPS is often the first topic to be dropped when educators face time constraints — and concerns with what and how to assess the topic remain.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="500" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-500x500.png" alt="Photo focused on a young person working on a computer in a classroom." class="wp-image-89304" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-500x500.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-250x250.png 250w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-150x150.png 150w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-768x768.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-800x800.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-100x100.png 100w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-300x300.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-450x450.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-900x900.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-400x400.png 400w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36-600x600.png 600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-36.png 1080w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>In this context, and as part of a larger, longitudinal project to promote data science teaching in schools called <a href="http://www.prodabi.de" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ProDaBi</a>, Carsten and Lukas have been developing, implementing, and evaluating concepts and materials on the topics of data science and AI. Lukas explained the importance of students developing <em>data awareness</em> in the context of the digital systems they use in their everyday lives, such as search engines, streaming services, social media apps, digital assistants, and chatbots, and emphasised the difference between being a user of these systems and a <em>data-aware</em> user. Using the example of image recognition and ‘I am not a robot’ Captcha services, Lukas explained how young people need to develop a data-aware perspective of the secondary purposes of the data collected by these (and other) systems, as well as the more obvious, primary purposes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Lukas went on to illustrate the human interaction system model, which presents a continuum of possible different roles, from the student as the <em>user</em> of digital artefacts to the student as the <em>designer</em> of digital artefacts.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-blog-entry"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="800" height="303" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image3-800x303.png" alt=" Figure 1. Different roles in interactions with data-driven technologies " class="wp-image-89895" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image3-800x303.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image3-300x113.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image3-500x189.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image3-768x290.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image3-450x170.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image3-900x340.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image3.png 1301w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">&nbsp;<strong><em>Figure 1. Different roles in interactions with data-driven technologies</em></strong></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>To become data-aware users of digital artefacts, students need to be able to understand and reflect on those digital artefacts. Only then can they proceed to become responsible designers of digital artefacts. However, when surveyed, some students were only moderately interested in engaging with the inner workings of the digital technologies they use in their everyday lives. Many students prefer to use the systems and are less interested in how they process data.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The explanatory model approach in computing education</strong></h2>



<p>Lukas explained how students often become more interested in data-driven technologies when learning about them with explanatory models. Such models can foster data awareness, giving students a different perspective of data-driven technologies and helping them become more empowered users of them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To illustrate, Lukas gave the example of an explanatory model about the role of data in digital systems. Such a model can be used to introduce the idea that data is explicitly and implicitly collected in the interaction between the user and the technology, and used for primary and secondary purposes.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="443" height="590" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image4.png" alt="The four parts of the explanatory model." class="wp-image-89896" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image4.png 443w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image4-188x250.png 188w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 443px) 100vw, 443px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><strong><em>Figure 2. The four parts of the explanatory model</em></strong></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Lukas then introduced two teaching units that were developed for use with middle school children to evaluate the success of the explanatory model approach in computing education. The first unit explores location data collected by mobile phone networks and the second features recommendation systems used by movie streaming services such as Netflix and Amazon Prime.</p>



<p>Taking the second unit as their focus, Lukas and Carsten outlined the four parts of the explanatory model approach:&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Part 1</h3>



<p>The teaching unit begins by introducing recommendation systems and asking students to think about what a streaming service is, how a personalised start page is constructed, and how personal recommendations might be generated. Students then complete an unplugged activity to simulate the process of making movie recommendations for a peer:</p>



<p>Task 1: Students write down movie recommendations for another student.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Task 2: They then ask each other questions (they collect data).&nbsp;</p>



<p>Task 3: They write down revised movie recommendations.</p>



<p>Task 4: They share and evaluate their recommendations.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Task 5: Together they reflect on which collected data was helpful in this exercise and what kind of data a recommendation system might collect. This reflection introduces the concepts of explicit and implicit data collection.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Part 2</h3>



<p>In part 2, students are given a prepared Jupyter Notebook, which allows them to explore a simulation of a recommendation system. Students rate movies and receive personal recommendations. They reconstruct a data model about users, using the idea of collaborative filtering with the k-nearest neighbours algorithm (see Figure 3).&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-blog-entry"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="800" height="318" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image5-800x318.png" alt="Figure 3. Data model of movie ratings" class="wp-image-89897" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image5-800x318.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image5-300x119.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image5-500x199.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image5-768x305.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image5-450x179.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image5-900x358.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image5.png 959w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><strong><em>Figure 3. Data model of movie ratings</em></strong></figcaption></figure></div>


<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Part 3</h3>



<p>In part 3, the concepts of primary and secondary purposes for data collection are introduced. Students discuss examples of secondary purposes such as personalised paywalls for movies that can be purchased, and subscriptions based on the predictions of future behaviour. The discussion includes various topics about individual and societal issues (e.g. filter bubbles, behaviour engineering, information asymmetry, and responsible development of data-driven technologies).&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Part 4</h3>



<p>Finally, students use the explanatory model as an ‘analytical lens’. They choose other examples from their everyday lives of technologies that implement recommendation systems and analyse these examples, assessing the data practices involved. Students present their results in class and discuss their role in these situations and possible actions they can take to become more empowered, data-aware users.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Uses of explanatory models</h2>



<p>Using the explanatory model is one approach to make the Informatics, People and Society strand of the German informatics curriculum more engaging for students, and addresses some of the problems teachers identify with delivering this competency area.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="356" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/image3-500x356.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-89074" style="width:500px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/image3-500x356.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/image3-300x214.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/image3-450x321.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/image3.jpg 720w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>In presenting the idea of the explanatory model, Carsten and Lukas emphasised that the model in use <em>delivers content</em> as well as functioning as<em> a tool to design teaching content</em>. In the example above, we see how the explanatory model introduces the concepts of:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li>Explicit and implicit data collection</li>



<li>Primary and secondary purposes of that data&nbsp;</li>



<li>Data models&nbsp;</li>
</ol>



<p>The explanatory model framework can also be used as a focus for academic research in computing education. For example, further research is needed to evaluate if explanatory models are appropriate or ‘correct’ models and to determine the extent to which they are useful in computing education.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In summary, an explanatory model provides a specific perspective on and explanation of particular computing concepts and digital artefacts. In the example given here, the model focuses on the role of data in a recommender system. Explanatory models are representations of concepts, artefacts, and socio-technical systems, but can also serve as tools to support teaching and learning processes and research in computing education.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image6.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="744" height="339" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image6.png" alt="Figure 4. Overview of the perspectives of explanatory models" class="wp-image-89898" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image6.png 744w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image6-300x137.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image6-500x228.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image6-450x205.png 450w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 744px) 100vw, 744px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><strong><em>Figure 4. Overview of the perspectives of explanatory models</em></strong>. Click to enlarge.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>The teaching units referred to above are published on <a href="http://www.prodabi.de" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">www.prodabi.de</a> (in German and English).&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/fullHtml/10.1145/3632620.3671118" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">See the background paper to the seminar</a>, called ‘<em>Learning an explanatory model of data-driven technologies can lead to empowered behaviour: A mixed-methods study in K-12 Computing education</em>’.</p>



<p>You can also <a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/pdf/10.1145/3699538.3699558" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">view the paper describing the development of the explanatory model approach</a>, called ‘<em>New perspectives on the future of Computing education: Teaching and learning explanatory models</em>’.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Join our next seminar</h2>



<p>In our current seminar series, we’re exploring teaching about AI and data science. Join us at our next seminar on <strong>Tuesday 13 May at 17:00–18:30 BST</strong> to hear Henriikka Vartiainen and Matti Tedre (University of Eastern Finland) discuss <strong>how to empower students by teaching them how to develop AI and machine learning (ML) apps without code in the classroom</strong>.</p>



<p>To sign up and take part in our research seminars, click below:</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-3 wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://form.raspberrypi.org/f/research-seminar-sign-up">I want to join the seminar</a></div>
</div>



<p>You can also view the <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research/seminars">schedule of our upcoming seminars</a>, and catch up on past seminars on our <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research/seminars/previous">previous seminars and recordings page</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/research-insights-to-help-learners-develop-data-awareness/">Research insights to help learners develop data awareness</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/research-insights-to-help-learners-develop-data-awareness/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to bring digital literacy into your classroom: practical tips from the Hello World podcast</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teacher-tips-digital-literacy/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teacher-tips-digital-literacy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[James Robinson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 08:34:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hello World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital literacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teacher tips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89845</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Are you looking to strengthen digital literacy in your classroom? In the latest episode of the Hello World podcast, three experienced teachers from the USA and the UK share practical tips they’ve used in their classrooms to help their students build digital literacy. Whether you’re just getting started with digital literacy or looking for new&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teacher-tips-digital-literacy/">How to bring digital literacy into your classroom: practical tips from the Hello World podcast</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/podcast/teacher-tips-how-to-improve-digital-literacy-in-your-classroom" target="_blank" rel=" noreferrer noopener"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/YouTube-thumbnails-for-Hello-World-podcast-TEMPLATES-12-500x281.png" alt="Teacher tips: Digital literacy thumbnail. The background of the image comprises of a still taken from the episode, featuring Hello World podcast host James Robinson on the right of the image. The episode title 'Teacher tips: Digital literacy' is overlayed on the left of the screen. The Hello World logo has been superimposed on the top right hand corner of the image." class="wp-image-89846" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/YouTube-thumbnails-for-Hello-World-podcast-TEMPLATES-12-500x281.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/YouTube-thumbnails-for-Hello-World-podcast-TEMPLATES-12-300x169.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/YouTube-thumbnails-for-Hello-World-podcast-TEMPLATES-12-768x432.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/YouTube-thumbnails-for-Hello-World-podcast-TEMPLATES-12-1536x864.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/YouTube-thumbnails-for-Hello-World-podcast-TEMPLATES-12-800x450.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/YouTube-thumbnails-for-Hello-World-podcast-TEMPLATES-12-450x253.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/YouTube-thumbnails-for-Hello-World-podcast-TEMPLATES-12-900x506.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/YouTube-thumbnails-for-Hello-World-podcast-TEMPLATES-12.png 1920w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></a></figure></div>


<p>Are you looking to strengthen digital literacy in your classroom? In <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/podcast/teacher-tips-how-to-improve-digital-literacy-in-your-classroom">the latest episode of the Hello World podcast</a>, three experienced teachers from the USA and the UK share practical tips they’ve used in their classrooms to help their students build digital literacy. Whether you’re just getting started with digital literacy or looking for new ideas, the episode is full of real-world advice you can apply straight away.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="500" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Instagram-Post-1-500x500.png" alt="Behind the scenes image of the team recording an episode of the Hello World podcast." class="wp-image-89876" style="width:400px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Instagram-Post-1-500x500.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Instagram-Post-1-250x250.png 250w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Instagram-Post-1-150x150.png 150w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Instagram-Post-1-768x768.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Instagram-Post-1-800x800.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Instagram-Post-1-100x100.png 100w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Instagram-Post-1-300x300.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Instagram-Post-1-450x450.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Instagram-Post-1.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Behind the scenes whilst recording the Teacher Tips: Digital literacy episode of the Hello World podcast.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>The episode also marks the launch of a new mini-series on the Hello World podcast focusing on digital literacy. Throughout the series, which totals three episodes, we’ll continue conversations that feature in the latest issue of the <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hello World magazine</a>, sharing expert insights and real-world examples from educators who are integrating digital literacy into their classrooms.</p>



<p>So tune in this week, then stay tuned!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Who features in this episode, and what will I learn?</h2>



<p>We&#8217;ve got tips from three teachers whose articles feature in <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/issues/26">Hello World&#8217;s newest magazine issue</a>.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Katie Dahlman from Bloomington, MN, USA</h3>



<p>Get ready for some top tips from Katie Dahlman, a preschool teacher and Digital Learning Specialist in Bloomington Public Schools in Minnesota, USA. With over 16 years of experience as an early childhood educator, Katie has dedicated her time to developing engaging computer science (CS) lessons for young learners.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="490" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/IMG_2481-1-500x490.jpeg" alt="Headshot of Katie Dahlamn, a guest teacher who featured on the 'Teacher tips: Digital literacy' episode of the Hello World podcast." class="wp-image-89847" style="width:400px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/IMG_2481-1-500x490.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/IMG_2481-1-255x250.jpeg 255w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/IMG_2481-1-768x752.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/IMG_2481-1-1536x1505.jpeg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/IMG_2481-1-2048x2006.jpeg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/IMG_2481-1-800x784.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/IMG_2481-1-450x441.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/IMG_2481-1-900x882.jpeg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>Katie believes that digital literacy starts with building foundational skills to prepare students for their roles as digital citizens. One of the tips Katie shares in the episode emphasises the importance of integrating computational thinking into the classroom:&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>“My second tip for enhancing digital literacy in your classroom is to integrate computational thinking skills and vocabulary into your existing curriculum.”</em></p>
</blockquote>



<p>Read Katie&#8217;s article &#8216;Tech tinkering and teamwork’ on pages 52–53 of <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/issues/26">Hello World, issue 26</a>.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Curt Hitchens from Rock Spring, GA, USA</h3>



<p>We also hear from Curt Hitchens, a computer science teacher at Saddle Ridge Elementary and Middle School in Rock Spring, Georgia, USA. Since 2018, Curt has been teaching computer science and now serves as a Virtual CS Specialist for the Georgia Department of Education.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1080" height="1080" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-5.png" alt="Headshot of Curt Hitchens, a guest teacher who featured on the 'Teacher tips: Digital literacy' episode of the Hello World podcast." class="wp-image-89853" style="width:400px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-5.png 1080w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-5-250x250.png 250w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-5-500x500.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-5-150x150.png 150w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-5-768x768.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-5-800x800.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-5-100x100.png 100w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-5-300x300.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-5-450x450.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-5-900x900.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1080px) 100vw, 1080px" /></figure></div>


<p>Curt explains in the podcast that digital literacy is about equipping students with the necessary skills to use technology effectively in everyday situations and the workplace. He also shares an important tip for teachers, encouraging them to give students regular chances to engage in hands-on learning:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&nbsp;“Make sure that you&#8217;re providing consistent opportunities for creation and exploration within your classes.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Read Curt&#8217;s article &#8216;Computer science opportunities in rural schools’ on pages 46–47 of <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/issues/26">Issue 26</a>.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Halima Bhayat, London, UK</h3>



<p>The episode also features Halima Bhayat, the Head of Computing and Digital T Levels at Ursuline High School in London, UK. Halima is an Asian Women of Achievement 2021 Finalist, a digit&lt;all&gt; ambassador, an Amazon teacher, and the Computing at School Merton lead for all schools.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="500" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-4-500x500.png" alt="Headshot of Halima Bhayat, a guest teacher who featured on the 'Teacher tips: Digital literacy' episode of the Hello World podcast." class="wp-image-89854" style="width:400px" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-4-500x500.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-4-250x250.png 250w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-4-150x150.png 150w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-4-768x768.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-4-800x800.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-4-100x100.png 100w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-4-300x300.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-4-450x450.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-4-900x900.png 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Untitled-design-4.png 1080w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>With a wealth of experience, she emphasises that digital literacy is more than about using technology — it&#8217;s about understanding how the digital world functions, how technology shapes our daily lives, and how it impacts individuals and communities.</p>



<p>One of Halima’s top tips for enhancing digital literacy in the classroom is to focus on touch typing. She believes that students should be equipped with fast and efficient typing skills, as so many tasks today are online.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“My first tip would be to get [your students] touch typing, get them to start becoming faster with their fingers on those keyboards, because lots of things have become online.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Read Halima&#8217;s article &#8216;From switches to success’ on pages 76–77 of <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/issues/26">Issue 26</a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Listen now</h2>



<p>To hear more practical tips and discover what else our guest teachers have to say, <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/podcast/teacher-tips-how-to-improve-digital-literacy-in-your-classroom">listen to or watch the full episode here</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We hope this episode inspires you and helps you to engage your students in computing. We’d love to hear your thoughts, your feedback, and any of your own tips on the topic of digital literacy in the comments section below.</p>



<p>We hope you enjoy the episode!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>More to listen to next week</strong></h2>



<p>Next week, the podcast brings you an insightful conversation featuring Rachel Arthur, Chief Learning Officer at the Raspberry Pi Foundation, Dr Jessica Hamer from King’s College London, and Becky Patel from Tech She Can.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="324" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Apr25_newsletter2_HW_podcast_girlsincomputing-1-500x324.jpg" alt="Photo of Dr. Jessica Hamer, Becky Patel and Rachel Arthur, on set of the Hello World podcast." class="wp-image-89851" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Apr25_newsletter2_HW_podcast_girlsincomputing-1-500x324.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Apr25_newsletter2_HW_podcast_girlsincomputing-1-300x194.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Apr25_newsletter2_HW_podcast_girlsincomputing-1-768x498.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Apr25_newsletter2_HW_podcast_girlsincomputing-1-1536x995.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Apr25_newsletter2_HW_podcast_girlsincomputing-1-800x518.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Apr25_newsletter2_HW_podcast_girlsincomputing-1-450x292.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Apr25_newsletter2_HW_podcast_girlsincomputing-1-900x583.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Apr25_newsletter2_HW_podcast_girlsincomputing-1.jpg 1972w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>They’ll discuss the current state of girls&#8217; engagement in computing and explore ways to empower young women in computing at school, at university, and onwards into their careers.</p>



<p>You can watch, or listen, to each episode of our podcast on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLxyaWvsfmq49s-6lJKH1sNcYAeBUizoMr">YouTube</a>, or listen via your preferred audio streaming service, whether that’s <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/hello-world/id1564031383">Apple Podcasts</a>, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/1CagYUqVlkJK9zRN6yaQwG">Spotify</a>, or <a href="https://music.amazon.com/podcasts/7954c4f7-884c-4a91-90e3-1fbd3fdc4ff3/hello-world">Amazon Music</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world">Subscribe to Hello World</a> today to ensure you never miss a podcast episode or issue of the magazine. </p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-4 wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-text-align-center wp-element-button" href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world">Subscribe</a></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teacher-tips-digital-literacy/">How to bring digital literacy into your classroom: practical tips from the Hello World podcast</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/teacher-tips-digital-literacy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Raspberry Pi Foundation joins UNESCO’s Global Education Coalition</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/raspberry-pi-foundation-joins-unescos-global-education-coalition/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/raspberry-pi-foundation-joins-unescos-global-education-coalition/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben Garside]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 09:03:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unesco]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89785</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Introduction We are thrilled to announce that the Raspberry Pi Foundation (RPF) has been accepted as a member of UNESCO’s Global Education Coalition (GEC).&#160; Initiated during the COVID-19 pandemic, when 1.6 billion learners were shut out of the classroom, the GEC aimed to provide continuity of education in times of crisis. Since then, the Coalition&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/raspberry-pi-foundation-joins-unescos-global-education-coalition/">Raspberry Pi Foundation joins UNESCO’s Global Education Coalition</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Introduction</strong></h2>



<p>We are thrilled to announce that the Raspberry Pi Foundation (RPF) has been accepted as a member of UNESCO’s Global Education Coalition (GEC).&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="802" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-1.jpeg" alt="Global Education Coalition." class="wp-image-89794" style="width:742px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-1.jpeg 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-1-300x150.jpeg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-1-500x251.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-1-768x385.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-1-1536x770.jpeg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-1-800x400.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-1-450x226.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-1-900x451.jpeg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure></div>


<p>Initiated during the COVID-19 pandemic, when 1.6 billion learners were shut out of the classroom, the GEC aimed to provide continuity of education in times of crisis. Since then, the Coalition has grown into a global multistakeholder network, and we are proud to help drive education transformation and accelerate the path to achieving <a href="https://www.unesco.org/en/sdgs">UNESCO’s Sustainable Development</a> Goal 4 (SDG 4 – Quality Education).</p>



<p>UNESCO’s vision to transform education for the world’s most underserved aligns with our mission at the Raspberry Pi Foundation. Being part of the Coalition enables us to work together to achieve this shared aim.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In addition to being part of the GEC, we have been invited to join the Digital Transformation Collaborative (DTC), a tech-focused subgroup that empowers educators and education leaders to include emerging technologies in their teaching practices and decision-making through capacity building and training.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Coalition achievements</strong></h2>



<p>We’re joining a coalition that has already achieved a lot. Having attended the GEC annual conference last week in Paris, Ms Stefania Giannini, UNESCO Assistant Director-General for Education, stated that to date the GTC has:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Helped over 858,898 youth develop skills that make them more employable</li>



<li>Trained 794,580 teachers</li>



<li>Offered learning resources to more than 1,000,000 learners studying foundational subjects, such as science, technology, engineering, and mathematics</li>



<li>Reached 2,459,192 of the most marginalised girls and women</li>
</ul>



<p>Source: <a href="https://www.unesco.org/en/global-education-coalition">https://www.unesco.org/en/global-education-coalition</a></p>



<p>Whilst these are amazing achievements to celebrate, there is still more work to do, with Ms Giannini also highlighting that there are currently 251 million children and youth out of school and that 44 million more teachers are needed for universal primary and secondary education by 2030.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="1205" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-3.jpeg" alt="A group of educators at a conference." class="wp-image-89802" style="width:742px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-3.jpeg 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-3-300x225.jpeg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-3-500x377.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-3-768x578.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-3-1536x1157.jpeg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-3-800x603.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-3-450x339.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-3-900x678.jpeg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Digital Transformation Collaborative</strong></h2>



<p><strong>Our commitment to the Coalition</strong></p>



<p>The Digital Transformation Collaborative (DTC), which the Foundation has committed to support, aims to play a crucial role in shaping the future of education through technology. The group has established a framework structured around six core pillars:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li>Coordination and leadership</li>



<li>Connectivity and infrastructure</li>



<li>Cost and sustainability</li>



<li>Capacity and culture</li>



<li>Content and solutions</li>



<li>Data and evidence</li>
</ol>



<p>Through our work at the Foundation, we believe we have the expertise to provide meaningful support through the sharing of our expertise across these issues. Many of these are challenges we work to overcome through the delivery of our programmes.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="1205" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-2.jpeg" alt="Six pillars for the digital transformation of education." class="wp-image-89801" style="width:738px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-2.jpeg 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-2-300x225.jpeg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-2-500x377.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-2-768x578.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-2-1536x1157.jpeg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-2-800x603.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-2-450x339.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-2-900x678.jpeg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Conclusion</strong></h2>



<p>Joining UNESCO’s Global Education Coalition marks a significant milestone for the Raspberry Pi Foundation. Our mission to empower the underserved aligns with the Coalition’s goals. We are excited to contribute our expertise and resources to this global effort, driving forward the agenda for inclusive and equitable quality education for all.</p>



<p>I’m looking forward to writing more on our projects and initiatives within the GEC as we move forward and work together to transform global education.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/raspberry-pi-foundation-joins-unescos-global-education-coalition/">Raspberry Pi Foundation joins UNESCO’s Global Education Coalition</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/raspberry-pi-foundation-joins-unescos-global-education-coalition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hello World #26 out now: Digital Literacy</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/hello-world-26-out-now-digital-literacy/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/hello-world-26-out-now-digital-literacy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Meg Wang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 10:38:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hello World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital literacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hello world magazine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89782</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We often believe we understand the meaning of ‘digital literacy’, but it can be a misleading term. Do we mean digital skills? Online safety? Where does AI fit in? As computer science education evolves to meet the needs of our increasingly digital world, we believe that true digital literacy empowers young people to engage with&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/hello-world-26-out-now-digital-literacy/">Hello World #26 out now: Digital Literacy</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We often believe we understand the meaning of ‘digital literacy’, but it can be a misleading term. Do we mean digital skills? Online safety? Where does AI fit in? As computer science education evolves to meet the needs of our increasingly digital world, we believe that true digital literacy empowers young people to engage with technology thoughtfully, critically, and confidently.</p>



<p>In this issue of Hello World, <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org//hello-world/issues/26" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">out today for free</a>, we discuss what digital literacy means, how it is taught in different countries around the world, and how educators are rethinking digital literacy for their students and themselves.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1200" height="628" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/HW_Twitter_Image.png" alt="Digital image of Hello World, issue 26 'digital literacy' displayed at an angle." class="wp-image-89788" style="width:840px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/HW_Twitter_Image.png 1200w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/HW_Twitter_Image-300x157.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/HW_Twitter_Image-500x262.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/HW_Twitter_Image-768x402.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/HW_Twitter_Image-800x419.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/HW_Twitter_Image-450x236.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/HW_Twitter_Image-900x471.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Digital literacy</strong></h2>



<p>As the use of digital technology grows, a broader view of digital literacy is necessary. Digital literacy is more than knowing how to use software. It’s the ability to use digital technologies effectively, safely, and responsibly.</p>



<p>In Issue 26 of Hello World, we explore this topic in detail and hear insights from educators across the world, including:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Becci Peters shares how Computing at School (CAS) in the UK is supporting digital literacy skills for students and educators</li>



<li>Sourav Pattanayak discusses how digital literacy is defined in India, and the formal and informal ways educators are teaching digital literacy</li>



<li>Sandra Hartman explores strategies for enhancing digital literacy in the US</li>



<li>Gavin Davenport asks what would happen if we considered digital literacy in the same way as we consider traditional literacy</li>
</ul>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="248" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/PI_TOWERS_CC006-500x248.jpg" alt="Photo of young people sitting at a desk, working on small computers." class="wp-image-89803" style="width:718px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/PI_TOWERS_CC006-500x248.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/PI_TOWERS_CC006-300x149.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/PI_TOWERS_CC006-768x381.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/PI_TOWERS_CC006-1536x763.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/PI_TOWERS_CC006-2048x1017.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/PI_TOWERS_CC006-800x397.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/PI_TOWERS_CC006-450x223.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/PI_TOWERS_CC006-900x447.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>This issue also includes inspiring articles from the world of computer science education:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Leah Dungay tells us about a programme combining physics, video games, and the Large Hadron Collider to engage young people in particle physics&nbsp;</li>



<li>Gina Fugate shares how digital accessibility enhances digital experiences for all</li>



<li>Halima Bhayat shares her inspiring journey in computer science</li>
</ul>



<p>And there is lots more for you to discover in issue 26.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-5 wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-text-align-center wp-element-button" href="https://www.raspberrypi.org//hello-world/issues/26">Download your free digital copy</a></div>
</div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>New podcast series in audio and video</strong></h2>



<p>We’re also pleased to announce that the Hello World podcast has returned alongside the magazine with a miniseries also focused on digital literacy.</p>



<p>We asked for your thoughts on the podcast in our previous annual survey, and you kindly sent us lots of helpful feedback. Based on that, we’re trialling new episode formats, welcoming additional hosts, and bringing in more expert voices from around the world.</p>



<p>On Tuesday 15 April we’ll be releasing our first teacher tips episode, a shorter podcast with 3 teachers sharing practical, actionable tips for improving digital literacy in the classroom.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="324" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Apr25_newsletter2_HW_podcast_girlsincomputing-500x324.jpg" alt="Image featuring Dr. Jessica Hamer, Becky Patel and Rachel Arthur after recording an episode of the Hello World podcast." class="wp-image-89786" style="width:691px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Apr25_newsletter2_HW_podcast_girlsincomputing-500x324.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Apr25_newsletter2_HW_podcast_girlsincomputing-300x194.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Apr25_newsletter2_HW_podcast_girlsincomputing-768x498.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Apr25_newsletter2_HW_podcast_girlsincomputing-1536x995.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Apr25_newsletter2_HW_podcast_girlsincomputing-800x518.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Apr25_newsletter2_HW_podcast_girlsincomputing-450x292.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Apr25_newsletter2_HW_podcast_girlsincomputing-900x583.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/Apr25_newsletter2_HW_podcast_girlsincomputing.jpg 1972w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>The week after, Tuesday 22 April, you’ll be able to hear a brilliant conversation between the Raspberry Pi Foundation’s Chief Learning Officer, Rachel Arthur, and two special guests: Dr Jessica Hamer from King&#8217;s College London&#8217;s School of Education, Communication and Society, and Becky Patel from Tech She Can. They’ll be discussing the current state of girls’ engagement in computing — a wide-reaching and important conversation exploring how we can empower more girls in computing through school, university and their careers.</p>



<p>Then on Tuesday 29 April the final episode in the miniseries will be a panel debate about “digital natives” where we’ll be asking, ‘Are young people who grew up with technology around them truly tech-savvy, or are they dependent on digital tools without understanding how they work?’ James Robinson — Senior Learning Manager here at the Raspberry Pi Foundation and regular host of the podcast — will lead this discussion as global educators debate the myth of the &#8220;digital native,&#8221; uncover how it could overlook complex issues of access, skills, and education, and consider what it really takes to be tech-smart in the modern world.</p>



<p>More information and links to listen can be found inside the magazine.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Share your thoughts &amp; subscribe to Hello World</strong></h2>



<p>We hope you enjoy this issue of <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world">Hello World</a>, and please get in touch with your article ideas or what you would like to see in the magazine.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Share your thoughts and ideas about Hello World and the new issue with us via the Raspberry PI Foundation social media channels</li>



<li>Find out how you can <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/write-for-us">write for the magazine</a></li>
</ul>



<p><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world/subscribe">Subscribe to Hello World for free</a> to never miss an issue.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/hello-world-26-out-now-digital-literacy/">Hello World #26 out now: Digital Literacy</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/hello-world-26-out-now-digital-literacy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Supporting teachers to integrate AI in K–12 CS education</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/supporting-teachers-to-integrate-ai-in-k-12-cs-education/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/supporting-teachers-to-integrate-ai-in-k-12-cs-education/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Bobby Whyte]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 09:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research seminar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI education]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89752</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Teaching about artificial intelligence (AI) is a growing challenge for educators around the world. In our current seminar series, we are gaining insights from international computing education researchers on how to teach about AI and data science in the classroom. In our second seminar, Franz Jetzinger from the Technical University of Munich, Germany, presented his&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/supporting-teachers-to-integrate-ai-in-k-12-cs-education/">Supporting teachers to integrate AI in K–12 CS education</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Teaching about artificial intelligence (AI) is a growing challenge for educators around the world. In our current seminar series, we are gaining insights from international computing education researchers on how to teach about AI and data science in the classroom. In our second seminar, Franz Jetzinger from the Technical University of Munich, Germany, presented his work on supporting teachers to integrate AI into their classrooms. Franz brings a wealth of relevant experience to his research as an accomplished textbook author and K–12 computer science teacher.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="629" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-500x629.jpeg" alt="A photo of Franz Jetzinger in a library. " class="wp-image-89766" style="width:460px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-500x629.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-199x250.jpeg 199w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-768x967.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-800x1007.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-450x566.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-900x1133.jpeg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image.jpeg 1125w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p>Franz started by demonstrating how widespread AI systems and technologies are becoming. He argued that embedding lessons about AI in the classroom presents three challenges:&nbsp;</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>What</strong> to teach (defining AI and learning content)</li>



<li><strong>How</strong> to teach (i.e. appropriate pedagogies)</li>



<li><strong>How to prepare teachers</strong> (i.e. effective professional development)&nbsp;</li>
</ol>



<p>As various models and frameworks for teaching about AI already exist, Franz’s research aims to address the second and third challenges — there is a notable lack of empirical evidence integrating AI in K–12 settings or teacher professional development (PD) to support teachers.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Using professional development to help prepare teachers</strong></h2>



<p>In Bavaria, computer science (CS) has been a compulsory high school subject for over 20 years. However, a recent update has brought compulsory CS lessons (including AI) to Year 11 students (15–16 years old). Competencies targeted in the new curriculum include defining AI, explaining the functionality of different machine learning algorithms, and understanding how artificial neurons work.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1920" height="1280" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-04.jpg" alt="Two students are seated at a desk, collaborating on a computing task." class="wp-image-87821" style="width:640px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-04.jpg 1920w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-04-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-04-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-04-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-04-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-04-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-04-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-04-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /></figure></div>


<p>To help prepare teachers to effectively teach this new curriculum and about AI, Franz and colleagues derived a set of core competencies to be used along with existing frameworks (e.g. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1609/aaai.v33i01.33019795">the Five Big Ideas of AI</a>) and the Bavarian curriculum. The PD programme Franz and colleagues developed was shaped by a set of key design principles:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Blended learning</strong>: A blended format was chosen to address the need for scalability and limited resources and to enable self-directed and active learning&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Dual-level pedagogy (or ‘pedagogical double-decker’)</strong>: Teachers were taught with the same materials to be used in the classroom to aid familiarity</li>



<li><strong>Advanced organiser</strong>: A broad overview document was created to support teachers learning new topics&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Moodle</strong>: An online learning platform was used to enable collaboration and communication via a MOOC (massive open online course)</li>
</ol>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Analysing the effectiveness of the PD programme</strong></h2>



<p>Over 300 teachers attended the MOOC, which had an introductory session beforehand and a follow-up workshop. The programme’s effectiveness was evaluated with a pre/post assessment where teachers completed a survey of 15 closed, multiple-choice questions on their AI competencies and knowledge. Pre/post comparisons showed teachers’ scores improved significantly having taken part in the PD. This is surprising as a large proportion of participants achieved high pre-scores, indicating a highly motivated cohort with notable prior experience teaching about AI.</p>



<p>Additionally, a group of teachers (<em>n</em>=9) were invited to give feedback on which aspects of the PD programme they felt contributed to the success of implementing the curriculum in the classroom. They reported that the PD programme supported content knowledge and pedagogical content knowledge well, but they required additional support to design suitable learning assessments.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="612" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image.png" alt="" class="wp-image-89753" style="width:762px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image.png 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-300x115.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-500x191.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-768x294.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-1536x588.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-800x306.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-450x172.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-900x344.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">The design of the professional development programme</figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Using action research to aid AI teaching&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p>A separate strand of Franz’s research focuses on the other key challenge of how to effectively teach about AI. Franz engaged teachers (<em>n</em>=14) in action research, a method whereby teachers engage in classroom-based research projects. The project explored what topic-specific difficulties students faced during the lessons and how teachers adapted their teaching to overcome these challenges.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="864" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-1.png" alt="" class="wp-image-89754" style="width:760px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-1.png 1600w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-1-300x162.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-1-500x270.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-1-768x415.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-1-1536x829.png 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-1-800x432.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-1-450x243.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/04/image-1-900x486.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">The AI curriculum in Bavaria</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Findings revealed that students struggled with determining whether AI would benefit certain tasks (e.g. object recognition, text-to-speech) or not (e.g. GPS positioning, sorting data). Franz and colleagues reasoned that students were largely not aware of how AI systems deal with uncertainty and overestimated their capabilities. Therefore, an important step in teaching students about AI is defining ‘what an AI problem is’.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1225" height="816" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/03/image4.png" alt="A teenager learning computer science." class="wp-image-83499" style="width:644px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/03/image4.png 1225w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/03/image4-300x200.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/03/image4-500x333.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/03/image4-768x512.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/03/image4-800x533.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/03/image4-450x300.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/03/image4-900x600.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1225px) 100vw, 1225px" /></figure></div>


<p>Similarly, students struggled with distinguishing between rule-based and data-driven approaches, believing in some cases that a trained model becomes ‘rule-based’ or that all data models are data-driven. Students also struggled with certain data science concepts, such as hyperparameter, overfitting and underfitting, and information gain. Franz’s team argue that the chosen tool, Orange Data Mining, did not provide an appropriate scaffold for encountering these concepts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Finally, teachers found challenges in bringing real-world examples into the classroom, including the use of reinforcement learning and neural networks. Franz and colleagues reasoned that focusing on the function of neural networks, as opposed to their structure, would aid student understanding. The use of high-quality (i.e. well-prepared) real-world data sets was also suggested as a strategy for bridging theoretical ideas with practical examples.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Addressing the challenges of teaching AI</strong></h2>



<p>Franz’s research provides important insights into the discipline-specific challenges educators face when introducing AI into the classroom. It also underscores the importance of appropriate professional development and age-appropriate and research-informed materials and tools to support students engaging with ideas about AI, data science, and machine learning.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1397" height="918" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-21.jpg" alt="Students sitting in a lecture at a university." class="wp-image-87829" style="width:642px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-21.jpg 1397w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-21-300x197.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-21-500x329.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-21-768x505.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-21-800x526.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-21-450x296.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/07/ICS_Discovery-day-Queen-Mary_6.7.22-21-900x591.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1397px) 100vw, 1397px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Further reading and resources</strong></h2>



<p>If you are interested in reading more about Franz’s work on teacher professional development, you can read his paper on <a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/abs/10.1145/3626252.3630782">a scalable professional development offer for computer science teachers</a> or you can learn more about his <a href="https://www.edu.sot.tum.de/en/ddi/home/">research group here</a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Join our next seminar</strong></h2>



<p>In our current seminar series, we are exploring teaching about AI and data science. Join us at our next seminar on Tuesday 8 April at 17:00–18:30 BST to hear David Weintrop, Rotem Israel-Fishelson, and Peter F. Moon from the University of Maryland introduce ‘API Can Code’, an interest-driven data science curriculum for high-school students.</p>



<p>To sign up and take part in the seminar, click the button below; we will then send you information about joining. We hope to see you there.</p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-6 wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link wp-element-button" href="https://form.raspberrypi.org/f/research-seminar-sign-up" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">I want to join the next seminar</a></div>
</div>



<p>The <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research/seminars">schedule of our upcoming seminars</a> is online. You can catch up on past seminars on our <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/research/seminars/previous">previous seminars and recordings page</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/supporting-teachers-to-integrate-ai-in-k-12-cs-education/">Supporting teachers to integrate AI in K–12 CS education</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/supporting-teachers-to-integrate-ai-in-k-12-cs-education/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Empowering India&#8217;s digital future: Our computing curriculum&#8217;s impact</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/empowering-indias-digital-future-our-computing-curriculums-impact/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/empowering-indias-digital-future-our-computing-curriculums-impact/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben Durbin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 15:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Impact of our work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89727</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Raspberry Pi Foundation has been working in India since 2018 to enable young people to realise their potential through the power of computing and digital technologies.&#160; We’ve supported Code Clubs, partnered with government organisations, and designed and delivered a complete computing curriculum for students in grades 6 to 12 and at the undergraduate level.&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/empowering-indias-digital-future-our-computing-curriculums-impact/">Empowering India&#8217;s digital future: Our computing curriculum&#8217;s impact</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Raspberry Pi Foundation has been working in India since 2018 to enable young people to realise their potential through the power of computing and digital technologies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’ve supported Code Clubs, partnered with government organisations, and designed and delivered a complete computing curriculum for students in grades 6 to 12 and at the undergraduate level. Our curriculum is tailored to the Indian context, and we provide extensive support to help teachers deliver it effectively.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2560" height="1707" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1949-scaled.jpg" alt="Three female students at the Coding Academy in Telangana." class="wp-image-85245" style="width:704px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1949-scaled.jpg 2560w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1949-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1949-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1949-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1949-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1949-2048x1365.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1949-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1949-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2023/10/YP7_1949-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /></figure></div>


<p>In another <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/computing-curriculum-framework-adapting-to-indias-diverse-landscapes/">recent blog</a>, we shared in detail how we’ve created an impactful curriculum for India. We&#8217;re now excited to share our new report evaluating how our curriculum is being taught in Telangana and Odisha. This report demonstrates the impact we&#8217;ve had so far, highlighting our successes and the key lessons we have learnt.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Key findings from the evaluation</strong></h2>



<p>Our evaluations of how the curriculum is being taught show that teachers are well-equipped to deliver the curriculum and provide high-quality and accessible learning experiences that develop students’ computing knowledge and skills.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="767" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/IMG_20240927_150327741_HDR.jpg" alt="A group of students in a classroom." class="wp-image-89141" style="width:706px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/IMG_20240927_150327741_HDR.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/IMG_20240927_150327741_HDR-300x230.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/IMG_20240927_150327741_HDR-500x384.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/IMG_20240927_150327741_HDR-768x589.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/IMG_20240927_150327741_HDR-800x614.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/IMG_20240927_150327741_HDR-450x345.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/12/IMG_20240927_150327741_HDR-900x690.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>In Telangana, we partnered with the Telangana Social Welfare Residential Educational Institutions Society (TGSWREIS) to introduce our curriculum at the Coding Academy School and Coding Academy College. Our report found that all school and college teachers we trained agreed they felt confident teaching students using the resources provided. Students were very positive about the classes, and their assessment scores demonstrated strong learning outcomes: 77% of school students and 70% of college students achieved at least 60% of available marks.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1200" height="742" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/image.png" alt="" class="wp-image-89728" style="width:630px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/image.png 1200w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/image-300x186.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/image-500x309.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/image-768x475.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/image-800x495.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/image-450x278.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/image-900x557.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></figure></div>


<p>In Odisha, we worked with Learning Links Foundation and Quest Alliance, in partnership with Panchasakha Sikhya Setu (PSS) Abhiyan, to deliver the IT and Coding Curriculum (Kaushali) to students in grades 9 and 10. Our findings were also very positive:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>87% of teacher respondents agreed that the curriculum resources were high quality and useful for their teaching</li>



<li>91% felt more confident about teaching IT and coding due to the curriculum resources</li>



<li>93% of teachers agreed that the training helped them understand the curriculum&#8217;s structure, content, and objectives</li>



<li>89% felt confident in teaching the curriculum after the training</li>



<li>Teachers also reported a positive impact on their students, with almost all agreeing that it improved students&#8217; coding skills, digital literacy, and understanding of responsible digital citizenship</li>
</ul>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1370" height="742" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/image-1.png" alt="" class="wp-image-89729" style="width:628px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/image-1.png 1370w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/image-1-300x162.png 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/image-1-500x271.png 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/image-1-768x416.png 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/image-1-800x433.png 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/image-1-450x244.png 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/image-1-900x487.png 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1370px) 100vw, 1370px" /></figure></div>


<p>The report also highlights how students better understood how computing and coding are used in the world and developed an increased interest in pursuing careers in these fields.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Key factors for effective implementation</strong></h2>



<p>Our evaluations show the importance of several factors when launching a computing curriculum:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Aligning content with students&#8217; experience and interests:</strong> Content should be tailored to students&#8217; existing knowledge, culturally relevant, and follow industry standards to prepare them for employment</li>



<li><strong>Providing extensive support to teachers:</strong> This includes careful selection and training of master teachers, comprehensive training for teachers that considers their knowledge and experience, and ongoing support through webinars, calls, and classroom observations</li>



<li><strong>Ensuring sufficient quantity and quality of infrastructure:</strong> Adequate equipment and internet access are crucial for effective teaching and learning</li>
</ul>



<p>We are committed to always improving our approach to ensure that all young people in India have the opportunity to learn about computing.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Join us in shaping the future</strong></h2>



<p>You can read our new report <a href="https://static.raspberrypi.org/files/RPF_CurriculumProjects_India.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>. If you are interested in partnering with us or want to learn more about our mission, please contact <a href="mailto:india@raspberrypi.org" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">india@raspberrypi.org</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/empowering-indias-digital-future-our-computing-curriculums-impact/">Empowering India&#8217;s digital future: Our computing curriculum&#8217;s impact</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/empowering-indias-digital-future-our-computing-curriculums-impact/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Experience CS: a new way to teach computer science</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-cs-a-new-way-to-teach-computer-science/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-cs-a-new-way-to-teach-computer-science/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Philip Colligan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 17:04:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Experience CS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing education]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89689</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I am delighted to announce Experience CS, a free, integrated computer science curriculum for elementary and middle school students (8–14 years old) that will be available in June 2025.&#160; Experience CS enables educators to teach computer science through a standards-aligned curriculum that integrates computer science concepts and knowledge into core subjects like maths, science, languages,&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-cs-a-new-way-to-teach-computer-science/">Experience CS: a new way to teach computer science</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>I am delighted to announce Experience CS, a free, integrated computer science curriculum for elementary and middle school students (8–14 years old) that will be available in June 2025.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Experience CS enables educators to teach computer science through a standards-aligned curriculum that integrates computer science concepts and knowledge into core subjects like maths, science, languages, and the arts.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="651" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_025.jpg" alt="An educator helps students with a coding task." class="wp-image-89708" style="width:690px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_025.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_025-300x195.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_025-500x326.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_025-768x500.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_025-800x521.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_025-450x293.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_025-900x586.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>This cross-curricular and integrated approach is one of the most effective ways to provide younger students with an introduction to computer science and is increasingly important as the impact of digital technology reaches every corner of our lives. We also know that embedding CS in real-world contexts helps make it meaningful and relevant for students, which is essential if we are going to inspire kids from different backgrounds to want to learn more about computer science and technology.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Built by educators, for educators&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p>The team behind Experience CS includes educators with significant experience of teaching CS in elementary and middle school settings and everything we do is being informed by the world&#8217;s leading research into effective pedagogy as well as extensive testing and research in classrooms. This won&#8217;t stop when we launch. We will continue to develop and improve the curriculum and resources in response to feedback from teachers and students.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="668" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_020.jpg" alt="Two students use computers in a classroom." class="wp-image-89706" style="width:694px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_020.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_020-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_020-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_020-768x513.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_020-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_020-450x301.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_020-900x601.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>One of the most important design principles for Experience CS is that it can be used by any educator. You don&#8217;t need a CS qualification or any previous experience in teaching CS classes to deliver engaging and creative learning experiences for your students.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We will provide lesson plans, classroom resources, and an online platform that is designed to be easy and safe to use. We will also provide educators with professional development to help build their confidence, knowledge, and skills. You don&#8217;t need to adapt or amend the resources to use them, but you will be able to if you want to. We trust teachers to know what is best for their classrooms.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>A creative and safe learning experience&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p>Crucially, Experience CS will be a creative learning experience. We&#8217;ve all seen those apps and platforms that purport to teach computer science by having young people direct their favourite pop culture character around a maze. While those types of games can be fun, we think that they fail to convey the creative potential of computer science and leave more students feeling &#8220;why bother&#8221; rather than being inspired to learn more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why Experience CS includes self-directed creative projects using the popular programming platform Scratch, with clear instructions and endless opportunities for young people to express themselves creatively.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="668" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_027.jpg" alt="Students use their laptops in a classroom, supervised by a teacher. " class="wp-image-89715" style="width:702px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_027.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_027-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_027-500x334.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_027-768x513.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_027-800x534.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_027-450x301.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_027-900x601.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<p>We know that online safety is the most important consideration for schools, teachers, and parents, which is why we have built a version of Scratch that is safe for schools. That means it won&#8217;t have the community and sharing features that are so central to the full Scratch platform. It will come with simple and intuitive classroom management features that enable teachers to create accounts, set assignments, review progress, and provide feedback to students.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Free forever, for everyone</strong></h2>



<p>Our promise is that Experience CS will be available for teachers and students anywhere in the world to use for free, for as long as you need it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Initially, we are developing the curriculum and resources for the US and Canadian education systems and we will be mapping the lessons to national and local standards in both countries. The materials will all be available in English, French, and Spanish. We will also be focusing our professional development and support for schools in the US and Canada, including working with a fantastic network of educational partners.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="1334" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_0430.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-89719" style="width:524px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_0430.jpg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_0430-187x250.jpg 187w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_0430-500x667.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_0430-768x1025.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_0430-800x1067.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_0430-450x600.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_0430-900x1201.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Building on the legacy of CS First</strong><em>&nbsp;</em></h2>



<p>We are delighted that Experience CS is supported by Google and that we are able to build on the fantastic work that they have done over many years to support educators and students through CS First.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Google has today announced that CS First will no longer be available from June 30, 2025 and that they are recommending that their users should move over to Experience CS for the next school year. That is a huge vote of confidence from a team that really knows what they are talking about. I want to pay tribute to everyone at Google who has worked so hard over the years to support teachers and inspire students through CS First.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are looking forward to working with all of the CS First community to make sure that you are supported through the transition and set up ready to go for the start of the new school year. You can find out more about the support we will be offering by registering <a href="https://experience-cs.org/?utm_source=rpf&amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;utm_campaign=exp-cs-blog" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-cs-a-new-way-to-teach-computer-science/">Experience CS: a new way to teach computer science</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/experience-cs-a-new-way-to-teach-computer-science/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Three ways to help students learn about the impact of technology</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/three-ways-to-help-students-learn-about-the-impact-of-technology/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/three-ways-to-help-students-learn-about-the-impact-of-technology/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sway Grantham]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 15:09:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hello World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[impact of tech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89638</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As adults, it’s easy for us to see the impact technology has had on society and on our lives. Yet when I tell pupils that, within my lifetime, it wasn’t always illegal to hold your mobile phone to your ear and have a call while driving, they are horrified. They are living in the now&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/three-ways-to-help-students-learn-about-the-impact-of-technology/">Three ways to help students learn about the impact of technology</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As adults, it’s easy for us to see the impact technology has had on society and on our lives. Yet when I tell pupils that, within my lifetime, it wasn’t always illegal to hold your mobile phone to your ear and have a call while driving, they are horrified. They are living in the now and don’t yet have the perspective to allow them to see the change that has happened.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1500" height="1012" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/BARROWHILL_CC4282.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-89026" style="width:678px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/BARROWHILL_CC4282.jpg 1500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/BARROWHILL_CC4282-300x202.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/BARROWHILL_CC4282-500x337.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/BARROWHILL_CC4282-768x518.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/BARROWHILL_CC4282-800x540.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/BARROWHILL_CC4282-450x304.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2024/11/BARROWHILL_CC4282-900x607.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1500px) 100vw, 1500px" /></figure></div>


<p>With the greater understanding we now have of technology and its impact, we can better learn from previous mistakes, make decisions around ethical behaviour (such as whether to use a phone while driving), and critically engage in real-world issues.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As teachers, allocating some time to this topic throughout the year can seem challenging, but by implementing a few small changes, the benefits might be more than you imagine. Here are three ways you can help your students explore the impact of technology.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">1. <strong>Change the format of your lessons by stepping away from devices&nbsp;</strong></h3>



<p>As teachers know, some computing lessons work best when students don’t use devices, whether it’s a matter of students designing programs before starting to code them, drawing&nbsp; maps of their school network, or discussing the implications of bias in AI training models. It’s important that learners recognise that computers are tools — sometimes they allow us to do and achieve great things, but sometimes there are other approaches that are more suitable.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1778" height="1170" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_024.jpg" alt="A group of young people investigate computer hardware together." class="wp-image-81490" style="width:682px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_024.jpg 1778w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_024-300x197.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_024-500x329.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_024-768x505.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_024-1536x1011.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_024-800x526.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_024-450x296.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2022/09/ATHENS_CODE_CLUB_024-900x592.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1778px) 100vw, 1778px" /></figure></div>


<p>Spending time discussing the impact of technology can help learners decide for themselves when technology is an asset, and when it is a burden. Another advantage of changing the format of your computing lessons away from device usage is that they may appeal to a wider range of students. While some students may not be interested in using technology, they may enjoy debating ethics, discussing world events, or finding solutions to real-world problems — all of which can take centre stage in a more discussion-focused computing lesson.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>This approach can also demonstrate to your class that lots of different skill sets are needed in the computing industry, and inspire your learners to consider career paths they might have otherwise dismissed. In addition, open, discussion-based lessons can give your learners food for thought, encouraging them to approach tasks in subsequent lessons with a greater appreciation of broader issues — whether they’re designing a program, deciding what features to build into a website, or how to structure a database.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">2. <strong>Connect your lessons to real-world events</strong></h3>



<p>Young people exist in an interesting space when it comes to world events. Even if they’re not engaged in current affairs, they’ll probably still encounter a lot of content about what’s happening in the world. They may see snippets of news footage on television, hear adults talking about a big event, or — with so much of their lives now happening online — stumble across trending stories and associated opinions while using social media, apps, and websites.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2560" height="1707" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Hills-Road-Dojo__22-01-23-36-1-scaled.jpg" alt="Close up of two young people working at a computer." class="wp-image-89303" style="width:684px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Hills-Road-Dojo__22-01-23-36-1-scaled.jpg 2560w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Hills-Road-Dojo__22-01-23-36-1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Hills-Road-Dojo__22-01-23-36-1-500x333.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Hills-Road-Dojo__22-01-23-36-1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Hills-Road-Dojo__22-01-23-36-1-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Hills-Road-Dojo__22-01-23-36-1-2048x1365.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Hills-Road-Dojo__22-01-23-36-1-800x533.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Hills-Road-Dojo__22-01-23-36-1-450x300.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/01/Hills-Road-Dojo__22-01-23-36-1-900x600.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /></figure></div>


<p>Young people will often try to make sense of all these bits of information, filling in the blanks. The problem is that if we don’t talk to young people about what they’re hearing, they may fill in the blanks incorrectly. Before you know it, they might be anxious that artificial intelligence will take over the world, or that adults hate TikTok for no reason.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s important to equip young people with the skills to think about real-world events — and developments related to technology — critically and calmly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Headlines such as “Why the USA is banning TikTok” or self-help articles with titles like “Why muting people on social media will change your life” could make brilliant focus points for a lesson or activity about the impact of technology. Discussing these kinds of headlines and articles can help your learners consider their own opinions, apply what they know about how technology works, and gain a sense of grounding in our often turbulent world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>By encouraging your learners to articulate what they know and apply it to real-world situations, you’ll enrich their computing education while also nurturing responsible digital citizens.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">3. <strong>Encourage students to have difficult conversations</strong></h3>



<p>The role of a computing teacher is often broad. Beyond curriculum and teaching responsibilities, it will usually involve providing tech support (changing ink in printers, for instance) and dealing with safeguarding incidents that have happened between pupils at the weekend.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Safeguarding is a key part of teaching. Effective safeguarding should include teaching your learners about what to do in difficult scenarios, like when a WhatsApp group goes awry, when an image is shared on social media when it shouldn’t have been, or when a game becomes popular that your learners aren’t old enough to play.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="667" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/AdobeStock_782584541.jpeg" alt="Computing teachers often have to be prepared with a lesson to deal with safeguarding incidents, such as a WhatsApp group gone awry." class="wp-image-89641" style="width:669px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/AdobeStock_782584541.jpeg 1000w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/AdobeStock_782584541-300x200.jpeg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/AdobeStock_782584541-500x334.jpeg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/AdobeStock_782584541-768x512.jpeg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/AdobeStock_782584541-800x534.jpeg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/AdobeStock_782584541-450x300.jpeg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/AdobeStock_782584541-900x600.jpeg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Computing teachers often have to be prepared with a lesson to deal with safeguarding incidents, such as a WhatsApp group gone awry.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Each of these scenarios is an example of technology’s impact on our lives. It’s important that your learners know how to deal with these scenarios and can have different opinions while talking and listening to each other. Also, if your learners can do these things, it will make things easier in the future if you need to talk to a particular learner about something inappropriate they’ve done.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>By encouraging your learners to have difficult conversations, you’ll practise how to navigate the tension between legality, rules from home, and best-practice advice from external sources. You’ll also have lessons that you can refer back to: “Remember when we were discussing the TikTok ban? How might some of those conversations relate to this situation? What about when we discussed when to block people on games or on social media? Would that be appropriate here?”&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Raising awareness that the impact of technology can enrich lessons</strong></h2>



<p>Technology is going to continue to impact the lives of the pupils we work with, whether they can recognise that or not. Increasing their awareness of the impact technology is having, in both positive and negative ways, will enrich your lessons, show that content is relevant to your learners, and help protect them when they have to make their own critical decisions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are suggestions in this article to use with learners of all ages, but if you want more support on how to teach the topic with older learners, we have an online course for educators (<strong>helloworld.cc/impactoftech</strong>) and a unit of work for 14-year-olds (<strong>helloworld.cc/ks4impact</strong>).</p>



<p><em>A version of this article also appears in&nbsp;</em><a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/hello-world"><em>Hello World</em></a><em>&nbsp;issue 24.</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/three-ways-to-help-students-learn-about-the-impact-of-technology/">Three ways to help students learn about the impact of technology</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/three-ways-to-help-students-learn-about-the-impact-of-technology/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Celebrating young tech creators at Coolest Projects Ireland 2025</title>
		<link>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/celebrating-young-tech-creators-at-coolest-projects-ireland-2025/</link>
					<comments>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/celebrating-young-tech-creators-at-coolest-projects-ireland-2025/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sophie Ashford]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 10:52:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Coolest Projects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital making]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coolest projects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding for kids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coolest projects 2025]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.raspberrypi.org/?p=89619</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Earlier this month, young creators gathered at the Sport Ireland Campus National Indoor Training Centre in Dublin for Coolest Projects Ireland 2025, an inspiring showcase of creativity, coding, and problem solving. With more than 80 participants sharing over 60 incredible projects, this year’s event highlighted the passion and innovation of young creators from across Northern&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/celebrating-young-tech-creators-at-coolest-projects-ireland-2025/">Celebrating young tech creators at Coolest Projects Ireland 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Earlier this month, young creators gathered at the Sport Ireland Campus National Indoor Training Centre in Dublin for Coolest Projects Ireland 2025, an inspiring showcase of creativity, coding, and problem solving. With more than 80 participants sharing over 60 incredible projects, this year’s event highlighted the passion and innovation of young creators from across Northern Ireland and the Republic of Ireland.</p>



<p>The day offered the chance for young people to share their digital projects, engage with a like-minded community, chat with VIP judges, and take part in exciting coding activities like <a href="https://astro-pi.org/mission-zero" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Astro Pi Mission Zero</a>. The event was once again supported by Meta, who sponsored the new AI category, continuing their commitment to promoting the importance of digital skills to young people.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="375" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1648-500x375.jpg" alt="Photo of two young people showing the Coolest Projects judges their project at Coolest Projects Ireland 2025." class="wp-image-89620" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1648-500x375.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1648-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1648-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1648-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1648-2048x1536.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1648-800x600.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1648-450x338.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1648-900x675.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Celebrating creativity </strong></h2>



<p>Coolest Projects is a space for all digital projects, across all levels and categories, from hardware inventions to AI to Scratch. The event celebrates not just the finished products, but also the learning journeys of young creators and skills such as problems solving and creativity.</p>



<p>Helen Gardner, Programme Manager at the Raspberry Pi Foundation, shared her enthusiasm about this year’s showcase:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Returning to Dublin for Coolest Projects is always such a joy! It’s incredible to see the enthusiasm, creativity, and talent of young creators as they bring their ideas to life. This event is all about celebrating the community and inspiring the next generation of problem-solvers. It’s always so inspiring to witness their amazing projects and the energy they bring to the day!”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Participants at Coolest Projects Ireland included young people from schools, coding clubs such as Code Club and CoderDojo, and independent makers. Many were returning participants, excited to showcase their latest projects and connect with fellow creators. The sense of community and encouragement was felt throughout the event, with mentors, parents, and judges offering valuable support and feedback to support growth and celebrate achievements.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Spotlight on the judges favourites</strong></h2>



<p>This year, judges were particularly impressed with the originality and impact of the projects. We caught up with four of the creators to find out why being involved in Coolest Projects Ireland was important to them.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="375" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1896-500x375.jpg" alt="Photo of creators on stage at Coolest Projects Ireland alongside Meta judges." class="wp-image-89621" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1896-500x375.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1896-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1896-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1896-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1896-2048x1536.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1896-800x600.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1896-450x337.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1896-900x675.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<p><br>Sister duo, Riddhiba and Aarushiba, created Innovaid, a project that uses technology to improve safety at events.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“We wanted to solve a problem that was affecting a large number of people. Having read news articles, and having talked to people who have had bad experiences at concerts and large events, we wanted to solve this problem that has been ongoing for many years. Although technology has advanced rapidly in the past years, there are still flaws in large event management leading to incidents and deaths. We wanted to incorporate safety, medical aid, crowd management, and inclusivity.”</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Coolest Projects Ireland was an amazing experience for both of us, we got the opportunity to meet with so many people that were so passionate about technology and coding. We met many people who also wanted to make a change in society, or wanted to solve problems.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Coolest Projects also welcomed an AI category, supported by Meta, for the first time, which included Kirsty’s entry, A haon, dó, trí – Learn with me. Kirsty’s entry used machine learning to help learners master the Irish language in an engaging and interactive way. Kirsty shared a little about her journey with the project</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="667" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1748-500x667.jpg" alt="Photo of young creator Kirsty, with her A haon, dó, trí – Learn with me project." class="wp-image-89622" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1748-500x667.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1748-187x250.jpg 187w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1748-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1748-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1748-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1748-800x1067.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1748-450x600.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1748-900x1200.jpg 900w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1748-scaled.jpg 1920w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I really enjoyed some of the machine learning with Scratch projects on the <a href="https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/pathways/scratch-machine-learning" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Raspberry Pi site</a>. While doing the ‘Alien language’ project, it occurred to me that I could use a similar approach to build a game to help young kids learn Irish.”</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I had to build my own Irish language training data set so I recorded lots of speech samples from my school friends. However, I go to an all-girls school, which would have meant my training data would have been very limited! So I recorded some boys&#8217; voices at my CoderDojo to make my data set more varied and balanced.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In the Games category, Timi received acknowledgement for his project, Stakes &amp; Laughters Maximus.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I got the idea from a story my dad told me about when I was younger. I apparently got really upset when I lost a game of Snakes and Ladders. So, I wanted to make a Snakes and Ladders game that wasn&#8217;t just about luck. I wanted players to have to think strategically about how to use their luck.”</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“There were many challenges! Everything from the character movement to the turn system and the items presented roadblocks. But I broke through them by carefully thinking about what I wanted to achieve and then using code to create the logic for it.”</p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="387" src="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1583-500x387.jpg" alt="Photo of Timi's project - Stakes &amp; Laughters Maximus displayed on a monitor." class="wp-image-89623" srcset="https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1583-500x387.jpg 500w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1583-300x232.jpg 300w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1583-768x595.jpg 768w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1583-1536x1190.jpg 1536w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1583-2048x1586.jpg 2048w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1583-800x620.jpg 800w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1583-450x349.jpg 450w, https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_1583-900x697.jpg 900w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Get involved</strong></h2>



<p>The <a href="https://online.coolestprojects.org/events/cp-2025/gallery">Coolest Projects online showcase</a> is open for entries, providing young people worldwide the opportunity to share their digital creations.</p>



<p>We also have upcoming in-person events in the US, UK, and around the world thanks to our partner organisations. You can find out more and get involved with these through <a href="https://online.coolestprojects.org/take-part">the Coolest Projects website.</a></p>



<p>Finally, we want to say a huge thank you to everyone who made Coolest Projects Ireland 2025 such a fantastic experience! We can’t wait to see what young innovators create next year.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/celebrating-young-tech-creators-at-coolest-projects-ireland-2025/">Celebrating young tech creators at Coolest Projects Ireland 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/celebrating-young-tech-creators-at-coolest-projects-ireland-2025/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
